<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>prabhupada &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/prabhupada/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 15:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 06:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[braham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contradiction in vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scholar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ishwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prajapati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebuttal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refuted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi &#160; The Qur’an states that Allah has created everything, the Bible states that God has created it, every religion whether Islam or Christianity takes a firm stand about the creator of the universe. But Vedas seems to be confused as to who created the universe. Vedas doesn’t answer who is the &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Qur’an states that Allah has created everything, the Bible states that God has created it, every religion whether Islam or Christianity takes a firm stand about the creator of the universe. But Vedas seems to be confused as to who created the universe. Vedas doesn’t answer who is the creator. There is no unanimous statement about who really created the universe among Hindus, some say Shiva created this entire universe, some say Vishnu or his avatars created it, some claim Brahma created it, All these stories are of Puranas and Upanishads, but we have to see only what the Vedas says about the creator because Vedas are the oldest scripture of Hinduism. Vedas also makes blunder about the process of creation. I won’t be explaining Vedic verses briefly, verses are pretty easy to understand. Readers themselves can draw conclusions after reading the verses. I am using Hindi translations of Swami Karpatri, Shri Ram Sharma and Shripad Damodar.</p>
<p><span id="more-1192"></span></p>
<p>Veda mentions different gods as the creator of the universe, Rig Veda 2.20.1; 2.13.5 says Indra created the earth, Rig Veda 10.82.1 and Yajur Veda 17.25 says Vishwakarma created the heaven and earth, Rig Veda 10.190.3 says Dhatar created the heaven, earth, sun and the moon. Atharva Veda 9.5.20 says that the breast of the God Aja became the earth, we read in Purusha Sukta that the feet of the lord became the earth, all these Vedic verses contradict each other. Atharva Veda 13.1.6 states that Rohita created the heaven and earth. A verse states that Prajapati created the universe, another verse in Yajur Veda 14.30 states that Prajapati prayed to a Divine Speech and thence earth and heaven were produced. Some also say the creation took place after the association of father and daughter mentioned in Rig Veda 10.61.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Who created living creatures?</strong></p>
<p>Vedas is confused about who created the humans or all creatures, It’s mentioned in Yajur Veda</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 14.28 With one they praised; creatures were produced…With five they praised; beings were created</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="465" height="154" class="wp-image-7269" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra1.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.png 465w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-300x99.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 465px) 100vw, 465px" /></p>
<p>According to scholars, Prajapati prayed to a divine speech and after that creatures were produced, So Prajapati is the creator of living beings here. Rig Veda says it were Vedic deities Indra and Varuna who created all living creatures,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.82.5 O Indra-Varuna, as ye created all these creatures of the world by your surpassing might…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="443" height="167" class="wp-image-7270" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra2.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.png 443w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1-300x113.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 443px) 100vw, 443px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Atharva Vedas has another story, it says Vedic god Rohita created the creatures,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 13.1.52 Rohita made the earth to be his altar, heaven his Dakshina. Then heat he took for Agni, and with rain for molten butter he [Rohita] created every living thing [or universe].</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let’s analyse the Purusha Sukta. Purusha Sukta is often quoted to show the process of creation. Some Hindu scholars even say that scientists must read Purusha Sukta to know about the creation and cosmos, they say this Sukta is very unique. I can’t figure out what’s so unique about this Sukta. Later I found that its uniqueness lies in its riddles, It has so many contradictions. It’s about gods sacrificing Purusha and each of his body part becomes the creation. The word Purusha here may or may not denote Man. Purusha is literally translated as Man, but majority of scholars translates it (in this verse) as Supreme Soul (God), according to Mahidhara and Sayana it is Spirit or Man, other scholars translates it as Almighty God and Universe. If Purusha is the Almighty god then how come the Almighty God (Purusha) himself was born? Veda says,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.5 From him Viraj was born; again Purusa from Viraj was born…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7271" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra3.png?w=625" width="570" height="139" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.png 418w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2-300x73.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The word Viraj or Virat here is translated by some as universe. But scholars have different opinion on this word. Majority of scholars including Sayana and Mahidhara say it’s an egg. Some say it’s the egg from which the universe or Men were born, some also say it’s known as Adi Purusa. The word Viraj occurs in Atharva Veda 11.4.12 as Prana (Vital Spirit), in Atharva Veda 9.2.5 Viraj is translated as milch cow, and by Arya Samaj scholars as Splendid Speech [Goddess]. Some interpret Rig Veda 10.90.5 as, The almighty God created Viraj, and Viraj then created the Men (Purusha) or living creatures, they translate the latter word Purusha literally as Men. This is wrong since the creation of men and other living beings occurs in verses 8, 10 and 12. There is also a reference (Manu 3.195) which shows that Viraj had sons. Maharishi Manu also makes blunder about the creation which contradicts Vedas also, but on this Viraj issue he tries to make it simple saying that it was Brahma who produced Viraj, He writes</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 1.31-32 But for the sake of the prosperity of the worlds he caused the Brahmana, the Kshatriya, the Vaisya, and the Sudra to proceed from his mouth, his arms, his thighs, and his feet. Dividing his own body, the Lord became half male and half female; with that (female) he produced Virag.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So this affirms the statement of some scholars who say that Purusha is the unborn Almighty God and from him Viraj was born. But it makes the situation more complex because Vedas states in the beginning only Viraj was present and from him Purusha was born,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 19.6.9 In the beginning rose Viraj: Purusha from Viraj was born. As soon as he was born he spread westward and eastward o’er the earth.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="574" height="62" class="wp-image-7272" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra4.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.png 574w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3-300x32.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 574px) 100vw, 574px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now this is senseless and as complicated as the saying ”What came first the chicken or the egg?” This is a clear contradiction, because Purusha is unborn they say and from Purusha, Viraj was born. But this verse states the In the beginning rose (Sambhavat) Viraj and from him Purusha was born. To strengthen my argument I would like to quote next two verses of Atharva Veda 19.6.9 which would also clear the mist,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 19.6.10-11 When Gods performed the sacrifice with Purusha as their offering. Spring was the butter, summer was the fuel, autumn was the gift. That sacrifice, first-born Purusha, they hallowed with the sprinkled Rains. The Deities, the Sadhyas, all the Vasus sacrificed with him.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="602" height="141" class="wp-image-7273" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra5.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.png 602w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So this shows that the sacrificed Purusha was born from Viraj. Purusha was the first to take birth from Viraj. So how is it possible that the Almighty God (Purusha) himself was born from an egg (Viraj)?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Who was Sacrificed?</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.6 When Gods prepared the sacrifice with Purusa as their offering, Its oil was spring, the holy gift was autumn; summer was the wood.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="109" class="wp-image-7274" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra6.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Krishna Yajur Veda,</p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.3.5 The Sadhya gods were in this world and nothing else living. They offered Agni as a sacrifice to Agni [Fire], for they found nothing else to offer; thence indeed these creatures were born; in that he casts the fire on the fire after producing it, (it serves for) the propagation of offspring.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>How the creation of universe (or of earth) took place?</strong></p>
<p>While Purusha Sukta is often quoted, The Rig Veda 10.72 hymn is often ignored by the scholars. Both have similarity and difference. The similarity is that both these Suktas talk about how the creation took place and the difference is that both these Suktas give a complete different picture about creation of universe. According to Purusha Sukta the earth was gendered from the Almighty god’s feet (Rigved 10.90.14), while the 72<sup>nd</sup> hymn states that the earth was born from a tree,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.72.1-4 Let us proclaim with a clear voice the generations of the gods (the divine company), who, when their praises are recited, look (favourably on the worshipper) in this latter age. Brahmanaspati filled these (generations of the gods) with breath as a blacksmith (his bellows) in the first age of the gods the existent was born of the non-existent. In the first age of the gods the existent was born of the non-existent; after that the quarters (of the horizon) were born, and after them the upward-growing (trees). The earth was born from the upward-growing (tree), the quarters were born from the earth; Daksha was born from Aditi, and afterwards Aditi from Daksha. – Tr. Wilson</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="467" height="277" class="wp-image-7275" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra7.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.png 467w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6-300x178.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Founder of Arya Samaj Swami Dayanand Saraswati argued against the creation of universe out of nothing. He criticized the Qur’an’s concept of creation out of nothing which is similar to this 72<sup>nd</sup> hymn of Rigved Mandal 10. Hindu scholars gave more importance to the Purusha Sukta and rejected the 72<sup>nd</sup> Sukta. Both these Suktas of the same Rig Veda are contradictory.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>So who really created the universe?</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.6 When <strong>Gods</strong> prepared the sacrifice with Purusa as their offering, Its oil was spring, the holy gift was autumn; summer was the wood.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="90" class="wp-image-7276" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra8.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>Vedas doesn’t give the list of gods who sacrificed Purusha. But it’s mentioned in Atharva Veda 13.1.55 that Rohita brought the world which rose from the sacrifice (of Purusha). It either means that Rohita alone sacrificed Purusha or Rohita was among the gods or Rishis who sacrificed Purusha. Rohita is considered a sage in that verse. It’s mentioned in Rigved,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.129.6-7 Who verily knows and who can here declare it, whence it was born and whence comes this creation? The Gods are later than this world’s production. Who knows then whence it first came into being? He, the first origin of this creation, whether he formed it all or did not form it, Whose eye controls this world in highest heaven, <strong>he verily knows it, or perhaps he knows not</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="448" height="351" class="wp-image-7277" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra9.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.png 448w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8-300x235.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 448px) 100vw, 448px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda’s English translation,</p>
<p>”[6] Who knew the way? Who there declared Whence this arose? Projection whence? <strong>For after this projection came the gods</strong>. Who therefore knew indeed, came out this whence?</p>
[7] This projection whence arose, Whether held or whether not, He the ruler in the supreme sky, of this He, O Sharman! knows, or know not He perchance”- Rig Veda 10.129.6-7, Tr. Swami Vivekananda. [Source: <a href="http://www.swamivivekananda.org.in/main/e-library/hymns/the-hymn-on-creation/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.swamivivekananda.org.in/main/e-library/hymns/the-hymn-on-creation/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When Gods are later than this world’s production then who sacrificed Purusha? As we read in Purusha Sukta that it were the Gods who sacrificed Purusha. According to Vedas It was only after the sacrifice of Purusha that entire universe including this world came into existence. Manu also alludes that the Rishis were born after the creation of universe (Manu 1.34-35). So how is it possible that this creation took place without the gods? And who really sacrificed Purusha then?</p>
<p>When the Vedas which was believed by every Hindu god as highest authoritative text doesn’t have the answer about who really created the universe, then why do you believe it to be the word of god? Some may try to twist and turn these verses to hide the fallacies of Vedas, but truth will remain truth. They may deceive themselves but intellectuals will definitely find the truth. It is clear that the composer or God of Vedas is not the creator. Vedas juggles about the creator, but it’s not difficult to find the real creator of this world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lying in Hinduism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/lying-in-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 08:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deceit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[is lying allowed in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskcon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taqiyya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/lying-in-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Sulaiman Razvi Hindu god allows lying on five occasions especially while enjoying a woman, Krishna said, Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 98.38-44 &#8221;&#8230;Hari began to laugh and thus addressed Uddhava, using words of good import and worlds sanctioned by the Vedas, &#8221;O Uddhava, untruth spoken to women or on the sporting ground, or &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/lying-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Lying in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Hindu god allows lying on five occasions especially while enjoying a woman, Krishna said,<br />
Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 98.38-44 &#8221;&#8230;Hari began to laugh and thus addressed Uddhava, using words of good import and worlds sanctioned by the Vedas, &#8221;O Uddhava, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">untruth spoken to women or on the sporting ground</span></span>, or in an emergency which endangers life or for the good of the vows or the Brahmin is not contemptible&#8230;&#8221; Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen<br />
<span id="more-1973"></span><br />
Matysa Purana 31.16 &#8221;Sarmistha said:- &#8221;King! <span style="color: #ff0000;">there is no sin in speaking untruth at the time of indulging in sexual pleasure</span>s, on the occasion of marriage, when life is in danger, wealth is at stake, and in joke. Lying on these five occasions is venal.&#8221; Tr. Various Sanskrit Scholars, Edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p>Mahabharata 8.69 &#8221;In a situation of peril to life and in marriage, falsehood becomes utterable. In a situation involving the loss of one&#8217;s entire property, falsehood becomes utterable. On an occasion of marriage, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">or of enjoying a woman</span></span>, or when life is in danger, or when one&#8217;s entire property is about to be taken away, or for the sake of a Brahmana, falsehood may be uttered. These five kinds of falsehood have been declared to be sinless. On these occasions falsehood would become truth and truth would become falsehood.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.82 &#8220;Sarmishtha then said, &#8216;It hath been said, O king, that it is not sinful to lie on the occasion of a joke, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">in respect of women sought to be enjoyed</span></span>, on occasions of marriage, in peril of immediate death and of the loss of one&#8217;s whole fortune. Lying is excusable on these five occasions.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Vasishtha Samhita 16.35 (Men) may speak an untruth at the time of marriage, during dalliance, when their lives are in danger or the loss of their whole property is imminent, and for the sake of a Brâhmana; they declare that an untruth spoken in these five cases does not make (the speaker) an outcast.</p>
<p>Gautama Samhita 23.29 Some (declare, that) an untruth (spoken) at the time of marriage, during dalliance, in jest or while (one suffers severe) pain is venial.</p>
<p>So Krishna allows lying for personal benefits. No wonder why so many Hindu fanatics use lie and deceit to mock others. Many Hindus are unaware of these verses and they mock others by using their own invented lies. A verse in Rigved states that Vedic God Indra slew Sushna by Maya (deception),</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.11.7 &#8220;Thou slewest, Indra, by stratagems, the wily Sushna: the wise have known of this thy (greatness)&#8230;&#8221; Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati the founder of Arya Samaj wrote in his commentary on this verse,</p>
<p>&#8220;God commands that highly intelligent persons should overthrow enemies by using all legitimate means consisting of persuasion (Saam), bribery (Daam), Dand (punishment) and Bhed (polarization, divide and rule, blackmail)&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>This was also Chankya Niti, Chanakya wrote,</p>
<p>Arthashastra of Kautilya Chapter 10 &#8220;&#8230;Negotiation, bribery, causing dissension, and open attack are forms of stratagem (upaya)&#8230;Offering money is bribery (upapradana). Causing fears and suspicion as well as threatening is known as sowing dissesion. Killing, harassing, and plundering is attack (danda)&#8230;&#8221; Tr. R. Shamasastry</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati also advocates lying to propagate ones faith he writes,</p>
<p>“Now it must be understood that if it was the belief of Shankar that God and the human soul were identical and that the world was an illusion, it was not good; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">but if he had avowed this doctrine simply in order to refute Jainism more successfully, it was a little good</span><strong>.</strong>” Satyarth Prakash, by Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Chapter 11, Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>He means if one lies just to demean others faith in order to propagate the Vedic faith then it is a good thing. Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON had similar views,<br />
‘’According to Lord Śrī Caitanya Mahāprabhu, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Ś</span><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">rīpāda Śaṅkarācārya preached the Māyāvāda philosophy for a particular purpose. Such a philosophy was necessary to defeat the Buddhist philosophy</span></span> of the nonexistence of the spirit soul, but it was never meant for perpetual acceptance. It was an emergency. Thus Lord Kṛṣṇa was accepted by Śaṅkarācārya as the Supreme Personality of Godhead in his commentation on Bhagavad-gītā.’’ By A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada, Srimad Bhagavatam 3.4.20 <a href="http://www.vedabase.com/en/sb/3/4/20" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.vedabase.com/en/sb/3/4/20<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada also wrote,<br />
&#8220;In this regard, it is stated in the Padma Purana that Lord Siva appeared as a brahmana in the age of Kali to preach the Mayavada philosophy, which is nothing but a type of Buddhist philosophy. It is stated in Padma Purana: Lord Siva, speaking to Parvati-devi, foretold that he would spread the Mayavada philosophy in the guise of a sannyasi brahmana just to eradicate Buddhist philosophy. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">This sannyasi was Sripada Sankaracarya. In order to overcome the effects of Buddhist philosophy and spread Vedanta philosophy, Sripada Sankaracarya had to make some compromise with the Buddhist philosophy, and as such he preached the philosophy of monism, for it was required at that time</span></span>. Otherwise there was no need for his preaching Mayavada philosophy. At the present moment there is no need for Mayavada philosophy or Buddhist philosophy, and Lord Caitanya rejected both of them. This Krishna consciousness movement is spreading the philosophy of Lord Caitanya and rejecting the philosophy of both classes of Mayavadi. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Strictly speaking, both Buddhist philosophy and Sankara&#8217;s philosophy are but different types of Mayavada dealing on the platform of material existence. Neither of these philosophies has spiritual significance</span></span>. There is spiritual significance only after one accepts the philosophy of Bhagavad-gita, which culminates in surrendering unto the Supreme Personality of Godhead. Generally people worship Lord Siva for some material benefit, and although they cannot see him personally, they derive great material profit by worshiping him.&#8221; <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 4.24.17 </strong><a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.24.17" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.24.17<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>So both Swami Prabhupada and Dayanand says that it&#8217;s OK to lie and deceive to propagate ones faith. Also read <a href="/index.php/2015/06/25/hindu-god-is-a-cheat/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu god is a cheater</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/lying-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Lying in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption in Vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand saraswati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolation in hinduism vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskcon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda vs puranas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am reproducing some excerpts written by a Hindu scholar named Swami B.V. Giri. Who has proved Puranas and Itihas as part of the Vedas which is contrary to what Arya Samajis are promoting on the internet. He considers Puranas and Itihas to be the fifth Vedas, he has put forth this arguement on the &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am reproducing some excerpts written by a Hindu scholar named Swami B.V. Giri. Who has proved Puranas and Itihas as part of the Vedas which is contrary to what Arya Samajis are promoting on the internet. He considers Puranas and Itihas to be the fifth Vedas, he has put forth this arguement on the basis of Vedas and other scriptures. According to Swami Giri Vedas are corrupted and 94% of the Vedas are lost, the present Vedas contain only 6% of the original text and there is no use of Vedas in this age thus Puranas are much superior than Vedas.<br />
<span id="more-1960"></span><br />
Written by Swami B.V. Giri</p>
<p><strong>OBJECTION: In your arguments you have mostly quoted <em>purana-vakya</em> (quotes from Puranic texts) to substantiate your points. However, this is unacceptable. The <em>Vedas</em> are eternal as they emanate from the Lord Himself (<em>apaurusaya</em>), whereas the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>smrti-sastras</em>, although they give knowledge about God, are authored by men. They are auxiliary to the <em>Vedas</em> and hence their statements should be considered as secondary when compared to the statements made in the <em>Vedas</em>. Therefore, in order to validate your claims, you must give quotes from <em>sruti</em> only.</strong></p>
<p><strong>REFUTATION:</strong> That the <em>Vedas</em> are eternal and <em>apauruseya</em> is a fact that all <em>sampradayas</em>, including the school of Sankara, unanimously agree with. They constitute the means of receiving knowledge about the Absolute Truth. However, there are certain factors that make it practically impossible to study the <em>Vedas</em> in this age:</p>
<p id="pWEIpKn"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="288" height="239" class="size-full wp-image-7205  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23fe9dbeb17.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>  After Srila Vyasadeva divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four books (<em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em>), his disciples further divided them into 1,130 divisions. This is stated in the <em>Kurma Purana</em> (52.19-20):</p>
<p class="verse"><em>eka-vimsati-bhedena rg-vedam krtavan pura<br />
sakhanam satenaiva yajur-vedam athakarot</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sama-vedam sahasrena sakhanam prabibheda sah<br />
atharvanam atho vedam bibedha navakena tu</em></p>
<p class="translation">‘Previously the <em>Rg Veda</em> was divided into 21 sections, the <em>Yajur Veda</em> into 100 sections, the <em>Sama Veda</em> into 1,000 sections and the <em>Atharva Veda</em> into 9 divisions.’</p>
<p>Each division has 4 minor divisions, namely the <em>Samhitas, Brahmanas, Aranyakas</em> and <em>Upanisads.</em> Thus altogether the 4 <em>Vedas</em> contain 1,130 <em>Samhitas,</em> 1,130 <em>Brahmanas,</em> 1,130 <em>Aranyakas,</em> and 1,130 <em>Upanisads.</em> This makes a total of 4,520 divisions.<br />
At present, most of these texts have disappeared due to the influence of time. We can only find 11 <em>Samhitas</em>, 18 <em>Brahmanas</em>, 7 <em>Aranyakas</em> and 220 <em>Upanisads</em> which constitutes a mere 6% of the entire Vedic canon!</p>
<ol>
<li>Even if the <em>Vedas</em> were complete in there entirety, in order to understand them one must first study the <em>Vedangas</em> which includes <em>Siksa</em> (the science of phonetics), <em>Vyakarana</em> (grammatical rules), <em>Kalpa</em> (ritualistic rules), <em>Nirukta</em> (obscure word meanings), <em>Chanda</em> (Metres for chanting Vedic hymns), and <em>Jyotisa</em> (astrology and astronomy).</li>
<li>Since the language of the <em>Vedas</em> is enshrouded in mysterious meanings, one must also be willing to sacrifice years of study in order to learn <em>Vaidika</em> (classical) Sanskrit. This entails primarily learning the basic grammar (which generally takes 12 years or so) and then memorising extra vocabulary in order to decipher the mystical language of the <em>Vedas</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">1</span></li>
</ol>
<p>Apart from that, it is practically impossible for those born in the age of Kali (who are generally ‘<em>mandah sumanda-matayo</em>’) to memorise even the slightest thing. What to speak of the entire <em>Vedas</em> or even the 6% that still survives today! At present, amongst the <em>brahmana</em> communities in India, it is generally observed that <em>vedadhyayana</em> simply consists of memorising the text of one of the four <em>Vedas</em> ‘parrot-fashion’, but as we can see from above, there is much more to it than that. Therefore, we may conclude that although the <em>Vedas</em> are perfect <em>sabda-pramana</em>, it is impractical to become thoroughly conversant with the <em>Vedas</em> in this day and age in order to understand the Supreme. Hence the solution lies in the <em>Puranas</em> and the <em>Itihasas.</em> This is explained in the following verse &#8211;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em> bharata-vyapadesena hyamnayarthah pradarsitah<br />
vedah pratisthah sarve sarve purane natra samsayah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;On the pretext of writing the <em>Mahabharata</em>, Vyasa explained the meaning of the <em>Vedas</em>. Certainly all the topics of the <em>Vedas</em> have been established in the <em>Puranas.</em>&#8221; (<em>Visnu Purana</em>)</p>
<p>Furthermore, it is explained in the <em>Mahabharata</em> (<em>Adi Parva</em> 1.267) and <em>Manu Samhita</em> –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>itihasa puranabhyam vedam samupabrmhayet</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; One must complement one’s study of the <em>Vedas</em> with the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>In the <em>Prabhasa-khanda</em> of the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (5.3.121-124) it is said –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>veda-van niscalam manye puranartham dvijottamah<br />
vedah pratisthitah sarve purane natra samsayah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>bibhety-alpa-srutad vedo mam ayam calayisyati<br />
itihasa-puranais tu niscalo’yam krtah purah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yan na drstam hi vedesu tad drstam smrtisu dvijah<br />
ubhayor yan na drstam hi tat puranah pragiyate<br />
yo veda caturo vedan sangopanisado dvijah<br />
puranam naiva janati na ca sa syad vicaksana</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; O best of the <em>brahmanas</em>, the meaning of the <em>Puranas</em> is unchanging just like that of the <em>Vedas</em>. The <em>Vedas</em> are all sheltered within the <em>Puranas</em> without a doubt. The <em>Veda</em> has a fear that unqualified people will read her and then distort her meaning. Thus, the significance of the <em>Veda</em> was fixed in the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas.</em> That which is not found in the <em>Vedas</em> is found in the <em>Smrti</em>. That which is not found in the <em>Smrti</em> is to be found in the <em>Puranas</em>. Those who know even the <em>Vedas</em> and <em>Upanisads</em> are not learned if they do not know the <em>Puranas</em>.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="AUanNYs"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="262" height="155" class="size-full wp-image-7206  alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23febf07008.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> The reason they are called ‘<em>Puranas</em>’ is because they make the <em>Vedas</em> complete (<em>puranat puranam iti canyatra</em>). This is not to suggest that the <em>Vedas</em> are incomplete. It simply means that the <em>Puranas</em> are explanatory supplements which aid one to understand the concise and ambiguous passages in the <em>Vedas.</em> If the <em>Puranas</em> complete the <em>Vedas</em>, it is only logical that they must be Vedic in nature.<br />
Our Tattvavadi friends have stated that <em>Puranic</em> evidence is secondary to those statements of the <em>sruti</em> because they are composed by mortals. Generally it is correct to state that the <em>sruti</em> is primary and the <em>smrti</em> secondary in that it (<em>sruti</em>) seeks to elaborate on the meaning of the <em>smrti.</em> However, under the circumstances, the <em>puranas</em> and <em>itihasas</em> are now to be considered primary evidence. As regards the mortal composition of the <em>puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em>, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">2</span> we beg to differ with this view, on the basis of the following references in the <em>sruti-sastras</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>rcah samani chandamsi puranam yajusa saha<br />
ucchistaj-jajnire sarve divi deva divi-sritah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Rg, Sama, Yajur</em> and <em>Atharva</em> became manifest from the Lord, along with the <em>Puranas</em> and all the Devas residing in the heavens.&#8221; (<em>Atharva Veda</em> 11.7.24)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sa brhatim disam anu vyacalat tam itihasas ca puranam ca gathas ca itihasasya ca sa vai puranasya ca gathanam ca narasamsinam ca priyam dhama bhavati ya evam veda</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;He approached the <em>brhati</em> meter, and thus the <em>Itihasas, Puranas, Gathas</em> and <em>Narasamsis</em> became favorable to him. One who knows this verily becomes the beloved abode of the <em>Itihasas, Puranas, Gathas</em> and <em>Narasamsis</em>.&#8221; (<em>Atharva Veda</em> 15.6.10–12)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>evam ime sarva veda nirmitah sa-kalpah sa-rahasyah sa-brahmanah sopanisatkah setihasah sanvakhyatah sa-puranan</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;In this way, all the <em>Vedas</em> were manifested along with <em>the Kalpas, Rahasyas, Brahmanas, Upanisads, Itihasas, Anvakhyatas</em> and the <em>Puranas.&#8221;</em> (<em>Gopatha Brahmana, purva</em> 2.10)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>nama va rg-vedo yajur-vedah sama-veda atharvanas caturtha itihasa-puranah pancamo vedanam vedah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Indeed, <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em> are the names of the four <em>Vedas.</em> The <em>Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> are the fifth <em>Veda.&#8221; (Kauthumiya Chandogya Upanisad 7.1.4)</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>asya mahato bhutasya nihsvasitam etad yad rg-vedo yajur-vedah sama<br />
vedo’tharvangirasa itihasah puranam ityadina</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O Maitreya, the <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva Vedas</em> as well as the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> all manifest from the breathing of the Lord.&#8221; <em>(Madhyandina-sruti, Brhad-aranyaka Upanisad</em> 2.4.10)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From these above <em>sruti</em> statements it is clear that the <em>puranas</em> are part of the <em>Vedas</em> and originate from the same source as the <em>Vedas</em>, namely the Supreme Lord Himself. One may argue that since the <em>Puranas</em> have names such as <em>Skanda, Agni, Markandeya</em> etc. they must have been composed by those personalities, therefore they are not eternal and thus cannot be apauruseya. However, if that is the case, then certain sections of the <em>Vedas</em> must also be considered to be <em>pauruseya-vakya</em> since they have names like <em>Katha</em> <em>Upanisad, Aitareya Upanisad</em> (Katha and Aitareya being names of sages). It is understood that certain parts of the <em>Vedas</em> are named after certain <em>rsis,</em> not because they composed them, but because they were the main exponents of those portions. Since persons with the names <em>Katha</em> and <em>Aitareya</em> appear in every millenium, one should not misunderstand that before the appearance of those persons described in the <em>Vedas</em>, these names were simply meaningless words.</p>
<p id="nPGgFwG"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="252" height="171" class="size-full wp-image-7207  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23fed3311f7.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> Similarly many of the <em>Puranas</em> are named after the first person who expounded them. Many times however, due to the influence of time, a scripture may become forgotten on this planet and thus a deva or sage speaks it again, and it becomes known by that name. Such an example is found in the <em>Bhagavatam</em> wherein the sun-god imparts the <em>Vajasaneyi-samhita</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> to Yajnavalkya Muni –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>atha ha bhagavams tava carana-nalina-yugalam tri-bhuvana-gurubhir<br />
abhivanditam aham ayata-yama-yajus-kama upasaramiti.</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>evam stutam sa bhagavan vaji-rupa-dharo ravih<br />
yajumsy ayata-yamani munaye ’dat prasaditah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Therefore, O lord, with prayers I approach your two lotus feet, which are adored by the preceptors of the three worlds, because I wish to receive from you <em>mantras</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> that are unknown to anyone else.&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Being pleased by such exaltation, the sun-god took the form of a horse and presented to the <em>muni</em> <em>mantras</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> which were previously unknown to any mortal.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 12.6.72-73)</p>
<p>In his treatise Visnu Tattva Vinirnaya, Sri Madhva, quoting Brahmanda Purana explains thus:</p>
<p class="verse"><em>puranani tadarthani sarge sarge’nythaiva tu<br />
kriyante’tastvanityani tadarthah purva-sargavat<br />
vedanam srsthivakyani bhaveyurvyaktyapeksaya<br />
avantarabhimananam devanam va vyapeksaya<br />
nanityatvat kutastesamanityatvam sthiratmanam</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, the <em>Puranas</em> are supposed to explain the meaning of the <em>Vedas</em> and are only different by the changes in words, chanda (metre), rsi, sequence etc. at the beginning of each creation. In this way they are considered to be non-eternal, but their meaning will be the same as in the previous creation.<br />
Therefore Madhva categorizes the <em>Puranas</em> as <em>‘nitya-anitya’</em> because they originally emanate from the Supreme Lord, but they are sometimes unmanifest.<br />
As a side note, it may be asked that if the <em>Puranas</em> are indeed subsidiary to the <em>sruti-sastras,</em> why does Sri Madhvacarya himself quote them so often in his works? Not only that, he even uses <em>puranic</em> evidence in order to establish the <em>nityatva</em> of the <em>Vedas!</em> If the <em>Puranas</em> are not eternal and <em>apauruseya,</em> why would he use their ‘secondary statements’ as a <em>pramana</em> to validify something which is superior?<br />
Another point is that in the chanting of the <em>Brahma-yajna</em> (formal study of the <em>Vedas</em>), the <em>Puranas</em> are included. If they were not <em>Vedic</em> in nature they would not be included. Therefore the <em>Taittiriya Aranyaka</em> (2.9) states <em>yad brahmananitihasa-puranani</em>: &#8220;The <em>Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> are <em>Vedas.&#8221;</em><br />
It has already been stated above in the quote from <em>Chandogya Upanisad</em> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">3</span> that the <em>Puranas</em> are known as the fifth Veda. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">4</span> The reason behind this is because the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em> are derived originally from the <em>Yajur Veda.</em> This is explained by <em>Sri Suta</em> in the <em>Vayu Purana-</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>itihasa-purananam vaktaram samyag eva hi<br />
mam caiva pratijagraha bhagavan isvarah prabhuh<br />
eka asid yajur-vedas tam caturdha vyakalpayat<br />
catur-hotram abhut tasmins tena yajnam akalpayat<br />
adhvaryavam yajurbhis tu rgbhir hotram tathaiva ca<br />
audgatram samabhis caiva brahmatvam capyatharvabhih<br />
akhyanais capyupakhyanair gathabhir dvija-sattamah<br />
purana-samhitas cakre puranartha-visaradah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yac-chistam tu yajur-veda iti sastrartha-nirnayah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That almighty Lord (Sri Vyasa) chose me as the qualified speaker of the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em>. In the beginning there was only one <em>Veda</em> – the <em>Yajur Veda</em>. This was divided into four portions. From these stemmed the four performances known as the <em>catur-homa</em> by which he (Vyasa) arranged for the performance of sacrifice. The <em>Adhvaryu</em> priest uses the <em>Yajur mantras,</em> the <em>Hotra</em> priest uses the <em>Rg mantras,</em> the <em>Udgata</em> priest uses the <em>Sama mantras,</em> and the <em>Brahma</em> priest uses the <em>Atharva mantras.</em></p>
<p class="translation">O best of all the <em>brahmanas</em>, after this he (Vyasa) who understands the meaning of the <em>Puranas</em>, compiled them and the <em>Itihasas</em> by combining various <em>akhyanas, upakhyanas</em> and <em>gathas</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">5</span> Whatever remained after Vyasa had divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four divisions was considered to also be the <em>Yajur Veda.</em> Thus is the conclusion of the <em>sastras.&#8221; </em>(<em>Vayu Purana</em> 60.16-18, 21-22)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The statement of Sri Suta Gosvami in the above verse from <em>Vayu Purana</em> in which he says that ‘Whatever remained after Vyasa had divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four divisions was considered to also be the <em>Yajur Veda</em>’ indicates that the essence of the original <em>Purana</em> (which was the remaining part of the <em>Yajur Veda</em>) became the condensed version of the <em>Purana</em> consisting of four-hundred-thousand <em>slokas</em>, available on the earth-planet.<br />
Further evidence for this is found in the <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.8-9)wherein the Lord says –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>kalenagrahanam matva puranasya dvijottamah<br />
vyasa-rupam aham krtva samharami yuge yuge</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O best of the <em>brahmanas</em>, understanding that the <em>Purana</em> would gradually become forgotten, in every <em>yuga</em> I appear in the form of Vyasa and condense it.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the next <em>sloka</em> of that <em>Purana</em>, the Lord continues –</p>
<p class="verse"><em> catur-laksa-pramanena dvapare dvapare sada<br />
tad astadasadha krtva</em> <em>bhur-loke’smin prabhasyate<br />
adyapyamartya-loke tu sata-koti-pravistaram<br />
tad artho’tra catur-laksah sanksepena nivesitah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Purana</em> contains four-hundred-thousand verses which is divided into eighteen parts. These are passed on via oral tradition every Dvapara-yuga on the earth-planet. Even today the original <em>Purana</em> which consists of one-billion verses exists in the heavenly planets. The essential meaning of that <em>Purana</em> is contained in the smaller version of four-hundred-thousand verses.&#8221;</p>
<p>The same point is raised in the <em>Vayaviya Samhita</em> (7.1.1. 37-38) –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sanksipya caturo vedams caturdha vyabhajat prabhuh<br />
vyasta-vedataya khyato veda-vyasa iti smrtah<br />
puranam api sanksiptam· catur-laksa-pramanatah<br />
adyapyamartya-loke tu sata-koti-pravistaram</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sanksiptam ityatra teneti sesah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That Lord who is most intelligent then divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four. He therefore became known as Veda Vyasa. He also summarized the <em>Puranas</em> into four-hundred-thousand verses which are still available in the heavenly domain in the form if one billion verses.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, it should be explained that although the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em> are known as the fifth <em>Veda —</em> that does not mean that they are literally identical in all ways with the <em>Vedas</em>. If that were so, <em>Purana</em> and <em>Itihasa</em> would just be names of certain sections of the <em>Vedas</em>. The difference between them is in annotation and the order of words. The <em>Vedas</em> are chanted in a particular style involving three tone accents (<em>svaras</em>) called <em>udatta</em>, <em>anudatta</em> and <em>svarita</em>. If a word is chanted in the wrong accent, the whole meaning of the sentence can change.<br />
As regards the order of words, the <em>Vedas</em> maintain a particular sequence which has not changed since the dawn of creation. There is no scope for even the slightest change in the Vedic texts, whereas the texts of the <em>Puranas</em> change according to <em>kalpa-bheda</em>. It is for this reason that we find occasional differencies in certain editions of the <em>Puranas.</em><br />
Another distinction between the <em>Vedas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> is that although the <em>Puranas</em> are considered part of the <em>Brahma-yajna</em>, they are not used in the performance of Vedic sacrifices.<br />
Unfortunately, major problems also arise when trying to studsy the <em>Puranas.</em> Firstly, although the <em>Puranas</em> are much more accessible than the <em>Vedas</em> and more readily available, they too are not available in their entirety. The eighteen <em>Puranas</em> and eighteen <em>Upa-Puranas</em> are a vast body of literature and there are so many different versions that it is difficult to know which editions are complete and which texts have been interpolated. This is due to the fact that there are no current disciplic schools nor bona-fide commentaries for most of these works.<br />
Secondly, we can understand that independent study of the <em>Puranas</em> yields no fruit since each seems to establish a different deity as Supreme. By studying the <em>Puranas</em> without proper guidance, the result is only confusion. <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.65, 68-69) states –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>pancangam ca puranam syad akhyanam itarat smrtam<br />
sattvikesu ca kalpesu mahatmyam adhikam hareh<br />
rajasesu ca mahatmyam adhikam brahmano viduh<br />
tadvad agnes ca mahatmyam tamasesu sivasya ca<br />
sankirnesu sarasvatyah pitrnam ca nigadyate</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; A <em>Purana</em> consists of five elements, as opposed to an <em>Akhyana</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">6</span> The <em>sattvika</em> <em>Puranas</em> glorify Hari; the <em>rajasika Puranas</em> glorify Brahma, and the <em>tamasika</em> <em>Puranas</em> glorify Siva and Agni. <em>Puranas</em> dealing with mixed modes of nature glorify Sarasvati and the fore-fathers.&#8221; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">7</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The divisions of the eighteen <em>Puranas</em> is defined by Lord Siva to Uma in the <em>Padma Purana</em> (<em>Uttara Khanda</em> 236.18-21):</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>vaisnavanam naradiyam ca tatha bhagavatam subham<br />
garudam ca tatha padmam varaham subha-darsane</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sattvikani puranani vijneyani subhani vai<br />
brahmandam brahma-vaivarta markandeyam tathaiva ca<br />
bhavisyam vamanam brahmam rajasani nibodha me<br />
matsyam kaurmam tatha laingam saivam skandam tathaiva ca<br />
agneyam ca sad etani tamasani nibodha me</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; O beautiful lady, one should know that the <em>Visnu, Naradiya, Bhagavata, Garuda, Padma</em> and <em>Varaha</em> are all in the mode of goodness. The <em>Brahmanda, Brahma-vaivarta, Markandeya, Bhavisya, Vamana</em> and <em>Brahma</em> are in the mode of passion. The <em>Matsya, Kurma, Linga, Siva, Skanda</em> and <em>Agni</em> are in the mode of ignorance.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sri Krsna has clearly expressed in <em>Bhagavad-gita</em> that goodness is superior to passion and ignorance. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">8</span> Similarly, Sri Suta Gosvami explains in the <em>Bhagavata</em>(1.2.24) that &#8220;Passion is better than ignorance because it can lead to realization of the Absolute Truth.&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">9</span> In this verse Suta speaks about which type of worship produces the ultimate benefit, and his conclusion is that one can only achieve the best result by worshipping Lord Visnu. The <em>sattvika Puranas</em> recommend the worship of Visnu / Krsna, whereas the <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas</em> advocate the worship of minor deities and therefore do not lead the aspirant towards the Absolute Truth.<br />
It is noteworthy that the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> commence with a questioner inquiring from a learned speaker about the nature of the Absolute. The speaker’s answers are clear, direct and unambiguous, leaving no room for misinterpretation. However, in the <em>tamasika</em> and <em>rajasika Puranas</em> questions are put to the speaker which do not pertain to the Absolute Truth. For example, in the <em>Linga Purana</em> the sages request Suta to speak about the glories of the Lingam form of Lord Siva. We may conclude from this that although Sri Suta Gosvami is learned in transcendental subject matters and expert in explaining them, the questions by the sages here restrict him from speaking on it. All <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika</em> <em>Puranas</em> contain this characteristic defect and therefore are not reliable sources of transcendental knowledge.<br />
One may ask at this point why Srila Vyasadeva wrote these <em>Puranas.</em> According to the various desires of the materially conditioned <em>jivas</em>, he arranged the <em>Puranas</em>. Nevertheless, all <em>Puranas</em> contain glorification of Lord Visnu. This was included by Vyasa in order that those in the lower modes of passion and ignorance will slowly develop interest in the Supreme Lord Hari while studying the <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas.</em> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">10</span>Therefore in the <em>Hari Vamsa</em> (3.323.34)it is said –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>vede ramayane caiva purane bharate tatha<br />
adav-ante ca madhye ca harih sarvatra giyate</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;In the <em>Vedas</em>, the <em>Ramayana, Puranas</em> and <em>Mahabharata</em>, from the very beginning to the end, as well as within the middle, only Hari, the Supreme Personality of Godhead, is explained.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yet it must be understood that although <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas</em> do not speak extensively on the Absolute Truth, this does not mean that they give no valid knowledge at all. If this was the case why would <em>acaryas</em> such as Madhva cite from <em>Puranas</em> such as <em>Skanda, Brahma, Brahmanda, Brahma-vaivarta</em> etc which are not <em>sattvika</em> by nature? The <em>Puranas</em> in the lower modes may also give some insight into the Absolute Truth, although not to the same extent as the <em>sattvika Puranas.</em><br />
By this we may conclude that the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> are the ultimate <em>pramana</em>. This is also declared by the <em>Padma Purana &#8211; sattvika moksa-dah proktah: </em>&#8220;The <em>sattvika Puranas</em> give salvation.&#8221; Unfortunatly, as stated before, there are no current disciplic schools nor bona-fide commentaries for most of these works. Some of the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> recommend the path of <em>bhakti,</em> while others glorify the path of <em>jnana</em> or <em>yoga.</em><br />
One possibility to resolve this dilemma is to study the <em>Vedanta-sutra</em>. This work of Vyasadeva contains the essence of the <em>Vedas</em> and the <em>Puranas.</em> Still, the language of the <em>Vedanta-sutras</em> is ambiguous to say the least, and has therefore been interpreted in a number of ways by numerous scholars ( Madhva, Sankara, Ramanuja, Bhaskara, Bodhayana, Dramida, Guhadeva to name but a few). The foundations of many of the <em>sutras</em> lie in Upanisadic passages, yet Vyasa does not mention in his work as to which passages the particular <em>sutra</em> is commenting on. Thus both the student and the commentator must determine this for themselves. It is no wonder then that Vedavyasa felt discontent even after compiling the <em>Vedas</em>, <em>Puranas</em>, <em>Mahabharata</em> and <em>Vedanta-sutra &#8211;</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>tathapi bata me daihyo hy atma caivatmana vibhuh<br />
asampanna ivabhati brahma-varcasya sattamah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;I am feeling incomplete, although I am fully equipped with everything required by the <em>Vedas</em>.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 1.4.30)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The reason for his discontentment was then explained by Narada Muni –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>jijnasitam susampannam api te mahad-adbhutam<br />
krtavan bharatam yas tvam sarvartha-paribrmhitam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;You have completed your inquiries and your studies in the proper fashion, and you have written a great and wonderful work, the <em>Mahabharata</em>, which elaborately explains the different goals of life.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 1.5.3)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>bhavatanudita-prayam yaso bhagavato ’malam<br />
yenaivasau na tusyeta manye tad darsanam khilam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;You have not actually broadcast the sublime and spotless glories of the Personality of Godhead. That philosophy which does not satisfy the transcendental senses of the Lord is considered worthless.&#8221;</p>
<p class="verse"><em>yatha dharmadayas cartha muni-varyanukirtitah<br />
</em><em>na tatha vasudevasya mahima hy anuvarnitah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O best of sages, since you have broadly described the four goals of human life beginning with religious performances, you have not described the glories of the Supreme Personality, Vasudeva.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em>1.5.8-9)</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="dKlyYWY"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="180" height="257" class="size-full wp-image-7208  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23feed43e2f.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> On the advice of Narada, Vyasa meditated and the <em>Bhagavata</em> was manifest to him. This is the natural commentary of Vyasa’s own <em>sutras</em> (<em>artho’yam brahma-sutranam</em>) and thus includes the purport of the entire <em>Vedic</em> literature (<em>vedartha-paribrmhitah</em>) It is free from the problems that we find with the <em>Vedas</em> and the other <em>Puranas</em> – it is available in it’s entirety, it has commentated upon by various Vaisnava <em>acaryas</em>, it is divinely composed and <em>Puranic</em> in nature. In it’s opening <em>sloka</em> it gives the essence of the <em>Vedas</em> since it begins with the holy <em>gayatri mantra·</em> (<em>gayatri-bhasya-rupo ’sah</em>) which is itself the essence of the <em>vedas.</em> This is also confirmed in the <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.20-22) and <em>Agni Purana</em> (272.6.7) &#8211;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>yatradhikrtya gayatrim vamyate dharma-vistarah<br />
vrtasura-vadhopetam tad bhagavatam istyate</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>likhitva tac ca yo dadyad dhema-simha-samanvitam<br />
prausthapadyam paurnamasyam sa yati paramam gatim<br />
asta-dasa-sahasrani puranam tat prakirtitam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That <em>purana</em> is known as the <em>Bhagavata</em> which gives the highest religious principles, refers to the sacred <em>gayatri mantra</em>, and tells the story of the slaying of Vrtasura. This <em>purana</em> has 18,000 verses and whoever writes down the entire text and places it on a golden throne and gives it in charity to a qualified person on the day of the full-moon of the month of Bhadra will attain the Supreme abode.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Most importantly, the <em>Bhagavata</em> is the crowning glory of the divine author’s literary efforts, soothing his heart when he felt that his work remained incomplete.<br />
There are many verses that praise the <em>Bhagavata</em> above all the other <em>Puranas.</em> In the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (<em>Visnu-khanda</em> 6.4.3) it says –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>srimad bhagavatasyatha srimad bhagavatah sada<br />
svarupam ekam evasti sac-cid-ananda-laksana</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> and the Supreme Lord are always of the same nature – possessed of eternal existence, knowledge and bliss.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the <em>Visnu Khanda</em> of the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (5.16.40-42, 44,33) –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sataso &#8216;tha sahasrais ca kim anyaih sastra-samgrahaih<br />
na yasya tisthate gehe sastram bhagavatam kalau</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>katham sa vaisnavo jneyah sastram bhagavatam kalau<br />
grhe na tisthate yasya sa viprah svapacadhamah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yatra yatra bhaved vipra sastram bhagavatam kalau<br />
tatra tatra harir yati tridasaih saha narada</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yah pathet prayato nityam slokam bhagavatam mune<br />
asta-dasa-purananam phalam prapnoti manavah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;If the <em>Bhagavata</em> is not kept in one&#8217;s house in the Kali Yuga, of what avail are collections of other scriptures by the hundreds and thousands? How can he be condidered a Vaisnava who, in the Kali Yuga, does not keep the <em>Bhagavata</em> in his house? Even if he is a <em>brahmana,</em> he is lower than an outcaste. O Narada, O Sage, wherever the <em>Bhagavata</em> is found in the Kali-yuga, there Hari goes together with all the demigods. O Muni, that pius soul who daily recites a verse from the <em>Bhagavata</em> reaps the fruits of the eighteen <em>Puranas</em>.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the <em>Padma Purana</em> (<em>Uttara-khanda</em> 193.3)</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>puranesu tu sarvesu srimad bhagavatam param<br />
yatra prati-padam krsno giyate bahudharsibhih</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Of all the <em>puranas</em>, the <em>Bhagavata</em> is the greatest. In every line the sages glorify Sri Krsna in various ways.&#8221;</p>
<p>Also in the <em>Padma Purana &#8211;</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>padau yadiyau prathama-dvitiyau trtiya-turyau kathitau yad-uru<br />
nabhis tatha pancama eva sasto bhujantaram dor-yugalam tathanyau</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>kanthas tu rajan navamo yadiyo mukharavindam dasamam praphullam<br />
ekadaso yas ca lalata-pattam siro’pi yad dvadasa eva bhati</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>namami devam karuna-nidhanam tamala-varnam suhitavataram<br />
apara-samsara-samudra-setum bhajamahe bhagavata-svarupam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The first and second cantos of the <em>Bhagavata</em> are Sri Krsna’s feet. The third and fourth cantos are His thighs. The fifth canto is His navel. The sixth canto is His chest. The seventh and eighth cantos are His arms. The ninth canto is His throat. The tenth canto is His beautiful lotus-face. The eleventh canto is His forehead. The twelth canto is His head.</p>
<p>I bow down to that Lord , the ocean of mercy whose color is like that of a <em>tamala</em> tree and who appears in this world for the welfare of all. I worship Him as the bridge for crossing the unfathomable ocean of material existence. The <em>Bhagavata</em> has appeared as His very Self.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In the <em>Garuda Purana &#8211;</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>artho ’yam brahma-sutranam bharatartha-vinirnayah<br />
gayatri-bhasya-rupo ’sah vedartha-paribrmhitah<br />
grantho ’stadasa-sahasrah srimad-bhagavatabhidhah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> is the authorized explanation of <em>Brahma-sutras</em>, and it is a further explanation of <em>Mahabharata</em>. It is the expansion of the <em>gayatri-mantra</em> and the essence of all Vedic knowledge. This <em>Bhagavata</em>, containing eighteen thousand verses, is known as the explanation of all Vedic literature.&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">11</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong> CONCLUSION:</strong> In this way we have shown through the <em>pramana</em> of the <em>srutis, smrtis, Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> that the <em>Mahabharata</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> are indeed considered to be the fifth <em>Veda</em>, and that they are of higher importance and significance in the age of Kali than the four <em>Vedas</em>. Of them, the highest is the the <em>Bhagavata</em>, the crest-jewel of all the Vedic literatures. For this reason the <em>Bhagavata</em>(1.3.43) says:</p>
<p class="verse"><em>krsne sva-dhamopagate dharma-jnanadibhih saha<br />
kalau nasta-drsam esa puranarko’dhunditah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> is as brilliant as the sun. After Sri Krsna has left for His abode, accompanied by <em>dharma</em> and knowledge, it has arisen to save us from the darkness of the age of Kali.&#8221;</p>
<p>____________________________</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">1</span>&#8211; This is affirmed by Lord Krsna in the <em>Bhagavata</em> (11.3.44) – &#8220;<em>paroksa-vada vedo’yam&#8221;</em> (The <em>Vedas</em> speak indirectly).</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">2</span>&#8211; In the case of the <em>Bhagavata,</em> this itself is a contradiction from the point of view of the Madhva <em>sampradaya.</em> If the <em>Vedas</em> are considered a primary authority merely because they issued from the mouth of God Himself, the <em>Bhagavata</em> and <em>Mahabharata</em> should also fall into such a category since the author of these works was Veda Vyasa, whom the Tattvavadis consider to be a direct <em>avatara</em> of Narayana.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">3</span>&#8211; This verse from <em>Chandogya Upanisad</em> is also quoted by Madhvacarya in <em>Visnu Tattva Vinirnaya</em> (5). It is also worth noting that in Prof. K.T. Pandurangi’s work The <em>Principal Upanisads</em> (Dvaita Vedanta Studies and Research Foundation, Bangalore 1999) wherein he explains Madhvacarya’s <em>Upanisad</em> commentaries, the author gives the same meaning of this verse.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">4</span>&#8211; This is also confirmed in the <em>Bhagavata</em> (1.4.20):</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>rg-yajuh-samatharvakhya<br />
vedas catvara uddhrtah<br />
itihasa-puranas ca<br />
pancamo veda ucyate</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;The <em>Vedas</em> were divided into four, namely <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em>. The <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> are said to be the fifth <em>Veda</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">5</span>&#8211; In his <em>tika</em> on the <em>Visnu Purana</em> 3.6.16, Srila Sridhara Svami explains these terms thus:</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>svayam-drstartha</em>&#8211;<em>kathanam prahur akhyanakam budhah srutasyarthasya<br />
kathanam upakhyanam pracaksate gathas tu pitr-prthivyadi gitayah</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;An <em>Akhyana</em> is a description of that which is witnessed by the speaker. An <em>Upakhyana</em> is a description of something the speaker has not seen, but merely heard about. A <em>Gatha</em> is a song dedicated to the forefathers and beings present upon the earth.&#8221;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">6</span>&#8211; The word <em>sankspitam</em> in this verse is important. This means ‘condensed’ and not ‘composed’. In other words Sri Vyasa condensed the already existing <em>Vedas</em>, then taking unused verses from that condensed portion, he compiled the <em>Puranas</em>. Thus, the <em>Puranas</em> must be understood to be equal to the <em>Vedas</em>.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">7</span>&#8211; The five elements of a <em>Purana</em> are described in <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.65) &#8211;</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>sargas ca pratisargas ca<br />
vamso manvantarani ca<br />
vamsyanucaritam caiva<br />
purana panca-laksanam</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;The five subjects which make up a <em>Purana</em> are creation (<em>sarga</em>), secondary creation (<em>pratisarga</em>), geneology of kings (<em>vamsa</em>), the description of the Manus (<em>manvantara</em>) and the activities of those kings (<em>vamsanucarita</em>). &#8220;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">8</span>&#8211; In this verse the word ‘<em>agni</em>’ (fire) refers to the Vedic sacrifices wherein one offers oblations into various sacred fires. ‘<em>Kalpesu</em>’ means ‘scripture (in this case <em>Purana</em>) according to the definition given in the Medini Sanskrit dictionary 1.21.2 (<em>kalpa sastre vidhau nyaye samvarte brahmane dine</em> – the word <em>kalpa</em> means ‘scripture’, ‘rule’, ‘logic’, and ‘day of Brahma’.) The word ‘<em>ca</em>’ in the phrase ‘<em>sivasya ca</em>’ implies the consort of Lord Siva, namely Goddess Uma. ‘<em>Sankirnesu</em>’means ‘in the various <em>Puranas</em> which are in mixed modes of goodness, passion and ignorance. The word ‘<em>sarasvatyah</em>’ refers to the presiding deity of speech and, by implication, the various devas referred to in various scriptures which she embodies. <em>’Pitrnam’</em> refers to the <em>karma-khanda</em> rituals meant for attaining the heavenly planets of the manes (<em>karmana pitr-lokah</em>).</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">9</span>&#8211; <em>sattvat sanjayate jnanam<br />
</em> <em>rajaso lobhaeva ca<br />
pramada-mohau tamaso<br />
</em> <em>.bhavato’jnanam eva ca</em> (Bg 14.17)</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">10</span>&#8211; <em>tamasas tu rajas tasmat<br />
</em><em>sattvam yad brahma-darsanam</em></p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">11</span>&#8211; Quoted by Sri Madhva in his <em>Bhagavata-tatparya.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Hinduism?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[33 gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrisitanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[definition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism oldest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindusim vs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat rai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polytheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shashtra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind? At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Written by Ibn Muhammad<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is a hodge-podge or conglomeration of many mutually conflicting religions, and is not the child, so to say, of any one father. Those who practice it differ very much from one another in their faith and practice. Hinduism includes in it Vedism, Brahmanism, Sivaism, Vishnuism, Polytheism, Pantheism, Idolatory in is greatest forms, Tree-Worship, Serpent-Worship, Demon-Worship and so on.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span id="more-5644"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is not easy therefore to give a definition of Hinduism,  &#8220;Hinduism and its gods,&#8221; says Sir Alfred Lyall, &#8220;are a troubled sea, without shore or visible horizon, driven to and fro by the winds of boundless credulity and grotesque invention. A tangled jungle of disorderly superstitions, ghosts and demons, demi-gods and deified saints, household gods, tribe gods, local gods, universal gods, with their countless shrines and temples, and din of their disordent rites, deities who abhor a fly&#8217;s death, those who delight still in human victims, and those who would not either sacrifice or make offerings, such religious chaos&#8221;. <strong><sup>[1]</sup></strong><br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Authoritative Books not one but many</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A further difficulty regarding Hinduism lies in the fact that all its professors have no common sacred Book or Books to depend upon for their doctrines. Some refer to Vedas as the basis of their faith. Others rest their faith on the Shrutis, a term which includes not only the four Vedas but their Brahmanas and Upanishads as well. The Mahabharata styles itself as the fifth Veda, containing the quintessense of all the rest. Other Hindus agains follow the teachings of the Puranas. The present day educated Hindus are mainly depending upon the Bhagavad Gita, a philosophical treatise, for their guidance in matters of faith. We shall therefore briefly inquire into the contents of all these books to see what they teach about God and the way in which man should worship Him.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Religion of the Vedas</h3>
<h4>(a) Nature Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Vedism, or the Religion of the Vedas, teaches the worship of the deified forces or phenomenon of Nature, such as Fire, the Sun, Wnd and Rain. Here is the opening verse of the Rigveda, the oldest Veda, of which the others are mere repetitions and borrowing:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निमीळे पुरोहितं यज्ञस्य देवं रत्वीजम |  होतारं रत्नधातमम || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;I Laud Agni, the great high priest, god, minister of sacrifice, the herald, lavishest of wealth.&#8221; [Rigveda Mandal 1: Sookt 1: Mantra 1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The whole of the Veda goes on in this strain throughout in the hymns collected for different purposes. The contrast between the opening  verse of the Rigveda which teaches Polytheism, and that of the Jewish Bible and of the Holy Qur&#8217;an which teach Monotheism, cannot fail to be noted even by the most superficial reader. Thus the Jewish Pentateuch begins,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>בראשית ברא אלהים את השמים ואת הארץ׃</strong><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.&#8221; [Genesis 1:1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Holy Qur&#8217;an strikes the key note of its whole teaching in a still more profound manner, unparalleled in other religions:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"> &#8211; </span><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">الْحَمْدُ للَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَـلَمِينَ &#8211; الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ &#8211; مَـلِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. All Praise is due to Allah, Lord of the Worlds, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. Master of the Day of Judgement.&#8221;[Surah Al-Fatiha 1:1-4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Thus Vedism teaches the worship of the powers of Nature.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(b) Polytheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That it teaches polytheism is also evident from the expression used in the same verse and in all the succeeding verses as well:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निः पूर्वेभिर्र्षिभिरीड्यो नूतनैरुत | स देवानेह वक्षति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;He (Agni) shall bring hitherward the gods.&#8221; [Rigveda 1:1:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्ने यं यज्ञमध्वरं विश्वतः परिभूरसि | स इद्देवेषु गछति ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Verily goes to the gods.&#8221;[verse 4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निर्होता कविक्रतुः सत्यश्चित्रश्रवस्तमः | देवो देवेभिरा गमत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;May Agni, priest, the god, come hither with the gods.&#8221; [verse 5]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The number of gods in Hindu Pantheon is given as 33 in one place (Rigveda 1:34:11), which says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>आ नासत्या तरिभिर एकादशैर इह देवेभिर यातम मधुपेयम अश्विना | परायुस तारिष्टं नी रपांसि मर्क्षतं सेधतं दवेषो भवतं सचाभुवा ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Come, O Nasatyas, with the thrice-eleven Gods; come, O ye Asvins, to the drinking of the meath. Make long our days of life, and wipe out all our sins: ward off our enemies; be with us evermore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Similarly it is mentioned in Rigveda 8:30:2,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>इति सतुतासो असथा रिशादसो ये सथ तरयश्च तरिंशच्च | मनोर्देवा यज्ञियासः || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Thus be ye lauded, ye destroyers of the foe, ye Three-and-Thirty Deities, The Gods of man, the Holy Ones.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Rigeveda 10:52:6 the number is 3,339. It says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>तरीणि शता तरी सहस्राण्यग्निं तरिंशच्च देवा नवचासपर्यन | औक्षन घर्तैरस्त्र्णन बर्हिरस्मा आदिद्धोतारं नयसादयन्त || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Deities three thousand, three hundred and thirty-nine, have served and honoured Agni, Strewn sacred grass, anointed him with butter, and seated him as Priest, the Gods&#8217; Invoker.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Later Hinduism has gone still further by saying that there are no less than 33 crores of them.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(c) Pantheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Why not then say that everything is God, and God is everything? The Purusha Sukta (Rigveda 10:90) which every orthodox Brahmin is expected even now to recite daily in his prayers shows that Pantheism is also taught in the later portions of the Vedas:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>पुरुष एवेदं सर्वं यद भूतं यच्च भव्यम | उताम्र्तत्वस्येशानो यदन्नेनातिरोहति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;This Purusha(i.e. Brahma or God) is all that yet has been and all that is to be.&#8221; [verse 2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The caste system which has proved the curse of India is likewise taught in the same hymn:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>बराह्मणो.अस्य मुखमासीद बाहू राजन्यः कर्तः | ऊरूतदस्य यद वैश्यः पद्भ्यां शूद्रो अजायत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Brahmana was his (Purusha&#8217;s) mouth. Of both his arms was the Kshatriya made. His thighs became the Vaishya. From his feet the Sudra produced.&#8221;[verse 12]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Religion of the Upanishads</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Upanishads reject the Karma, Kanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. Hence they consist of speculations about the individual souls (atma) and the Supreme soul (Param-atma), and about the relationship subsisting between them, their aim being to get rid of man&#8217;s earthly existence by absorption of the individual soul into the World Soul through correct or true knowledge. They teach that the Universe or Nature (Prakriti) is unreal or <em>Maaya</em>, that is to say, it does not really exist but it only an illusion of the mind. What really exists in the Supreme Soul or Brahman, and the individual souls are all emanations from Him and identical with Him. Only they do not know it, as Brahman has invested Himself/Itself with the <em>Maaya</em>, and they also are under the influence of the same mystic power. The individual souls can be disillusioned only by means of Correct knowledge, and as soon as this consummation is reached, they know themselves to be Brahman, and get absorbed into Him. The famous formula referring to this theory is <strong><em>&#8216;Tat tvam asi&#8217;</em></strong> </span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">तत् त्वम् असि </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;That art thou&#8217;, whoever knows this &#8216;becomes the All&#8217;. Even the gods are not able to prevent him from becoming it. For he becomes their self. <em>[Brihadaranyak Upanishad 1:4:6]</em><br />
</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This theory is known as the Vedanta, the essence of the teaching of the Vedas, and has taken an immense hold on the minds of the people and lent a deeper colour to all subsequent literature. A Christian missionary asked a Brahmin, &#8220;Who and where is Brahman?&#8221; &#8220;He is talking to you,&#8221; was the prompt reply.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A Vedantist once began to dilate upon the truth of his belief in the presence of a king and vehemently maintained that the whole world was <em>Mithya</em> or unreal, imaginary: whereupon an elephant was ordered to be brought quite near to him and the man fled in terror. &#8220;Why do you run away for your life? The elephant is <em>Mithya</em>&#8221; said the king. But the Vedantist proved himself equal to the occasion and without a moment&#8217;s hesistation replied that the running away too was <em>Mithya</em>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Such is the fool&#8217;s paradise in which most of the misguided Hindus live. The expression that is often heard on their lips, and which has unfortunately recently been made famous by Dr. Zakir Naik through his televised public talks:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><em>EKAM EVA ADVITIYAM</em><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;One only without a second&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It does not mean that they believe in the &#8216;Only One True God&#8217; but it is the Vedantic or Pantheistic formula which asserts that the only real existence of the World Soul and the identity of the individual souls within it, totally denying the existence of the phenomenal world.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Puranas</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The characteristic of popular Hinduism of today is the belief in Divine incarnations, idolatory and caste. Popular Hinduism believes in the doctrine of Trimurti or Hindu Trinity as Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, in their characteristic of the Creator, Preserver and Destroyer of the Universe.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Vishnu Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The distinct feature of Vishnu worship is the incarnation of God. When wickedness in the world increases Vishnu is said to take upon himself the form of an animal or man in order to be able to protect the good and to punish the bad. The principle incarnations He is said to have so far assumed are those of (1) a fish, (2) a tortoise, (3) a Boar, (4) a man-lion (5) a Dwarf, (6) a Brahmin hero called Parasu Ram, (7) a Kshatriya Prince, the hero of Ramayana, (8) a shepherd Prince Krishna and (9) a Kshatriya heretic, Buddha.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Krishna declares:<br />
</span></h4>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;On an occasion of marriage, or of enjoying a woman, or when life is in danger, or when one&#8217;s entire property is about to be taken away, or for the sake of a Brahmin, falsehood may be uttered. These five kinds of falsehood have been declared to be sinless. On these occasions falsehood would become truth and truth would become falsehood.&#8221; [Mahabharata Book 8; Karna Parva; Section 69]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Cow Worship</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is natural for Indians to set a high value upon the cow on account of its utility, but the worship the Hindus pay to it is irrational and absurd to a degree. It is considered to be the most sacred of all animals. Every part of its body is considered to be inhabited by some deity or other. Even its excreta are considered to be most sacred. Its urine is looked upon as the best of all holy waters; a sin destroying liquid which sanctifies everything it touches, while nothing purifies like cow-dung. The ashes of its dung sprinkled over a sinner are able to convert him into a saint.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Veneration of Cow in Hindu Culture</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Present day Hindu culture is pivoted solely on the cow. Its material and spiritual concepts are both engulfed in cow worship. Such an animal worship is known as zoolatry. This is a vestide of animistic cultures among whom the worship of monkeys, sheep, elephants, cows and even snakes was prevalent. Animal worship culminated in the taking of human beings for gods so that the silhouettes were stamped on the coins and painted on the flags, and upon their honour depended the glory and honour of their realms.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Among cultivators cow worship is not a strange thing. In many countries, notably, India, Iran and Egypt, it was prevalent. Among Hindus veneration of the cow is referred to in the Vedas as Puranas and in Hindu Jurisprudence and folklore. In the Vedas several verses refer to saluting and prostrating before the cow as the following sections illustrate:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Prajapati and Parameshthin are the two horns, Indra is the head, Agni the forehead, Yama the joint of the neck. King Soma is the brain, Sky is the upper jaw, Earth is the lower jaw&#8230; All worlds and all the gods are as the cow from head to foot.&#8221; [Atharvaved Kaand 9: Sookt 7]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;You are being created and have been created for salutations and prostrations. Salutations and prostration to you, O image of God, to your hair, to your hooves.&#8221; [Atharva 10:10]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Curiously enough, the Vedic Rishis likened the chanting of their mantras (hymn) to the lowing of the cows:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अभि विप्रा अनूषत गावो वत्सं न मातरः | इन्द्रं सोमस्य पीतये || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;As the cows moo in the presence of their calves so do Brahmins recite their mantras while drinking the soma juice in the presence of Indra devta.&#8221; [Rigveda 9:12:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In old Vedic timesthe pious people picked out the grain from the cow-dung, and then ate it. They also squeezed out its water and drank it (Mahabharata). Its urine was considered a source of redemption of sins and a means of cow-dung bathed with water extracted thus. Krishna Ji revered the bull by stroking its back before mounting it. In short, in Hindu religion the cow in venerated to an extent which gods and godesses and even God Himself does not merit.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Cow-Worship and the humiliation of Man</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is to be noted that the sacredness of the cow as compared with the scant regard for human life has come to this that Swami Dayanand Saraswati in accordance with the Vedas, opines that the blood of thousands or hundreds of thousands of humans, may be shed to please these animals; (See his translation of Yajurveda 33:14 and Rigveda 1:121:10)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Vedic times, there lived an untouchable people in a village named Kikat, in todays Bihar. The used to rear cattle. Obviously to the Aryans this was a crime. So they invoked their god Indra to wage war against them and loot their cows.<br />
</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"></span></p>
<p id="VJgEpTj"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="620" height="145" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7245 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"> </span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;O Indra, what do the cows make for you among the Kikatas. They neither yield milk for your offerings, nor do they warm the vessel of libation. Bring to us these cows, bring to us also the wealth of Pramagand (their King). O Brave one, grant us the possessions of the people of low status.&#8221; [Rigveda 3:53:14]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">On the basis of this clear prnouncement, non-Aryans and untouchables have no right to keep cows. Aryans and Brahmins whenever they wish can kill them and appropriate their possessions. Hindu culture thus becomes the culture of the progress, civilization and welfare of the Aryan people alone.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Status of the Cow</h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The fact remains that Hindu culture is based on the cow. Actually it is cow-worship as may be inferred from the discussion so far. As the Noble Qur&#8217;an states,<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;And their hearts absorbed (the worship of) the calf because of their disbelief.&#8221; [Surah Baqarah 2:93]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The cow is also called mother and this is a relic of the age of ignorance. In primitive times when the mother of a young child died, the child too would die of malnutrition after two or three days. The father did not know how to save the child&#8217;s life as a substitute for the mother&#8217;s milk was not known. By chance, some wise person thought of the idea of giving goat&#8217;s milk to the child. As the goat was easier to control and milk than the cow, goat&#8217;s milk was used to save the infant&#8217;s life. Later on the cow was tamed for this purpose. From then on the polytheists began to call the cow &#8216;mata&#8217; i.e. mother. But other animals as well, such as goats, sheep, camels, supply milk as substitute for mother&#8217;s milk; yet they are never called &#8216;mother&#8217;. Strangely enough, in this age of science when so many baby-foods have been invented, none of these is called &#8216;mother&#8217;, yet wealthy and educated Hindus still apply this epithet to the cow alone.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The nation which cannot differentiate between a cow&#8217;s tail and a man&#8217;s head, lives in an extreme abyss of culture. The cow is at the utmost an animal, while even the most degraded man, being still a human being, is yet far superior to a cow.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Gita</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Since Mahabharata fails to serve as a handy and useful book of the essence of Hinduism, the present day educated Hindus are adopting the Bhagvat Gita as their guide.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Like all the other scriptures this famous poem too fails to teach True Religion to mankind. It is a highly Philosophic poem just as ill-suited to teach Religion as Berkley&#8217;s <em>Principle of Human Knowledge </em>or Milton&#8217;s <em>Paradise Lost</em> can be. The principle of its composition is Eclecticism and tries to combine Sankhya, Yoga, and Vedanta teaching into one whole to support the Vaishnava theory of Krishna&#8217;s deification.But is does promote ideas like Polytheism and Caste. Krishna claims to be the author of the caste system in India:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The four Castes were created by me according to the appointment of qualities and works.&#8221; [Gita 4:13]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Gita does not insist on the worship of the One and Only True God but promotes belief in polytheism:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Those who worship gods go to the gods&#8221; [9:25]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Worship the gods thereby; The gods shall yield thee grace.&#8221; [3:3]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That there are inconsistencies in the Bhagvad Gita is admitted today even by Hindu scholars. For example at Chapter 9, stanza 29 Krishna declares that &#8216;none is hateful to me, none dear.&#8217; And yet the remarkable verses at the close of Chapter 12 contradict it, &#8216;Linked by no ties to earth, steadfast in Me, That man I love&#8217;. At Gita Chapter 5, stanza 15 it is said, that &#8216;the Lord receives the sin and merit of none.&#8217; Yet at Chapter 5, stanza 29, and again at Chapter 9, stanza 24, Krishna calls himself &#8216;the Lord and enjoyer&#8217; of all sacrifices and penances. How, it may well be asked, can the Supreme Being &#8216;enjoy&#8217; that which he does not even &#8216;receive&#8217;?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The doctrine of transmigration is the basis from which the argument of Bhagvad Gita takes its start. Matter and spirit are without beginning (13:20). God (Krishna-Vishnu) is eternal, almighty, unborn, without beginning, the great Lord of the World (10:3). He is different not only from the fleeting world, but also from the changeless and indestructible energy of all beings. Vishnu is born from age to age (4:6-8). Krishna-Vishnu is wholly distinct from Brahma and Brahman is distinctly a lower deity than Krishna (11:15,37). In 12:1-7, the two classes, those who believe in a personal God Krishna-Vishnu, i.e. theists, and those who believe in Brahma ,i.e. pantheists are contrasted, and preference is given to former. In other words, final bliss is difficult of attainment for those who follow the Vedas and seek the heaven of Brahma. All external observances and duties prescribed by the Vedas are held to be mischievous and thrown overboard (7:20; 18:34,66). The Vedas and the works enjoined by them cannot win one the vision of the Divine (11:48,53). What a contempt is expressed for the Vedas in the following words: &#8220;Steady understanding does not belong to those, whose minds are drawn by that flowery talk (i.e. Vedas) which is full of ordinances of specific acts for the attainment of pleasures and power, and which promises birth as the fruit of acts- that flowery talk which those unwise ones utter, who are enamoure of Vedic words, who say there is nothing else, who are full of desires, an whose goal is heaven. The Vedas merely relate to the effects of the three qualities; do you, O Arjuna! rise above those effects of the three qualities.&#8221; (2:42-45). Thus the Vedas are being spoken of in very disparaging terms and the followers of Krishna were inimical to the Vedas.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This was in brief about Hinduism and in our future articles all the topics discussed here would be dealt with in detail separately.<br />
</span></p>
<p><img alt="" /></p>
<h5>REFERENCES</h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>[1] </strong><em>Asiatic Studies</em>, Vol 1, pp 2, 3<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
