<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>caste system &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/caste-system/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 14:23:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Upanishads: An analysis</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apara Vidya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chandogya Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganganath Jha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mundaka Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panditaa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polygyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prajapati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rahu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rishi Yajnavalkya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Maadhavananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Nikhilananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad In the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad. Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>In <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="229" height="356" class="wp-image-7250 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa1.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-193x300.jpeg 193w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /> the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad.</p>
<p>Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to be superior to the Vedas. This is the reason that the maximum number of quotations in their books are from the Upanishads while Vedic mantras are rarely quoted. Upanishads are considered as the primary source of Hindu theology.</p>
<p>More than 200 Upanishads are known, of which a dozen are variously referred to as the principal, (mukhya) main or old Upanishads. They are:</p>
<p>1. Isavasya 2. Aitareya 3. Chandogya 4. Kena 5. Taittiriya 6. Katha 7. Shvetashvatara 8. Brihadaranyak 9. Prasna 10. Mundak 11. Maandukya 12. Kaushtaki  Upanishad.</p>
<p><span id="more-5645"></span></p>
<p>Scholars disagree about the exact dates of the composition of the Upanishads. According to Dr. Radhakrishnan, they were composed between 800 B.C to 600 B.C.</p>
<p>Many Upanishads are collections of mutually unrelated and mutually contradictory statements. Every Upanishads is self refuting. Also, one Upanishad says one thing about a certain theme while another Upanishad says something entirely different. It appears that Upanishad writers were not intending to write a book. May be these were their personal notes which they expanded over time without any connection to earlier notes. This is the reason that many mutually contradictory schools like Advaita (Monism), Vishishtadvaita (qualified Monism) and Dvaita (Dualism) are derived from the Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>Opposition to the Vedas</strong></p>
<p>The Upanishads reject the Karmakaanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. For example, Mundaka Upanishad 1/1/5 calls the four Vedas as ‘lower knowledge’  (Apra) and says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="614" height="65" class="wp-image-7251" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-9.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa2.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“The lower knowledge (Apara) is the Rig-veda, Yajur-veda, Sama-veda, Atharva-veda, Siksha (phonetics), Kalpa (ceremonial), Vyakarana (grammar), Nirukta (etymology), Khandas (metre), Jyotisha (astronomy);”</p>
<p>Explaning the word ‘Apara’ Shankaracharya has written in his commentary on verse 4,</p>
<p><strong><em>Apara Vidya</em> is ignorance and that ought to be dispelled.</strong> When what is known is <em>Apara Vidya</em>, i.e., the subject of ignorance, nothing can be known as it is.</p>
<p>Condemning the Karma-kanda of the four Vedas, the same Upanishad says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="454" height="64" class="wp-image-7252" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-10.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa3.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“But frail, in truth, are those boats, the sacrifices (Yagyas), the eighteen (consisting of the sixteen <em>Ritviks</em>, the sacrificer and his wife), in which this lower ceremonial has been told. Fools who praise this as the highest good, are subject again and again to old age and death.”</p>
<p>(Mundaka Upanishad 1/2/7)</p>
<p>Believers in Karma-kaanda are being insulted as fools. This condemnation of ritualism continues in verses 8 and 9.</p>
<p><strong>Mythical Teachings</strong></p>
<p>In contrast to the above condemnation of Vedic rituals, other Upanishads themselves give strange unscientific rituals to obtain various blessings. For example consider the following recipes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="624" height="61" class="wp-image-7253" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-11.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa4.gif?w=860&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a fair complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study one Veda and that he should attain a full term of life, then they (husband and wife) should have rice cooked in milk and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>(Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad 6/4/14)</p>
<p>Here, the recipe given to produce a white son is white milk and white rice. Will this recipe work for an African kid? Let us not go far away. Will it work for the indigenous dark races of India? Will it make them white? Further how is this recipe supposed to make the born chlid a scholar of one Veda? Will the missionaries of Upanishads kindly explain this amazing scientific (?) verse to us?</p>
<p>Notice one more thing. Contrary to the condemnation of the Vedas by Mundaka Upanishad, this verse is giving a recipe to make the child a scholar of one Veda.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 15</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a tawny or brown complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study two Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in curds and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>This is also an amazing technique of producing colourful children. Additionally, just with a slight change of recipe the child will become a scholar of two Vedas.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 16</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a dark complexion and red eyes should be born to him</strong>, that he should study three Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in water and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Are all Trivedis and Tripathis in India born by this recipe?</p>
<p><strong>Verse 17</strong></p>
<p>After a long search I was finally able to find a recipe for producing a girl child in Hindu texts. This verse gives that recipe.</p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a daughter should be born to him</strong> who will be a scholar and attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked with sesamum and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a daughter.</p>
<p>I will not comment on this par excellence scientific (?) recipe mentioned in this verse. My primary concern here is about the word scholar (Panditaa in Sanskrit), for which we see the next topic ‘Upanishads and Women’ below.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 18</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that a son should be born to him who will be a famous scholar, frequenting assemblies and speaking delightful words, a student of all the Vedas and an enjoyer of the full term of life,<strong> he should have rice cooked with the meat of a young bull or of one more advanced in years</strong> and he and his wife should eat it with clarified butter. Then they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Since the time this recipe has been abandoned in India, true Vedic scholars are not taking birth. Hindus should start eating this diet to know the Vedas properly. Commenting on this recipe, Shankaracharya writes,</p>
<p>“The meat is restricted to that of a vigorous bull,  able to breed, or one more advanced in years.”</p>
<p>Let me share one last recipe with you.</p>
<p><strong>verse 12</strong> of the same chapter says,</p>
<p><strong>Now, if a man’s wife has a lover whom he detests</strong>, he should perform the following rite in order to cast an evil spell upon him: Let him put fire in an unbaked earthen vessel, spread stalks of reed and kusa grass inversely and offer in the sacrificial fire the reed tips, soaked in clarified butter, inversely, repeating the following mantra: “You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your prana and apana, you, (**HERE THE NAME OF THE LOVER SHOULD BE UTTERED**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your sons and cattle, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your Vedic rites and those done according to the Smritis, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your hopes and expectations, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! He whom a brahmin who knows this rite curses, departs from this world impotent and shorn of merit. <strong>Therefore let no one even joke with the wife of a Vedic scholar who knows this rite;</strong> for he who has this knowledge is a dangerous enemy.</p>
<p>I feel this is nothing but a fraudulent way of looting the innocent folk who are afraid of mantra-tantra. How will burning the fire in a vessel cause the death of someone else? And why is this formula not taught to a wife whose husband has a lover whom she detests? This clearly shows a sanction of polygamy in Hindu texts.</p>
<p><strong>Upanishads and Women</strong></p>
<p>I was initially glad to see that even a girl in Hinduism can become a scholar as per Briahadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/17 quoted above. However, when I read the oldest commentary of the leading scholar of Hinduism, Adi Shankaracharya, on this verse, I was disappointed. He writes,</p>
<p>दुहितुः पांडित्यं गृहतंत्रविषयमेव वेदे अनधिकारात</p>
<p>“The scholarship of the daughter is regarding domestic affairs only, for she is not entitled to read the Vedas.”</p>
<p><strong>Women as objects of lust</strong></p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/8/1 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="603" height="72" class="wp-image-7254" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-12.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa5.gif?w=816&amp;h=98" /></p>
<p>“Woman, O Gautama, is the fire, her sexual organ is the fuel, what invites is the smoke, the vagina is the flame, what is done inside is the embers, the pleasures are the sparks.”</p>
<p>A simlar verse is found in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/12/13.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 2/13/1-2 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="386" height="163" class="wp-image-7255" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-13.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa6.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>1. A man’s beckoning to a woman is the syllable <em>Him</em>; his gratifying her is the <em>Prastava</em>; his lying with her is the <em>Pratihara</em>; his spending time with her is the <em>Nidhana</em>; and the finishing of the sexual act is also the <em>Nidhana</em>. This is the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse.</p>
<p>2. He who thus knows the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse does not suffer from the pang of separation and procreates from every intercourse; he reaches the full length of life, lives brightly, becomes great in children and cattle, great in fame. For him the injunction is: <strong>“Do not reject a woman who comes to you seeking intercourse”</strong>.</p>
<p>This is the Upanishadic version of Kamasutra, so much that many scholars prefer not to comment on them. Scholar Ganganath Jha has translated Chandogya Upanishad into English but he has left these verses untranslated.</p>
<p><strong>Why and How woman was created?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/2-3 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="241" class="wp-image-7256" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-14.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa7.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Prajapati said to Himself: “Well, let Me make a firm basis for it (semen).” So He created woman. Having created her, He worshipped her bottom portion. Therefore one should worship the bottom portion of a woman. He (Prajapati) extended His organ that projects and with it impregnated her.”</p>
<p>Her lap is the sacrificial altar, her hair the sacrificial grass, her skin within the organ the lighted fire; the two labia of the vulva are the two stones of the soma—press. He who, knowing this, practises sexual intercourse wins as great a world as is won through the Vijapeya sacrifice; he acquires for himself the fruit of the good deeds of the woman. But he who, without knowing this, practises sexual intercourse turns over to the woman his own good deeds.</p>
<p>Let me bring to your notice that the English translation of Brihadaranyak Upanishad published by Swami Maadhavananda does not translate verses 3, 4 and 5 and even the Shankar bhashya is not translated. I have reproduced the translation of Swami Nikhilananda  which can be found here</p>
<p><a href="http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Now let me quote the Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/4-5</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="372" height="317" class="wp-image-7257" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-15.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa8.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>4) Having known this, Uddalaka the son of Aruna, Naka the son of Mudgala and Kumara—harita said: “Many mortals, brahmins only in name, perform the sexual act without knowledge of what has been said and <strong>depart from this world impotent</strong> and without merit.” Even if this much semen—of one asleep or of one awake—is spilled,</p>
<p>5) <strong>He should touch it</strong> and repeat the following mantra: “Whatever semen of mine has spilt on earth, whatever has flowed to plants, whatever to water, I reclaim it.” <strong>With these words he should take the semen with his ring finger and thumb and rub it between his breasts or eyebrows,</strong> repeating the following mantra: “Let the semen return to me, let Vigour come to me again, let glow and good fortune come to me again. May the deities who dwell in the sacrificial fire put the semen back in its proper place.”</p>
<p>Readers can themselves judge these words.</p>
<p><strong>Beat your wife?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadranyak Upanishad 6/4/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="376" height="106" class="wp-image-7258" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-16.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa9.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>If she (the wife) does not willingly yield her body to him (her husband), he should buy her with presents. If she is still unyielding, <strong>he should beat her with a stick or with his hand and overcome her</strong>, repeating the following mantra: “With power and glory I take away your glory.” Thus she becomes discredited.</p>
<p>What kind of teaching is this? These are only productions of imbalanced minds.</p>
<p>I would suggest that you read the remaining portion of the chapter (i.e. Brihad. Upanishad Part 6, Chapter 4) from the above link yourself because it is too obscene to be posted here.</p>
<p><strong>Polygyny</strong></p>
<p>Throughout the Upanishads there are evidences of polygyny being sanctioned. The Rishis of the Upanishads used to have several wives. For example, Yajnavalkya has two wives as is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/5/1.</p>
<p>अथ ह याज्ञवल्क्यस्य द्वे भार्ये बभूवतुर्मैत्रेयी च कात्यायनी च</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya had two wives: Maitreyi and Katyayani”</p>
<p><strong>Unscientific concepts</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the above mentioned mythical teachings, the Upanishads contain many factually unscientific errors.</p>
<p>1. Chandogya Upanishad 8/13/1 says</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="611" height="96" class="wp-image-7259" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa10.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>From the dark I come to the variegated; from the variegated I come to the Dark. Shaking off evil as a horse shakes dust from its hair, freeing myself from the body <strong>as the moon frees itself from the mouth of Rahu</strong>, I fulfil all ends and obtain the uncreated World of Brahman.</p>
<p>The lunar eclipse is thus thought to be the work of Rahu, an Asura (demon), who eats the moon.</p>
<p>2. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/3/2 mentions the dimensions of the place where those people go who have performed the Horse Sacrifice (Ashwamedh)? It says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="148" class="wp-image-7260" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa11.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Thirty—two times the space traversed by the sun’s chariot in a day makes this plane (loka); around it, covering twice the area, is the world (prithivi); around the world, covering twice the area, is the ocean. Now, as is the edge of a razor or the wing of a fly, so is there just that much space between the two halves of the cosmic shell. Through that opening they go out. “Fire, in the form of a falcon, delivered them to Vayu. Vayu, placing them in itself, took them where previous performers of the Horse Sacrifice were.”</p>
<p>Even a primary pass child today knows that there is no such meeting point of the sky and earth and no opening. They also know that there is no chariot pulling the Sun.</p>
<p>3. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/19 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="418" height="42" class="wp-image-7261" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa12.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“seventy two thousand (72,000) nerves called <strong>hita</strong>, which extend from the heart throughout the whole body.”</p>
<p>I would like to see the scientific confirmation of this statement. There are millions of nerves and blood vessels extending throught the body from the heart and not just 72,000. Another erroneous figure given in the Upanishads.</p>
<p>These are only few of the unscientific teachings of the ‘world renowned’ Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>The roots of caste based discrimination</strong></p>
<p>Upanishads clearly spell out that caste is based on birth due to the deeds of previous lives. This is the reason for this idea taking such root in the Hindu society that it continues to divide Indian society even today.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/10/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="99" class="wp-image-7262" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa13.gif?w=821&amp;h=134" /></p>
<p>“Those whose conduct here on earth has been good will quickly attain some good birth—<strong>birth as a brahmin, birth as a kshatriya, or birth as a vaisya</strong>. But those whose conduct here has been evil will quickly attain some evil birth—<strong>birth as a dog, birth as a pig, or birth as a chandala</strong>.”</p>
<p>On one hand Upanishads talk of one Soul permeating all; only Brahma being real and the world being an illusion, while on the other hand they sanction this cruel birth based caste system. It seems that even the Rishis bent of proving that the world is an illusion, used  to keep personal gains in mind. This idea becomes clear when we observe the lifestyle of Rishi Yajnavalkya, who in trying to prove the world to be an illusion, extracted huge fee (<em>Dakshina</em>) from others. When he was unable to respond to some questions he used to threaten the questioner with dire consequences, which turned the questioner silent out of fear.</p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/1/1-2 says,</p>
<p>“Janaka, Emperor of Videha, performed a sacrifice in which gifts were freely distributed among the priests. Brahmin scholars from the countries of Kuru and Panchala were assembled there. Emperor Tanaka of Videha wished to know which of these brahmins was the most erudite Vedic scholar. So he confined a <strong>thousand cows in a pen and fastened on the horns of each ten padas of gold</strong>.</p>
<p>He said to them: “Venerable brahmins, let him among you who is the best Vedic scholar drive these cows home.” None of the brahmins dared. <strong>Then Yajnavalkya said to one of his pupils: “Dear Samsrava, drive these cows home.”</strong> He drove them away. The brahmins were furious and said: “How does he dare to call himself the best Vedic scholar among us?” Now among them there was Asvala, the hotri priest of Emperor Janaka of Videha. He asked Yajnavalkya: “Are you indeed the best Vedic scholar among us, O Yajnavalkya?” He replied: “I bow to the best Vedic scholar, but I just wish to have these cows.” Thereupon the hotri Asvala determined to question him.”</p>
<p>The Yajnavalkya started answering the questions. Interestingly, Shankaracharya mentions in the preface of his commentary of Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/27,</p>
<p>“One should take away catlle of Vedic scholars who do not truly know Brahma.”</p>
<p>Similarly, when Balaki proposes to speak about God to Ajatashatru, King of Kashi, Ajatasatru offers him, for this proposal, a thousand cows as his fee. (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/1)</p>
<p>When King Janaka asked Rishi Yajnavalkya a questions about Brahma, he immediately offered the fee of thousand cows with a bull as large as an elephant (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/1/4).</p>
<p>All of these examples prove that imparting the mythical and highly philosophized knowledge of Brahma was a good profession to earn money. However, if someone used to ask difficult questions about God refuting the Rishis conjectures, they were threatened and silenced, as they feared loosing their profession. Two glaring examples can be given.</p>
<p>Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, questioned Yajnavalkya. When she cornered Yajnavalkya with her final quetion, all she got was a threat. This is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/6/1</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya ,” said she, “if all this is pervaded by water, by what, is water pervaded?” “By air, O Gargi.” “By what,is air pervaded?” “By the sky, O Gargi.” “By what is the sky pervaded?” “By the world of the gandharvas, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gandharvas pervaded?” “By the world of the sun, O Gargi. “By what is the world of the sun pervaded?” “By the world of the moon, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the moon pervaded?” “By the world of the stars, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the stars pervaded?” “By the world of the gods, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gods pervaded?” “By the world of Indra, O Gargi. “By what is the world of Indra pervaded?” “By the World of Virij, O Gargi. “By what is the World of Virij pervaded?” “By the World of Hiranyagarbha, O Gargi.” “By what is the World of Hiranyagarbha pervaded?” <strong>“Do not, O Gargi,” said he, “question too much, lest your head should fall off. You are questioning too much about a deity about whom we should not ask too much. Do not ask too much, O Gargi.” Thereupon Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, kept silent.</strong></p>
<p>The freedom of thought of Gargi was curbed by Yajnavalkya by threatening her of death. Is this not a ploy to hide the truth? Thinking people can judge for themselves.</p>
<p>Gargi was fortunate to not die but Shakalya was not so fortunate after disputing with Yajnavalkya. That is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/26-27.</p>
<p>“Now I ask you about that Person who is to be known only from the Upanishads, who definitely projects those beings and again withdraws them into Himself and who is at the same time transcendental. “If you cannot clearly explain Him to me, your head shall fall off?’ Sakalya did not know Him; his head fell off; and robbers snatched away his bones, mistaking them for something else.</p>
<p>Then Yajnavalkya said: “Venerable brahmins, whosoever among you wishes to question me may now do so, or all of you may. Or whosoever among you desires it, I shall question him, or I shall question all of you. But the brahmins did not dare.”</p>
<p><strong>The ultimate effect of Upanishads</strong></p>
<p>The above mentioned curbs on free thinking are nothing compared to that effect where all distinction of good and evil is erased from the Knower of Brahma (Brahmagyani).  Kaushitaki Upanishad 3/1/ records Lord Indra as saying the following,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="656" height="66" class="wp-image-7263" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa14.gif?w=834&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>“He who knows me thus, <strong>by no deed of his is his life harmed, not by the murder of his mother, not by the murder of his father, not by theft, not by the killing of a Brahman. If he is going to commit a sin, the bloom does not depart from his face!</strong>”</p>
<p>The theoretical commandment is exemplified by Lord Indra himself who brags about his murders in this very verse.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="123" class="wp-image-7264" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa15.gif?w=734&amp;h=149" /></p>
<p>“I slew the three-headed son of Tvashtri; I delivered the Arunmukhas, the devotees, to the wolves (salavrika); breaking many treaties, I killed the people of Prahlada in heaven, the people of Puloma in the sky, the people of Kalakanga on earth. And not one hair of me was harmed there.”</p>
<p>Thus the people who allow Upanishads to influence them are least bothered about right and wrong. That is why M. N Roy, in his book <em>Fascism; its philosophy, profession and practice</em> traced the influence of Upanishads on Fascism through people like Arthur Schopenhauer and Friedrich Nietzsche. Roy was the first to point out the fact that the roots of fascism lie in the ancient Brahminical religion, and he showed how European, particularly German, fascist philosophers borrowed concepts from Brahminical scholars and scriptures, concepts such as the Aryan race theory, the supremacy of the strong over the weak, the concept of the tyrannical superman and so on. In fact, M.N. Roy issued a’ sharp warning to Indians not to fall prey to Hindu revivalism because he saw that it was nothing but fascism in a different garb. You can see that for yourself. What was the destruction of the Babri Masjid and the mass slaughter of the Muslims but naked fascism? Goebbels, Hitler’s chief propagandist, wrote in one of his books, ‘The state must have the power to break its own laws’. That is precisely what happened on 6 December, 1992. The state was actively involved in the breaking of the mosque. Goebbels also remarked, ‘Repeat a lie- a hundred times and it becomes a truth’. You can see this Chanakyan tactic in all the false Hindutva propaganda about Muslims, Christians and Communists. We all know what horrendous and baseless things they are writing about Muslims in the school textbooks now. They have attributed all the ills of India to the Muslims, painting all of them as immoral.</p>
<p>Hindutva fascism has to be fought at the ideological level, by a superior ideology based on rationalism, and not just on the political plane. Islam is the alternative and hope for those weak humans in India who are discriminated by the cruel divisions of Caste System whose roots lie in the ancient Hindu texts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>मातंग चांडालपुत्र से ब्राह्मण बने ?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/matang-became-brahmin-from-chandal-hindi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 07:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caste System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Responses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambedkar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahmin become shudra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chandal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lower caste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matang brahmana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[untouchables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/matang-became-brahmin-from-chandal-hindi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed &#160; जब भी हिंदू धर्म में व्याप्त जाति व्यवस्था पर वार्तालाप की जाती है प्राय: जाति परिवर्तन के अनेकों उधारण दिये जाते हैं और ये संदेश दिया जाता है कि जाति बदली जा सकती है। हम अपने इस लेख और आने वालें लेखों में कुछ ऐसे ही उधारणों पर चर्चा करेंगे। मातंग चांडालपुत्र &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/matang-became-brahmin-from-chandal-hindi/" data-wpel-link="internal">मातंग चांडालपुत्र से ब्राह्मण बने ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>जब भी हिंदू धर्म में व्याप्त जाति व्यवस्था पर वार्तालाप की जाती है प्राय: जाति परिवर्तन के अनेकों उधारण दिये जाते हैं और ये संदेश दिया जाता है कि जाति बदली जा सकती है। हम अपने इस लेख और आने वालें लेखों में कुछ ऐसे ही उधारणों पर चर्चा करेंगे।</p>
<p><span id="more-5639"></span></p>
<p><strong>मातंग</strong> <strong>चांडालपुत्र</strong> <strong>से</strong> <strong>ब्राह्मण</strong> <strong>बने</strong><strong> ?</strong></p>
<p>मतंग (ना की मातंग) ऋषि की कथा विस्तार से महाभारत के अनुशासन पर्व (अध्याय 27 से 29) में आती है। उसमे आता है कि मतंग ऋषि एक ब्राह्मणी के पेट से शूद्रजातीय नाई द्वारा पैदा किए गए एक चांडाल है (अनुशासन पर्व अध्याय 27 श्लोक 17)। शूद्र वर्ण में जन्मे मतंग ऋषि घोर तप करते हैं। उनकी तपस्या से प्रसन्न हो कर इन्द्र उनके पास कई बार आते है और वर मांगने के लिए कहते है। मतंग वर मांगते है कि “मैं ब्राह्मण बन जाऊं । इस पर इंद्र बार-बार इसे छोड़ कर कोई अन्य वर मांगने के लिए कहते हैं।</p>
<p>इन्द्र का कहना है कि:</p>
<p><strong>चण्डालयोनौ</strong> <strong>जातेन</strong> <strong>नावाप्यं</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>कथंचन</strong><strong>     –  </strong><strong>महाभारत</strong> <strong>अनुशासन</strong> <strong>पर्व</strong> <strong>अध्याय</strong><strong> 29 </strong><strong>श्लोक</strong><strong> 4</strong></p>
<p><em>चाण्डाल</em> <em>की</em> <em>योनि</em> <em>में</em> <em>जन्म</em> <em>लेने</em> <em>वाले</em> <em>को</em> <em>किसी</em> <em>तरह</em> <em>भी</em> <em>ब्राह्मणत्व</em> <em>नहीं</em> <em>मिल</em> <em>सकता।</em></p>
<p>मतंग ब्राह्मणत्वं ते विरुद्धमिह दृश्यते । ब्राह्मणयं दुर्लभतरं    – महाभारत अनुशासन पर्व अध्याय 29 श्लोक 8</p>
<p><em>मतंग</em> <em>इस</em> <em>जन्म</em> <em>में</em> <em>तुम्हारे</em> <em>लिए</em> <em>ब्राह्मणत्व</em> <em>की</em> <em>प्राप्ति</em> <em>असंभव</em> <em>दिखायी</em> <em>देती</em> <em>है।</em> <em>ब्राह्मणत्व</em> <em>अत्यंत</em> <em>दुर्लभ</em> <em>है।</em></p>
<p>लेकिन मतंग नहीं मानते। इन्द्र चले जाते हैं। ऐसा कई बार होता है। अंतिम बार इंद्र आते हैं। मतंग पहले सा आग्रह नहीं करते वह अन्य वर मांगते हैं। वह कहते हैं-</p>
<p><strong>यथा</strong> <strong>कामविहारी</strong> <strong>स्यां</strong> <strong>कामरूपी</strong> <strong>विहड्नमः</strong> <strong>।ब्रह्मक्षत्राविरोधेन</strong> <strong>पूजां</strong> <strong>च</strong> <strong>प्राप्नुयामहम्</strong> <strong>॥</strong></p>
<p><strong>यथा</strong> <strong>ममाक्षया</strong> <strong>किर्तिर्भवेच्चापि</strong> <strong>पुरंदर</strong> <strong>।कर्तुमर्हसि</strong> <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>देव</strong> <strong>शीरसा</strong> <strong>त्वां</strong> <strong>प्रसादये</strong><strong>  </strong><strong>॥</strong><strong>         – </strong><strong>महाभारत</strong> <strong>अनुशासन</strong> <strong>पर्व</strong> <strong>अ०</strong><strong> 29 </strong><strong>श०</strong><strong> 22-23</strong></p>
<p><em>देव</em> <em>पुरंदर</em> <em>आप</em> <em>ऐसी</em> <em>कृपा</em> <em>करें</em><em>, </em><em>जिससे</em> <em>मैं</em> <em>इच्छानुसार</em> <em>विचरनेवाला</em> <em>तथा</em> <em>अपनी</em> <em>इच्छा</em> <em>के</em> <em>अनुसार</em> <em>रूपधारण</em> <em>करने</em> <em>वाला</em> <em>आकाशचारी</em> <em>देवता</em> <em>होऊँ</em> <em>।</em> <em>ब्राह्मण</em> <em>और</em> <em>क्षत्रियों</em> <em>के</em> <em>विरोध</em> <em>से</em> <em>रहित</em> <em>हो</em> <em>मैं</em> <em>सर्वत्र</em> <em>पूजा</em> <em>एवं</em> <em>सत्कार</em> <em>प्राप्त</em> <em>करूँ</em> <em>तथा</em> <em>मेरी</em> <em>अक्षय</em> <em>किर्ति</em> <em>का</em> <em>विस्तार</em> <em>हो।</em> <em>मैं</em> <em>आपके</em> <em>चरणों</em> <em>में</em> <em>मस्तक</em> <em>रख</em> <em>कर</em> <em>आपकी</em> <em>प्रसन्नता</em> <em>चाहता</em> <em>हूँ।</em> <em>आप</em> <em>मेरी</em> <em>इस</em> <em>प्राथना</em> <em>को</em> <em>सफल</em> <em>बनाइये</em> <em>।।</em></p>
<p>इंद्र वर देते हुए कहते हैं-</p>
<p><strong>छंदोदेव</strong> <strong>इति</strong> <strong>ख्यातः</strong> <strong>स्त्रीणां</strong> <strong>पुज्यो</strong> <strong>भविष्यसि</strong> <strong>।किर्तिश्र्च</strong> <strong>ते</strong> <strong>तुला</strong> <strong>वत्स</strong> <strong>त्रिषु</strong> <strong>लोकेषु</strong> <strong>यास्यति॥महाभारत</strong> <strong>अनुशासन</strong> <strong>पर्व</strong> <strong>अ०</strong><strong> 29 </strong><strong>श०</strong><strong> 24</strong></p>
<p><em>इंद्र</em><em>  </em><em>ने</em> <em>कहा</em><em> –</em><em>वत्स</em><em> ! </em><em>तुम</em> <em>स्त्रियों</em> <em>के</em> <em>पूजनीय</em> <em>होओगे।</em> <em>छंदोदेव</em> <em>के</em> <em>नाम</em> <em>से</em> <em>तुम्हारी</em> <em>ख्याति</em> <em>होगी</em> <em>और</em> <em>तीनों</em> <em>लोकों</em> <em>में</em> <em>तुम्हारी</em> <em>अनुपम</em> <em>किर्ति</em> <em>का</em> <em>विस्तार</em> <em>होगा</em><em>  </em><em>।।</em></p>
<p>स्पष्ट है की मतंग चांडाल से ब्राह्मण नहीं बना ।इसी बात को 29 वे अध्याय के 26 वें श्लोक में दोहराया गया है-</p>
<p><strong>एवमेतत्</strong> <strong>परं</strong> <strong>स्थानं</strong> <strong>ब्राह्मण्यं</strong> <strong>नाम</strong> <strong>भारत</strong> <strong>।</strong><strong> </strong><strong>तच्च</strong> <strong>दुष्प्रापमिह</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>महेंद्रवचनं</strong> <strong>यथा</strong><strong>   </strong><strong>॥</strong><strong>     </strong><strong>महाभारत</strong> <strong>अनुशासन</strong> <strong>पर्व</strong><strong>   29 </strong><strong>अ०</strong> <strong>श०</strong><strong> 26</strong></p>
<p><em>भारत</em><em> ! </em><em>इस</em> <em>तरह</em> <em>यह</em> <em>ब्राह्मणत्व</em> <em>परम</em> <em>उत्तम</em> <em>स्थान</em> <em>है।</em> <em>जैसा</em> <em>की</em> <em>इंद्र</em> <em>का</em> <em>कथन</em> <em>है</em><em>, </em><em>यह</em> <em>इस</em> <em>जीवन</em> <em>में</em> <em>दूसरे</em> <em>वर्ण</em> <em>के</em> <em>लोगों</em> <em>के</em> <em>लिए</em> <em>दुर्लभ</em> <em>है।</em></p>
<p>आर्यसमाजियों की धोकेभाज़ी- मूल मंत्र में हेराफेरी</p>
<p>इतनी स्पष्ट मतंगकथा के होते हुए भी किस तरह लोग भ्रांति में पड़ते हैं। इस का कारण स्वामी दयानंद जी का सत्यार्थ प्रकाश है, जिस में लिखा है-“ महाभारत में……मातंग ऋषि चांडाल कुल से ब्राह्मण हो गए थे।” (चतुर्थ समुल्लास)। इस बात को पुष्ट करने के लिए सत्यार्थप्रकाश के आर्यसमाज शताब्दी संस्करण (रामलाल कपूर ट्रस्ट प्रकाशन) के पृष्ठ 141 पर पादटिप्पणी में संपादकों ने महाभारत ,अनुशासन पर्व (3/19) का एक श्लोक,बिना अर्थ लिखे ,अंकित कर दिया है-</p>
<p>स्थाने मातंगो ब्राह्मण्यमलभद् भरतर्षभ,</p>
<p>चण्डालयोनौ जातो हि कथं ब्राह्मण्यमवाप्तवान्</p>
<p>कुछ ऐसा हि प्रयास सत्यार्थप्रकाश मानक संस्करण( श्रीमद् दयानंद सत्यार्थ प्रकाश न्यास ) द्वारा किया गया। इस संस्करण में विशेष टिप्पणी भाग पृष्ठ 27 में मतंग ऋषि के प्रकरण पर यह टिप्पणी बिना अर्थ के की गयी है-</p>
<p>स्थाने मतंगो ब्राह्मण्यमलभद् भरतर्षभ,</p>
<p>चण्डालयोनौ जातो हि कथं ब्राह्मण्यमवाप्तवान्             -महा,अनु (3/19)</p>
<p>इसी पथ पर चलते हुए कुछ वीरों ने (या कहिए झूठो ने) भी वीरता (पढ़िये कायरता) दिखाने की कोशिश की है:</p>
<p id="mczlQyS"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="605" height="155" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7665 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ab41a7c0.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ab41a7c0.png 605w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ab41a7c0-300x77.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 605px) 100vw, 605px" /></p>
[Note: The url is erased without the permission of the writer Neer Mohammed by the admin of VedKaBhed]
<p>इस श्लोक में आर्यसमाजियों ने हेराफेरी की है। मूल में “न” शब्द था, जो पादटिप्पणी में गायब है। अर्थ वैसे ही नहीं लिखा था। आर्यसमाजियों की बोधिक ईमानदारी का अंदाजा पाठक स्वयं लगा सकते हैं। अब यह जिज्ञासा बनी रहती है कि वास्तव में इस श्लोक का क्या अर्थ है। प्रकरण विश्वामित्र का चल रहा है। अध्याय के अंत में युधिष्ठिर का प्रश्नात्मक कथन है</p>
<p>स्थाने मतंगो ब्राह्मण्यं नालभद् भरतर्षभ,</p>
<p>चण्डालयोनौ जातो हि कथं ब्राह्मण्यमवाप्तवान्             -महा,अनु (3/19)</p>
<p>प्रमाण</p>
<p>1.गीता प्रैस गोरखपुर महाभारत हिन्दी अनुवाद सहित पृ. 5439</p>
<p id="hBeZOmF"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="626" height="147" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7666 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ac4690bf.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ac4690bf.png 626w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257ac4690bf-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 626px) 100vw, 626px" /></p>
<p>इस का अर्थ प्रकरण में इस तरह आता है: भरतश्रेष्ठ, मतंग को जो ब्राह्मणत्व नहीं प्राप्त हुआ,यह उचित ही था,क्योंकि उस का जन्म चांडाल की योनि में हुआ था,परंतु विश्वामित्र ने कैसे ब्राह्मणत्व प्राप्त कर लिया ?</p>
<p>स्वामी दयानंद का कथन महाभारत के उपरोक्त विवरण के बिलकुल विपरीत होने के कारण निराधार और कपोलकल्पित है। यहा स्पष्ट है की मतंग ब्राह्मण नहीं बनते, इस श्लोक में विश्वामित्र जी का भी उल्लेख किया गया है। इसकी यथार्थता हम इस श्रंखला के अगले लेख में देखेंगे।</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/matang-became-brahmin-from-chandal-hindi/" data-wpel-link="internal">मातंग चांडालपुत्र से ब्राह्मण बने ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Manu and the Shudras</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caste System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chandala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand saraswati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lowecaste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status of shudra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[untouchables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>[This is a 31 page hand written Ms. of Dr. Ambedkar. The chapter has no title. It is also left incomplete. The title is suggested—editor.] I The reader is now aware that in the Scheme of Manu there were two principal social divisions : those outside the Chaturvarna and those inside the Chaturvarna. The reader &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/" data-wpel-link="internal">Manu and the Shudras</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[[This is a 31 page hand written Ms. of Dr. Ambedkar. The chapter has no title. It is also left incomplete. The title is suggested—editor.]
<strong><br />
</strong><span id="more-1632"></span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:330px;">I</h3>
<p>The reader is now aware that in the Scheme of Manu there were two principal social divisions : those outside the Chaturvarna and those inside the Chaturvarna. The reader also knows that the present day Untouchables are the counterpart of those outside the Chaturvarna and that those inside the Chaturvarna were contrasted with those outside. They were a composite body made up of four different classes, the Brahmins, the Kshatriyas, the Vaishyas and the Shudras. The Hindu social system is not only a system in which the idea of classes is more dominant than the idea of community but it is a system which is based on inequality between classes and therefore between individuals. To put it concretely, the classes i. e. the Brahmins, Kshatriyas, Vaishyas, Shudras and Antyajas (Untouchables) are not horizontal, all on the same level. They are vertical i.e. one above the other. No Hindu will controvert this statement. Every Indian knows it. If there is any person who would have any doubt about it he can only be a foreigner. But any doubt which a foreigner might have will be dissolved if he is referred to the law of Manu who is the chief architect of the Hindu society and whose law has formed the foundations on which it is built. For his benefit I reproduce such texts from the Manu Smriti as go to prove that Hindu society is based on the principle of inequality.<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:300px;"><strong>II</strong></h3>
<p>It might be argued that the inequality prescribed by Manu in his Smriti is after all of historical importance. It is past history and cannot be supposed to have any bearing on the present conduct of the Hindu. I am sure nothing can be greater error than this. Manu is not a matter of the past. It is even more than a past of the present. It is a ‘living past’ and therefore as really present as any present can be.<br />
That the inequality laid down by Manu was the law of the land under the pre-British days may not be known to many foreigners. Only a few instances will show that such was the case.<br />
Under the rule of the Marathas and the Peshwas the Untouchables were not allowed within the gates of Poona city, the capital of the Peshwas between 3 p. m. and 9 a. m. because, before nine and after three, their bodies cast too long a shadow; and whenever their shadow fell upon a Brahmin it polluted him, so that he dare not taste food or water until he had bathed and washed the impurity away. So also no Untouchable was allowed to live in a walled town ; cattle and dogs could freely enter but not the Untouchables<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1">[1]</a><br />
Under the rule of the Marathas and the Peshwas the Untouchables might not spit on the ground lest a Hindu should be polluted by touching it with his foot, but had to hang an earthen pot round his neck to hold his spittle. He was made to drag a thorny branch of a tree with him to brush out his footsteps and when a Brahman came by, had to lie at a distance on his face lest his shadow might fall on the Brahman<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2" class="broken_link">[2]</a><br />
In Maharashtra an Untouchable was required to wear a black thread either in his neck or on his wrist for the purpose of ready identification.<br />
In Gujarat the Untouchables were compelled to wear a horn as their distinguishing mark<a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3" class="broken_link">[3]</a>.<br />
In the Punjab a sweeper was required while walking through streets in towns to carry a broom in his hand or under his armpit as a mark of his being a scavenger<a href="#_ftn4" name="_ftnref4" class="broken_link">[4]</a>.<br />
In Bombay the Untouchables were not permitted to wear clean or untorn clothes. In fact the shopkeepers took the precaution to see that before cloth was sold to the Untouchable it was torn &amp; soiled.<br />
In Malabar the Untouchables were not allowed to build houses above one storey in height<a href="#_ftn5" name="_ftnref5">[5]</a> and not allowed to cremate their dead<a href="#_ftn6" name="_ftnref6" class="broken_link">[6]</a>.<br />
In Malabar the Untouchables were not permitted to carry umbrellas, to wear shoes or golden ornaments, to milk cows or even to use the ordinary language of the country<a href="#_ftn7" name="_ftnref7" class="broken_link">[7]</a>.<br />
In South India Untouchables were expressly forbidden to cover the upper part of their body above the waist and in the case of women of the Untouchables they were compelled to go with the upper part of their bodies quite bare<a href="#_ftn8" name="_ftnref8" class="broken_link">[8]</a>.<br />
In the Bombay Presidency so high a caste as that of Sonars (gold- smiths) was forbidden to wear their Dhoties with folds<a href="#_ftn9" name="_ftnref9" class="broken_link">[9]</a> and prohibited to use <em>Namaskar</em> as the word of salutation#.</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p># The following letter will be interesting to the reader as it throws a flood of light as to whether the Dhamia prescribed by Manu was or was not the law of the land-</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>&#8221; To<br />
Damulsett Trimbucksett<br />
Head of the Caste of Goldsmiths.<br />
&#8221; The Hon &#8216;ble the President in Council having thought proper to prohibit the Caste of Goldsmiths from making use of the form of salutation termed Namaskar, you are hereby pre-emptorily enjoined to make known this order and resolution to the whole caste and to take care that the same be strictly observed.<br />
By order</p>
<p style="padding-left:390px;"> Secretary to Government</p>
<p style="padding-left:390px;"> sig. W. Page</p>
<p>Bombay<br />
9th August 1779.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>                                                              Resolution of Government </strong><br />
<strong>                                                               Dated 28th July 1779.</strong><br />
&#8221; Frequent disputes having arisen for some time between the Brahmins and Goldsmiths respecting a mode of salutation termed &#8221; Namaskar &#8221; made use of by the latter, and which the Brahmins allege they have no right to perform, and that the exercise of such ceremony by the Goldsmiths is a great breach and profanation of the rights of the Gentoo {Hindu] Religion, and repeated complaints having been made to us by the Brahmins, and the Peishwa also having several times written to the President, requesting the use of the Namaskar might be prohibited to the Goldsmiths-Resolved as it i« necessary. This matter should be decided by us in order that the dispute between the two castes may be put an end to, and the Brahmins appear to have reason <em>for</em> their complaint, that the Goldsmiths be forbidden the use of the Namaskar, and this being a matter wherein the Company&#8217;s interest is not concerned, our Resolution may be put on the footing of a compliment to the Peishwa whom the President is desired to make acquainted with our determination.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Under the Maratha rule any one other than a Brahmin uttering a Veda Mantra was liable to have his tongue cut off and as a matter of fact the tongues of several Sonars (goldsmiths) were actually cut off by the order of the Peshwa for their daring to utter the Vedas contrary to law.<br />
All over India Brahmin was exempt from capital punishment. He could not be hanged even if he committed murder.<br />
Under the Peshwas distinction was observed in the punishment of the criminals according to the caste. Hard labour and death were punishments mostly visited on the Untouchables<a href="#_ftn10" name="_ftnref10" class="broken_link">[10]</a>.<br />
Under the Peshwas Brahmin clerks had the privilege of their goods being exempted from certain duties and their imported corn being carried to them without any ferry charges; and Brahmin landlords had their lands assessed at distinctly lower rates than those levied from other classes. In Bengal the amount of rent for land varied with the caste of the occupant and if the tenant was an Untouchable he had to pay the highest rent.<br />
These facts will show that Manu though born some time before B. C. or sometime after A. D. is not dead and while the Hindu Kings reigned, justice between Hindu and Hindu, touchable and untouchable was rendered according to the Law of Manu and that law was avowedly based on inequality.<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:300px;"><strong>III<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>This is the dharma laid down by Manu. It is called Manav Dharma i. e. Dharma which by its inherent goodness can be applied to all men in all times and in all places. Whether the fact that it has not had any force outside India is a blessing or a curse I do not stop to inquire. It is important to note that this Manav Dharma is based upon the theory that the Brahman is to have all the privileges and the Shudra is not to have even the rights of a human being, that the Brahman is to be above everybody in all things merely by reason of his high birth and the Shudra is to be below everybody and is to have none of the things no matter how great may be his worth.<br />
Nothing can show the shamelessness and absurdity of this Manava Dharma better than turning it upside down. I know of no better attempt in this behalf than that of Dr. R. P. Pranjape agreat Educationist, Politician and Social reformer and I make no apology for reproducing it in full—</p>
<p style="padding-left:240px;"><strong>Peep Into the Future<a href="#_ftn11" name="_ftnref11"><strong>[11]</strong></a></strong></p>
<p>This piece Was written against the Non-Brahmin Parties which were then in power in the Bombay and Madras Presidency and in the Central Provinces. The Non-Brahmin parties were founded with the express object of not allowing a single community to have a monopoly in State Service. The Brahmins have a more or less complete monopoly in the State services in all provinces in India and in all departments of State. The Non-Brahmin parties had therefore laid down the principle, known as the principle of communal ratio, that given minimum qualifications candidates belonging to non-Brahmin communities should be given preference over Brahmin candidates when making appointments in the public services. In my view there was nothing wrong in this principle. It was undoubtedly wrong that the administration of the country should be in the hands of a single community however clever such a community might be.<br />
The Non-Brahmin Party held the view that good Government was better than efficient Government was not a principle to be confined only to the composition of the Legislature &amp; the Executive. But that it must also be made applicable to the field of administration. It was through administration that the State came directly in contact with the masses. No administration could do any good unless it was sympathetic. No administration could be sympathetic if it was manned by the Brahmins alone. How can the Brahmin who holds himself superior to the masses, despises the rest as low caste and Shudras, is opposed to their aspiration, is instinctively led to be partial to his community and being uninterested in the masses is open to corruption be a good administrator ? He is as much an alien to the Indian masses as any foreigner can be. As against this the Brahmins have been taking their stand on efficiency pure &amp; simple. They know that this is the only card they can play successfully by reason of their advanced position in education. But they forget that if efficiency was the only criterion then in all probability there would be very little chance for them to monopolise State service in the way and to the extent they have done. For if efficiency was made the only criterion there would be nothing wrong in employing Englishmen, Frenchmen, Germans &amp; Turks instead of the Brahmins of India. Be that as it may, the Non-Brahmin Parties refused to make a fetish to efficiency and insisted that there must be introduced the principle of communal ratio in the public services in order to introduce into the administration an admixture of all castes &amp; creeds and thereby make it a good administration. In carrying out this principle the Non-Brahmin Parties in their eagerness to cleanse the administration of Brahmindom while they were in power, did often forget the principle that in redressing the balance between the Brahmins and non-Brahmins in the public services they were limited by the rule of minimum efficiency. But that does not mean that the principle they adopted for their guidance was not commendable in the interests of the masses.<br />
This policy no doubt set the teeth of many Brahmins on edge. They were vehement in their anger. This piece by Dr. Paranjpe is the finest satire on the policy of the non-Brahmin Party. It caricatures the principle of the non-Brahman party in a manner which is inimitable and at the time when it came out, I know many non-Brahmin leaders were not only furious but also speechless. My complaint against Dr. Paranjpe is that he did not see the humour of it. The non-Brahmin Party was doing nothing new. It was merely turning Manu Smriti upside down. It was turning the tables. It was putting the Brahmin in the position in which Manu had placed the Shudra. Did not Manu give privileges to Brahmin merely because he was a Brahmin ? Did not Manu deny any right to the Shudra even though he deserved it ? Can there be much complaint if now the Shudra is given some privileges because he is a Shudra ? It may sound absurd but the rule is not without precedent and that precedent is the Manu Smriti itself. And who can throw stones at the non-Brahmin Party ? The Brahmins may if they are without sin. But can the authors and worshippers, upholders of Manu Smriti claim that they are without sin? Dr. Paranjpe&#8217;s piece is the finest condemnation of the inquity that underlies this Manav Dharma. It shows as nothing else does what a Brahmin feels when he is placed in the position of a Shudra.</p>
<h3 style="padding-left:360px;">IV</h3>
<p>Inequality is not confined to Hindus. It prevailed elsewhere also and was responsible for dividing society into higher and lower free and servile classes. (Left incomplete in Ms—ed.)</p>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> Dr. Murray Milchell-Great Religions of India, p. 63</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2" class="broken_link">[2]</a> Bombay Gazetteer. Vol. XII. p. 175.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3" class="broken_link">[3]</a> Ency R.&amp;. E. Vol. IX p. 636 (b).</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref4" name="_ftn4">[4]</a> Punjab Census Report 1911 p. 413</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref5" name="_ftn5" class="broken_link">[5]</a> Bhattacharya-p. 259.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref6" name="_ftn6">[6]</a> Madras Census 1891 .p. 299</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref7" name="_ftn7" class="broken_link">[7]</a> Bhatacharya-Hindu Castes-p. 259.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref8" name="_ftn8" class="broken_link">[8]</a> Madras Census 1891 p. 224</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref9" name="_ftn9" class="broken_link">[9]</a> This mode of wearing dhoties was referred for Brahmins only. The Shudras were to wear it without folds.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref10" name="_ftn10" class="broken_link">[10]</a> G. B. <em>Vom &amp;.Off&#8217;icial Wrling sof Mot Hstuart Elphinst OM.</em> 1884.pp.310-ll.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref11" name="_ftn11" class="broken_link">[11]</a> Reproduced from-Gujarali Punch-May 1921 (Not quoted in the Ms.—ed.)</h6>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/" data-wpel-link="internal">Manu and the Shudras</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
