<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>honor killing &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/honor-killing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 10:42:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honor killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed &#160; Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show Satyamev Jayate has once again brought the issue to public attention. In the discussions that followed the verse &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7866 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png" alt="" width="359" height="239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" />Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show <em>Satyamev Jayate</em> has once again brought the issue to public attention.</p>
<p>In the discussions that followed the verse <strong>यत्र</strong> <strong>नार्यस्तु</strong> <strong>पूज्यन्ते</strong> <strong>रमन्ते</strong> <strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>देवता</strong>  (Devatas reside where women are worshipped) was used repeatedly. This painted a misleading picture of the ancient indian society suggesting that misogyny sprung up from nowhere. A closer examination reveals, however, that this verse from Manu Smriti has been divorced from its context and the word <strong>“</strong><strong>पूजन</strong><strong>” or “</strong><strong>पुजा”</strong> has been interpreted rather arbitrarily to suit a particular view. We reserve the discussion of this verse for future articles.</p>
<p><span id="more-856"></span></p>
<p>Earlier there were 40 accepted Vedic sanskar (sacraments), now however only 16 of these are conducted. The first of these 16 sanskar is that of “<strong>Garbahabhan</strong>” (conception), the second being “<strong>Punsavan</strong>”. Before coming to the main subject of the article, I would like to place before the reader a few facts about these sanskar (sacraments).</p>
<p><strong>Varna System or Death System?</strong></p>
<p>What follows is a brief analysis of these sanskar (sacraments) and the caste system. In Hinduism the evil of caste gets associated with the person from his birth itself. On the face of it Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj seem to reject the birth based caste system and accept a social system based on merit but do they practice what they preach? To investigate this let us consider the following three verses from Manu Smriti. The first two of these occur as they are in Swami Dayanand’s <em>Sanskar Vidhi</em> published by Arya Sahitya Prachar Trust (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7867" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png" alt="" width="549" height="267" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a.png 652w" sizes="(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px" /></p>
<p>(A)&#8221;Garbhan and other Sanskar (sacrament) of dwija should be performed with holy rites prescribed by the Veda. Because these sanctify the body and purify in this life and after death&#8221; ( Manu Smriti 2-26)</p>
<p>(B)&#8221;By womb related sacraments (Garbhadan, Punswan, Simantyan), Jatkarma, Chudakarma and Upanyan sanskar (sacraments) the defects related to the womb and the semen of the Dwijas is removed&#8221; (Manu Smriti 2-27).</p>
<p>(C)“Let (the first part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s name (denote something) auspicious, a Kshatriya&#8217;s be connected with power, and a Vaisya&#8217;s with wealth, but a Sudra&#8217;s (express something) contemptible.</p>
<p>(The second part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s (name) shall be (a word) implying happiness, of a Kshatriya&#8217;s (a word) implying protection, of a Vaisya&#8217;s (a term) expressive of thriving, and of a Sudra&#8217;s (an expression) denoting service.” [Manu Smriti 2/31-32]
<p>The third verse is not from the above mentioned book however the idea is mentioned in the book in following manner</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7869" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png" alt="" width="550" height="66" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a.png 611w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>“The male child born should be named thus &#8211; if the child is Brāhman &#8211; name him ‘Devsharmā’, if he is Kshatriya- name him ‘Devvarmā’, if he is Vaishya &#8211; name him ‘Devgūpta’,if he is a Shūdra name him ‘Devdās’.</p>
<p>Here it has been advised to name a child in the naming ceremony (10 days after birth) according to the above mentioned rules.</p>
<p>Whether such practices can remedy deficiencies of semen or womb is irrelevant but a number of questions arise after reading the above, why is this practice limited only to the Dwijas (Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaishya)? What is the basis of this distinction drawn between the Dwijas (referred to as ‘twice-born’ henceforth) on one hand and the Shudras on another? Certainly there is no difference in merit of 10 days old twice-born and Shudra, then why is a child born in Shudra family believed to be a ‘Shudra’ and has ‘das’ appended to his name? These people who keep insisting that Varna system is not based on birth but on merit have no answers to these questions.</p>
<p><strong>Punsavan Sanskar (Sacrament)</strong></p>
<p>What exactly is this Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament)? Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelkar while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ sukta from Atharvaved, in his commentary of Atharvaved writes,</p>
<p>“The birth of son is called ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ and birth of girl is called ‘<strong>Straishuya</strong>’”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar has named the section where he explains this sukta as “Certain birth of son” this in itself explains the term ‘Punsavan’. Swami Dayanand’s associate who later became the leader of Sanatan Dharma, Pandit Bhimsen Sharma while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ writes,</p>
<p><strong>उत्पत्स्यमानगर्भस्य</strong> <strong>बेजिकगार्भिकदोषपरिहारार्न्थ</strong> <strong>पुंरूपत्वसंपत्तये</strong> <strong>च</strong> <strong>पुंसवनम्</strong></p>
<p>(षोडशसंस्कारविधी, तृतीय संस्करण,1926, पृ. 72-73)</p>
<p>“Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament) is conducted to remove the semen and womb related deficiencies of the unborn child and to make it male”</p>
<p>In other words the sanskar (sacrament) is conducted so that a male child is born and if the unborn child is female then it should be transformed to a male child. This is the ancient Vedic way of getting rid of female foetuses. Even if we leave aside the question of effectiveness of such a procedure, the mentality operating behind such practices can be easily seen. If the female foetus itself is converted to male foetus then there is no question of birth of girls. This indicates that why even today people do not wish a girl child to be born to them.</p>
<p>While today, scientific methods are used to detect the sex of the foetus and to kill it if it is a girl, in Vedic times the foetus itself was transformed (at least people wished to do so) to a male foetus. The underlying mentality is same, only the methods have changed.</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand presents five proofs related to Punsavan Sanskar, without mentioning their meaning. However, the meanings given by other Arya Samaji Scholars make the picture clearer. Below is the meaning given by Ramgopal Vidyalankar in his book titled <em>Sanskar-Prakash Arthart Mahrshi Dayanand Sarsvati Parnit Sanskarvidhi</em> on pages 43-44</p>
<p><strong>पुमानग्निः</strong> <strong>पुमानिन्द्र</strong><strong>: </strong><strong>पुमान्देवो</strong> <strong>ब्रहस्पति</strong><strong>:  </strong><strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>पुत्रं</strong> <strong>विन्दस्व</strong> <strong>तं</strong> <strong>पुमाननु</strong> <strong>जायतां</strong> <strong>स्वाहा</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>मंत्रब्राह्मण</strong><strong> 1/4/9]</strong></p>
<p>“Agni, Indra, and learned scholar of diverse disciplines &#8211; give you strength. May you get a strong son and let even his descendent be strong.” [Mantra Brahman 1/4/9]
<p><strong>शमीमश्वत्थ</strong> <strong>आरूढ़स्तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवानं</strong> <strong>कृतम्</strong> <strong>तद्वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेद्नं</strong> <strong>तत्स्त्रीष्वाभरामसि</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/1]</strong></p>
<p>“’Punsavan is done after a man as virile as a horse conceives a woman calm by nature as it is the best solution to get a son. The sanskar (sacrament) is conducted on women.” [Atharvaved 6/11/1]
<p>Let me also mention the interpretation of Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelekar</p>
<p>“(<strong>अश्व</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>त्थ</strong><strong>: </strong>) Peepal tree (<strong>शमी</strong> <strong>आरूढ़</strong><strong>:</strong>) where it grows on Shami tree (<strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवनं</strong> <strong>कृतं</strong> ) Punsavan is done there. (<strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>) This ensures birth of a son (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रीषु</strong> <strong>आ</strong> <strong>भरामसि</strong>) we give this to women ”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains the procedure of this sanskar (sacrament) in his exegesis of this verse</p>
<p>“1. The Peepal tree that grows on the Shami tree makes the foetus in the womb take male form. That is if a woman takes the medicine prepared out of this then she will definitely give birth to a son. 2. Such a Peepal tree ensures the birth of a son. 3. The consumption of it ensures the birth of a son. 4. Women should be given the medicine prepared from such a Peepal tree to ensure the birth of a son.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar continues</p>
<p>“The peepal tree growing on a Shami tree should be powdered and should be consumed with honey or milk etc. This makes the woman’s womb capable of producing a son. This medicine should be given to a woman who gives birth only to girls. This changes their womb and may generate strength to produce a male child.”</p>
<p>Now let us take a look at the second verse of ‘Punsavan’</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar writes</p>
<p><strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>रेतो</strong> <strong>भवति</strong> <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियामनुषिच्यते</strong> <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong> <strong>तत्प्रजापतिरब्रवित्</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/2]</strong></p>
<p>“God Prajapati has said that semen definitely is in man, this is nurtured in the woman and thus a son produced.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains this as</p>
<p>(<strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वे</strong> <strong>रेतः</strong> <strong>भवति</strong>)Semen definitely is in the man (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियो</strong> <strong>अनु</strong> <strong>षिच्यते</strong>) it is nurtured in the women ( <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>)it is a means to get a son,( <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अब्रवित्</strong> ) this is said by Prajapati .</p>
<p>Let us turn to the 3rd verse.</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar &#8211;</p>
<p><strong>प्रजापतिरनुमतिः</strong> <strong>सिनीवाल्यचीक्लृपत्</strong><strong>  </strong><strong>स्त्रैषूमन्यत्र</strong> <strong>दधत्पुमांसमु</strong> <strong>दधदिह</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/3]</strong></p>
<p>“Prajapati, Anumati and Siniwali (Sanvatsar, Pournima and Amavasya) complete the foetus. The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere, the rules related to male are described here.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar writes &#8211;</p>
<p>“(<strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अनुमतिः</strong>) Father should be determined to get a son (<strong>सिनी</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>वाली</strong> <strong>अचीक्लृपत्</strong>) and the mother should be capable (of bearing a son) only if this happens (<strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>उ</strong> <strong>इह</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) a male foetus is formed (<strong>अन्यत्र</strong> <strong>स्त्रैषूयं</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) otherwise a female foetus is formed..”</p>
<p>Whatever has been said about this third verse of ‘Punsavan’ sukta of Atharvaved is quite clear except the second part which can have three meanings</p>
<p>The first and second are given these scholars</p>
<ol>
<li>The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere the rules related to men are described here.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation could have been accepted if the rules concerning the birth of females had been mentioned in the Vedas elsewhere but we have to say with great disappointment that perhaps this is not true. For this reason this interpretation is unacceptable. However, even with this interpretation the importance given to the birth of a son can be clearly seen.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Male foetus is formed (in the conditions mentioned above) otherwise a female foetus is formed.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation given by Shri Damodar is accepted but the implications of such an interpretation are noteworthy. If this interpretation is true then definitely birth of a son would be wished for since ‘Punsavan’ is performed by everyone.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Third interpretation would be – Let girl/female foetus be placed in some other womb and male fetus be placed in this womb. Even this meaning exposes the underlying mentality which wishes for a male child and rejects a female child.</li>
</ol>
<p>So, these are the verses used to prevent a female child from taking birth and ensuring the birth a male child. It would not be wrong to call this the ancient and Vedic version of female foeticide. The Hindu scriptures enjoining ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ fail to even mention the sanskar (sacrament) named “<strong>Straisuy</strong>”</p>
<p>As far as Vedas are concerned women are not allowed to give birth to a female child, there however, is the command to give birth to 10 sons. A verse from Rigveda reads</p>
<p><strong>इमां</strong> <strong>तवमिन्द्र</strong> <strong>मीढ्वः</strong> <strong>सुपुत्रां</strong> <strong>सुभगां</strong> <strong>कर्णु</strong> <strong>।</strong> <strong>दशास्यां</strong> <strong>पुत्राना</strong> <strong>धेहि</strong> <strong>पतिमेकादशं</strong> <strong>कर्धि</strong><strong> ||</strong> -ऋग्वेद 10/85/45</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand writes the meaning of this verse as follows</p>
<p>O majestic man capable of nurturing semen! Give a married woman or widow the best son and grant her good fortune. Produce 10 sons for a married woman and consider the 11th to be a woman.</p>
<p>This makes it clear that the birth of a girl is neither desired nor considered good since ancient times. However such verses can neither change the way sex is determined nor can they prevent the birth of a girl child. As such a girl once born has to be accepted. But nothing changes after this</p>
<p>In the ‘<strong>Harish-Narad dialogue</strong>’ in <em>Aitreya Brahman</em> which is an explanation of the Rigved, Narad says:</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>कृपणं</strong> <strong>ह</strong> <strong>दुहिता</strong></p>
<p>“Daughter leads to suffering and is a cause of misery”</p>
<p>While explaining this, scholar Sayancharya quotes an ancient verse</p>
<p><strong>संभवे</strong> <strong>स्वजनदुः</strong> <strong>खकारिका</strong> <strong>संप्रदानसमयेर्थदारिका</strong> <strong>योवनेपि</strong> <strong>बहुदोषकारिका</strong> <strong>दारिका</strong> <strong>ह्रदयदारिका</strong> <strong>पितुः</strong></p>
<p>“When a girl is born, she makes relatives unhappy; when she gets married she takes away wealth. She commits a lot of mistakes in her youth that is why it is said that she cleaves her father’s heart”</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya writes with respect to ‘daughter’ in his Nirukt</p>
<p>“Daughter is called Duhita because she is <em><u>Durhita</u></em> (one who does bad) and <em>Durehita</em> (it is better if she stays far away). She is <em>Dogdha</em> (one who sucks parent’s wealth)” – (Nirukt Adhayay 3, Khand 4)</p>
<p>In the next Adhyay of the same book, while explaining the word  ‘Kanya’ Acharya Yaska writes,</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>क्वेयं</strong> <strong>नेत्व्य</strong></p>
<p>(Nirukt Adhyay 4 Khand 15)</p>
<p>“Kanya is so called because as soon as she takes birth parents start worrying about her marriage”</p>
<p>These examples show the negative view associated with the birth of girl in Hindu culture and Hindu religious scriptures. It is this mentality which is criticized in the Qur’an in the following words &#8211;</p>
<p>And when one of them is informed of [the birth of] a female, his face becomes dark, and he suppresses grief. He hides himself from the people because of the ill of which he has been informed. Should he keep it in humiliation or bury it in the ground? Unquestionably, evil is what they decide. (Qur’an 16/58-59)</p>
<p>Allah, the Exalted puts an end to the discrimination between a boy and a girl in the Qur’an</p>
<p>To Allah belongs the dominion of the heavens and the earth; He creates what he wills. He gives to whom He wills female [children], and He gives to whom He wills males. (Qur’an 42/49)</p>
<p>A point worth noting is that in this verse daughters are mentioned before sons. Commenting on this verse Sayyidina Wathilah ibn Aska said, fortunate is the woman who has a daughter as her first child.</p>
<p>Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) said,</p>
<p>If anyone has a female child, and does not bury her alive, or slight her, or prefer his sons to her, Allah will bring him into Paradise. [Narrated by Abdullah ibn Abbas; Abu Dawud, Kitaab al-Adab, Hadith 5127)</p>
<p>To conclude, I would like to say that to put an end to the evil practice of female foeticide and the negative view associated with a girl child, the mentality operating behind these needs to be destroyed. How do we do that? Well,</p>
<p><strong>किं</strong> <strong>ग्राहृयमग्राहृयमिति</strong> <strong>कवयो</strong> <strong>नात्र</strong> <strong>मोहिताः</strong><strong>, </strong><strong>अज्ञस्तु</strong> <strong>मूढ़मतित्वात्सतृणमभ्यवहारी</strong> <strong>।।</strong></p>
<p>Deciding between the acceptable and unacceptable is not difficult. A wise person embraces the acceptable and rejects the unacceptable but a foolish person due to his foolishness believes a cow and donkey to be the same.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dowry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honor killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad Newspapers in India carry reports of rape and burning of women for not bringing sufficient dowry or their inability to satisfy the demands of greedy in-laws. The Indian National Crime Records Bureau (NCRB) reports that there were about 8172 dowry death cases registered in India in 2008 [1]. Dowry (known as Dahejin Hindi) &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color: #56595e;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<h6 style="color: #56595e;"></h6>
<p id="ViJCGjO"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="294" height="294" class="size-full wp-image-7897  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1.png 294w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Newspapers in India carry reports of rape and burning of women for not bringing sufficient dowry or their inability to satisfy the demands of greedy in-laws. The Indian National Crime Records Bureau (NCRB) reports that there were about 8172 dowry death cases registered in India in 2008 <sup id="cite_ref-3" class="reference">[1]</sup>. Dowry (known as <em style="color: #999999;">Dahej</em>in Hindi) has been traditionally practiced in the Hindu society since centuries. Dowry is given by the parents of the girl and it consists of various household things like dresses, ornaments, electrical goods, bedroom furniture, etc. at the time of the marriage. Additionally, rich people also give cash, car, property or land as part of dowry. But for middle class people, and those who are not so well off, the custom of dowry has become an evil. Ordinary people with average wages spend all their savings in preparation of a dowry for their daughter to take with her after her marriage. The Indian government has banned giving and accepting dowry in Hindu marriage. This article will give historic background to the age old tradition of dowry in Hindu marriage.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><span id="more-839"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #56595e;">Dowry in Hindu Scriptures</h2>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><em style="color: #999999;">Vedas </em>are considered as the oldest Hindu texts. Several passages in the Vedas make mention of dowry in Hindu marriages.<em style="color: #999999;">Rigveda </em>Mandal 1, Suktas 125 and 126 talk of the dowry King Swanaya paid to Kakshivat on the marriage of his daughter with him. Rigveda 1/126/2-3 mentions,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">शतं राज्ञो नाधमानस्य निष्काञ्छतमश्वान परयतान सद्य आदम |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">शतं कक्षीवानसुरस्य गोनां दिवि शरवो.अजरमा ततान ||</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">उप मा शयावाः सवनयेन दत्ता वधूमन्तो दश रथासोस्थुः |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">षष्टिः सहस्रमनु गव्यमागात सनत कक्षीवानभिपित्वे अह्नाम ||</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;From which generous prince, soliciting (my acceptance), I, Kakshivat, unhesitatingly accepted a hundred nishkas, a hundred vigorous steeds, and a hundred bulls, whereby he has spread his imperishable fame through heaven. Ten chariots drawn by bay steeds, and carrying my wives, stood near me, given me by Swanaya ; and a thousand and sixty cows followed : these, after a short interval of time, did Kashivat deliver (to his father).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The legend which is cited by the commentator of the four Vedas, Acharya Sayana, relates that Kakshivat, having finished his course of study, and taken leave of his preceptor, was journeying homewards, when night came on, and he fell asleep by the roadside: early in the morning, Raja Swanaya, the son of Bhavayavya, attended by his retinue, came to the spot, and disturbed the Brahmin&#8217;s slumbers: upon his starting up, the Raja addressed him with great cordiality, and being struck by his personal appearance, determined, if he was of suitable rank and birth, to give him his daughters in marriage. After ascertaining his fitness, he took Kakshivat home with him, and there married him to his ten daughters, presenting him at the same time with a hundred &#8216;nishkas&#8217; of gold, a hundred horses, a hundred bulls, one thousand and sixty cows, and eleven chariots, one for each of his wives and one for himself, each drawn by four horses. With these presents Kakshivat returned home, and placed them at the disposal of his father, Dirghatamas.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This evidence is corroborated by Rishi Shaunaka&#8217;s <em style="color: #999999;">Brhaddevata </em>which also repeats these mantras explaining their purport.<em style="color: #999999;">Brhaddevata </em>3/146-150 says,</p>
<p id="NrxFUFR"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="398" height="325" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7644 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7.png 398w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7-300x245.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px" /></p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8216;I am a son of the seer Dirghatamas, son of Ucathya, O king.&#8217; Thereupon he (Swanaya) gave him ten maidens decked with ornaments. and the same number of chariots, strong-bodied bay steeds going in teams of four, for the purpose of conveying the maidens, money and (utensils of) inferior metal, goats and sheep. Further he gave (him) a hundred necklets and a hundred bulls. This is told in the next hymn with (the stanza) &#8216;A hundred&#8217; and so forth. A hundred horses, a hundred necklets, ten chariots with maidens, (steeds) going in teams of four, and a thousand and sixty cows.Kakshivat, who obtained (all this) from Swanaya Bhavayavya, both praised (him) after receiving (it) and recited (the hymn) &#8216;At morn&#8217; to his father.</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This reference besides proving the existence of Polygamy in Vedic society, also shows the prevalence of dowry in that society.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><em style="color: #999999;">Rigveda </em>Mandal 10, Sukta 85 as well as <em style="color: #999999;">Atharvaved </em>Kaand 14, Suktas 1 and 2, contain details about the Hindu marriage ceremony. Verses from these hymns are chanted during Hindu wedding ceremonies. Rigveda 10/85/13 and Atharvaved 14/1/13 talking of the wedding season says,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">सूर्याया वहतुः प्रागात्सविता यमवासृजत् |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">अघासुहन्यन्ते गावो.अर्जुन्योः पर्युह्यते ||</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;Surya&#8217;s bridal procession which Savita despatched has advanced;<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> the oxen are whipped along</span></strong> in the Magha (constellations); she is borne (to her husband&#8217;s house) in the Arjuni (constellations).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The purport of this mantra is that the Dowry (in this case the oxen) must reach the husband&#8217;s home before the bride is escorted there.The next two mantras describe that two men from the bride&#8217;s family must take this Dowry to the husband&#8217;s home well before the wedding ceremony. For more details about the process of giving Dowry refer to the commentary of Arya Samaj scholar <strong><span class="st">Sripad </span>Damodar Satvalekar</strong> on these mantras<strong><em style="color: #999999;"> (Atharvaveda ka Subodh Bhashya </em></strong>Kaand 14).</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This system of Dowry has continued since Vedic times till today. Other Hindu texts contain detailed accounts of dowry. For example, Mahabharata Adi Parv Section 197/ Shlokas 15-18 provide details of the dowry presented by King Drupada on the marriage of his daughter <b>Kṛṣṇā Draupadi </b><span class="Unicode" title="International Alphabet of Sanskrit Transliteration">with the five Pandavas (Polyandry).<br />
</span></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">15 कृते विवाहे दरुपदॊ धनं ददौ; महारथेभ्यॊ बहुरूपम उत्तमम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     शतं रथानां वरहेमभूषिणां; चतुर्युजां हेमखलीन मालिनाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">16 शतं गजानाम अभिपद्मिनीं तथा; शतं गिरीणाम इव हेमशृङ्गिणाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     तथैव दासी शतम अग्र्ययौवनं; महार्हवेषाभरणाम्बर सरजम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">17 पृथक पृथक चैव दशायुतान्वितं; धनं ददौ सौमकिर अग्निसाक्षिकम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     तथैव वस्त्राणि च भूषणानि; परभावयुक्तानि महाधनानि</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">18 कृते विवाहे च ततः सम पाण्डवाः; परभूतरत्नाम उपलभ्य तां शरियम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     विजह्रुर इन्द्र परतिमा महाबलाः; पुरे तु पाञ्चाल नृपस्य तस्य ह</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;After the weddings were over, king Drupada gave unto those mighty car-warriors diverse kinds of excellent wealth. And the king gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">one hundred cars with golden standards, each drawn by four steeds with golden bridles</span></strong>. And he gave them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">one hundred elephants all possessing auspicious marks on their temples and faces and like unto a hundred mountains with golden peaks</span></strong>. He also gave them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">a hundred female servants all in the prime of youth and clad in costly robes and ornaments and floral wreaths</span></strong>. And the illustrious monarch of the Lunar race gave unto each of those princes of celestial beauty, making the sacred fire a witness of his gifts, <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">much wealth and many costly robes and ornaments of great splendour</span></strong>. The sons of Pandu endued with great strength, after their wedding were over, and after they had obtained Krishna like unto a second Sri along with great wealth, passed their days in joy and happiness, like so many Indras, in the capital of the king of the Panchalas.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The Mahabharata also informs us of dowry given during the marriage of Abhimanyu, son of Arjuna with Uttara, daughter of King Viraat. Mahabharata Virat Parv, section 72, shlokas 36-37 say</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">36 तस्मै सप्त सहस्राणि हयानां वातरंहसाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     दवे च नागशते मुख्ये परादाद बहुधनं तदा</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">37 हुत्वा सम्यक् समिद्धाग्निमर्चयित्वा द्विजन्मः</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     राज्यं बलं कोशं च सर्वमात्मानमेव च</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>And Virata then gave him <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">(as dowry) seven thousand steeds endued with the speed of the wind and two hundred elephants of the best kind and much wealth also</span></strong>. And having duly poured libations of clarified butter on the blazing fire, and paid homage unto the twice-born ones, <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Virata offered to the Pandavas his kingdom, army, treasury, and his own self</span></strong>.</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Mahabharata Adi Parv section 220 details the dowry provided by Krishna and Balrama on the marriage of their sister Subhadra.</p>
<table style="color: #56595e;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>तेषां ददौ हृषीकेशो जन्यार्थे धनमुत्तमम्।<br />
हरणं वै सुभद्राया ज्ञातिदेयं महायशाः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>रथानां काञ्चनाङ्गानां किङ्किणीजालमालिनाम्।<br />
चतुर्युजामुपेतानां सूतैः कुशलशिक्षितैः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>सहस्रं प्रददौ कृष्मो गवामयुतमेव च।<br />
श्रीमान्माथुरदेश्यानां दोग्ध्रीणां पुण्यवर्चसाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>बडवानां च शुद्धानां चन्द्रांशुसमवर्चसाम्।<br />
ददौ जनार्दनः प्रीत्या सहस्रं हेमभूषितम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>तथैवाश्वतरीणां च दान्तानां वातरंहसाम्।<br />
शतान्यञ्जनकेशीनां श्वेतानां पञ्चपञ्च च।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>स्नानपानोत्सवे चैव प्रयुक्तं वयसान्वितम्।<br />
स्त्रीणां सहस्रं गौरीणां सुवेषाणां सुवर्चसाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>सुवर्णशतकण्ठीनामरोमाणां स्वलङ्कृताम्।<br />
परिचर्यासु दक्षाणां प्रददौ पुष्करेक्षणः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>पृष्ठ्यानामपि चाश्वानां बाह्लिकानां जनार्दनः।<br />
ददौ शतसहस्राख्यं कन्याधनमनुत्तमम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>कृताकृतस्य मुख्यस्य कनकस्याग्निवर्चसः।<br />
मनुष्यभारान्दाशार्हो ददौ दश जनार्दनः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>गजानां तु प्रभिन्नानां त्रिधा प्रस्रवतां मदम्।<br />
गिरिकूटनिकाशानां समरेष्वनिवर्तिनाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>क्लृप्तानां पटुघण्टानां चारूणां हेममालिनाम्।<br />
हस्त्यारोहैरुपेतानां सहस्रं साहसप्रियः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>रामः पाणिग्रहणिकं ददौ पार्थाय लाङ्गली।<br />
प्रीयमाणो हलधरः संबन्धं प्रति मानयन्।।</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>Then Hrishikesa of great renown gave unto the party of the bridegroom much wealth. And unto Subhadra he gave the nuptial presents <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">that had been given to her by her relatives. Krishna gave unto the Pandavas a thousand cars of gold furnished with rows of bells, and unto each of which were put four steeds driven by well-trained charioteers</span></strong>. He also gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ten thousand cows</span></strong> belonging to the country of Mathura, and yielding much milk and all of excellent colour. Well-pleased, Janardana also gave them a <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">thousand mares with gold harnesses and of colour white as the beams of the moon. He also gave them a thousand mules, all well-trained and possessing the speed of the wind, of white colour with black manes. And he of eyes like lotus-petals also gave unto them a thousand damsels well-skilled in assisting at bathing and at drinking, young in years and virgins all before their <i>first-season</i>, well-attired and of excellent complexion, each wearing a hundred pieces of gold around her neck, of skins perfectly polished, decked</span></strong> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">with every ornament, and well-skilled in every kind of personal service</span></strong>. Janardana also gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">hundreds of thousands of draft horses</span></strong> from the country of the Valhikas <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">as Subhadra&#8217;s excellent dower</span></strong>. That foremost one of Dasarha&#8217;s race also gave unto Subhadra as her peculium<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ten carrier-loads of first class gold</span></strong> possessing the splendour of fire, some purified and some in a state of ore. And Rama having the plough for his weapon and always loving bravery gave unto Arjuna, as a nuptial present, a<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">thousand elephants</span></strong> with secretions flowing in three streams from the three parts of their bodies (the temple, the ears, and the anus) each large as a mountain summit, irresistible in battle, decked with coverlets and bells, well-adorned with other golden ornaments, and equipped with excellent thrones on their backs.<br />
[Mahabharata Adiparv 220 Haranaharana parv, sholkas 44-55, printed by Gita Press Gorakhpur]</blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">It also reveals that slaves, especially women, were given as a part of the dowry to the bridegroom. In simple language, it meant commercialisation of women. Now let us turn to Ramayana and the dowry given by King Janaka on the marriage of Sita and Rama. Valmiki Ramayana mentions,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">अथ राजा विदेहानां ददौ कन्याधनं बहु ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">गवां शतसहस्राणि बहूनि मिथिलेश्वर:।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">कम्बलानां च मुख्यानां क्षौमकोट्यंबराणि च ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">हस्त्यश्वरथपादातं दिव्यरूपं स्वलङ्कृतम् ।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ददौ कन्यापिता तासां दासीदासमनुत्तमम्  ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">हिरण्यस्य सुवर्णस्य मुक्तानां विद्रुमस्य च।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ददौ परमसंहृष्ट: कन्याधनमनुत्तमम् ।।</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>Then that king Janaka of Mithila, the one from Videha lineage, gave innumerable patrimonial riches. He has also given umpteen number of cows, millions of excellent shawls and silk dresses, and elephants, horses, chariots, foot soldiers, besides hundreds of highly decorated girls, divine in their mien, as unexcelled chambermaids and handmaidens to the brides. Immensely pleased, king Janaka gave excellent ornaments made of fine gold, pearls and corals.<br />
[Valmiki Ramayana Sarg 74; Shlokas 3-6]</blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">All these passages show the extravagant spending in Hindu marriages and sadly these are the ideals people look upto. How can things improve when such people and events are made role models by the common folk?</p>
<h2 style="color: #56595e;">Dowry in the writings of Hindu scholars</h2>
<p style="color: #56595e;">You will be surprised to know that even the so-called &#8216;reformist&#8217; Hindu scholars consider Dowry as an <strong>&#8216;integral part&#8217;</strong> of the Hindu marriage. The leading figure amongst them is Swami Dayanand Saraswati, the founder of the protestant cult of Arya Samaj. In his book <strong><em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Vidhi</em></strong> he mentions the practice of dowry as being an integral part of the Hindu marriage. Ramgopal Vidyalankar of Gurukul Kangri has written a commentary on <em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Vidhi</em> known as <strong><em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Prakash</em></strong>. The following excerpt in Hindi is from Sanskar Prakash, 1984 Edition, Page 128</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ऒ गौर्गोर्गोः प्रतिगृह्यताम &#8211; यह गाय है, लीजिये, गाय लीजिये</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">इस वाक्य से वर की विनती कर के अपनी शक्ति के योग्य वर को गोदानादी द्रव्य, जो वर को योग्य हों, अर्पण करे और वर &#8216;ओं प्रतिगृह्यतामि'(<strong><span style="color: #ff0000;">लाओ लेता हूं</span></strong>) इस वाक्य से उस को ग्रहण करे.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><strong>Translation:<br />
</strong></p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>ऒ गौर्गोर्गोः प्रतिगृह्यताम -This is a cow. Accept, please accept this cow.<br />
With this sentence we request the groom to accept the cow and other materials in dowry, which are suitable for the groom and the groom accepts it by repeating the phrase &#8216;ओं प्रतिगृह्यतामि&#8217; (Give; I am accepting)</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">These words clearly establish that Dowry is an integral part of Hindu marriage and the dowry must be suitable for the groom depending on his social status.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Pandit Bhimsen Sharma, the pupil of Swami Dayanand Saraswati, has even alloted a share of the dowry to the mother-in-law of the bride in his book Shodash Sanskar Vidhi.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">After knowing all this information, we should realize where the source of dowry lies? To eradicate dowry Hindus need to discard these scriptures which are used to justify the evil of dowry and which inspire people to shamelessly demand dowry citing the example set by their scriptural &#8216;role-models&#8217;.</p>
<hr style="color: #56595e;" />
<p style="color: #56595e;"><span style="color: #696969;"><strong>Footnotes:<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">[1] <span style="color: black;">Figures at a Glance 2008. </span><i style="color: black;">National Crime Records Bureau</i><span style="color: black;">, Ministry of Home Affairs, Government of India, accessed on 16 Jun 2012. &lt;</span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130507071639/http://ncrb.nic.in/CII2008/cii-2008/figure%20at%20a%20glance.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://ncrb.nic.in/CII2008/cii-2008/figure%20at%20a%20glance.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="color: black;">&gt;.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
