<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>muslim invader &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/muslim-invader/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 14:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</title>
		<link>/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immolation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infanticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niyoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pyre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Sati Pratha is a Hindu practice where the wife ascends the funeral pyre of her husband and gives up her life. The word Sati may have been derived from the name of Shiva&#8217;s wife. Sati, also called Dakshayani, was one of the daughters of Prasuti and Daksha. She loved Shiva, but &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Sati Pratha is a Hindu practice where the wife ascends the funeral pyre of her husband and gives up her life. The word Sati may have been derived from the name of Shiva&#8217;s wife. Sati, also called Dakshayani, was one of the daughters of Prasuti and Daksha. She loved Shiva, but her father Daksha forbade her marriage to Shiva. She married Shiva anyway, and Daksha got revenge by not inviting Shiva to a festival during his absence. Sati killed herself by self-immolation on a fire. After Shiva returned and found Sati’s body, he killed and decapitated Daksha, later replacing his head with a goat’s. Sati Pratha was widespread during the Early Brahmanic Dark Ages (1500 BC &#8211; 500 BC). It was later enforced by the Brahmins on their usurpation of power during the Later Brahmanic Dark Ages (500 BC &#8211; 1000 AD). Sati Pratha can be found in almost every Hindu scripture.<br />
<span id="more-1671"></span><br />
There have been some cases of Sati Pratha in Independent India,</p>
<p>16/1/19 In Shahbazpur UP, kin and locals stop woman from performing ‘Sati’<br />
<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kanpur/in-up-kin-and-locals-stop-woman-from-performing-sati/articleshow/67550770.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kanpur/in-up-kin-and-locals-stop-woman-from-performing-sati/articleshow/67550770.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>21/11/18 On way to perform &#8216;sati&#8217;, woman Laungshree Devi resident of Angautha village dragged from pyre<br />
<a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/national/way-perform-sati-woman-dragged-704033.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.deccanherald.com/national/way-perform-sati-woman-dragged-704033.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>1 April 2015 Maharashtra: Woman&#8217;s body found from husband&#8217;s pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-maharashtra-woman-s-body-found-from-husband-s-pyre-2073728" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-maharashtra-woman-s-body-found-from-husband-s-pyre-2073728<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Dec 15 2014: In Bihar, 65-year-old woman jumps into husband&#8217;s funeral pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.firstpost.com/india/bihar-65-year-old-woman-jumps-husbands-funeral-pyre-1849693.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.firstpost.com/india/bihar-65-year-old-woman-jumps-husbands-funeral-pyre-1849693.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>9 Sep 2009 Indian women still commit ritual suicides<br />
<a href="https://www.rt.com/news/india-ritual-suicide-sati/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.rt.com/news/india-ritual-suicide-sati/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>14 October 2008 Relatives arrested after widow burns to death on funeral pyre<br />
<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/oct/14/india" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/oct/14/india<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>22 September 2006 Brothers arrested for throwing 95-year-old mother on funeral pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-406471/Brothers-arrested-throwing-95-year-old-mother-funeral-pyre.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-406471/Brothers-arrested-throwing-95-year-old-mother-funeral-pyre.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>22 August 2006 India wife dies on husband&#8217;s pyre<br />
<a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/south_asia/5273336.stm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/south_asia/5273336.stm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>An unusual occurence in Bihar<br />
&#8220;In 1987, 18-year-old Roop Kanwar was immolated in Rajasthan in front of the whole village. Hers was the fortieth case in independent India, and the 28th in Rajasthan. In this case too it was glorified as the ultimate religious act of a married woman. Public pressure forced the government to enact the Rajasthan Sati Prevention Ordinance on October 1, 1987. Rajasthan Chief Minister Vasundhara Raje Scindia had maintained a stony silence on whether her government will appeal against the judgment. And it had to be filed before March 31. This would have meant going against her mother’s professed views supporting sati. It would also have meant going against the Hindu revivalists in the BJP. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Incidentally, VHP Vice-President Acharya Dharmendra was the master of ceremonies at the first death anniversary of Roop Kanwar</span></span>.&#8221;<br />
<a href="http://archive.tehelka.com/story_main1.asp?filename=Ne040304bihar.asp" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://archive.tehelka.com/story_main1.asp?filename=Ne040304bihar.asp<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Widow burning was also celebrated as evident from archaeological evidence and structures built to honor women who gave up their lives after the death of their husbands,</p>
<p>“<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/chikkamagaluru-500-year-old-sculpture-found-inside-3000-year-old-stone-age-structure/articleshow/91629828.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Mastigallu<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> or maha sati kallu, similar to veeragallu (hero stone) sculptures, were erected for women who gave up their lives after their spouses. Karnataka&#8217;s mastigallus are from the period between 5th century CE and the 18th century.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN MAHABHARATA</strong></span></p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.125.33 &#8220;Vaisampayana continued, &#8216;Having said this, the daughter of the king of Madras, the wedded <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">wife of Pandu, ascended the funeral pyre of her lord</span></span>, that bull among men.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.126.30 &#8221; <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">His wife Madri, beholding him placed in the funeral pyre and about to be consumed, herself ascended the same pyre</span>, and sacrificing her life thus, hath gone with her lord to the region reserved for chaste wives.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.95.63-64 &#8220;And (one day) Pandu, beholding Madri decked with ornaments, had his desire kindled. And, as soon as he touched her, he died. <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Madri ascended the funeral pyre with her lord</span>.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 16.7.24-26 &#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The four wives of that heroic son of Sura ascended the funeral pyre and were consumed with the body of their lord</span></span>. All of them attained to those regions of felicity which were his.<span style="color: red;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">The son of Pandu burnt the body of his uncle together with those four wives of his</span>, using diverse kinds of scents and perfumed wood. As the funeral pyre blazed up</span>, a loud sound was heard of the burning wood and other combustible materials, along with the clear chant of Samans and the wailing of the citizens and others who witnessed the rite.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN RAMAYANA</strong></span></p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Ayodhya Kanda 3.66.12 &#8220;Today itself, I too in devotion to my husband, will meet my appointed end. I shall enter the fire, duly embracing this body of my husband.” Shri K.M.K. Murthy</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN PURANAS<br />
</strong></span><br />
Devi Bhagavatam 6.25.35-50 &#8230;Once Madri, full of youth and beauty, was staying alone in a solitary place and Pa<span style="text-decoration: underline;">nd</span>u seeing her embraced her and due to the curse, died. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">When the funeral pyre was ablaze, the chaste Madri entered into the fire and died a Sati</span></span>&#8230;</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 2.6.53-71 &#8230;Then those Munis, practising great vows, knew that Pandu was dead and performed duly, on the banks of the Ganges, the ceremony of burning the dead. At that time Madri gave over to Kunti the charge of her two sons and <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">followed the Sati practice along with her husband to go to Satyaloka</span>&#8230;</p>
<p>Agni Purana 222.19-23 &#8221;&#8230;The widow who practices self-control and austerities after the death of her husband, goes to heaven&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">the widow who burns herself on the same funeral pire wth her husband also goes to heaven</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Kurma Purana 2.34.108b-109 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A woman who enters the funeral pyre along with her husband</span></span>, shall uplift him even if is a Brahmana-slayer, an ungrateful fellow or one defiled by great sins. learned men know this to be the greatest expiation for women.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri.</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.38.1-11 &#8220;The 8 queens of Krishna, who have been named, with Rukmini at their head, embraced the body of Hari, and entered the funeral fire. <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Revati also embracing the corpse of Rama</span>, entered the blazing pile, which was cool to her, happy in contact with her lord. Hearing these events, <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Ugrasena and Anakadundubhi, with Devaki and Rohini, committed themselves to the flames</span>&#8230;&#8221; Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, KotiRudra Samhita 4.10. 23-24 &#8221;The Brahmin lady desirous of entering the pyre in order to follow her husband cursed the Raksasa king. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The chaste lady entered fire</span></span>&#8230;&#8221;<br />
Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 4.28.50 She then prepared a blazing fire with firewood and placed the dead body of her husband upon it. When this was finished, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">she lamented severely and prepared herself to perish in the fire with her husband</span></span>.<span style="font-size: 12pt;">&#8216;</span></p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse,<br />
&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">It is the long-standing tradition of the Vedic system that a faithful wife dies along with her husband</span></span>. This is called saha-maraṇa. In India this system was prevalent even to the date of British occupation. At that time, however, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">a wife who did not wish to die with her husband was sometimes forced to do so by her relatives</span></span>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Formerly that was not the case — the wife used to enter the fire voluntarily</span></span>. The British government stopped this practice, considering it inhuman. However, from the early history of India we find that when Mahārāja Pāṇḍu died, he was survived by two wives — Mādrī and Kuntī. The question was whether both should die or one should die. After the death of Mahārāja Pāṇḍu, his wives settled that one should remain and the other should go. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Mādrī would perish with her husband in the fire</span></span>, and Kuntī would remain to take charge of the five Pāṇḍava children. Even as late as 1936 we saw a devoted wife voluntarily enter the fire of her husband.’’ A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana 4.28.50 [Source: <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.28.50" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.28.50 <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p>He also wrote,<br />
‘’<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">I</span><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">n the Vedic culture there is a system known as satī or saha-maraṇa, in which a woman dies with her husband. According to this system, if the husband dies, the wife will voluntarily die by falling in the blazing funeral pyre of her husband</span></span>. Here, in this verse, the feelings inherent in this culture are expressed by the wife of the brāhmaṇa. A woman without a husband is like a dead body. Therefore according to Vedic culture a girl must be married. This is the responsibility of her father. A girl may be given in charity, and a husband may have more than one wife, but a girl must be married. This is Vedic culture. A woman is supposed to be always dependent—in her childhood she is dependent on her father, in youth on her husband, and in old age on her elderly sons. According to Manu-saṁhitā, she is never independent. Independence for a woman means miserable life. In this age, so many girls are unmarried and falsely imagining themselves free, but their life is miserable. Here is an instance in which a woman felt that without her husband she was nothing but a dead body.’’<strong>Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana 9.9.32</strong> [Source: <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.9.32" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.9.32<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Bhagwad Purana 9.9.36 After this way cursing Mitrasaha [&#8216;indulgent toward friends&#8217; or Saudâsa] she, being devoted to be with her husband, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">found her destination by stepping into the fire that burned the bones of her husband</span></span>.</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 11.31.19-20<span class="views-field views-field-field-translation"> <span class="field-content">Tormented by separation from the Lord, His parents gave up their lives at that very spot. My dear Parīkṣit, the wives of the Yādavas then climbed onto the funeral pyres, embracing their dead husbands.</span></span> <span class="views-field views-field-field-translation"><span class="field-content">The wives of Lord Balarāma also entered the fire and embraced His body, and Vasudeva’s wives entered his fire and embraced his body. The daughters-in-law of Lord Hari entered the funeral fires of their respective husbands, headed by Pradyumna. And Rukmiṇī and the other wives of Lord Kṛṣṇa — whose hearts were completely absorbed in Him — entered His fire.</span> </span></p>
<div class="views-row views-row-18 views-row-even"></div>
<div class="views-row views-row-18 views-row-even"></div>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.107.29 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A Wife who dies in the company of her husband</span></span> shall remain in heaven as many years as there are hairs on his person&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Garuda Purana II.4.88-97 &#8220;&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A woman who has been chaste and faithful to her husband should mount on the pyre after bowing to her (deceased) husband before the funeral rites start</span></span>. One who gets away from the pyre due to fainting should observe the vow named prajapatya. One who ascends the pyre and follows up her husband stays in heaven for a period equal to the number of hair on the body, three and a half crore. Just as the snake-charmer takes out the snake from the hole so also she takes out her husband from hell and enjoys with him in paradise. She who ascends the pyre goes to heaven. She is praised by the celestial nymphs and enjoys with her husband so long as the fourteen Indras rule in heaven successively. Even if the man has killed a brahmana or a friend or any other person of noble conduct he is purified of sins by his wife who ascends his pyre. A woman who enters fire after the death of her husband prospers in the heaven like Arundhati. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Until and unless the woman burns herself after her husband&#8217;s death she is never released from the bond of her sex</span></span>. A woman who follows her husband purifies the three families on her mother&#8217;s side, the three families on her father&#8217;s side and the three families on her husband&#8217;s side.&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Another verse mentioned in Garuda Purana translated by Ernest and Subrahmanyam shows how a widow repented,<br />
Garuda Purana 2.40 &#8221;Not knowing my duty I did not serve my husband, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">nor after his death enter the fire</span></span>. Having become widowed I performed no austerities;&#8211;O Dweller in the Body, make reparation for whatever you have done!&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.42 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">When a woman burns her body with her husband&#8217;s</span></span>, the fire burns her limbs only, but does not afflict her soul&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.45-46 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Likewise she who has joined her husband is never burnt. her inner soul becomes unified with that of her husband</span></span>, by death. The woman who does not burn herself in the fire, on her husband&#8217;s death, is certainly never released from feminine bodies.&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V. Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.48 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The Woman who ascends the funeral pyre, when her husband is dead, becomes equal to Arundhati, and attains the heaven</span></span>. [50] She who goes with her husband purifies three families her mother&#8217;s, her father&#8217;s, and that into which she was given.&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V. Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p>Brahma Purana Gautami Mahatmya 10.75 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Dying Immediately after the husband is the greatest duty of women</span></span>. This is the path laid down in the Vedas. [77] The woman who follows her husband shall stay in heaven for as many years as there are hairs in a man&#8217;s body, viz. three and a half crores of years.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.30.39 &#8221;By entering this burning pyre, I will be slightly after a long time, the dear guest of my husband in the world of the Pitrs (Manes)[41] After saying these words with firm decision, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Renuka decided to follow her husband by entering the fire</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 46.4-22 A king died childless, and his wife wept bitterly and embraced his corpse until a bird told her that she would have seven sons if <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">she mounted her husband&#8217;s funeral pyre</span></span>. She obeyed, and as she entered the fire the king arose and flew into the sky with her, by his power of yoga. When the queen entered her fertile period the king felt it his duty not to neglect her. He made love to her in the air, and his seed fell down from the sky. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Then he went with her to the world of Brahma to dwell eternally</span></span>. But the wives of the Seven Sages saw the cloud like seed falling from the sky into a flower, and they thought it was Soma. Wishing to be young forever, they bathed ritually, honoured their own husbands, and drank the king&#8217;s seed. The moment that they drank it [having thus unconsciously violated their chastity] they lost their holy lustre, and all their husbands abandoned them immediately as sinners. They gave birth to the seven Maruts (Storm Gods).</p>
<p>Padma Purana V.106.60 &#8221;Having raised her, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Narada said to the pure one about her dead (husband)</span>: &#8221;O innocent one of large eyes, please go to your husband. O you of large eyes, your husband, abandoned by his kinsmen, is dead. O auspicious one, you should not weep. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Enter fire (i.e. funeral pyre of your husband)</span></span>.&#8221;[65-68] If you will go to (i.e. desire to enter) fire there, then do not weep . O daughter, if you have committed a sin like enjoying another man (than your husband) then make an expiation to purify that. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">On entering into the fire your minor sins will perish</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Padma Purana VI.252.89-90 &#8221;Rukmaputri with Pradyumna, Usa with Aniruddha and all Yadava ladies <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">honoured the bodies of their husbands and entered fire</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande<br />
Skanda Purana III.i.12.115-116 &#8221;Ere long thereafter, King Manojava abandoned his body and went to the world of Siva, due to the power of that Tirtha. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">O Brahmanas, his wife Sumitra embraced his body then and ascended his funeral pyre</span></span>. She too attained the same world.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana V.i.53.38-41 &#8221;&#8230;The beautiful woman gathered fuel and twigs together and <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">kindled the funeral pyre which she ascended along with her husband</span></span>. She was mentally pleased in doing so&#8230;&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana III.ii.7.53-56 &#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A chaste woman who follows her husband from the house to the cremation ground for self-immolation undoubtedly attains the merit of a horse-sacrifice at every step</span></span>. Just as a snake-catcher forcibly retrieves a snake from its hole, so also a chaste woman retrieves her husband from the messengers of Yama and goes to heave. On seeing a chaste woman the messengers of Yama flee. On seeing the splendour of a chaste woman even the sun feels burning sensation, even the fire gets burnt and all other luminaries begin to tremble. A chaste woman sportingly enjoys heavenly pleasures along with her husband for as many crores and ten thousand years as there are hairs on her body.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare<br />
Narada Purana, Uttarabhaga 16.85-89 &#8220;She sold off her bangle and brought a great deal of fuel. She prepared the funeral pyre. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">After placing her dead husband on it, she poured ghee over the pyre (fuel). She too climbed on the funeral pyre</span></span> joining her face to his face, her heart near his heart and O gentle lady, her buttocks near his buttocks. With her foot she dragged the fire. The auspicious lady of charming limbs set fire to the ailing body of the husband along with her body. As the fire blazed brightly, she cast off her body and went to the world of the Devas taking her husband with her after annihilating many of his sins by means of her holy rites very difficult to be performed.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Narada Purana, Uttarabhaga 30.87 &#8220;With a great deal of merits the woman goes to the region of Visnu alongwith her husband if her body is cremated alongwith him. But a woman greedy of wealth and of her body (?) attains Yama&#8217;s torture and the affliction of being born in base wombs of lower species.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 46.51-53 &#8220;&#8230;Then after a long time that beloved slender-bodied queen of the king had pregnancy from that best of kings. During the pregnancy of the wife the king died. She, loyal to her husband, while desiring to get upon (the funeral pyre of) her husband, was prevented by the ministers, but could not be stopped.&#8221; Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>There is another fake story circulated on internet that, Wives of kings used to immolate themselves only if the Kings went into battle with Muslims, Jauhar wasn&#8217;t practiced when rival king was Hindu. Let&#8217;s not indulge in history and check what scripture says,<br />
Vishnu Purana 3.18.51-55 &#8220;It is related that there was formerly a king named Śatadhanu, whose wife Śaivyá was a woman of great virtue. She was devoted to her husband, benevolent, sincere, pure, adorned with every female excellence, with humility, and discretion&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">After a time the Rájá, triumphant over his enemies, died; and the princess ascended the funeral pile of her husband</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>There is no reference that King Satadhanu lived in the period of Muslims and here we read that the wife of the king ascended funeral pyre of her husband after he died in (or after) the battle. So this refutes the claim of people who tries to blame others for all evil practices of their religion. If self-immolation with husband is such a great virtue then why don&#8217;t Hindu scripture says the same about men? But not all women are suppose to practice Sati Pratha, Brahmin women are barred from practicing it as it will be Brahmin slaughter, other than Brahmin women, following women are also exempted from ascending the funeral pyre of their husbands,</p>
<p>Narada Purana I.7.52 &#8220;O blessed princess! The following (ladies) do not ascend funeral pyre, viz. those with infant children (depending on them), pregnant women, those whose monthly course has not yet started and women in the menses.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Shiva Purana narrates story of Shiva who in the form of a merchant went to his devotee who was a prostitute to test her, he had sexual relation with her and asked her to be his wife for 3 days and a night, this can also be considered as temporary marriage or fornication since the story doesn’t narrate rituals pertaining to marriage. So after having sex with her, Shiva decided to give up his life and asked the prostitute Mahananda to lit funeral pyre, the prostitute too decided to ascend the funeral pyre as she had vowed to be the merchant’s wife for three days.</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Satarudra Samhita 3, Chapter 26, verses 38-51 “O my beloved, when the phallic image is smashed and burnt I do not desire to live. I am telling you the truth. There is no doubt in this. O gentle lady, prepare a pyre for me immediately through your servants. With my mind fixed in Śiva, I shall enter the fire… Then the merchant who was only Śiva himself went round the blazing fire. Desirous of knowing her intentions he entered the fire firmly… Taking the gemset bangle I had taken the pledge that I shall be the avowed wife of this merchant for three days… As she was going to jump in the fire with her mind fixed in his feet, Śiva, the soul of the universe, appeared in front and stopped her.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN SMRITIS</strong><br />
</span><br />
Parasara Smriti 4.28 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A widow, who immolates herself on the same funeral pile with her deceased husband, resides in heaven</span></span> for ten millions of years, which is the number of hairs on the human body.&#8221; Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Brihaspati Smriti 24.11 A wife is considered half the body (of her husband), equally sharing the result of his good or wicked deeds; whether she ascends the pile after him, or chooses to survive him leading a virtuous life, she promotes the welfare of her husband.<br />
Vishnu Smriti 25.14 &#8221;After the death of her husband, to preserve her chastity, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">or to ascend the pile after him</span></span><span style="color: #000000;">.&#8221; Tr. Various Oriental Scholars</span></p>
<p>Atri Samhita 1.209 &#8220;The woman, who falls down from the funeral pyre, [of her husband], or who gets no menses on account of a disease, becomes purified by a Prajapatya and feeding ten Brahmanas.&#8221; Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Daksha Samhita 4.19 &#8220;A woman, who, after the demise of her husband, ascends the funeral pyre, becomes of good conduct and lives gloriously in the celestial region.&#8221; Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Vijnanesvara writes in Mitakshara on Yajnavalkya Smriti verse 88</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>‘’Moreover, though &#8221;deprived of her husband,&#8221; or bereft of her husband, she should not be without her father, &amp;c, Because, being without their protection, she &#8221;becomes infamous,&#8221; becomes blameworthy. This is (the rule, in case the widow wishes to pass her life) as a Brahmachari or celebate. Because it is ordained in the Vishnu Smriti (Ch. XXXV. 14):- &#8221;After the death of her husband (the widow should adopt one of these two courses) either to preserve her chastity (Brahmacharya) or to ascend the pile after him.&#8221; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">There is great virtue in Anvarohana (or self-immolation along with the deceased husband.)</span></span><br />
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Vyasa has shown the same thing, in the form of the parable of the she-pigeon:- &#8221;Devoted to her husband, she entered the raging fire</span></span>, and thereafter she obtained her (dead) lord who was adorned with a variegated bracelet. Then afterwards the bird went in company with his wife to heaven, and enjoyed it with her being honored with all acts (of service.)&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Talibanism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 18:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atrocities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destruction of temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghaznavi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains and buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persecution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: MilliGazette ] &#160; Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan? &#160; &#160; Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: <a href="http://www.milligazette.com/Archives/15042001/Art06.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MilliGazette<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="color:#0070c0;">Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan?<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5643"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and Osmania universities, and Dr MS Jayaprakash, professor of history at Kollam &#8211; throw some deep insights into the dark history of India when Buddhism was systematically eliminated by Brahminical forces who control Hinduism, then and now.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Says Jayaprakash: &#8216;The ruthless demolition of Buddha statues by Taliban has courted severe criticism from different quarters of the world. Surprisingly, the BJP-led Indian Government, supported by all Hindutva forces, also condemned the Taliban action. It is a paradox that the forerunners of the present Hindutva forces in India had wantonly destroyed not only Buddhist statues but also killed Buddhists in India. Therefore, any impartial student of history would unequivocally say that these Hindutva forces have no moral right to criticize Taliban now.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He elaborates: &#8216;Hundreds of Buddhist statues, stupas and viharas have been destroyed in India between 830 and 966 AD in the name of Hindu revivalism. Both literary and archaeological sources within and outside India speak volumes about the havoc done to Buddhism by Hindu fanatics. Spiritual leaders like Sankaracharya and many Hindu kings and rulers took pride in demolishing Buddhist images aiming at the total eradication of Buddhist culture. Today, their descendants destroyed the Babri Masjid and also published the list of mosques to be targeted in future. It is with this sin of pride that they presently condemn Taliban.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin elaborates the selfish compulsions of Brahminism to wipe-out Buddhism: &#8216;Buddhism tried to create a dynamic society in ancient India. Jainism also contributed its share. As Buddhism spread, iron ploughs and implement were used for development of agriculture. As a result, new areas were cultivated and agricultural productivity increased, apart from developing trade centres and road links. Subsistence-level economy changed to a surplus economy with grain storage facilities, exchange of goods, trade and development of bureaucratic administration. This also created social change &#8211; from elans consisting several families to tribes consisting several elans of similar socio-economic conditions. The emphasis of Brahmins, on the other hand, was for receiving and giving alms and not on production of goods. Those who give and receive alms were close to Gods and those who produce were considered as inferior. According to Manusmriti, a Sudra should not have wealth of his own. In case he has any, a Brahmin as his master can take it over without any hesitation. &#8216;Rigveda&#8217; goes a step further to kill those who do not give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the Brahmins. In other words, someone has to produce goods so that others can give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the recipient Brahmins. It was against this system of &#8216;downgrading those who produce&#8217; that Buddhism came into being.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Recalls Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;The Hindu ruler Pushyamitra Sunga had destroyed 84,000 Buddhist stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. This was followed by the demolition of Buddhist centres in Magadha. Thousands of Buddhist saints were killed mercilessly. King Jalaluka destroyed the Buddha viharas within his jurisdiction on the ground that chanting of hymns by Buddhists disturbed his sleep! In Kashmir, King Kinnara demolished thousands of viharas and captured the Buddhist villages to please Brahmins. A large number of Buddha viharas were usurped by Brahmins and converted into Hindu temples where entry of &#8216;untouchables&#8217; was prohibited. Notably, Buddhist places were regularized as Hindu temples by writing Puranas, which were invented myths or pseudo history. The important temples at Tirupathi, Aihole, Undavalli, Ellora, Bengal, Puri, Badarinath, Mathura, Ayodhya, Sringeri, Bodhigaya, Saranath, Delhi, Nalanda, Gudimallam, Nagarjunakonda, Srisailam and Sabarimala are some of the striking examples of Brahminical usurpation of Buddhist centres.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Detailing the divergence in both orientation and essence between Buddhism and Hinduism, Prof. Bahauddin says: &#8216;Equality, compassion, non-violence, utilization of human abilities for general welfare, etc. were the cardinal principles of Buddhism. According to &#8216;Sathpatha Brahmanam (22-6, 3-4-14), on the other hand, the whole universe is controlled by God, God is controlled by Mantram and Mantram is with Brahmins and, therefore, Brahmins are God (on earth). They used Mantram and Sapam to instil fear in the people to obey them, while Buddhism encouraged people to observe visible facts, to apply reason to get out of fear. Buddhism also encouraged people to do good things, besides guiding Kings to look after the people&#8217;s welfare. Buddhism considers the general welfare of the people, while Brahminism considers that the whole world was created for them all along. And, there is bound to be conflict between these two opposite ways of thinking.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr Jayaprakash, Sakaracharya had played &#8216;a demon&#8217;s role&#8217; in destruction of Buddhist statues and monuments at Nagarjunakonda (in present-day Andhra Pradesh). &#8216;A. N. Longhurst, who conducted excavations at Nagarjunakonda, had recorded this in his invaluable book, Memoirs of the Archaeological Survey of India No. 54, The Buddhist Antiquities of Nagarjunakonda (Delhi, 1938, p. 6). The ruthless manner in which all the buildings at Nagarjunakonda have been destroyed is simply appalling and cannot represent the work of treasure-seekers alone since so many pillars, statues, and sculptures have been wantonly smashed to pieces. Local tradition relates that the great Hindu philosopher and teacher, Sankaracharya, came to Nagarjunakonda with a host of followers and destroyed the Buddhist monuments. The cultivated lands on which ruined buildings stand represent a religious grant made to Sankaracharya.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Quoting Dr. B. R. Ambedkar, Prof. Bahauddin says that the conflict against Brahmin supremacy had, in fact, started before Buddhist period, between Vasishta Muni, a Brahmin, and Viswamitra, a non-Brahmin. &#8216;The dispute was about the learning of &#8216;Vedas&#8217;, the right to conduct religious ceremony, to receive gifts, and to perform coronation of King. Vasishta Muni insisted that these were the exclusive privileges of Brahmins, while Viswamitra was opposed to such exclusive rights. This dispute lasted for long period, and even Kings joined in it (Writings and Speeches of Dr. Ambedkar, vol. 7, p. 148-155. It was won by Brahmins.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin lists the different stages of Brahmin hostility against Buddhism: &#8216;1) 483-273 BC: The period after Buddha&#8217;s death upto Ashoka&#8217;s rule when attempts were made to include Brahminical ideas in Buddhist ideology. 2) 273-200 BC: When Buddhism spread all over India and became a world religion. 3) 200 BC-500 AD: The period when all possible efforts were made to disintegrate Buddhism from within by adulterating Buddhist teachings with Brahminical ideas and also through physical annihilation from outside. As a result, Buddhism divided itself into 18 sects, of which Hinayana and Mahayana were prominent ones. 4) 500-700 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in North India and efforts began to drive out Buddhism and Jainism from South India. 5) 700-1100 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in South India and, with added vigour, it moved again to North India to obtain complete supremacy over Buddhism and Jainism. 6) 1100-1400 AD: Buddhism and Jainism were destroyed from the remaining Southern States of Karnataka and Kerala and, thus, total supremacy of Brahminism all over India was achieved.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;Within Kerala, Sankaracharya and his close associate Kumarila Bhatta, an avowed foe of Buddhism, organized a religious crusade against Buddhists. A vivid description of Sankaracharya&#8217;s pleasure of seeing people of non-Brahminic faith being burnt to death is available in &#8216;Sankara Digvijaya&#8217;. Kumarila instigated King Suddhanvan of Ujjain to exterminate Buddhists. The &#8216;Mricchakatika&#8217; of Sudraka describes how the King&#8217;s brother-in-law in Ujjain inhumanly tortured the Buddhist monks, by using them as bullocks by inserting a string through their nose and yoking them to the cart! The &#8216;Keralolpathi&#8217; documents the extermination of Buddhism from Kerala by Kumarila. About the activities of Sankaracharya, even Vivekananda had observed: &#8216;And, such was the heart of Sankara that he burnt to death lots of Buddhist monks by defeating them in argument. What can you call such action on Sankara&#8217;s part except fanaticism&#8217; (Complete works of Swami Vivekananda, Vol. III, p. 118, Calcutta, 1997).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, there are hundreds of places in Kerala having names &#8216;palli&#8217; either affixed or suffixed with them. &#8216;Karunagapalli, Karthikapalli, Pallickal, Pallippuram, Edappally, etc. are some examples of these places. The term &#8216;palli&#8217; means a Buddha vihara. Notably, Kerala had 1200 years of Buddhist tradition. Earlier, the schools in Malayalam were called as &#8216;Ezhuthupalli&#8217; or &#8216;Pallikoodam&#8217;. It is also worth noticing that the Christians and Muslims in Kerala use the term &#8216;palli&#8217; to denote their church and mosque alike. These &#8216;pallies&#8217; or viharas had been ruthlessly demolished by the Hindu forces under the leadership of Sankaracharya and Kumarila. They could exterminate 1200 years of Buddhist tradition and converted Kerala into a Brahminical state based on the &#8216;Chaturvarna&#8217; system. Original inhabitants of Kerala, like the Ezhavas, Pulayas, etc., were crushed under the weight of casteism. Many a viharas was transformed into temples and majority of people were prevented from entering temples under the pretext of caste pollution. It can also be noted that the name &#8216;Kerala&#8217; is the Sanskritised Aryan version of the Dravidian and Buddhist term &#8216;Cherala&#8217;. The Parasurama legend is nothing but an invented myth for regularizing the Brahminical &#8216;Kerala&#8217; hiding its glorious Buddhist traditions.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jainism, too, met with the same fate in South India. Prof. Bahauddin elaborates: &#8216;Very little information is available about growth of Jainism in South India during 300-400 AD. The Jain book, &#8216;Digambara Darsana&#8217;, recounts the starting of a Sangham at Madurai in 470 AD and Jainism became widespread and strong during 500-600 AD (Kumaraswamy Iyengar, &#8216;Studies in South Indian Jainism&#8217;, p. 51-58)….. The Jains used to instal the images of their saints in their religious places, a practice which was followed by Brahmins. Hindu temples appeared all over Tamilnadu probably after converting the Jain religious places. The idols of 63 Brahmin Sanyasis, who led destruction of Jainism, still adorn the walls of some Hindu temples in Tamilnadu. The remains of destroyed Jain idols, their abandoned religious and living places are scattered all over Tamilnadu to narrate their story. Frescos depicting the kings of Jains could be seen on the walls near the Golden Tank at Madurai Meenakshi Temple where, of the total 12 annual festivals, five depict the killing of Jains according to Kumaraswamy Iyengar (p. 78-79).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, a number of Buddha statues have been discovered at places like Ambalapuzha, Karunagapalli, Pallickal, Bharanikkavu, Mavelikara and Neelamperur in Kerala. &#8216;They are either in the form of smashed pieces or thrown away from viharas. Lord Ayyappa of Sabarimala and Lord Padmanabha at Thiruvananthapuram are the proxy images of Buddha being worshipped as Vishnu. Hundreds of Buddhists were killed on the banks of Aluva river. The term &#8216;Aluva&#8217; was derived from &#8216;Alawai&#8217; which means &#8216;Trisul&#8217;, a weapon used by Hindu fanatics to stab Buddhists. Similarly, on the banks of the Vaigai river in Tamilnadu, thousands of Buddhists were killed by the Vaishnava Saint, Sambanthar. Thevaram, a Tamil book, documents this brutal extermination of Buddhism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls the strong reasons to believe that a large section of Jains had embraced Islam: &#8216;The spread of Islam in Tamilnadu can be considered in three or four stages. Islam spread in Kerala and Tamilnadu when Jainism was under pressure (650-750 AD). The new religion was received without resistance…. Since Islam considers every human being with equality Jainism and Buddhism had no conflict with it. When Muhammad ibn Al-Qasim attacked Sindh, the Buddhists supported him because they were facing annihilation at that time. A similar situation was prevailing in South India during 650-750 AD…. Muslims in Tamilnadu are called Anchuvanthar, Labba (teacher), Rauthar, Marakar (sailor) or Jonakan (Yavankan). The Anchuvanam is the guild of traders and groups of artisans. The Muslim mohallas of &#8216;Anchuvan Vamsagar&#8217;, &#8216;Anchuvanathar&#8217;, etc. are scattered all over Tamilnadu and seem to be the en bloc conversion of Jain guilds engaged in different activities, especially weaving. Those who ran away from Tamilnadu settled down in Sravanabalagola and Gomatheswaram in Karnataka. And, those who could not leave due to their economic interests converted to Islam. If we analyze the body structure, food, language, dress, ornaments, customs and habits of Anchuvanthar, it could be see that those are a continuation of Jain way of living and customs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Till recently, the weavers in such Muslim mohallas will not eat at noon or night, and take only one meal before dusk. This was a continuation of Jain habits. There is a separate place in such villages called &#8216;Odukkam&#8217; where Jain Munist used to sit in prayer. On the last Wednesday of the month called &#8216;Odukkathae&#8217; Wednesday, the Muslims gather together to sing religious songs, which is also a Jain tradition. When religious functions like Maulood, Rathif, etc. are organized in the house, a white cloth with lotus symbol on it called &#8216;Mekett&#8217; is tied, which resembles the &#8216;Asmanagiri&#8217; of the Jains…. The architecture of Muslim stone mosques are completely of Jain architecture. The pillars of earlier mosques have practically no difference with the Jain temple pillars. The close relationship between traders and weavers had probably cemented by conversion to Islam. During 950-1200 AD, there were large number of Sufis, Fakirs, wandering poets, singing minstrels, etc. among Muslims all over Tamilnadu. Nadirshah with 500 disciples settled down in &#8216;Trichinopoly&#8217; during 1000 AD. Aliyar Shah and his disciples made Madurai as their centre. Baba Fakhruddin travelled all over Tamilnadu. Nagur became another Sufi centre. The Muslim religious literature of Tamilnadu of that period was least different from those created by Jains and Hindus during the &#8216;Bhakti&#8217; movement.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recounts the spread of Jainism and Buddhism in Kerala, thus: &#8216;Jainism spread in North Kerala around 200 BC. The Jain architectural remains in Canara and Malabar are not available anywhere else in South of Nepal. While Jainism entered North Kerala via Mangalore, Salem, Coimbatore and Wayanad, it entered Southern Kerala from Tirunelveli, Kanyakumari, Nagercoil, Chitharal, etc. The hill near Anamala, which was an important Jain centre, is still called &#8216;Jain Durgam&#8217;. The close-by Kurumala was also a Jain centre. From Anamala through Munnar, Devikulam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor, etc. they reached Neryamangalam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor and other places. The &#8216;Kallil Kshetram&#8217; in Perumbavoor is an important Jain monument as also the &#8216;Jainmedu&#8217; in Vadakethara village of Palakkad district. Kerala&#8217;s cave temples at Chitharal, Kallil, Trikur, Erunilamkode (Thrissur district) and Thiruveghapuram (Palakkad district) were constructed during the period of Jain King Mahendra Verman-I (610-640 AD). Temple records of Rameswaram, Sucheendram, Poothadi (Wayanad), Keenalur (Kozhicode) , etc. show that they were part of &#8216;Kunavai Koottam&#8217; during 10-11th centuries. &#8216;Koottam&#8217; is the place of living for Jain Sanyasis. Temple records show that all these present-day Hindu temples were Jain religious places till 11th century. Place names with Kallu, Poothan, Aathan, Kotha, Palli, Ambalam, etc. were all Jain centres. Spread all over Kerala, names of these places show that Buddhism and Jainism were widespread. The famous Kalpathi in Palakkad district was a Buddhist-Jain centre. The &#8216;Ratholsavam&#8217; there is akin to the &#8216;Kettukazhcha&#8217; of Buddhists. The present Bhagavati temples were also Jain temples. The group, &#8216;Adikal&#8217;, had a prominent position among Jains who became &#8216;Pisharadi&#8217; after absorption of Jainism in Hinduism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&#8216;Similarly, the Buddhist stoopa at Kodungallore, located in Methala village South-East of Thrikanamathilakam, is an important Buddhist ruin in Kerala…. Mahismathi was the capital of Chera King Satyaputran, which shows the relationship of Chera country (Kerala) with Buddhism. There is a reference in &#8216;Manimekhala&#8217; about a Buddhist Chaityam in Kerala. While Vadakkumnatha Temple at Thrissur and Kurumba Temple at Kodungallore were Buddhist temples, Buddha statues were discovered from Kollam, Alappuzha, Mavelikara, Pallikkal, Karumadi and other places…. Treating mental patients in Thiruvadi temple and leprosy patients in Thakazhi temple shows that they were Buddhist temples since these kind of humanitarian services were not rendered out from Hindu temples…. By 900 AD Buddhism and Jainism were almost wiped out from Tamilnadu. The second settlement wave of Brahmins in Kerala during 900 AD was with Pandyan Kings&#8217; support. Karnataka and Kerala were the only two states where Buddhism and Jainism were still surviving and the second immigration of Brahmins might have been for driving out these two religions from the remaining places.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls: &#8216;Very few people know that Buddhism and Jainism were the prominent religions of Kerala till 1200 AD. I was also under the impression that Hinduism was in Kerala from the very beginning. When facts were pieced together, a different picture emerged. Only from the end of 1800 AD the evidence became available about Buddha, Buddhism, Ashoka, etc. That fact itself is a pathetic story….&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash in conclusion: &#8216;This is what really happened in India, the land of Buddha. But our so-called eminent historians, except a few, are bent upon eclipsing the cruelty done to Buddhists in India. These pseudo historians have succeeded in creating an impression that India is a land of righteousness and toleration. The entire world has been duped by them. The deed on the part of Taliban can be justified on the ground that Islam does not permit idols. But one has to note that Islam does not allow the demolition of other people&#8217;s religious centres and images. Whatever may be the argument for and against Taliban action, the Hindu atrocities on Buddhism in India has no parallel in the entire world history of religious struggle. Let the world know the cruel and crooked face of the &#8216;Indian vulture without culture&#8217;!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
