<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>iconoclast &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/iconoclast/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 09:59:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 14:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aravsthan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bow down]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circumambulate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idol worship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idolater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lingam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makkeshwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims worship the kaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shave head beard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sulaiman razvi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ujjain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vikramaditya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi [This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time] The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Written by Sulaiman Razvi<br />
</span></p>
[This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time]
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for prayer. However some Islamophobes especially some Hindus allege that Muslims worship the Kaaba or the Black Stone and they accuse Muslims of being idolaters. First of all they have to know what exactly is Idol worship, only then they should accuse Muslims of Idolatry. Idol worship is a veneration or worship of the Idol of any God. Islam is known for its staunch monotheistic stand. Islam prohibits Idol worship, It is mentioned in the Qur&#8217;an,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span id="more-161"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">22:30 &#8221;…so shun the abomination of idols, and shun the word that is false.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">14:35 Remember Abraham said: &#8220;O my Lord! make this city one of peace and security: and <span style="text-decoration:underline;">preserve me and my sons from worshipping idols</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">5:90 O ye who believe! Intoxicants and gambling, <span style="color:red;">(dedication of) stones</span>, and (divination by) arrows, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">are an abomination― of Satan&#8217;s handiwork</span>: eschew such (abomination), that ye may prosper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Hadith,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Abu Dawood (Kitab Al-Aqdiyah) [24:3592] Narrated Khuraym Ibn Fatik: The Apostle of Allah (peace be upon him) offered the morning prayer. When he finished it, he stood up and said three times: False witness has been made equivalent to attributing a partner to Allah. He then recited: &#8220;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">So avoid the abomination of idols</span> and avoid speaking falsehood as people pure of faith to Allah, not associating anything with Him.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba or Black Stone to be God. Kaaba is a direction,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…when a person making supplication (du&#8217;a) faces the sky–just as those performing the prayer (Salat) face the Ka&#8217;bah, since the sky is the qiblah of those who supplicate, as the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Ka&#8217;bah is the qiblah of those who perform the prayer</span>…&#8221;-(Sahih Muslim bi Sharh al-Nawawi. 18 vols. Cairo 1349/1930. Reprint (18 vols. in 9). Beirut: Dar al-Fikr, 1401/1981, 5.24)<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8216;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8216;Allah&#8217;s direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah</span>. (And if thou shouldst follow their desires) their religion and direction of prayer (after the knowledge which hath come unto thee) that the Religion of Allah is Islam and His direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah&#8221;– Tanwir al Miqbas min Tafsir ibn Abbas 2:120<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">People used to stand on the Kaaba and give Azaan. Kaaba has been rebuilt several times, it was brought down by the Sahabas. Can any Hindu even think of destroying idol of their god? Ibn Az Zubayr brought Kaaba down to rebuild it and later it was again brought down and rebuilt by Ibn Hajjaj,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;he (Ibn Az Zubayr) decided to bring the Ka`bah down. The people hesitated to bring it down, fearing that the first person to climb on the House would be struck down. A man went on top of the House and threw some stones down, and when the people saw that no harm touched him, they started doing the same. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">They brought the House down to ground level</span>…`Abdul-Malik wrote back, `We do not agree with Ibn Az-Zubayr&#8217;s actions. As, for the Ka`bah&#8217;s height, leave it as it is. As for what he added from the Hijr, bring it down, and build the House as it was before and close the door.&#8217; <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Therefore, Al-Hajjaj brought down the House and rebuilt it as it was</span>.&#8221;- Tafsir Ibn Kathir [<a href="http://www.qtafsir.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=303&amp;Itemid=36" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Source<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Idolaters won&#8217;t stand on their idols nor they will destroy their Idols. How can such claims be made that Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone when Quran and Hadiths clearly prohibit any form of Idol worship? Hazrat Umar R.A said,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…No doubt, I know that you are a <strong>stone</strong> and can neither benefit anyone nor harm anyone. Had I not seen Allah&#8217;s Apostle kissing you I would not have kissed you.&#8221; Sahih Bukhari, Kitab al Hajj 26, Hadith no 667.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be God. Muslims do not worship the Kaaba. When some Hindus are told these facts they say,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:#c00000;font-size:12pt;">&#8221;They too, whom you call Idol worshippers, do not regard the image as God. They profess to worship God behind the Idol/image&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">How true it is, let&#8217;s analyse. Hindu scriptures clearly states that &#8216;You should establish an Idol of God and worship it for the Idol is God himself&#8217;. Whatever we or the Islamophobes says carries no weight unless it is backed by some evidence, let&#8217;s have a look at what Hindu scripture have to say about it because if they are accusing us of Idolatry then our way of worship must be similar with idol worshippers.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Garuda Purana 12.17 Then the son should place upon the <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">bed a golden image, and having worshiped it</span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.24.19 O sinless one! <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Establish my image in this city and worship it</span><br />
</span>three times, morning, mid-day and evening carefully and with devotion<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.13.49 These Saktis, capable of bestowing all the desires, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">will be worshipped in Pratimas(images of clay, etc.)</span> in the whole of India.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Vishnudharmottara Purana, Kanda 3, Adhyay 93, 2 in the former three ages, Krta, Treta, and Dvapara men were able to see a god directly but in the Kali age ment have lost that faculty; <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">therefore they have to worship them (the gods) in an image</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 11.23.21-33 … one is to worship one&#8217;s own Deity <span style="color:red;"><strong>in front</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">of fire or the </span><strong>image of any god</strong></span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">This shows that the Idol must be in front of the worshipper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">BhrGhSuPari Grihasutra 2.14.2 <span style="color:red;">Having prepared the image of the god and worshipping it </span>with the unbroken rice and flowers as available&#8230;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;It (clay) should be washed well and pasted with scented poweder and milk. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The idol should be made</span> with the hands on a raises platform. All the limbs, joints, etc. should be perfectly shaped with the respective weapons of the deity concerned. It should be seated on Padmasana (lotus pose) <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">and worshipped respectfully</span>&#8221;.-Shiva Purana 1.1.16.6-7, Tr. J.L. Shastri<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;O my child, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">one should worship the beautiful and universally auspicious idol (of Devi) </span>which is the destroyer of great demons placing it on a car (chatior)&#8221;.-Devi Purana 30.6cd-7ab, Tr. R.S. Bhattacharya<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Harivamsa Purana, Vishnu Parva 2.74.52 Those who <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">make my idol with stones taken from you and worship [it]</span> daily with devotion shall eventually attain my path.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">These verses clearly commands Hindus to worship the Idol of their god, but Quran nor any Hadith tells us to worship the Kaaba. Hindu texts and Scholars say that Idol is God himself. Pratima means Idol, image, picture of god but Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKON translates Pratima as Deity Form or Deity because he considers the Idol to be another form or incarnation of God. This fact is enough to prove that Muslims do not worship the Kaaba as Quran, Hadiths nor Muslims says Kaaba is Allah (S.W.T). Let me quote few verses from Hindu scriptures and passages written by Hindu scholars on this issue,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…think of the name as Brahman, and meditate upon it, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">just as people worship the idol, thinking it to be Vishnu Himself</span>.- Chandogya Upanishad Commentary by Shankarcharya on 12.1.4 ,The Upanishads and Sri Sankara&#8217;s Commentary, Volumes 4-5, p.200.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagavad Purana),<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">dravyaiḥ prasiddhair mad-yāgaḥ <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>diṣv amāyinaḥ bhaktasya ca yathā-labdhair hṛdi bhāvena caiva hi<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11.27.15 <span style="color:red;">One should worship Me in My Deity forms [Pratima/Idol]</span> by offering the most excellent paraphernalia. But a devotee completely freed from material desire may worship Me with whatever he is able to obtain…</span><span style="font-size:14pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">śailī dāru-mayī lauhī lepyā lekhyā ca saikatī mano-mayī maṇi-mayī <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>ṣṭa-vidhā smṛtā<br />
</span></p>
<p><a href="http://vedabase.com/en/sb/11/27/12" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="font-size:12pt;"> (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.12 <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The Deity form[Idol] of the Lord is said to appear in eight varieties</span> — stone, wood, metal, earth, paint, sand, the mind or jewels.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī explains that certain Deity forms, such as those made of sand, are manifested for a brief time to fulfill a personal desire of the worshiper. Those, however, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">who desire to attain pure love of God should worship the permanent form of the Deity (made, for instance, of marble, gold or brass)</span>, and they should maintain continual worship. In Kṛṣṇa consciousness there is no scope for neglecting the worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagwat Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.48 <span style="color:red;">Whenever one develops faith in Me in <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>My form [Idol] as the Deity</strong></span> or in other bona fide manifestations one should <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>worship Me in that form</strong></span></span>. I certainly exist both within all created beings and also separately in My original form, since I am the Supreme Soul of all.<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: The Supreme Personality of Godhead is worshiped according to the faith of a particular worshiper. The Deity form, arcā, is specifically mentioned here because Deity worship is essential for spiritual progress. <span style="color:red;">Śrīla Bhaktisiddhānta Sarasvatī Ṭhākura mentions that inexperienced persons may think that the Deity [Idol] is meant for the sense gratification of the worshiper, since superficially the Deity [Idol] is made of external substances such as marble or brass</span>. But through the process of installing the Deity by <span style="color:red;"><strong>chanting of authorized mantras, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">one invites the Supreme Personality of Godhead to enter the Deity form [Idol]</span>.</strong></span> By regulated, faithful worship one gradually <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>understands that the Deity [Idol] is completely nondifferent from the Supreme Lord Himself</strong></span>…<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;But, greater is the difficulty of those whose minds cling to the Unmanifested; for the goal of the Unmanifested is hard for the embodied being to reach.&#8221; Gita 12:5<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse &#8221;Therefore, the bhakti-yogi accepts the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity of Krishna as worshipable</span> because there is some bodily conception fixed in the mind, which can thus be applied. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">Of course, worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead in His form within the temple is not idol worship</span>. There is evidence in the Vedic literature that worship may be saguna and nirguna—of the Supreme possessing or not possessing attributes. Worship of the Deity in the temple is saguna worship, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">for the Lord is represented by material qualities</span>. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But the form of the Lord, though represented by material qualities such as <span style="color:red;">stone, wood or oil paint, is not actually material. That is the absolute nature of the Supreme Lord</span></span>…God has an authorized <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">representation in the Deity form [Idol]</span>, which is called arca-vigraha. This arca-vigraha is an incarnation of the Supreme Lord&#8221;.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 4.30.27:<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The form of the Lord as worshiped in the temples is called arca-vigraha or arcavatara, the worshipable form [Idol Worship],</span><br />
<span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">the Deity incarnation</span>. This facility is offered to neophyte devotees so that they can see the real form of the Lord face to face and offer their respectful obeisances and sacrifices in the form of arca. Through such facilities the neophytes gradually invoke their original Krsna consciousness. <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity worship in the form of temple worship is the most valuable benediction </span><strong>given by the Lord to beginners</strong></span>. All neophytes must therefore engage in the worship of the Lord by keeping the arca-vigraha (arcavatara)[Idol] at home or in the temple.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another Hindu scholar named Swami Sivananda writes,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;<span style="color:red;">Though the image is worshipped</span>, <span style="color:red;">the devotee feels the presence of the Lord <span style="text-decoration:underline;">in it</span></span> and pours out his devotion unto it.…<span style="color:red;">When you worship an image</span>, you do not say: &#8220;This image has come from Jaipur. It was brought by Prabhu Singh. Its weight is 50 lbs. It is made of white marble. It has cost me Rs. 500/-.&#8221; <span style="color:red;"><strong>You superimpose all the attributes of the Lord on the image and pray</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">: &#8220;</span><strong>O</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Antaryamin (Inner Ruler)! </span><strong>You are</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> all-pervading. You are omnipotent, omniscient, all-merciful. You are the source for everything. You are self-existent. You are Sat-Chit-Ananda. </span><strong>You</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> are eternal, unchanging. You are the Life of my life, Soul of my soul! Give me light and knowledge! Let me dwell in Thee for ever.&#8221;</span></span> When your devotion and meditation become intense and deep, you do not see the stone image. You behold the Lord only who is Chaitanya. <span style="color:red;">Image-worship is very necessary for beginners</span>…For a beginner, Pratima is an absolute necessity. <span style="color:red;"><strong>By worshipping an idol</strong>, Isvara is pleased</span>…<span style="color:red;">Even so, the Lord is highly pleased when a small portion of His Virat (cosmic) body is worshipped. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">An idol is a part of the body of the Lord</span></span>. The whole world is His body, Virat form. The devotion goes to the Lord<span style="color:red;">. The worshipper superimposes on the image the Lord and all His attributes</span>. He does Shodasopachara for the idol, the sixteen kinds of paying respects or service to the Lord…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The idol speaks. It will answer your questions and solve your problems</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">. The God in you has the power to awaken the latent </span><strong>Divinity in the idol</strong></span>…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The awakened Divinity in the idol</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;">acts as a guardian angel blessing all, conferring the highest good on those who bow to it…</span><br />
<span style="color:red;">The image in the temple at Tirupati assumed human form and gave witness in the court to help His devotees</span>.- All About Hinduism, By Sri Swami Sivananda, p.70-4<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;To the worshipper <span style="text-decoration:underline;">who believes the symbol, any kind of image is the body of the Lord under the form of stone, clay, brass, picture, Saligrama, etc. Such worship can never be idolatry</span>. <span style="color:red;">All matter is a manifestation of God. God is present in everything which exists</span>. Everything is an object of worship, for all is a manifestation of God who is therein worshipped.&#8221; – All About Hinduism, By Swami Sivananda, p.72<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be Allah nor do we adore the Kaaba as the Hindus does to their Idols thinking it to be god himself,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"> Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11:30:7 There we should bathe for purification, fast, and fix our minds in meditation. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">We should then worship the demigods by bathing their images</span>, anointing them with sandalwood pulp, and presenting them various offerings<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">So it is evident from all these verses that the Idolaters indeed think their Idols to be God. Another bogus claim made by some Hindus is that Kaaba was actually a Hindu temple and the Black Stone is actually Shiva Lingam. There is nothing to refute as there is no evidence which proves their point. There is absolutely no evidence at all. This hoax was started by a self-proclaimed historian (popularly known as Mythistorian by experts) who believed that all religious monuments and religions are corrupted form of Hinduism and that Christianity is altered version of Kishna Neti and Islam is the altered version of the Sanskrit word Ishalayam. He gave fake reference from an imaginary book created by him. Surprisingly Hindus believes this book exis and even quote, well, Islam is such a beautiful religion that anyone would like to link their religion with it. The Mythistorian&#8217;s work is full of mistakes and does not contain a single fact. He was ignorant of history. He made such poor remarks on other religions, for example he claimed that the Muslim&#8217;s Namaz is originally a Sanskrit word called Namah. I wonder whether he did some research or just wrote his frustrations. The Arabic word for prayer is Salah. Namaz is an Urdu word originated from Farsi, the word Namaz is used by Muslims of Indian subcontinent for prayer. He and his claims have been refuted by Imran Khan in his Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba Is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. Readers can go through the blog and see the idiotic claims made by Hindu nationalist. Shri Shri Ravi Shankar had also made such claims but later in a debate with Dr. Zakir Naik he honestly acknowledged that his claims are incorrect. There is no evidence at all that could suggest the Kaaba was a Hindu temple. There is also no preserved history which could suggest that Hindus lived in Makka or went there. Even a Muslim can make such claims. For example,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;Hindu God Ram was a normal Muslim, his name is altered version of the Arabic word Akram. His brother Luxman was also a Muslim his original name was Luqman, and his close disciple was Humam Bajar Ali which was changed to Hanuman Bajrang Bali. The Hindu God Krishna was also a Muslim his real name was Karim Shah. Shiva was also a Muslim his original name was Shuaa&#8221;. </span></p>
<p>So does it make them Muslims?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another bogus claim made by Hindus is that the Black Stone is Shiva Lingam. How can this be so when both these have different meanings and their own origin. The meaning and origin of Shiva Lingam is discussed briefly in the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">An Analysis of Lingam</a>. As far as Black Stone is concerned. The Arabic word is Hajre Aswad. Hajr means stone, Aswad means black. While Lingam means make erected organ and Yoni denotes female genital organ. According to the tradition, the Hajre Aswad (Black Stone) was white and was sent from heaven,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Al Tirmizi Sayyidina Book of Hajj 9, Hadith 878 &#8221;Ibn Abbas narrated that Allah&#8217;s Messenger (SAW) said, &#8220;The <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Black Stone was sent down from Paradise</span> and it was more <span style="text-decoration:underline;">white than milk</span>, but the sins of the children of Adam turned it black.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Hindus try to link Yoni (Literally female genital which is the base of Shivling) with the silver frame of Hajre Aswad. They are not aware of the fact that the silver frame was not present during the time of Prophet Muhammad (P.B.U.H). When the Black Stone was broken into pieces during a war, Its fragments were cemented into a silver frame by Abd Allah Ibn Zubayr. The Black Stone is from Heaven (Tirmizi 878) whereas Yoni (Female genital or Shivling&#8217;s base) worship was initiated after the curse. There are two stories concerning its origin. First one is when the Sage Bhrigu was dishonoured by Shiva as Shiva was busy with his wife Parvati so Bhrigu cursed him to be worshipped in Linga and Yoni form which he desired the most, another story is that Shiva was cursed by the sages to be worshipped in Penis form for seducing their wives, Shiva&#8217;s male organ fell down to earth and burned everything, Shiva told Brahma and Vishnu that it will become calm only when Parvati takes hold of it in Yoni (female genital) form. For more information, read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">Analysis of Lingam</a>. So how can some people claim Black Stone is Hindu Idol when both these have their own origin and definition? Some Hindu brothers are easily deceived by Islamophobes. One should not blindly follow what the person is saying. It is incorrect to liken Shivling with Black Stone because ShivLingam is risen out from the Vulva shaped base known as Yoni whereas Black Stone is not and Shiva Lingam is not cemented into the walls of temple like the Black Stone. There is no evidence of Lingam worship in Arabia nor there is a mention of such Idol. I request the readers to read the Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> as I don&#8217;t want to add any repetitive refutations.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:13pt;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></span><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>:-</strong> It is inappropriate to say that Muslims worship the Kaba or Black stone since Idol worship means worshipping the Idol thinking it to be God himself. Kaba is only a direction for worship. Quran nor the Hadith tell us to worship the Kaaba, Islam strictly prohibits idol worship.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Talibanism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 18:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atrocities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destruction of temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghaznavi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains and buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persecution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: MilliGazette ] &#160; Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan? &#160; &#160; Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: <a href="http://www.milligazette.com/Archives/15042001/Art06.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MilliGazette<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="color:#0070c0;">Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan?<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5643"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and Osmania universities, and Dr MS Jayaprakash, professor of history at Kollam &#8211; throw some deep insights into the dark history of India when Buddhism was systematically eliminated by Brahminical forces who control Hinduism, then and now.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Says Jayaprakash: &#8216;The ruthless demolition of Buddha statues by Taliban has courted severe criticism from different quarters of the world. Surprisingly, the BJP-led Indian Government, supported by all Hindutva forces, also condemned the Taliban action. It is a paradox that the forerunners of the present Hindutva forces in India had wantonly destroyed not only Buddhist statues but also killed Buddhists in India. Therefore, any impartial student of history would unequivocally say that these Hindutva forces have no moral right to criticize Taliban now.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He elaborates: &#8216;Hundreds of Buddhist statues, stupas and viharas have been destroyed in India between 830 and 966 AD in the name of Hindu revivalism. Both literary and archaeological sources within and outside India speak volumes about the havoc done to Buddhism by Hindu fanatics. Spiritual leaders like Sankaracharya and many Hindu kings and rulers took pride in demolishing Buddhist images aiming at the total eradication of Buddhist culture. Today, their descendants destroyed the Babri Masjid and also published the list of mosques to be targeted in future. It is with this sin of pride that they presently condemn Taliban.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin elaborates the selfish compulsions of Brahminism to wipe-out Buddhism: &#8216;Buddhism tried to create a dynamic society in ancient India. Jainism also contributed its share. As Buddhism spread, iron ploughs and implement were used for development of agriculture. As a result, new areas were cultivated and agricultural productivity increased, apart from developing trade centres and road links. Subsistence-level economy changed to a surplus economy with grain storage facilities, exchange of goods, trade and development of bureaucratic administration. This also created social change &#8211; from elans consisting several families to tribes consisting several elans of similar socio-economic conditions. The emphasis of Brahmins, on the other hand, was for receiving and giving alms and not on production of goods. Those who give and receive alms were close to Gods and those who produce were considered as inferior. According to Manusmriti, a Sudra should not have wealth of his own. In case he has any, a Brahmin as his master can take it over without any hesitation. &#8216;Rigveda&#8217; goes a step further to kill those who do not give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the Brahmins. In other words, someone has to produce goods so that others can give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the recipient Brahmins. It was against this system of &#8216;downgrading those who produce&#8217; that Buddhism came into being.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Recalls Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;The Hindu ruler Pushyamitra Sunga had destroyed 84,000 Buddhist stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. This was followed by the demolition of Buddhist centres in Magadha. Thousands of Buddhist saints were killed mercilessly. King Jalaluka destroyed the Buddha viharas within his jurisdiction on the ground that chanting of hymns by Buddhists disturbed his sleep! In Kashmir, King Kinnara demolished thousands of viharas and captured the Buddhist villages to please Brahmins. A large number of Buddha viharas were usurped by Brahmins and converted into Hindu temples where entry of &#8216;untouchables&#8217; was prohibited. Notably, Buddhist places were regularized as Hindu temples by writing Puranas, which were invented myths or pseudo history. The important temples at Tirupathi, Aihole, Undavalli, Ellora, Bengal, Puri, Badarinath, Mathura, Ayodhya, Sringeri, Bodhigaya, Saranath, Delhi, Nalanda, Gudimallam, Nagarjunakonda, Srisailam and Sabarimala are some of the striking examples of Brahminical usurpation of Buddhist centres.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Detailing the divergence in both orientation and essence between Buddhism and Hinduism, Prof. Bahauddin says: &#8216;Equality, compassion, non-violence, utilization of human abilities for general welfare, etc. were the cardinal principles of Buddhism. According to &#8216;Sathpatha Brahmanam (22-6, 3-4-14), on the other hand, the whole universe is controlled by God, God is controlled by Mantram and Mantram is with Brahmins and, therefore, Brahmins are God (on earth). They used Mantram and Sapam to instil fear in the people to obey them, while Buddhism encouraged people to observe visible facts, to apply reason to get out of fear. Buddhism also encouraged people to do good things, besides guiding Kings to look after the people&#8217;s welfare. Buddhism considers the general welfare of the people, while Brahminism considers that the whole world was created for them all along. And, there is bound to be conflict between these two opposite ways of thinking.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr Jayaprakash, Sakaracharya had played &#8216;a demon&#8217;s role&#8217; in destruction of Buddhist statues and monuments at Nagarjunakonda (in present-day Andhra Pradesh). &#8216;A. N. Longhurst, who conducted excavations at Nagarjunakonda, had recorded this in his invaluable book, Memoirs of the Archaeological Survey of India No. 54, The Buddhist Antiquities of Nagarjunakonda (Delhi, 1938, p. 6). The ruthless manner in which all the buildings at Nagarjunakonda have been destroyed is simply appalling and cannot represent the work of treasure-seekers alone since so many pillars, statues, and sculptures have been wantonly smashed to pieces. Local tradition relates that the great Hindu philosopher and teacher, Sankaracharya, came to Nagarjunakonda with a host of followers and destroyed the Buddhist monuments. The cultivated lands on which ruined buildings stand represent a religious grant made to Sankaracharya.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Quoting Dr. B. R. Ambedkar, Prof. Bahauddin says that the conflict against Brahmin supremacy had, in fact, started before Buddhist period, between Vasishta Muni, a Brahmin, and Viswamitra, a non-Brahmin. &#8216;The dispute was about the learning of &#8216;Vedas&#8217;, the right to conduct religious ceremony, to receive gifts, and to perform coronation of King. Vasishta Muni insisted that these were the exclusive privileges of Brahmins, while Viswamitra was opposed to such exclusive rights. This dispute lasted for long period, and even Kings joined in it (Writings and Speeches of Dr. Ambedkar, vol. 7, p. 148-155. It was won by Brahmins.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin lists the different stages of Brahmin hostility against Buddhism: &#8216;1) 483-273 BC: The period after Buddha&#8217;s death upto Ashoka&#8217;s rule when attempts were made to include Brahminical ideas in Buddhist ideology. 2) 273-200 BC: When Buddhism spread all over India and became a world religion. 3) 200 BC-500 AD: The period when all possible efforts were made to disintegrate Buddhism from within by adulterating Buddhist teachings with Brahminical ideas and also through physical annihilation from outside. As a result, Buddhism divided itself into 18 sects, of which Hinayana and Mahayana were prominent ones. 4) 500-700 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in North India and efforts began to drive out Buddhism and Jainism from South India. 5) 700-1100 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in South India and, with added vigour, it moved again to North India to obtain complete supremacy over Buddhism and Jainism. 6) 1100-1400 AD: Buddhism and Jainism were destroyed from the remaining Southern States of Karnataka and Kerala and, thus, total supremacy of Brahminism all over India was achieved.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;Within Kerala, Sankaracharya and his close associate Kumarila Bhatta, an avowed foe of Buddhism, organized a religious crusade against Buddhists. A vivid description of Sankaracharya&#8217;s pleasure of seeing people of non-Brahminic faith being burnt to death is available in &#8216;Sankara Digvijaya&#8217;. Kumarila instigated King Suddhanvan of Ujjain to exterminate Buddhists. The &#8216;Mricchakatika&#8217; of Sudraka describes how the King&#8217;s brother-in-law in Ujjain inhumanly tortured the Buddhist monks, by using them as bullocks by inserting a string through their nose and yoking them to the cart! The &#8216;Keralolpathi&#8217; documents the extermination of Buddhism from Kerala by Kumarila. About the activities of Sankaracharya, even Vivekananda had observed: &#8216;And, such was the heart of Sankara that he burnt to death lots of Buddhist monks by defeating them in argument. What can you call such action on Sankara&#8217;s part except fanaticism&#8217; (Complete works of Swami Vivekananda, Vol. III, p. 118, Calcutta, 1997).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, there are hundreds of places in Kerala having names &#8216;palli&#8217; either affixed or suffixed with them. &#8216;Karunagapalli, Karthikapalli, Pallickal, Pallippuram, Edappally, etc. are some examples of these places. The term &#8216;palli&#8217; means a Buddha vihara. Notably, Kerala had 1200 years of Buddhist tradition. Earlier, the schools in Malayalam were called as &#8216;Ezhuthupalli&#8217; or &#8216;Pallikoodam&#8217;. It is also worth noticing that the Christians and Muslims in Kerala use the term &#8216;palli&#8217; to denote their church and mosque alike. These &#8216;pallies&#8217; or viharas had been ruthlessly demolished by the Hindu forces under the leadership of Sankaracharya and Kumarila. They could exterminate 1200 years of Buddhist tradition and converted Kerala into a Brahminical state based on the &#8216;Chaturvarna&#8217; system. Original inhabitants of Kerala, like the Ezhavas, Pulayas, etc., were crushed under the weight of casteism. Many a viharas was transformed into temples and majority of people were prevented from entering temples under the pretext of caste pollution. It can also be noted that the name &#8216;Kerala&#8217; is the Sanskritised Aryan version of the Dravidian and Buddhist term &#8216;Cherala&#8217;. The Parasurama legend is nothing but an invented myth for regularizing the Brahminical &#8216;Kerala&#8217; hiding its glorious Buddhist traditions.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jainism, too, met with the same fate in South India. Prof. Bahauddin elaborates: &#8216;Very little information is available about growth of Jainism in South India during 300-400 AD. The Jain book, &#8216;Digambara Darsana&#8217;, recounts the starting of a Sangham at Madurai in 470 AD and Jainism became widespread and strong during 500-600 AD (Kumaraswamy Iyengar, &#8216;Studies in South Indian Jainism&#8217;, p. 51-58)….. The Jains used to instal the images of their saints in their religious places, a practice which was followed by Brahmins. Hindu temples appeared all over Tamilnadu probably after converting the Jain religious places. The idols of 63 Brahmin Sanyasis, who led destruction of Jainism, still adorn the walls of some Hindu temples in Tamilnadu. The remains of destroyed Jain idols, their abandoned religious and living places are scattered all over Tamilnadu to narrate their story. Frescos depicting the kings of Jains could be seen on the walls near the Golden Tank at Madurai Meenakshi Temple where, of the total 12 annual festivals, five depict the killing of Jains according to Kumaraswamy Iyengar (p. 78-79).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, a number of Buddha statues have been discovered at places like Ambalapuzha, Karunagapalli, Pallickal, Bharanikkavu, Mavelikara and Neelamperur in Kerala. &#8216;They are either in the form of smashed pieces or thrown away from viharas. Lord Ayyappa of Sabarimala and Lord Padmanabha at Thiruvananthapuram are the proxy images of Buddha being worshipped as Vishnu. Hundreds of Buddhists were killed on the banks of Aluva river. The term &#8216;Aluva&#8217; was derived from &#8216;Alawai&#8217; which means &#8216;Trisul&#8217;, a weapon used by Hindu fanatics to stab Buddhists. Similarly, on the banks of the Vaigai river in Tamilnadu, thousands of Buddhists were killed by the Vaishnava Saint, Sambanthar. Thevaram, a Tamil book, documents this brutal extermination of Buddhism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls the strong reasons to believe that a large section of Jains had embraced Islam: &#8216;The spread of Islam in Tamilnadu can be considered in three or four stages. Islam spread in Kerala and Tamilnadu when Jainism was under pressure (650-750 AD). The new religion was received without resistance…. Since Islam considers every human being with equality Jainism and Buddhism had no conflict with it. When Muhammad ibn Al-Qasim attacked Sindh, the Buddhists supported him because they were facing annihilation at that time. A similar situation was prevailing in South India during 650-750 AD…. Muslims in Tamilnadu are called Anchuvanthar, Labba (teacher), Rauthar, Marakar (sailor) or Jonakan (Yavankan). The Anchuvanam is the guild of traders and groups of artisans. The Muslim mohallas of &#8216;Anchuvan Vamsagar&#8217;, &#8216;Anchuvanathar&#8217;, etc. are scattered all over Tamilnadu and seem to be the en bloc conversion of Jain guilds engaged in different activities, especially weaving. Those who ran away from Tamilnadu settled down in Sravanabalagola and Gomatheswaram in Karnataka. And, those who could not leave due to their economic interests converted to Islam. If we analyze the body structure, food, language, dress, ornaments, customs and habits of Anchuvanthar, it could be see that those are a continuation of Jain way of living and customs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Till recently, the weavers in such Muslim mohallas will not eat at noon or night, and take only one meal before dusk. This was a continuation of Jain habits. There is a separate place in such villages called &#8216;Odukkam&#8217; where Jain Munist used to sit in prayer. On the last Wednesday of the month called &#8216;Odukkathae&#8217; Wednesday, the Muslims gather together to sing religious songs, which is also a Jain tradition. When religious functions like Maulood, Rathif, etc. are organized in the house, a white cloth with lotus symbol on it called &#8216;Mekett&#8217; is tied, which resembles the &#8216;Asmanagiri&#8217; of the Jains…. The architecture of Muslim stone mosques are completely of Jain architecture. The pillars of earlier mosques have practically no difference with the Jain temple pillars. The close relationship between traders and weavers had probably cemented by conversion to Islam. During 950-1200 AD, there were large number of Sufis, Fakirs, wandering poets, singing minstrels, etc. among Muslims all over Tamilnadu. Nadirshah with 500 disciples settled down in &#8216;Trichinopoly&#8217; during 1000 AD. Aliyar Shah and his disciples made Madurai as their centre. Baba Fakhruddin travelled all over Tamilnadu. Nagur became another Sufi centre. The Muslim religious literature of Tamilnadu of that period was least different from those created by Jains and Hindus during the &#8216;Bhakti&#8217; movement.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recounts the spread of Jainism and Buddhism in Kerala, thus: &#8216;Jainism spread in North Kerala around 200 BC. The Jain architectural remains in Canara and Malabar are not available anywhere else in South of Nepal. While Jainism entered North Kerala via Mangalore, Salem, Coimbatore and Wayanad, it entered Southern Kerala from Tirunelveli, Kanyakumari, Nagercoil, Chitharal, etc. The hill near Anamala, which was an important Jain centre, is still called &#8216;Jain Durgam&#8217;. The close-by Kurumala was also a Jain centre. From Anamala through Munnar, Devikulam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor, etc. they reached Neryamangalam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor and other places. The &#8216;Kallil Kshetram&#8217; in Perumbavoor is an important Jain monument as also the &#8216;Jainmedu&#8217; in Vadakethara village of Palakkad district. Kerala&#8217;s cave temples at Chitharal, Kallil, Trikur, Erunilamkode (Thrissur district) and Thiruveghapuram (Palakkad district) were constructed during the period of Jain King Mahendra Verman-I (610-640 AD). Temple records of Rameswaram, Sucheendram, Poothadi (Wayanad), Keenalur (Kozhicode) , etc. show that they were part of &#8216;Kunavai Koottam&#8217; during 10-11th centuries. &#8216;Koottam&#8217; is the place of living for Jain Sanyasis. Temple records show that all these present-day Hindu temples were Jain religious places till 11th century. Place names with Kallu, Poothan, Aathan, Kotha, Palli, Ambalam, etc. were all Jain centres. Spread all over Kerala, names of these places show that Buddhism and Jainism were widespread. The famous Kalpathi in Palakkad district was a Buddhist-Jain centre. The &#8216;Ratholsavam&#8217; there is akin to the &#8216;Kettukazhcha&#8217; of Buddhists. The present Bhagavati temples were also Jain temples. The group, &#8216;Adikal&#8217;, had a prominent position among Jains who became &#8216;Pisharadi&#8217; after absorption of Jainism in Hinduism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&#8216;Similarly, the Buddhist stoopa at Kodungallore, located in Methala village South-East of Thrikanamathilakam, is an important Buddhist ruin in Kerala…. Mahismathi was the capital of Chera King Satyaputran, which shows the relationship of Chera country (Kerala) with Buddhism. There is a reference in &#8216;Manimekhala&#8217; about a Buddhist Chaityam in Kerala. While Vadakkumnatha Temple at Thrissur and Kurumba Temple at Kodungallore were Buddhist temples, Buddha statues were discovered from Kollam, Alappuzha, Mavelikara, Pallikkal, Karumadi and other places…. Treating mental patients in Thiruvadi temple and leprosy patients in Thakazhi temple shows that they were Buddhist temples since these kind of humanitarian services were not rendered out from Hindu temples…. By 900 AD Buddhism and Jainism were almost wiped out from Tamilnadu. The second settlement wave of Brahmins in Kerala during 900 AD was with Pandyan Kings&#8217; support. Karnataka and Kerala were the only two states where Buddhism and Jainism were still surviving and the second immigration of Brahmins might have been for driving out these two religions from the remaining places.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls: &#8216;Very few people know that Buddhism and Jainism were the prominent religions of Kerala till 1200 AD. I was also under the impression that Hinduism was in Kerala from the very beginning. When facts were pieced together, a different picture emerged. Only from the end of 1800 AD the evidence became available about Buddha, Buddhism, Ashoka, etc. That fact itself is a pathetic story….&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash in conclusion: &#8216;This is what really happened in India, the land of Buddha. But our so-called eminent historians, except a few, are bent upon eclipsing the cruelty done to Buddhists in India. These pseudo historians have succeeded in creating an impression that India is a land of righteousness and toleration. The entire world has been duped by them. The deed on the part of Taliban can be justified on the ground that Islam does not permit idols. But one has to note that Islam does not allow the demolition of other people&#8217;s religious centres and images. Whatever may be the argument for and against Taliban action, the Hindu atrocities on Buddhism in India has no parallel in the entire world history of religious struggle. Let the world know the cruel and crooked face of the &#8216;Indian vulture without culture&#8217;!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
