<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>lost &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/lost/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 13:32:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Vedas Have Been Changed</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altered]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[path]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakhas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Textual Corruption of the Vedas (English)  Hindi Article 999 Sukta&#8217;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority Response to No Corruption in Vedas &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas Have Been Changed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><a title="Textual Corruption of the Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas (English)</a>  <a href="/index.php/2014/04/29/textual-corruption-vedas-hindi/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindi Article</a></h2>
<h2><a title="999 Sukta&#039;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">999 Sukta&#8217;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption</a></h2>
<h2 class="entry-title"><a title="Origin of Vedas, Their Inspirations and Authority" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority</a></h2>
<h2 class="entry-title"><a title="Response to No Corruption in Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to No Corruption in Vedas</a></h2>
<p><span id="more-910"></span><br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas Have Been Changed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sukta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad How and where the Vedas originated are subjects of much debate amongst Hindu circles. The opinions are divergent. Some believe that the Vedas are millions of years old while others consider them to be not more than five thousand years old. When I read through the many articles written on this &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>How and where the Vedas originated are subjects of much debate amongst Hindu circles. The opinions are divergent. Some believe that the Vedas are millions of years old while others consider them to be not more than five thousand years old. When I read through the many articles written on this subject by Hindus themselves, I found that almost all of them assumed the Vedas to be eternal. Hence, the question of the origin of Vedas is never dealt with properly. Those Hindus who addressed this question trivialized it, knowing well the amount of contradictory opinions within Hindu texts. I will attempt to bring together whatever information we get from authoritative Hindu texts regarding this issue.</p>
<p><span id="more-908"></span></p>
<p><strong>Conflicting Reports</strong></p>
<p>1. <em>The Vedas were produced from deities Agni, Vayu and Surya</em></p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad says</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="372" height="196" class="wp-image-7517" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting1.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“1. Prajapati brooded over the worlds, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, Agni (fire) from the earth, Vayu (air) from the sky, Aditya (the sun) from heaven.</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. He brooded over these three deities, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, the Rik verses from Agni, the Yagus verses from Vayu, the Saman verses from Aditya.” [Chandogya Upanishad- Adhyay 4, Khanda 17, Mantras1 and 2]</strong></p>
<p>The same view is expressed in Shatpath Brahman 11:5:8:1,2. This reference clearly mentions that Agni, Vayu and Aditya are not the names of any Rishis but are demi gods. Note that only three Vedas are mentioned here. There is no mention of Atharvaved. However, Gopath Brahman (1:49), which is the specific Brahman of Atharvaveda, mentions its deity to be the Moon.</p>
<p>2. <em>The Vedas are the breathings of the Great Being</em></p>
<p>Shatapath Brahman (14:5:4:10) and Brihadaranyak Upanishad (2:4:10) says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="387" height="149" class="wp-image-7518" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting2.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“As clouds of smoke proceed by themselves out of a lighted fire kindled with damp fuel, thus, verily, has been breathed forth from this Great Being what we have as Rig-veda, Yagur-veda, Sama-veda, Atharvangirasas, Itihasa (legends), Purana (cosmogonies), Vidya (knowledge), the Upanishads, Slokas (verses), Sutras (prose rules), Anuvyakhyanas (glosses), Vyakhyanas (commentaries)’. From him alone all these were breathed forth.”</strong></p>
<p>Mr. Agniveer has used this verse from Shatapath Brahman to prove that Vedas have emanated from God. He says,</p>
<p><strong>Shatpath Brahman 14.5.4.10 states that Ishwar, who is present even beyond the Akash/Sky created the Vedas. The way breath goes out of body and then comes in, during inception of creation, Ishwar creates the Vedas and illuminates the world, and in the phase of dissolution (Pralay), Vedas no more remain in world. However just as a sapling remains inside the seed, Vedas still remain in knowledge of Ishwar, unchanged.</strong></p>
<p>The interpretation that he tries to put on this verse is unfounded. If he uses this verse as proof of Vedic origin, then he cannot brush aside the fact that even the Puranas, Itihasas, etc are on the same level as the Vedas. He simply gives the reference and his own meaning without quoting the exact verse for fear that his own ideology might be undermined. Anyway, let us move on with other opinions.</p>
<p>3. <em>The Vedas were scraped off from Brihadaranyak Upanishadas being his hair and his mouth</em></p>
<p>Atharvaveda (10:7:20) says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="566" height="104" class="wp-image-7519" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting3.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“Declare who is that Skambha, from whom they cut off the Rik verses; from whom they scraped off the Yajush; of whom the Saman verses are the hairs, and the verses of Atharva and Angiras the mouth”</strong></p>
<p>4. Shvetashvatara Upanishad 6: 18 says,</p>
<p><strong>“Seeking for freedom I go for refuge to that God who is the light of his own thoughts, he who first creates Brahma and delivers the Vedas to him”</strong></p>
<p>5. Mundak Upanishad 1:1:1,2 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="403" height="176" class="wp-image-7520" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting4.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“1. BRAHMA was the first of the Devas, the maker of the universe, the preserver of the world. He told the knowledge of Brahman, the foundation of all knowledge, to his eldest son Atharva.</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. Whatever Brahma told Atharvan, that knowledge of Brahman Atharvan told to Angir; he told it to Satyavaha Bharadvaga, and Bharadvaga told it in succession to Angiras.”</strong></p>
<p>Mr. Agniveer makes yet another error on this issue. He claims that Brahma learned the four Vedas from the Rishis. However, according to these references from Svetashvatara and Mundak Upanishads, Brahma was directly taught by God and he in turn taught the other Rishis.  An interesting point to be noted here is that in the same Khanda,  verse 5, Angiras calls the four Vedas as ‘lower knowledge’  (Apra) and says that God cannot be known through the Vedas.</p>
<p>From the above given passages it is clear that there is no clear understanding of the origin of Vedas. The texts mutually contradict. Numerous other Hindu texts have still more variant views about the origin of Vedas. I will summarily mention those views also:</p>
<ol>
<li>According to Taittiriya Brahman (2:39:1) ‘Vedas are the hair of Prajapati’s beard’.</li>
<li>According to Bhagavat Puran (3:12:34-37) ‘Vedas issued from the four mouths of Brahma’.</li>
<li>Vishnu Puran says that ‘Vedas were produced from Gayatri’.</li>
<li>Vishu Puran also says that ‘the Vedas are Vishnu’.</li>
<li>According to Mahabharata, Shanti Parv, ‘Saraswati was the mother of Vedas’.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Rishis as the authors of Vedas</strong></p>
<p>A Rishi is a poet of the Vedas. The meaning of the word <em>Rishi </em>(ऋषि ) as given in <em>Nirukt</em> is <em>Rishidarshanat </em>(ऋषिर्दार्शनात), which means ‘seer’. The famous quote of Yask Muni states that  यस्य वाक्य मस ऋषि, meaning <em>‘Rishi </em>is the one whose quote itself is the mantra’. This is suffient to show that Rishis were the ones who made up the mantras. This is backed up by Taittiriya Brahman (2:8:8:5) which states</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="238" height="41" class="wp-image-7521" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting5.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“Wise Rishis are the makers of mantras”</strong></p>
<p>The assumption that Vedas are eternal makes many Hindus to say that Rishis were given the Vedas. Of this there is not the slightest proof. This Rishis again and again claim to have composed the hymns themselves just as a carpenter makes objects. In some hymns they express no consciousness whatever of deriving assistance from any supernatural source.</p>
<p><strong>How many Rishis?</strong></p>
<p><strong>A.   4 Rishis</strong></p>
<p>Arya Samaj/agniveer claims that Vedas were reaveled to four Rishis, viz, Agni, Vayu, Angira and Surya. However, the reference I gave earlier from Chandogya Upanishad (4:17:1-2) disproves this assertion. This reference clearly calls these four ‘persons’ as <em>Devatas</em> or deities, and not Rishis. The imaginary Rishis of Arya Samaj are nowhere to be found in authoritative Hindu texts. If they were real Rishis we would certainly have their biographies.</p>
<p><strong>B.   414 Rishis</strong></p>
<p>Another view about the Vedic authorship is that Vedic mantras are the works of 414 Rishis, whose names are to be found in <em>Anukarmani</em>. When we read the Vedas, we find the name of a Rishi mentioned with every Sookt (hymn), who can be considered as the author of that particular Sookt. However, Arya Samaj scholars opine that these Rishis are not the ones who conjured up the mantras. Rather, they were the people who comprehended the meaning of the hymns by their meditation. This opinion is false due to the following reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Rishis whose names are borne at the beginning of the Sooktas, many times their names appear even inside the Sooktas. What is the name of a Rishi doing inside a Vedic Mantra? For example, Vishwamitra JI is the Rishi of the third Mandal (Book) of Rigveda. His name appears in Rigveda 3:53:7,9</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="781" height="496" class="wp-image-7522" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting6.jpg?w=866" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.jpeg 781w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2-300x191.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2-768x488.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 781px) 100vw, 781px" /></p>
<p><strong>“Bounteous are these, Angirases, Virupas: the Asura’s Heroes and the Sons of Heaven. They, giving store of wealth to Visvamitra, prolong his life through countless Soma-pressings.</strong></p>
<p><strong>8 Maghavan weareth every shape at pleasure, effecting magic changes in his body, Holy One, drinker out of season, coming thrice, in a moment, through fit prayers, from heaven.</strong></p>
<p><strong>9 The mighty sage, God-born and God-incited, who looks on men, restrained the billowy river.When Visvamitra was Sudas’s escort, then Indra through the Kusikas grew friendly.”</strong></p>
<p>Also, Rishi Kanva is the Rishi of the major part of the 8th Mandal of Rigveda. His name occurs some fifty times within the Mantras of Mandal 8.</p>
<ul>
<li>Not only the names of Rishis but also the names of their contemporary rulers and rishis appear in the Vedic Mantras. For example, Rishi Vashishtha is the Rishi of the 7th Mandal of Rigveda. This Mandal is thus also called as Vashishtha Mandal. Vashishtha was a contemporary of Rishi Vishvamitra and the <em>Purohit</em> (priest) of Raja Ramchandra. His name occurs 45 times.</li>
<li>When the Sookta bears the name of a male Rishi, the genders used in the hymn are always masculine. When the Sookta bears the name of a female Rshika, all the genders used in the Mantras of that Sookt are feminine. This phenomenon is certain proof that the Sookt has been produced by that very Rishi or Rishika. For example, see the Yama-Yami Sookt (Rigveda 10:10), where Yama and Yami both are having a dialogue.</li>
<li>Many Sooktas contain similar dialogues between a man and a woman. They have been assigned as that Sooktas Rishi and Rishika. For example, the dialogue between Indra and his wife, Indrani (Rigveda 10:86)</li>
<li>In some Sooktas, the <em>Devata </em>(deity) of one mantra is the Rishi of next mantra and vice versa. This type of Sookta is known as a dialogue between a Rishi and the Deity. Now, if the Rishi  was only a seer of the mantras, how is it possible that in a particular Sookt, the Rishi becomes a <em>Devata  </em>in one mantra and a <em>Devata </em>becomes a Rishi in another? For example see Rigveda 10:51, where a dialogue is going on between Agni Sauchik and the <em>Devata</em>. Here, in mantras 1,3,5,7 and 9 Agni Sauchik is the <em>Devata</em> while in mantras 2,4,6,and 8 he is the Rishi.</li>
<li>We may ask has Swami Dayanand Ji really understood any portion of the Vedas. If yes, then why is his name not mentioned in the Vedas?</li>
<li>Not even one Sookt in the entire Vedas bears the names of Sri Ram, Sri Krishna, Sri Vyas Ji, who are the stars of Indian literature. Does this imply they never understood the Vedas?</li>
<li>Vedas also contain the mention of the family trees, varnas (Brahmin, Kshatriya,etc) of some Rishis. If the Rishis were only seers, how come did the tales of their mutual conflicts find their way into Vedic Mantras? For example, Vedas inform us about 22 Rishis of Kanva family,  36 Rishis of Atri family, 11 Rishis of Vashishtha family, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Opinions of Rishis concerning the origin of Vedic Hymns</strong></p>
<p>As I have already said that the names of the Rishis of each hymn are found in the <em>Anukarmani</em>. It is a record of the number of verses, name and family of Rishis, names of deities, etc.</p>
<p>In later times when the Vedas were claimed to be eternal, it was pretended that these Rishis were only the ones by whom hymns “were seen” or to whom they were communicated.  However, there is no proof for this.</p>
<p>Now what is the opinion of the Rishis themselves regarding the origin of Vedas. Following points make it clear:</p>
<p><strong>[a]</strong> In the very second mantra of Rigveda is it mentioned</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="79" class="wp-image-7523" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting7.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“Worthy is Agni to be praised by living as by ancient seers. He shall bring. hitherward the gods.”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[b] </strong>Rigveda 10:54:6 ascribes the making of hymns to a Rishi</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="569" height="133" class="wp-image-7524" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting8.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“An acceptable and honorific hymn has been uttered to Indra by Brihaduktha, maker of hymns”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[c]</strong> Again it is mentioned in Rigveda 7:22:9</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="572" height="131" class="wp-image-7525" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting9.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“Among all Rsis, Indra, old and recent, who have engendered hymns as sacred singers, Even with us be thine auspicious friendships.  Preserve us evermore with blessings.”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[d]  </strong>Who prepares the hymns? Rigveda 5:2:11 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="570" height="126" class="wp-image-7526" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-9.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting10.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“As a skilled craftsman makes a car, a singer I, Mighty One! this hymn for you have fashioned. If you, O Agni, God, accept it gladly, may we obtain thereby the heavenly waters.”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[e]</strong> Rigveda 4:16:21 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="566" height="130" class="wp-image-7527" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-10.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting11.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“Now, Indra! lauded, glorified with praises, let power swell. high like rivers for the singer. For you a new hymn, Lord of Bays, is fashioned. May we, car-borne, through song be victors ever.”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[f]</strong> Rigveda 7:35:14</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="574" height="103" class="wp-image-7528" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-11.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting12.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“So may the Rudras, Vasus, and Adityas accept the new hymn which we now are making. May all the Holy Ones of earth and heaven, and the Cow’s offipring hear our invocation.”</strong></p>
<p><strong>[g]</strong> Rigveda 6:34:1 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="563" height="104" class="wp-image-7529" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-12.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting13.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“FULL Many songs have met in you, O Indra, and many a noble thought from you proceed. Now and of old the eulogies of sages, their holy hymns and lauds, have yearned for Indra.”</strong></p>
<p>From this we come to know that instead of the hymns being eternal, or of an infinite age, they are composed by the Rishis themselves. The Rishis explicitly speak of ancient and new hymns. The Rishis entertained the idea that the gods would be more highly gratified if their praises were celebrated in new, and perhaps more elaborate and beautiful compositions, than if older prayers had been repeated.</p>
<p>Panini openly states the fact that there are old and new Brahmanas; whereas according to the doctrine of later times, the brahmanas are neither old nor new, but eternal and of divine origin. He rests his opinoin as to the difference of dates on the evidence of language. One argument of the eternity of Vedas is that sound is eternal. To any person of common sense the simple statement of this proof, is its refutation. The same argument would prove every book to be eternal.</p>
<p>Some Hindus might respond that by the new Rishis and Hymns are meant the Rishis and Hymns of the present life, while the old Rishis and Hymns are of the previous life. This view is far from logical. According to the belief of Arya Samaj, if these are the same Vedas that have always been. then classifying the Hymns into old and new is meaningless. This is because the Hymns that would be new would also be old.</p>
<p><strong>Internal evidence of the authorship of Vedas</strong></p>
<p>When a deed is produced in court, which is affirmed to have been written many hundred years ago, there are often means of judging from the document itself as to its age. Suppose, for example, it contained the names of Einstein, Gandhi or Hitler, it could at once be known that it could not be older than last century. If it were asserted that these referred to other persons of the same name who lived long before or that they were prophecies, the conclusion would be that it was an attempt to support one falsehood by another. If the Vedas are eternal, why are the names of so many persons mentioned in them who lived in comparatively recent times?</p>
<p>The hymns of the Rigveda themselves supply us with numerous data by which we can judge of the circumstances to which they owed their origin, and of the manner in which they were created. They afford us very distinct indications of the locality in which they were composed.  The Indus is the great river; the Ganges is only twice mentioned; the Sarasvati was the eastern boundary.</p>
<p>The hymns show us Aryan tribes living in a state of warfare with surrounding enemies (some of them, probably, alien in race and language), and gradually, as we may infer, forcing their way onward to the east and south. They supply us with numerous specimen of the particular sorts of prayers, viz., for protection and victory, which men circumstanced would naturally address to the gods whom they worshipped as well as of the more common applications which men in general offer up for the various blessings that constitute the sum of human welfare.</p>
<p>The following hymn to Indra, asking him to destroy the Dasyus, the aborigines, and give food and a camp with running water, bears internal evidence that it was composed at a time when the Aryans were invading India:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="575" height="602" class="wp-image-7530" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-13.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting14.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>1 GLAD you: your glory has been quaffed, Lord of Bay Steeds, as ’twere the bowl’s enlivening mead.<br />
For you the Strong there is strong drink, mighty, omnipotent to win.<br />
2 Let our strong drink, most excellent, exhilarating, come to you,<br />
Victorious, Indra bringing gain, immortal conquering in fight,<br />
3 You, Hero, winner of the spoil, urgest to speed the car of man.<br />
Burn, like a vessel with the flame, the lawless Dasyu, Conqueror!<br />
4 Empowered by your own might, O Sage, you stole Sarya’s chariot wheel.<br />
You bare Kutsa with the steeds of Wind to Susna as his death.<br />
5 Most mighty is you rapturous joy, most splendid is your active power,<br />
Wherewith, foe-slaying, sending bliss, you art supreme in gaining steeds.<br />
6 As you, O Indra, to the ancient singers wast ever joy, as water to the thirsty,<br />
So unto you I sing this invocation. May we find strengthening food in full abundance.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Conclusion as to the authorship of the Vedas</strong></p>
<p>Quotations have been given from Hindu sacred books containing many different opinions as to the origin of Vedas. In opposition to these, the authorship of many of the hymns is distinctly claimed by persons whose names are given. The hymns themselves demonstrate that they were composed when the Aryans were entering India, when they had not advanced much beyond the border, and were engaged in constant wars with the natives.</p>
<p>Victory in battle was often ascribed to the virtue of a hymn. Thus in Rigveda 7:33:3,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="586" height="104" class="wp-image-7531" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-14.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/042615_0122_needediting15.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>“So, verily, with these he crossed the river, in company with these he slaughtered Bheda. So in the fight with the Ten Kings, Vasisthas! did Indra help Sudas through your devotions.”</strong></p>
<p>Such hymns were considered unfailing spells, and became the sacred war-songs of the whole tribe. They were handed down from the father to son as the most valuable heirloom.</p>
<p>The legitimate conclusion is that the Vedic hymns were written by the authors whose names they bear, and they are not eternal.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Textual Corruption of the Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sukta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad Make sure that you read the article &#8216;Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration and Authority&#8216; to have a better comprehension of this article. After reading about the origin of Vedas, we now move on to the textual corruption of the Vedas.  A lot of claims are made by many modern Hindus about &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>Make sure that you read the article &#8216;<a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration and Authority</a>&#8216; to have a better comprehension of this article.</p>
<p>After reading about the origin of Vedas, we now move on to the textual corruption of the Vedas.  A lot of claims are made by many modern Hindus about the perfect preservation of the Vedas. Mr. Agniveer too makes such high flying claims. I have analyzed this topic objectively and want to present the result before the readers.</p>
<p><span id="more-906"></span></p>
<p>Let me start by sharing with you an interesting yet ludicrous story that is mentioned in the Shanti Parv of Mahabharata; the story of the Vedas being stolen from the Creator of the Worlds by two demons, Madhu and Kaitabha. We read about this in Shanti Parv, Section 348. The two mighty Danavas (demons), having seized the Vedas, quickly dived into the ocean of waters which they saw and proceeded to its bottom. Seeing the Vedas forcibly taken away from him, Brahma Ji became filled with grief, and started wailing.  The Vedas were later recovered by Vishu Ji&#8217;s timely intervention but still it shows the insecurity of the Vedic texts from the very beginning. If Brahma Ji had memorized the Vedas, how could the Vedas have been stolen? Perhaps his memory was not that strong after all. I only shared this story to give the readers an idea of a book which according to Mr. Agniveer is the  &#8216;greatest wonder of human civilization&#8217;. Truly a wonder it is.</p>
<p><strong>What is the total number of the Vedas?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Three, Four or Five Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>One opinion is that there are three deiies, and from them originate the three Vedas or three types of mantras.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="372" height="196" class="wp-image-7494" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext1.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;1. Prajapati brooded over the worlds, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, Agni (fire) from the earth, Vayu (air) from the sky, Aditya (the sun) from heaven.</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. He brooded over these three deities, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, the Rik verses from Agni, the Yagus verses from Vayu, the Saman verses from Aditya.&#8221; [Chandogya Upanishad- Adhyay 4, Khanda 17, Mantras1 and 2]</strong></p>
<p>The same view is expressed in Shatpath Brahman 11:5:8:1,2. Note only three Vedas are spoken here. Further Manu 1:23 says,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;But from fire, wind, and the sun he drew forth the threefold eternal Veda, called Rik, Yagus, and Saman, for the due performance of the sacrifice.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Also see Manu 2:118, 2:118, 2:230, 9:188, where only three Vedas have been mentioned.</p>
<p>Even Swami Dayanand writes in Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 3, on the authority of Manu Smriti 3:1,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Thus after joining the school at the age of 8 years, if a student studies the Vedas with their subsidiary subjects for 36 years, (i.e., he devotes 12 years to the study of each of the three Vedas), he completes his education at the age of 36+8=44.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, according to Swamiji and Manu Smriti, Vedas are only 3. Is Atharvaved really a genuine Veda?</p>
<p>The popular opinion is that Vedas are four in number viz. Rigved, Yajurved, Samved and Atharvaved. Another opinion is that Vedas are five in number because Atharvaved is actually two Vedas; one is Atharvaved and the other Angirasved.</p>
<p>The divergent opinions regarding the number of Vedas do not end here. Another authoritative view which holds its place is that Vedas number 1131 as we shall see.</p>
<p><strong>1131 Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>According to the Mahabhasya of Patanjali, there were 21 Shakhas of Rigveda, 9 of Atharvaveda, 101 of Yajurveda (86 of Krishna Yajurveda and 15 of Shukla Yajurveda, according to later authorities) and a 1000 shakhas of Samaveda. All these add to give the figure 1131. All these Shakhas are considered to be Vedas. The words Shakha means a &#8216;branch&#8217; or a &#8216;limb&#8217; and refers to a particular traditional text followed, as in the phrase śākhām adhite, (&#8220;he recites a particular version of the Veda&#8221;).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="585" height="501" class="wp-image-7495" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext2.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.jpeg 585w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37-300x257.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 585px) 100vw, 585px" /></p>
<p>However, out of these 1131 Shakhas, only 11 Shakhas remain alive. As far as Rigved is concerned, only one Shakha, Shaakal Shakha alone remains alive out of the 21 that existed at one time. Another shakha that may have survived is the Bāṣhkala, although this is uncertain. Out of the 101 Shakhas of Yajurveda, only 6 are alive. In fact, Yajurveda is classified broadly into Shukla Yajurveda  (White) and Krishna Yajurveda (Black). The former is popular in North India while the later is popular in South India.  Shukla Yajurveda is also known as Vajasaneyi. The Vajasaneyi Samhita has forty chapters or adhyayas and there are two extant Shakhas of Shukla Yajurveda viz. Kanvaand Madhyandina. Krishna Yajurveda has 4 extant Shakhas viz.</p>
<ul>
<li>Taittirīya</li>
<li>Maitrayani</li>
<li>Kaṭhak</li>
<li>Kapiṣṭhala</li>
</ul>
<p>There are three surviving Shakhas out of 1000 of the text of the Samaveda Samhita:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kauthuma Shakha is current in Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Orissa and since a few decades in Darbhanga, Bihar,</li>
<li>the Jaiminiya in the Carnatic, Tamilnadu and Kerala,</li>
<li>and the Rāṇāyanīya in the Maharastra.</li>
</ul>
<p>Out of the nine Shakhas of Atharvaveda, only two have survived</p>
<ul>
<li>Paippalāda, in regions south to Narmada river</li>
<li>Shaunakīya, in regions north to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>What we know today as Rigveda, Yajurveda, Samaveda and Atharvaveda are actually Shakhas from the multitude of other Shakhas. The so called Vedas are never named as Vedas in their hymns. In other words, Rigveda is never called Rigveda in the Rigveda itself. If it be said that in other scriptures they have been called as Vedas, we can respond that so many other things have been called as Vedas also. For example, Ayurveda (Medicine), Sarpaveda (snakes), Dhanurved (weapons), Itihasaveda (History), Puranaveda (Stories). These words are based on Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3.</p>
<p>Hence, 1121 versions of Vedas have been lost. If someone will say that the Shakhas are not Vedas but only the explanations/commentaries that would be erroneous. The presently known Vedas are also Shakhas. So are these commentaries or actual Vedas? To say that Shakhas are not the Vedas will be to undermine the present Vedas (read Shakhas) also. Considering the two opposing Shakhas of Yajurveda we may ask, &#8220;Is Madhyandina Shakha (Shukla Yajurveda) the original or Taittirīya Shakha (Krishna Yajurveda)?&#8221;.</p>
<p>The above analysis makes it clear that a large portion of the Vedas has been lost.</p>
<p><strong>A topical study of the corruption of the Vedic text</strong></p>
<p><strong>Missing Verses</strong></p>
<p>After the collection and codification of Vedas, many different manuscripts gained currency amongst the Brahmin groups. The number of mantras in every manuscript continued to be changed. The current version of Rigveda was collected by Shaakal Rishi and was thus called Shaakal Samhita. It is divided into 10 Mandals (Books).</p>
<p>Nirukt 7:8 mentions the following,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;There is a joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu in the ten books of the Rigveda.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>However, in the entire Rigveda, there is not a single mantra jointly praising Agni and Vishnu.  What is meant by joint oblation here? An oblation is an offering (Late Latin oblatio, from offerre, oblatum, to offer), a term, particularly in ecclesiastical usage, for a solemn offering or presentation to God. Where is an offering jointly made to Agni and Vishnu, we would like to see? This is a clear evidence that the Rigveda at the time of Yaska Muni had the joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu, but it is not found in today&#8217;s Rigveda, demonstrating corruption of the text.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption in recitation</strong></p>
<p>The oral tradition of the Vedas (Śrauta) consists of several pathas, &#8220;recitations&#8221; or ways of chanting the Vedic mantras.The padapatha consists of dividing the sentence into individual pada or words. The kramapatha consists of pairing two words at a time. There has been a lot of corruption in the former recitation. I will give some examples to demonstrate this.</p>
<p><strong>Example 1</strong></p>
<p>Yask Muni, the author of Nirukt and Nighantu, writes that Vaayah is one word [See Nirukt 6:28]. But in the Shaakal Shakha&#8217;s (Rigveda&#8217;s) padapatha, it has been divided and hence became meaningless. Rigveda 10:29:1 is the place which has made the mistake.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="152" class="wp-image-7496" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-1.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext3.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;As sits the young bird on the tree rejoicing, ye, swift Pair, have been roused by clear laudation,…&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Yaska himself criticizes Shakalya and says,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Sakalya has analyzed Vaayah into Vaa and yah, then the finite verb would have had the accute accent and the sense have been incomplete.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Example 2</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 5:39:1 goes as follows,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="77" class="wp-image-7497" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-2.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext4.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;O Indra, wielder of the thunderbolt, give us whatever excellent treasure there is. With both hands bring that wealth to us, O treasure-knower&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Yaska says on this,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Sakalya the author of Rigveda padapatha, does not analyze the word Mehanaa, while Gargya the author of Samaveda padapatha analyzes it into Me-iha-naa.&#8221; [Nirukt 4:4]</strong></p>
<p>Let us see what Samaveda, Book 4; Chapter 2; Decade 1; Mantra 4 does,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="569" height="78" class="wp-image-7498" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-3.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext5.gif" /></p>
<p>Now there is a world of difference between <strong>Mehanaasti </strong>and <strong>Me-iha-naasti</strong>. The former means &#8216;I have wealth&#8217; and the latter means &#8216;I do not have&#8217;.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Rigveda</strong></p>
<p>Shaakal Rishi is called as the collector of Rigveda. He had a number of students, who later expressed many differences and compiled their own versions of Rigveda. numbering upto 21. There are major differences between the Shaakal and Baskal samhitas of Rigveda. The Śākala recension has 1,017 regular hymns, while the Bāṣkala samhita has a total of 1025 hymns.  Thus, around  some 50 mantras are missing in Śākala samhita. There are differences even over the total number of mantras.</p>
<ul>
<li>According to Anuvakanukramani Rigveda has 10,580 mantras</li>
<li>According to Gayatri Parivar Rigveda has 10,552 mantras</li>
<li>According to Sayanacharya it has 10,000 mantras</li>
<li>According to Swami Dayanand Saraswati it has 10,589 mantras</li>
</ul>
<p>As per these figures, some 500 mantras are doubtful or interpolated. However, the story does not end here. Pandit Ram Govind Trivedi, mentions another surprising fact in the preface to his Hindi translation of the Rigveda. He says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="595" height="166" class="wp-image-7499" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-4.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext6.gif" /></p>
<p>&#8220;According to one Mantra of Rigveda (Page 1403, Mantra 8), we come to know that it has 15,000 Mantras. However, when we count the total Mantras, we get 10,469 Mantras. It is possible that  like a large portion of the books of Vedic literature and Vedas were destroyed by the anti-religious, similarly,  Mantras too suffered destruction for many reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Mantra he is talking about is Rigveda 10:114:8, which says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="565" height="106" class="wp-image-7500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-5.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext7.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>GAYATRI PARIVAR TRANSLATION</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="115" class="wp-image-7501" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-6.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext8.gif" /></p>
<p>According to this analysis, Vedas have easily lost about 4,500 Mantras.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Yajurveda</strong></p>
<p>As I said earlier, out of 101 Shaakhas of Yajurveda only 6 are extant. There are two principal texts of the Yajur-Yeda, called respectively the White and the Black, or the Vajasaneyi and Taittiriya Samhitas.</p>
<p>The Vishnu Purana gives the following explanation of their names : Vaisampayana, a pupil of the great Vyasa, was the original teacher of the Black Yajur-Veda. Yajnavalkya, one of his disciples, having displeased him, was called upon by his master to part with the knowledge which he had acquired from him. He forthwith vomited the Yajur-Yeda. The other disciples of Vaisampayana, assuming the form of partridges (tittiri), picked up from the ground its several dirtied texts. From this circumstance it received the name of Taittiriya Krishna Yajur-Veda. A more rational explanation is that Vaisampayana taught it to Yaska, who taught it to Tittiri, who also became a teacher. Yajnavalkya afterwards, by the performance of severe penances, induced the Sun to impart to him those Yajur texts which his master had not possessed. The Sun then assumed the form of a horse (Vajin), and communicated to him the desired texts. Hence the Sanhita was called Vajasaneyi, and also White (or bright) because it was revealed by the Sun.</p>
<ol>
<li>There are a lot of differences between the two versions. The first mantra of both is same despite some difference in the wording. The arrangement and wording of White Yajurveda upto Adhyay 15 is radically different from the Black Yajurveda. The mantras of the 39th Chapter of Shukla Yajurveda are not found in Krishna Yajurveda.</li>
<li>An amazing information about Shukla Yajurveda is that the last chapter (Chapter 40) is actually an Upanishad, the Ish Upanishad. As per the belief of Arya Samaj, Upanishads are not revealed scriptures. It is worth noting that while it is counted with the Upanishads, the Ish Upanishad remains non-revealed and when it is added to the Veda it become revealed.</li>
<li>The Ish Upanishad is not the only addition to this Yajurveda. A lot of Brahamanas have been inserted into the text of the Yajurveda. For example, Adhyay 24 is entirely a Brahman; Adhyay 30: verses 7 through 15 are all Brahmanas and not Mantras.</li>
</ol>
<p>Not only in the ancient period, but in recent times too there have been many changes in the Vedic texts by Swami Dayanand Saraswati and his followers.</p>
<p>Following is a list of changes that have been made.</p>
<ol>
<li>In the Yajurveda Bhasya of Dayanand Ji, Adhyay 9, Mantra 20 has been distorted by adding the word Gamyaat, which is not to be found in the text. Where did this word come from?</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="531" height="657" class="wp-image-7502" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-7.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext9.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Comparing the Yajurveda of Gayatri Parivar and Arya Samaj, there are many mantras missing in one or another of the versions. For example, the 25th Chapter of Gayatri Parivar Yajurveda has 47 mantras. Even the Yajurveda of Ralph Griffith has 47 mantras. But, the Arya Samaj version has an additional Mantra 48.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR/SANATAN DHARMI VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="581" height="509" class="wp-image-7503" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-8.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext10.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="484" height="567" class="wp-image-7504" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-9.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext11.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 26, mantra 26, the word <strong>Ayohtay </strong>was changed to <strong>Apohtay</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="44" class="wp-image-7505" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext12.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.jpeg 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38-300x24.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="521" height="153" class="wp-image-7506" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-10.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext13.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 39, mantra 5, the word <strong>Vishyandmaane </strong>was changed to <strong>Vishpandmaane</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="82" class="wp-image-7507" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-11.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext14.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="411" height="197" class="wp-image-7508" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-12.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext15.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>The longer ending in Yajurveda 13:58 has been deleted from Arya Samaj version, but exists in the Gayatri Parivar version.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="568" height="102" class="wp-image-7509" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-13.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext16.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="513" height="166" class="wp-image-7510" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-14.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext17.gif" /></p>
<p>No one can call these interpolations and alterations to be printing errors, because the translations also have been made of the interpolations. These are examples of deliberate interpolations.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption of Samaveda</strong></p>
<p>Samaveda is heavily borrowed from the Rigveda. It consists of a collection of hymns, portions of hymns, and detached verses, all but 75 taken from the Sakala Sakha of the Rigveda, the other 75 belong to the Bashkala Sakha, to be sung, using specifically indicated melodies, called Samagana. There are differences regarding the exact number of mantras in the Samaveda. As I said earlier,  according to Patanjali&#8217;s statement, &#8220;sahasravartma samvedah&#8221; सहस्रवर्त्म<br />
समवेदः, &#8220;There are thousand branches of Samaveda&#8221;. However, only three survive:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kauthuma Shakha is current in Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Orissa and since a few decades in Darbhanga, Bihar,</li>
<li>the Jaiminiya in the Karnatak, Tamilnadu and Kerala,</li>
<li>and the Rāṇāyanīya in the Maharastra.</li>
</ul>
<p>The total mantras in the Jaimniya Shakha is 1687. Kauthama Shakha has 1869 mantras . Thus, 182 mantras are missing fromKauthama Shakha. An analysis of both these versions reveals lots of Paath-Bhed (variant readings). Besides this, there is a difference in number of songs attributed to different branches. Shri Satvalekar in his preface to Samaveda Samhita has given the following table of songs (Samagana).</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td><strong>Songs of Jaiminiya Branch</strong></td>
<td><strong>Songs of Kauthamiya Branch</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gramgeyo-gān:</td>
<td>1233</td>
<td>1197</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Aranyageya-gān:</td>
<td>291</td>
<td>294</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ooh-gān:</td>
<td>1802</td>
<td>1026</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Oohya-gān:</td>
<td>356</td>
<td>205</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total</td>
<td>3681</td>
<td>2722</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>We can easily see that the Samaganas of Jaiminiya Version are 1000 more than those of Kauthamiya Version.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption in Atharvaveda</strong></p>
<p>Atharvaveda, also known as Brahmaveda is considered the youngest amongst all other Vedas. As I mentioned earlier, out of the nine versions of Atharvaveda according to Patanjali, only two are extant</p>
<ul>
<li>Paippalāda, in regions south to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Shaunakīya, in regions north to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>Both versions have lot of differences in the words and arrangement.  Paippalada Shaakha can further be divided into two parts; Atharvaveda and Angirasveda. It is mentioned in Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3:4-8 in the context of the Ashvamedha sacrifice; after theYagya (ritual) is completed, the householders should be instructed in Rigveda of the first day. old men should be instructed in Yajurveda on the second day, handsome youths should be instructed in Atharvaveda on the third day and handsome maiden should be instructed in Angirasveda on the  fourth day. Angirasveda is attributed to Rishi Angiras who is in the fourth generation after Rishi Atharva. There is no mention of Samaveda in this reference of Shatapath Brahman.</p>
<p>Patanjali Rishi, in his Mahabhasya, has given the first mantras of all the four Vedas. In the present Atharvaved (Shaunak Shaakha) it is not the first mantra, but the 26th mantra. This means 25 mantras are extra in that Shaunak shaakha.</p>
<p>Following is an exmaple of textual corruption in the Atharvaveda.</p>
<p>Atharvaveda Khand 20 and Sookt 127 is part of the Kuntap Sooktas. In the third mantra of this Sookt there has been  an alteration. The Atharvaveda of Arya Samaj and Gayatri Parivar both have it as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="365" height="67" class="wp-image-7511" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-15.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext18.gif" /></p>
<p>The word preceeding <strong>Maamahe</strong> is <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. However, in the Atharvaveda of Pandit Raja Ram Shashtri of Arya Samaj as well as the Atharvaveda printed in Germany, the text differs as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="317" height="56" class="wp-image-7512" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-16.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext19.gif" /></p>
<p>Here the word preceeding <strong>Maamahe </strong>is <strong>Rishye </strong>and not <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. This makes a difference in the meaning of the mantra.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>The above analysis proves beyond the shadow of a doubt that Vedas have suffered heavy interpolations and changes. Talking strictly, even if one accusation of the above analysis stands, the entire Vedic literature will be unacceptable as a genuine inspired document.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>999 Sukta&#039;s Lost,Still No Textual Corruption In Vedas?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[are]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no changes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[textual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedic scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed &#160; A lot of false claims, about Vedas, are being circulated over the internet by certain self proclaimed scholars.  One such claim is that the Vedas are free from any sort of textual corruption, and the Veda Samhitas are present today in their original form as they were revealed ( read compiled) &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">999 Sukta&#039;s Lost,Still No Textual Corruption In Vedas?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed<br />
&nbsp;<br />
A lot of false claims, about Vedas, are being circulated over the internet by certain self proclaimed scholars.  One such claim is that the Vedas are free from any sort of textual corruption, and the Veda Samhitas are present today in their original form as they were revealed ( read compiled) without the slightest change.<br />
<span id="more-834"></span><br />
However we come across abundant evidence which point to the fact that Vedas have been changed, and Ved Samhitas are not in the original form. As such the claims of so called ‘scholars’ is as ridiculous as some well wisher saying “you are dead” to a person who himself is claiming to be alive!<br />
In our article “<a title="Textual Corruption of the Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas</a>” we presented evidences that proved that Vedas have been changed. The article invoked a mixed response. A few apologists (“<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014131738/http://islamhinduism.com/responses/answering-agniveer/179-agniveer-or-deceiveer" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Decei<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>veer”) attempted to refute the article. Though the apologists’ response was disappointing, we took this as an opportunity to share our research with readers, expecting them to benefit from the discussion. Our rebuttal to the pseudo-scholarly response of the apologists can be read <a title="Response to no Corruption in Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">here</a>.<br />
This article is a continuation of our series on the textual corruption of Vedas. Here we intend to present more proofs and evidences revealing the textual corruption of Vedas.</p>
<h1><strong>999 lost Sukta’s of Rigveda</strong></h1>
<p>Shaunak Rishi in his Brahddevata, Katyayana’s in his Sarvanukramani,Sayan Acharya and Skand Swami in their Introduction of commentary of Rig Veda Mandal 1 Sukta 99 state that Kashyap rishi is the seer of 1000 suktas, in these suktas the number of mantras(richas/Verses) increase by one.</p>
<ol>
<li>Katyayana’s Sarvanukramani :</li>
</ol>
<p>Katyayana writes on sukt 99<br />
जातवेदस एका । जातवेदस्यम् एतदादीन्येकभूयांसिसूक्तसहस्त्रमेतत्तु कश्यपार्षम् ।<br />
Rishi Kashyap is the seer of 1000 Jatvedas suktas.<br />
2. Shaunak Rishi&#8217;s Brahddevata :<br />
Kashyap rishi is the seer of 1000 sukt addressed to Jatvedas which appear before the sukt addressed to Indra (Rigved Mandal 1 sukt 100). The first sukt of  these is “For Jatvedas…(जातवेदसे सुनवाम &#8230;&#8230;..Rigved Mandal 1 Sukt 99). According to Shakupanithe number of mantras increase by one(in the number of stanzas). (Brahddevata 3 -130 –B)</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Shadgurushishya&#8217;s Vedarth Dipika :</li>
</ol>
<p>According to Shadgurushishya’s writings these Richa’s( verses )were 5,00,499 in number.<br />
ऋचस्तु पंचलक्षा स्युः सैकोनशतपंचकम्<br />
&nbsp;<br />
In light of the above stated facts we can draw the following conclusions<br />
1. Kashyap rishi is the seer of Rigved Mandal 1 sukt 99, Jatvedas sukt.<br />
2. Kashyap rishi is the seer of a total of 1000 Jatvedas sukt, including Rigved Mandal 1 sukt 99,.<br />
3. Rigved Mandal 1 sukt 99 is the first sukt of these 1000 sukt.<br />
4. These 1000 verses, of which Kashyap rishi is seer, appear before Rigved Mandal 1 sukt 100.<br />
5. In these sukt the number of mantras increase by one, from which we conclude these 1000 suktas contain a total of 500,500 richa (verses).<br />
6. In the extant Rigveda Samhitas we get only one of these 1000 verses, this leads us to the conclusion that 999 sukt are lost from the Rigveda. Alternatively it can be said that 5,00,499 richa (verses )are lost.<br />
The evidences presented above convincingly prove that in the extant Rigveda Samhitas a large number of suktas are missing. In the present article we concentrated only the Rigveda. In future articles along with Rigveda we will be presenting before the readers the changes in the texts of Yajurveda, Samveda and Atharvaveda as well. We would like to conclude this article with a request, for the readers and scholars who would comment on it, to keep the following statement in mind<br />
प्रमाणसिद्धांतविरुद्धमत्र यत्किंचिदुक्तं मतिमान्धदोषात्<br />
मात्सर्यमुत्सार्य तदार्यचित्ताः प्रसादमाधाय विशोधयंतु<br />
If I have said anything contrary to proofs and principles because of my less knowledge, then instead of getting angry please do rectify my errors like a true scholar.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">999 Sukta&#039;s Lost,Still No Textual Corruption In Vedas?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
