<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>dowry &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/dowry/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 10:42:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dowry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari The Manusmriti also known as Manav Dharam Shastra, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari<br />
The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manusm%E1%B9%9Bti" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Manusmriti<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> also known as <em>Manav Dharam Shastra</em>, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  It is presumed that the actual human author of this compilation used the eponym ‘Manu’, which has led the text to be associated by Hindus with the first human being and the first king in the Indian tradition.<span id="more-4827"></span><br />
<span id="more-1261"></span><br />
Although no details of this eponymous author’s life are known, it is likely that he belonged to a conservative Brahman class somewhere in Northern India. Hindu apologists consider the Manusmriti as the divine code of conduct and, accordingly, the status of women as depicted in the text has been interpreted as Hindu divine law.  While defending Manusmriti as divine code of conduct for all including women, apologists often quote the verse: <em>“yatr naryasto pojyantay, ramantay tatr devta <strong>[3/56]</strong></em> <em>(where women are provided place of honor, gods are pleased and reside there in that household)</em>, but they deliberately forget all those verses that are full of prejudice, hatred  and discrimination against women.<br />
Here are some of the ‘celebrated’ derogatory comments about women in the Manusmriti :<br />
1. “Swabhav ev narinam …..” – 2/213. It is the nature of women to seduce men in this world; for that reason the wise are never unguarded in the company of females.<br />
2. “Avidvam samlam………..” – 2/214. Women, true to their class character, are capable of leading astray men in this world, not only a fool but even a learned and wise man. Both become slaves of desire.<br />
3. “Matra swastra ………..” – 2/215. Wise people should avoid sitting alone with one’s mother, daughter or sister. Since carnal desire is always strong, it can lead to temptation.<br />
4. “Naudwahay……………..” – 3/8. One should not marry women who has have reddish hair, redundant  parts of the body [such as six fingers], one who is often sick, one without hair or having excessive hair and one who has red eyes.<br />
5. “Nraksh vraksh ………..” – 3/9. One should not marry women whose names are similar to constellations,  trees, rivers, those from a low caste, mountains, birds, snakes, slaves or those whose names inspires terror.<br />
6. “Yasto na bhavet ….. …..” – 3/10. Wise men should not marry women who do not have a brother and whose parents are not socially well known.<br />
7. “Uchayangh…………….” – 3/11. Wise men should marry only women who are free from bodily defects, with beautiful names, grace/gait like an elephant, moderate hair on the head and body, soft limbs and small teeth.<br />
8. “Shudr-aiv bharya………” – 3/12.Brahman men can marry Brahman, Kshatriya, Vaish and even Shudra women but Shudra men can marry only Shudra women.<br />
9. “Na Brahman kshatriya..” – 3/14. Although Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish men have been allowed inter-caste marriages, even in distress they should not marry Shudra women.<br />
10. “Heenjati striyam……..” – 3/15. When twice born [dwij=Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish] men in their folly marry low caste Shudra women, they are responsible for the degradation of their whole family. Accordingly, their children adopt all the demerits of the Shudra caste.<br />
11. “Shudram shaynam……” – 3/17. A Brahman who marries a Shudra woman, degrades himself and his whole family  ,becomes morally degenerated , loses Brahman status and his children too attain status  of shudra.<br />
12. “Daiv pitrya………………” – 3/18. The offerings made by such a person at the time of established rituals are neither accepted by God nor by the departed soul; guests also refuse to have meals with him and he is bound to go to hell after death.<br />
13. “Chandalash ……………” – 3/240. Food offered and served to Brahman after Shradh ritual should not be seen by a chandal, a pig, a cock,a dog, and a menstruating women.<br />
14. “Na ashniyat…………….” – 4/43. A Brahman, true defender of his class, should not have his meals in the company of his wife  and even avoid looking at her. Furthermore, he should not look towards her when she is having her meals or when she sneezes/yawns.<br />
15. “Na ajyanti……………….” – 4/44. A Brahman in order to preserve his energy and intellect, must not look at women who applies collyrium to her eyes, one who is massaging her nude body or one who is delivering a child.<br />
16. “Mrshyanti…………….” – 4/217. One should not accept meals from a woman who has extra marital relations; nor from a family exclusively dominated/managed by women or a family whose 10 days of impurity because of death have not passed.<br />
17. “Balya va………………….” – 5/150. A female child, young woman or old woman is not supposed to work independently even at her place of residence.<br />
18. “Balye pitorvashay…….” – 5/151. Girls are supposed to be in the custody of their father when they are children, women must be under the custody of their husband when married and under the custody of her son as widows. In no circumstances is she allowed to assert herself independently.<br />
19. “Asheela  kamvrto………” – 5/157. Men may be lacking virtue, be sexual perverts, immoral and devoid of any good qualities, and yet women must constantly worship and serve their husbands.<br />
20. “Na ast strinam………..” – 5/158. Women have no divine right to perform any religious ritual, nor make vows or observe a fast. Her only duty is to obey and please her husband and she will for that reason alone be exalted in heaven.<br />
21. “Kamam to………………” – 5/160. At her pleasure [after the death of her husband], let her emaciate her body by living only on pure flowers, roots of vegetables and fruits. She must not even mention the name of any other men after her husband has died.<br />
22. “Vyabhacharay…………” – 5/167. Any women violating duty and code of conduct towards her husband, is disgraced and becomes a patient of leprosy. After death, she enters womb of Jackal.<br />
23. “Kanyam bhajanti……..” – 8/364. In case women enjoy sex with a man from a higher caste, the act is not punishable. But on the contrary, if women enjoy sex with lower caste men, she is to be punished and kept in isolation.<br />
24. “Utmam sevmansto…….” – 8/365. In case a man from a lower caste enjoys sex with a woman from a higher caste, the person in question is to be awarded the death sentence. And if a person satisfies his carnal desire with women of his own caste, he should be asked to pay compensation to the women’s faith.<br />
25. “Ya to kanya…………….” – 8/369. In case a woman tears the membrane [hymen] of her Vagina, she shall instantly have her head shaved or two fingers cut off and made to ride on Donkey.<br />
26. “Bhartaram…………….” – 8/370. In case a women, proud of the greatness of her excellence or her relatives, violates her duty towards her husband, the King shall arrange to have her thrown before dogs at a public place.<br />
27. “Pita rakhshati……….” – 9/3. Since women are not capable of living independently, she is to be kept under the custody of her father as child, under her husband as a woman and under her son as widow.<br />
28. “Imam hi sarw………..” – 9/6. It is the duty of all husbands to exert total control over their wives. Even physically weak husbands must strive to control their wives.<br />
29. “Pati bharyam ……….” – 9/8. The husband, after the conception of his wife, becomes the embryo and is born again of her. This explains why women are called Jaya.<br />
30. “Panam durjan………” – 9/13. Consuming liquor, association with wicked persons, separation from her husband, rambling around, sleeping for unreasonable hours and dwelling -are six demerits of women.<br />
31. “Naita rupam……………” – 9/14. Such women are not loyal and have extra marital relations with men without consideration for their age.<br />
32. “Poonshchalya…………” – 9/15. Because of their passion for men, immutable temper and natural heartlessness, they are not loyal to their husbands.<br />
33. “Na asti strinam………” – 9/18. While performing namkarm and jatkarm, Vedic mantras are not to be recited by women, because women are lacking in strength and knowledge of Vedic texts. Women are impure and represent falsehood.<br />
34. “Devra…sapinda………” – 9/58. On failure to produce offspring with her husband, she may obtain offspring by cohabitation with her brother-in-law [devar] or with some other relative [sapinda] on her in-law’s side.<br />
35. “Vidwayam…………….” – 9/60. He who is appointed to cohabit with a widow shall approach her at night, be anointed  with clarified butter and silently beget one son, but by no means a second one.<br />
36. “Yatha vidy……………..” – 9/70. In accordance with established law, the sister-in-law [bhabhi] must be clad in white garments; with pure intent her brother-in-law [devar] will cohabitate with her until she conceives.<br />
37. “Ati kramay……………” – 9/77. Any women who disobey orders of her lethargic, alcoholic and diseased husband shall be deserted for three months and be deprived of her ornaments.<br />
38. “Vandyashtamay…….” – 9/80. A barren wife may be superseded in the 8<sup>th</sup> year; she whose children die may be superseded in the 10<sup>th</sup> year and she who bears only daughters may be superseded in the 11<sup>th</sup> year;  but she who is quarrelsome may be superseded without delay.<br />
39. “Trinsha……………….” – 9/93. In case of any problem in performing religious rites, males between the age of 24 and 30 should marry a female between the age of 8 and 12.<br />
40. “Yambrahmansto…….” – 9/177. In case a Brahman man marries Shudra woman, their son will be called ‘Parshav’ or ‘Shudra’ because his social existence is like a dead body.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dowry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honor killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad Newspapers in India carry reports of rape and burning of women for not bringing sufficient dowry or their inability to satisfy the demands of greedy in-laws. The Indian National Crime Records Bureau (NCRB) reports that there were about 8172 dowry death cases registered in India in 2008 [1]. Dowry (known as Dahejin Hindi) &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color: #56595e;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<h6 style="color: #56595e;"></h6>
<p id="ViJCGjO"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="294" height="294" class="size-full wp-image-7897  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1.png 294w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f26988b768a1-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Newspapers in India carry reports of rape and burning of women for not bringing sufficient dowry or their inability to satisfy the demands of greedy in-laws. The Indian National Crime Records Bureau (NCRB) reports that there were about 8172 dowry death cases registered in India in 2008 <sup id="cite_ref-3" class="reference">[1]</sup>. Dowry (known as <em style="color: #999999;">Dahej</em>in Hindi) has been traditionally practiced in the Hindu society since centuries. Dowry is given by the parents of the girl and it consists of various household things like dresses, ornaments, electrical goods, bedroom furniture, etc. at the time of the marriage. Additionally, rich people also give cash, car, property or land as part of dowry. But for middle class people, and those who are not so well off, the custom of dowry has become an evil. Ordinary people with average wages spend all their savings in preparation of a dowry for their daughter to take with her after her marriage. The Indian government has banned giving and accepting dowry in Hindu marriage. This article will give historic background to the age old tradition of dowry in Hindu marriage.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><span id="more-839"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #56595e;">Dowry in Hindu Scriptures</h2>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><em style="color: #999999;">Vedas </em>are considered as the oldest Hindu texts. Several passages in the Vedas make mention of dowry in Hindu marriages.<em style="color: #999999;">Rigveda </em>Mandal 1, Suktas 125 and 126 talk of the dowry King Swanaya paid to Kakshivat on the marriage of his daughter with him. Rigveda 1/126/2-3 mentions,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">शतं राज्ञो नाधमानस्य निष्काञ्छतमश्वान परयतान सद्य आदम |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">शतं कक्षीवानसुरस्य गोनां दिवि शरवो.अजरमा ततान ||</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">उप मा शयावाः सवनयेन दत्ता वधूमन्तो दश रथासोस्थुः |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">षष्टिः सहस्रमनु गव्यमागात सनत कक्षीवानभिपित्वे अह्नाम ||</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;From which generous prince, soliciting (my acceptance), I, Kakshivat, unhesitatingly accepted a hundred nishkas, a hundred vigorous steeds, and a hundred bulls, whereby he has spread his imperishable fame through heaven. Ten chariots drawn by bay steeds, and carrying my wives, stood near me, given me by Swanaya ; and a thousand and sixty cows followed : these, after a short interval of time, did Kashivat deliver (to his father).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The legend which is cited by the commentator of the four Vedas, Acharya Sayana, relates that Kakshivat, having finished his course of study, and taken leave of his preceptor, was journeying homewards, when night came on, and he fell asleep by the roadside: early in the morning, Raja Swanaya, the son of Bhavayavya, attended by his retinue, came to the spot, and disturbed the Brahmin&#8217;s slumbers: upon his starting up, the Raja addressed him with great cordiality, and being struck by his personal appearance, determined, if he was of suitable rank and birth, to give him his daughters in marriage. After ascertaining his fitness, he took Kakshivat home with him, and there married him to his ten daughters, presenting him at the same time with a hundred &#8216;nishkas&#8217; of gold, a hundred horses, a hundred bulls, one thousand and sixty cows, and eleven chariots, one for each of his wives and one for himself, each drawn by four horses. With these presents Kakshivat returned home, and placed them at the disposal of his father, Dirghatamas.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This evidence is corroborated by Rishi Shaunaka&#8217;s <em style="color: #999999;">Brhaddevata </em>which also repeats these mantras explaining their purport.<em style="color: #999999;">Brhaddevata </em>3/146-150 says,</p>
<p id="NrxFUFR"><img decoding="async" width="398" height="325" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7644 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7.png 398w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2576b9186a7-300x245.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px" /></p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8216;I am a son of the seer Dirghatamas, son of Ucathya, O king.&#8217; Thereupon he (Swanaya) gave him ten maidens decked with ornaments. and the same number of chariots, strong-bodied bay steeds going in teams of four, for the purpose of conveying the maidens, money and (utensils of) inferior metal, goats and sheep. Further he gave (him) a hundred necklets and a hundred bulls. This is told in the next hymn with (the stanza) &#8216;A hundred&#8217; and so forth. A hundred horses, a hundred necklets, ten chariots with maidens, (steeds) going in teams of four, and a thousand and sixty cows.Kakshivat, who obtained (all this) from Swanaya Bhavayavya, both praised (him) after receiving (it) and recited (the hymn) &#8216;At morn&#8217; to his father.</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This reference besides proving the existence of Polygamy in Vedic society, also shows the prevalence of dowry in that society.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><em style="color: #999999;">Rigveda </em>Mandal 10, Sukta 85 as well as <em style="color: #999999;">Atharvaved </em>Kaand 14, Suktas 1 and 2, contain details about the Hindu marriage ceremony. Verses from these hymns are chanted during Hindu wedding ceremonies. Rigveda 10/85/13 and Atharvaved 14/1/13 talking of the wedding season says,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">सूर्याया वहतुः प्रागात्सविता यमवासृजत् |</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">अघासुहन्यन्ते गावो.अर्जुन्योः पर्युह्यते ||</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;Surya&#8217;s bridal procession which Savita despatched has advanced;<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> the oxen are whipped along</span></strong> in the Magha (constellations); she is borne (to her husband&#8217;s house) in the Arjuni (constellations).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The purport of this mantra is that the Dowry (in this case the oxen) must reach the husband&#8217;s home before the bride is escorted there.The next two mantras describe that two men from the bride&#8217;s family must take this Dowry to the husband&#8217;s home well before the wedding ceremony. For more details about the process of giving Dowry refer to the commentary of Arya Samaj scholar <strong><span class="st">Sripad </span>Damodar Satvalekar</strong> on these mantras<strong><em style="color: #999999;"> (Atharvaveda ka Subodh Bhashya </em></strong>Kaand 14).</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This system of Dowry has continued since Vedic times till today. Other Hindu texts contain detailed accounts of dowry. For example, Mahabharata Adi Parv Section 197/ Shlokas 15-18 provide details of the dowry presented by King Drupada on the marriage of his daughter <b>Kṛṣṇā Draupadi </b><span class="Unicode" title="International Alphabet of Sanskrit Transliteration">with the five Pandavas (Polyandry).<br />
</span></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">15 कृते विवाहे दरुपदॊ धनं ददौ; महारथेभ्यॊ बहुरूपम उत्तमम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     शतं रथानां वरहेमभूषिणां; चतुर्युजां हेमखलीन मालिनाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">16 शतं गजानाम अभिपद्मिनीं तथा; शतं गिरीणाम इव हेमशृङ्गिणाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     तथैव दासी शतम अग्र्ययौवनं; महार्हवेषाभरणाम्बर सरजम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">17 पृथक पृथक चैव दशायुतान्वितं; धनं ददौ सौमकिर अग्निसाक्षिकम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     तथैव वस्त्राणि च भूषणानि; परभावयुक्तानि महाधनानि</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">18 कृते विवाहे च ततः सम पाण्डवाः; परभूतरत्नाम उपलभ्य तां शरियम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     विजह्रुर इन्द्र परतिमा महाबलाः; पुरे तु पाञ्चाल नृपस्य तस्य ह</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>&#8220;After the weddings were over, king Drupada gave unto those mighty car-warriors diverse kinds of excellent wealth. And the king gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">one hundred cars with golden standards, each drawn by four steeds with golden bridles</span></strong>. And he gave them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">one hundred elephants all possessing auspicious marks on their temples and faces and like unto a hundred mountains with golden peaks</span></strong>. He also gave them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">a hundred female servants all in the prime of youth and clad in costly robes and ornaments and floral wreaths</span></strong>. And the illustrious monarch of the Lunar race gave unto each of those princes of celestial beauty, making the sacred fire a witness of his gifts, <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">much wealth and many costly robes and ornaments of great splendour</span></strong>. The sons of Pandu endued with great strength, after their wedding were over, and after they had obtained Krishna like unto a second Sri along with great wealth, passed their days in joy and happiness, like so many Indras, in the capital of the king of the Panchalas.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The Mahabharata also informs us of dowry given during the marriage of Abhimanyu, son of Arjuna with Uttara, daughter of King Viraat. Mahabharata Virat Parv, section 72, shlokas 36-37 say</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">36 तस्मै सप्त सहस्राणि हयानां वातरंहसाम</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     दवे च नागशते मुख्ये परादाद बहुधनं तदा</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">37 हुत्वा सम्यक् समिद्धाग्निमर्चयित्वा द्विजन्मः</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">     राज्यं बलं कोशं च सर्वमात्मानमेव च</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>And Virata then gave him <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">(as dowry) seven thousand steeds endued with the speed of the wind and two hundred elephants of the best kind and much wealth also</span></strong>. And having duly poured libations of clarified butter on the blazing fire, and paid homage unto the twice-born ones, <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Virata offered to the Pandavas his kingdom, army, treasury, and his own self</span></strong>.</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Mahabharata Adi Parv section 220 details the dowry provided by Krishna and Balrama on the marriage of their sister Subhadra.</p>
<table style="color: #56595e;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>तेषां ददौ हृषीकेशो जन्यार्थे धनमुत्तमम्।<br />
हरणं वै सुभद्राया ज्ञातिदेयं महायशाः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>रथानां काञ्चनाङ्गानां किङ्किणीजालमालिनाम्।<br />
चतुर्युजामुपेतानां सूतैः कुशलशिक्षितैः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>सहस्रं प्रददौ कृष्मो गवामयुतमेव च।<br />
श्रीमान्माथुरदेश्यानां दोग्ध्रीणां पुण्यवर्चसाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>बडवानां च शुद्धानां चन्द्रांशुसमवर्चसाम्।<br />
ददौ जनार्दनः प्रीत्या सहस्रं हेमभूषितम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>तथैवाश्वतरीणां च दान्तानां वातरंहसाम्।<br />
शतान्यञ्जनकेशीनां श्वेतानां पञ्चपञ्च च।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>स्नानपानोत्सवे चैव प्रयुक्तं वयसान्वितम्।<br />
स्त्रीणां सहस्रं गौरीणां सुवेषाणां सुवर्चसाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>सुवर्णशतकण्ठीनामरोमाणां स्वलङ्कृताम्।<br />
परिचर्यासु दक्षाणां प्रददौ पुष्करेक्षणः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>पृष्ठ्यानामपि चाश्वानां बाह्लिकानां जनार्दनः।<br />
ददौ शतसहस्राख्यं कन्याधनमनुत्तमम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>कृताकृतस्य मुख्यस्य कनकस्याग्निवर्चसः।<br />
मनुष्यभारान्दाशार्हो ददौ दश जनार्दनः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>गजानां तु प्रभिन्नानां त्रिधा प्रस्रवतां मदम्।<br />
गिरिकूटनिकाशानां समरेष्वनिवर्तिनाम्।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>क्लृप्तानां पटुघण्टानां चारूणां हेममालिनाम्।<br />
हस्त्यारोहैरुपेतानां सहस्रं साहसप्रियः।।</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>रामः पाणिग्रहणिकं ददौ पार्थाय लाङ्गली।<br />
प्रीयमाणो हलधरः संबन्धं प्रति मानयन्।।</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>Then Hrishikesa of great renown gave unto the party of the bridegroom much wealth. And unto Subhadra he gave the nuptial presents <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">that had been given to her by her relatives. Krishna gave unto the Pandavas a thousand cars of gold furnished with rows of bells, and unto each of which were put four steeds driven by well-trained charioteers</span></strong>. He also gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ten thousand cows</span></strong> belonging to the country of Mathura, and yielding much milk and all of excellent colour. Well-pleased, Janardana also gave them a <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">thousand mares with gold harnesses and of colour white as the beams of the moon. He also gave them a thousand mules, all well-trained and possessing the speed of the wind, of white colour with black manes. And he of eyes like lotus-petals also gave unto them a thousand damsels well-skilled in assisting at bathing and at drinking, young in years and virgins all before their <i>first-season</i>, well-attired and of excellent complexion, each wearing a hundred pieces of gold around her neck, of skins perfectly polished, decked</span></strong> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">with every ornament, and well-skilled in every kind of personal service</span></strong>. Janardana also gave unto them <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">hundreds of thousands of draft horses</span></strong> from the country of the Valhikas <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">as Subhadra&#8217;s excellent dower</span></strong>. That foremost one of Dasarha&#8217;s race also gave unto Subhadra as her peculium<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ten carrier-loads of first class gold</span></strong> possessing the splendour of fire, some purified and some in a state of ore. And Rama having the plough for his weapon and always loving bravery gave unto Arjuna, as a nuptial present, a<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">thousand elephants</span></strong> with secretions flowing in three streams from the three parts of their bodies (the temple, the ears, and the anus) each large as a mountain summit, irresistible in battle, decked with coverlets and bells, well-adorned with other golden ornaments, and equipped with excellent thrones on their backs.<br />
[Mahabharata Adiparv 220 Haranaharana parv, sholkas 44-55, printed by Gita Press Gorakhpur]</blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">It also reveals that slaves, especially women, were given as a part of the dowry to the bridegroom. In simple language, it meant commercialisation of women. Now let us turn to Ramayana and the dowry given by King Janaka on the marriage of Sita and Rama. Valmiki Ramayana mentions,</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">अथ राजा विदेहानां ददौ कन्याधनं बहु ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">गवां शतसहस्राणि बहूनि मिथिलेश्वर:।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">कम्बलानां च मुख्यानां क्षौमकोट्यंबराणि च ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">हस्त्यश्वरथपादातं दिव्यरूपं स्वलङ्कृतम् ।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ददौ कन्यापिता तासां दासीदासमनुत्तमम्  ।।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">हिरण्यस्य सुवर्णस्य मुक्तानां विद्रुमस्य च।</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ददौ परमसंहृष्ट: कन्याधनमनुत्तमम् ।।</p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>Then that king Janaka of Mithila, the one from Videha lineage, gave innumerable patrimonial riches. He has also given umpteen number of cows, millions of excellent shawls and silk dresses, and elephants, horses, chariots, foot soldiers, besides hundreds of highly decorated girls, divine in their mien, as unexcelled chambermaids and handmaidens to the brides. Immensely pleased, king Janaka gave excellent ornaments made of fine gold, pearls and corals.<br />
[Valmiki Ramayana Sarg 74; Shlokas 3-6]</blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">All these passages show the extravagant spending in Hindu marriages and sadly these are the ideals people look upto. How can things improve when such people and events are made role models by the common folk?</p>
<h2 style="color: #56595e;">Dowry in the writings of Hindu scholars</h2>
<p style="color: #56595e;">You will be surprised to know that even the so-called &#8216;reformist&#8217; Hindu scholars consider Dowry as an <strong>&#8216;integral part&#8217;</strong> of the Hindu marriage. The leading figure amongst them is Swami Dayanand Saraswati, the founder of the protestant cult of Arya Samaj. In his book <strong><em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Vidhi</em></strong> he mentions the practice of dowry as being an integral part of the Hindu marriage. Ramgopal Vidyalankar of Gurukul Kangri has written a commentary on <em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Vidhi</em> known as <strong><em style="color: #999999;">Sanskar Prakash</em></strong>. The following excerpt in Hindi is from Sanskar Prakash, 1984 Edition, Page 128</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">ऒ गौर्गोर्गोः प्रतिगृह्यताम &#8211; यह गाय है, लीजिये, गाय लीजिये</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">इस वाक्य से वर की विनती कर के अपनी शक्ति के योग्य वर को गोदानादी द्रव्य, जो वर को योग्य हों, अर्पण करे और वर &#8216;ओं प्रतिगृह्यतामि'(<strong><span style="color: #ff0000;">लाओ लेता हूं</span></strong>) इस वाक्य से उस को ग्रहण करे.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;"><strong>Translation:<br />
</strong></p>
<blockquote style="color: #56595e;"><p>ऒ गौर्गोर्गोः प्रतिगृह्यताम -This is a cow. Accept, please accept this cow.<br />
With this sentence we request the groom to accept the cow and other materials in dowry, which are suitable for the groom and the groom accepts it by repeating the phrase &#8216;ओं प्रतिगृह्यतामि&#8217; (Give; I am accepting)</p></blockquote>
<p style="color: #56595e;">These words clearly establish that Dowry is an integral part of Hindu marriage and the dowry must be suitable for the groom depending on his social status.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Pandit Bhimsen Sharma, the pupil of Swami Dayanand Saraswati, has even alloted a share of the dowry to the mother-in-law of the bride in his book Shodash Sanskar Vidhi.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">After knowing all this information, we should realize where the source of dowry lies? To eradicate dowry Hindus need to discard these scriptures which are used to justify the evil of dowry and which inspire people to shamelessly demand dowry citing the example set by their scriptural &#8216;role-models&#8217;.</p>
<hr style="color: #56595e;" />
<p style="color: #56595e;"><span style="color: #696969;"><strong>Footnotes:<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">[1] <span style="color: black;">Figures at a Glance 2008. </span><i style="color: black;">National Crime Records Bureau</i><span style="color: black;">, Ministry of Home Affairs, Government of India, accessed on 16 Jun 2012. &lt;</span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130507071639/http://ncrb.nic.in/CII2008/cii-2008/figure%20at%20a%20glance.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://ncrb.nic.in/CII2008/cii-2008/figure%20at%20a%20glance.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="color: black;">&gt;.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
