<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>interpolation in hinduism vedas &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/interpolation-in-hinduism-vedas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 11:22:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption in Vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand saraswati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolation in hinduism vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskcon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda vs puranas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am reproducing some excerpts written by a Hindu scholar named Swami B.V. Giri. Who has proved Puranas and Itihas as part of the Vedas which is contrary to what Arya Samajis are promoting on the internet. He considers Puranas and Itihas to be the fifth Vedas, he has put forth this arguement on the &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am reproducing some excerpts written by a Hindu scholar named Swami B.V. Giri. Who has proved Puranas and Itihas as part of the Vedas which is contrary to what Arya Samajis are promoting on the internet. He considers Puranas and Itihas to be the fifth Vedas, he has put forth this arguement on the basis of Vedas and other scriptures. According to Swami Giri Vedas are corrupted and 94% of the Vedas are lost, the present Vedas contain only 6% of the original text and there is no use of Vedas in this age thus Puranas are much superior than Vedas.<br />
<span id="more-1960"></span><br />
Written by Swami B.V. Giri</p>
<p><strong>OBJECTION: In your arguments you have mostly quoted <em>purana-vakya</em> (quotes from Puranic texts) to substantiate your points. However, this is unacceptable. The <em>Vedas</em> are eternal as they emanate from the Lord Himself (<em>apaurusaya</em>), whereas the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>smrti-sastras</em>, although they give knowledge about God, are authored by men. They are auxiliary to the <em>Vedas</em> and hence their statements should be considered as secondary when compared to the statements made in the <em>Vedas</em>. Therefore, in order to validate your claims, you must give quotes from <em>sruti</em> only.</strong></p>
<p><strong>REFUTATION:</strong> That the <em>Vedas</em> are eternal and <em>apauruseya</em> is a fact that all <em>sampradayas</em>, including the school of Sankara, unanimously agree with. They constitute the means of receiving knowledge about the Absolute Truth. However, there are certain factors that make it practically impossible to study the <em>Vedas</em> in this age:</p>
<p id="pWEIpKn"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="288" height="239" class="size-full wp-image-7205  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23fe9dbeb17.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>  After Srila Vyasadeva divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four books (<em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em>), his disciples further divided them into 1,130 divisions. This is stated in the <em>Kurma Purana</em> (52.19-20):</p>
<p class="verse"><em>eka-vimsati-bhedena rg-vedam krtavan pura<br />
sakhanam satenaiva yajur-vedam athakarot</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sama-vedam sahasrena sakhanam prabibheda sah<br />
atharvanam atho vedam bibedha navakena tu</em></p>
<p class="translation">‘Previously the <em>Rg Veda</em> was divided into 21 sections, the <em>Yajur Veda</em> into 100 sections, the <em>Sama Veda</em> into 1,000 sections and the <em>Atharva Veda</em> into 9 divisions.’</p>
<p>Each division has 4 minor divisions, namely the <em>Samhitas, Brahmanas, Aranyakas</em> and <em>Upanisads.</em> Thus altogether the 4 <em>Vedas</em> contain 1,130 <em>Samhitas,</em> 1,130 <em>Brahmanas,</em> 1,130 <em>Aranyakas,</em> and 1,130 <em>Upanisads.</em> This makes a total of 4,520 divisions.<br />
At present, most of these texts have disappeared due to the influence of time. We can only find 11 <em>Samhitas</em>, 18 <em>Brahmanas</em>, 7 <em>Aranyakas</em> and 220 <em>Upanisads</em> which constitutes a mere 6% of the entire Vedic canon!</p>
<ol>
<li>Even if the <em>Vedas</em> were complete in there entirety, in order to understand them one must first study the <em>Vedangas</em> which includes <em>Siksa</em> (the science of phonetics), <em>Vyakarana</em> (grammatical rules), <em>Kalpa</em> (ritualistic rules), <em>Nirukta</em> (obscure word meanings), <em>Chanda</em> (Metres for chanting Vedic hymns), and <em>Jyotisa</em> (astrology and astronomy).</li>
<li>Since the language of the <em>Vedas</em> is enshrouded in mysterious meanings, one must also be willing to sacrifice years of study in order to learn <em>Vaidika</em> (classical) Sanskrit. This entails primarily learning the basic grammar (which generally takes 12 years or so) and then memorising extra vocabulary in order to decipher the mystical language of the <em>Vedas</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">1</span></li>
</ol>
<p>Apart from that, it is practically impossible for those born in the age of Kali (who are generally ‘<em>mandah sumanda-matayo</em>’) to memorise even the slightest thing. What to speak of the entire <em>Vedas</em> or even the 6% that still survives today! At present, amongst the <em>brahmana</em> communities in India, it is generally observed that <em>vedadhyayana</em> simply consists of memorising the text of one of the four <em>Vedas</em> ‘parrot-fashion’, but as we can see from above, there is much more to it than that. Therefore, we may conclude that although the <em>Vedas</em> are perfect <em>sabda-pramana</em>, it is impractical to become thoroughly conversant with the <em>Vedas</em> in this day and age in order to understand the Supreme. Hence the solution lies in the <em>Puranas</em> and the <em>Itihasas.</em> This is explained in the following verse &#8211;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em> bharata-vyapadesena hyamnayarthah pradarsitah<br />
vedah pratisthah sarve sarve purane natra samsayah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;On the pretext of writing the <em>Mahabharata</em>, Vyasa explained the meaning of the <em>Vedas</em>. Certainly all the topics of the <em>Vedas</em> have been established in the <em>Puranas.</em>&#8221; (<em>Visnu Purana</em>)</p>
<p>Furthermore, it is explained in the <em>Mahabharata</em> (<em>Adi Parva</em> 1.267) and <em>Manu Samhita</em> –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>itihasa puranabhyam vedam samupabrmhayet</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; One must complement one’s study of the <em>Vedas</em> with the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>In the <em>Prabhasa-khanda</em> of the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (5.3.121-124) it is said –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>veda-van niscalam manye puranartham dvijottamah<br />
vedah pratisthitah sarve purane natra samsayah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>bibhety-alpa-srutad vedo mam ayam calayisyati<br />
itihasa-puranais tu niscalo’yam krtah purah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yan na drstam hi vedesu tad drstam smrtisu dvijah<br />
ubhayor yan na drstam hi tat puranah pragiyate<br />
yo veda caturo vedan sangopanisado dvijah<br />
puranam naiva janati na ca sa syad vicaksana</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; O best of the <em>brahmanas</em>, the meaning of the <em>Puranas</em> is unchanging just like that of the <em>Vedas</em>. The <em>Vedas</em> are all sheltered within the <em>Puranas</em> without a doubt. The <em>Veda</em> has a fear that unqualified people will read her and then distort her meaning. Thus, the significance of the <em>Veda</em> was fixed in the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas.</em> That which is not found in the <em>Vedas</em> is found in the <em>Smrti</em>. That which is not found in the <em>Smrti</em> is to be found in the <em>Puranas</em>. Those who know even the <em>Vedas</em> and <em>Upanisads</em> are not learned if they do not know the <em>Puranas</em>.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="AUanNYs"><img decoding="async" width="262" height="155" class="size-full wp-image-7206  alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23febf07008.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> The reason they are called ‘<em>Puranas</em>’ is because they make the <em>Vedas</em> complete (<em>puranat puranam iti canyatra</em>). This is not to suggest that the <em>Vedas</em> are incomplete. It simply means that the <em>Puranas</em> are explanatory supplements which aid one to understand the concise and ambiguous passages in the <em>Vedas.</em> If the <em>Puranas</em> complete the <em>Vedas</em>, it is only logical that they must be Vedic in nature.<br />
Our Tattvavadi friends have stated that <em>Puranic</em> evidence is secondary to those statements of the <em>sruti</em> because they are composed by mortals. Generally it is correct to state that the <em>sruti</em> is primary and the <em>smrti</em> secondary in that it (<em>sruti</em>) seeks to elaborate on the meaning of the <em>smrti.</em> However, under the circumstances, the <em>puranas</em> and <em>itihasas</em> are now to be considered primary evidence. As regards the mortal composition of the <em>puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em>, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">2</span> we beg to differ with this view, on the basis of the following references in the <em>sruti-sastras</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>rcah samani chandamsi puranam yajusa saha<br />
ucchistaj-jajnire sarve divi deva divi-sritah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Rg, Sama, Yajur</em> and <em>Atharva</em> became manifest from the Lord, along with the <em>Puranas</em> and all the Devas residing in the heavens.&#8221; (<em>Atharva Veda</em> 11.7.24)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sa brhatim disam anu vyacalat tam itihasas ca puranam ca gathas ca itihasasya ca sa vai puranasya ca gathanam ca narasamsinam ca priyam dhama bhavati ya evam veda</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;He approached the <em>brhati</em> meter, and thus the <em>Itihasas, Puranas, Gathas</em> and <em>Narasamsis</em> became favorable to him. One who knows this verily becomes the beloved abode of the <em>Itihasas, Puranas, Gathas</em> and <em>Narasamsis</em>.&#8221; (<em>Atharva Veda</em> 15.6.10–12)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>evam ime sarva veda nirmitah sa-kalpah sa-rahasyah sa-brahmanah sopanisatkah setihasah sanvakhyatah sa-puranan</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;In this way, all the <em>Vedas</em> were manifested along with <em>the Kalpas, Rahasyas, Brahmanas, Upanisads, Itihasas, Anvakhyatas</em> and the <em>Puranas.&#8221;</em> (<em>Gopatha Brahmana, purva</em> 2.10)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>nama va rg-vedo yajur-vedah sama-veda atharvanas caturtha itihasa-puranah pancamo vedanam vedah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Indeed, <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em> are the names of the four <em>Vedas.</em> The <em>Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> are the fifth <em>Veda.&#8221; (Kauthumiya Chandogya Upanisad 7.1.4)</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>asya mahato bhutasya nihsvasitam etad yad rg-vedo yajur-vedah sama<br />
vedo’tharvangirasa itihasah puranam ityadina</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O Maitreya, the <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva Vedas</em> as well as the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> all manifest from the breathing of the Lord.&#8221; <em>(Madhyandina-sruti, Brhad-aranyaka Upanisad</em> 2.4.10)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From these above <em>sruti</em> statements it is clear that the <em>puranas</em> are part of the <em>Vedas</em> and originate from the same source as the <em>Vedas</em>, namely the Supreme Lord Himself. One may argue that since the <em>Puranas</em> have names such as <em>Skanda, Agni, Markandeya</em> etc. they must have been composed by those personalities, therefore they are not eternal and thus cannot be apauruseya. However, if that is the case, then certain sections of the <em>Vedas</em> must also be considered to be <em>pauruseya-vakya</em> since they have names like <em>Katha</em> <em>Upanisad, Aitareya Upanisad</em> (Katha and Aitareya being names of sages). It is understood that certain parts of the <em>Vedas</em> are named after certain <em>rsis,</em> not because they composed them, but because they were the main exponents of those portions. Since persons with the names <em>Katha</em> and <em>Aitareya</em> appear in every millenium, one should not misunderstand that before the appearance of those persons described in the <em>Vedas</em>, these names were simply meaningless words.</p>
<p id="nPGgFwG"><img decoding="async" width="252" height="171" class="size-full wp-image-7207  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23fed3311f7.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> Similarly many of the <em>Puranas</em> are named after the first person who expounded them. Many times however, due to the influence of time, a scripture may become forgotten on this planet and thus a deva or sage speaks it again, and it becomes known by that name. Such an example is found in the <em>Bhagavatam</em> wherein the sun-god imparts the <em>Vajasaneyi-samhita</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> to Yajnavalkya Muni –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>atha ha bhagavams tava carana-nalina-yugalam tri-bhuvana-gurubhir<br />
abhivanditam aham ayata-yama-yajus-kama upasaramiti.</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>evam stutam sa bhagavan vaji-rupa-dharo ravih<br />
yajumsy ayata-yamani munaye ’dat prasaditah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Therefore, O lord, with prayers I approach your two lotus feet, which are adored by the preceptors of the three worlds, because I wish to receive from you <em>mantras</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> that are unknown to anyone else.&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Being pleased by such exaltation, the sun-god took the form of a horse and presented to the <em>muni</em> <em>mantras</em> of the <em>Yajur Veda</em> which were previously unknown to any mortal.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 12.6.72-73)</p>
<p>In his treatise Visnu Tattva Vinirnaya, Sri Madhva, quoting Brahmanda Purana explains thus:</p>
<p class="verse"><em>puranani tadarthani sarge sarge’nythaiva tu<br />
kriyante’tastvanityani tadarthah purva-sargavat<br />
vedanam srsthivakyani bhaveyurvyaktyapeksaya<br />
avantarabhimananam devanam va vyapeksaya<br />
nanityatvat kutastesamanityatvam sthiratmanam</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, the <em>Puranas</em> are supposed to explain the meaning of the <em>Vedas</em> and are only different by the changes in words, chanda (metre), rsi, sequence etc. at the beginning of each creation. In this way they are considered to be non-eternal, but their meaning will be the same as in the previous creation.<br />
Therefore Madhva categorizes the <em>Puranas</em> as <em>‘nitya-anitya’</em> because they originally emanate from the Supreme Lord, but they are sometimes unmanifest.<br />
As a side note, it may be asked that if the <em>Puranas</em> are indeed subsidiary to the <em>sruti-sastras,</em> why does Sri Madhvacarya himself quote them so often in his works? Not only that, he even uses <em>puranic</em> evidence in order to establish the <em>nityatva</em> of the <em>Vedas!</em> If the <em>Puranas</em> are not eternal and <em>apauruseya,</em> why would he use their ‘secondary statements’ as a <em>pramana</em> to validify something which is superior?<br />
Another point is that in the chanting of the <em>Brahma-yajna</em> (formal study of the <em>Vedas</em>), the <em>Puranas</em> are included. If they were not <em>Vedic</em> in nature they would not be included. Therefore the <em>Taittiriya Aranyaka</em> (2.9) states <em>yad brahmananitihasa-puranani</em>: &#8220;The <em>Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> are <em>Vedas.&#8221;</em><br />
It has already been stated above in the quote from <em>Chandogya Upanisad</em> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">3</span> that the <em>Puranas</em> are known as the fifth Veda. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">4</span> The reason behind this is because the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em> are derived originally from the <em>Yajur Veda.</em> This is explained by <em>Sri Suta</em> in the <em>Vayu Purana-</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>itihasa-purananam vaktaram samyag eva hi<br />
mam caiva pratijagraha bhagavan isvarah prabhuh<br />
eka asid yajur-vedas tam caturdha vyakalpayat<br />
catur-hotram abhut tasmins tena yajnam akalpayat<br />
adhvaryavam yajurbhis tu rgbhir hotram tathaiva ca<br />
audgatram samabhis caiva brahmatvam capyatharvabhih<br />
akhyanais capyupakhyanair gathabhir dvija-sattamah<br />
purana-samhitas cakre puranartha-visaradah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yac-chistam tu yajur-veda iti sastrartha-nirnayah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That almighty Lord (Sri Vyasa) chose me as the qualified speaker of the <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em>. In the beginning there was only one <em>Veda</em> – the <em>Yajur Veda</em>. This was divided into four portions. From these stemmed the four performances known as the <em>catur-homa</em> by which he (Vyasa) arranged for the performance of sacrifice. The <em>Adhvaryu</em> priest uses the <em>Yajur mantras,</em> the <em>Hotra</em> priest uses the <em>Rg mantras,</em> the <em>Udgata</em> priest uses the <em>Sama mantras,</em> and the <em>Brahma</em> priest uses the <em>Atharva mantras.</em></p>
<p class="translation">O best of all the <em>brahmanas</em>, after this he (Vyasa) who understands the meaning of the <em>Puranas</em>, compiled them and the <em>Itihasas</em> by combining various <em>akhyanas, upakhyanas</em> and <em>gathas</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">5</span> Whatever remained after Vyasa had divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four divisions was considered to also be the <em>Yajur Veda.</em> Thus is the conclusion of the <em>sastras.&#8221; </em>(<em>Vayu Purana</em> 60.16-18, 21-22)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The statement of Sri Suta Gosvami in the above verse from <em>Vayu Purana</em> in which he says that ‘Whatever remained after Vyasa had divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four divisions was considered to also be the <em>Yajur Veda</em>’ indicates that the essence of the original <em>Purana</em> (which was the remaining part of the <em>Yajur Veda</em>) became the condensed version of the <em>Purana</em> consisting of four-hundred-thousand <em>slokas</em>, available on the earth-planet.<br />
Further evidence for this is found in the <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.8-9)wherein the Lord says –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>kalenagrahanam matva puranasya dvijottamah<br />
vyasa-rupam aham krtva samharami yuge yuge</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O best of the <em>brahmanas</em>, understanding that the <em>Purana</em> would gradually become forgotten, in every <em>yuga</em> I appear in the form of Vyasa and condense it.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the next <em>sloka</em> of that <em>Purana</em>, the Lord continues –</p>
<p class="verse"><em> catur-laksa-pramanena dvapare dvapare sada<br />
tad astadasadha krtva</em> <em>bhur-loke’smin prabhasyate<br />
adyapyamartya-loke tu sata-koti-pravistaram<br />
tad artho’tra catur-laksah sanksepena nivesitah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Purana</em> contains four-hundred-thousand verses which is divided into eighteen parts. These are passed on via oral tradition every Dvapara-yuga on the earth-planet. Even today the original <em>Purana</em> which consists of one-billion verses exists in the heavenly planets. The essential meaning of that <em>Purana</em> is contained in the smaller version of four-hundred-thousand verses.&#8221;</p>
<p>The same point is raised in the <em>Vayaviya Samhita</em> (7.1.1. 37-38) –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sanksipya caturo vedams caturdha vyabhajat prabhuh<br />
vyasta-vedataya khyato veda-vyasa iti smrtah<br />
puranam api sanksiptam· catur-laksa-pramanatah<br />
adyapyamartya-loke tu sata-koti-pravistaram</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sanksiptam ityatra teneti sesah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That Lord who is most intelligent then divided the <em>Vedas</em> into four. He therefore became known as Veda Vyasa. He also summarized the <em>Puranas</em> into four-hundred-thousand verses which are still available in the heavenly domain in the form if one billion verses.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, it should be explained that although the <em>Puranas</em> and <em>Itihasas</em> are known as the fifth <em>Veda —</em> that does not mean that they are literally identical in all ways with the <em>Vedas</em>. If that were so, <em>Purana</em> and <em>Itihasa</em> would just be names of certain sections of the <em>Vedas</em>. The difference between them is in annotation and the order of words. The <em>Vedas</em> are chanted in a particular style involving three tone accents (<em>svaras</em>) called <em>udatta</em>, <em>anudatta</em> and <em>svarita</em>. If a word is chanted in the wrong accent, the whole meaning of the sentence can change.<br />
As regards the order of words, the <em>Vedas</em> maintain a particular sequence which has not changed since the dawn of creation. There is no scope for even the slightest change in the Vedic texts, whereas the texts of the <em>Puranas</em> change according to <em>kalpa-bheda</em>. It is for this reason that we find occasional differencies in certain editions of the <em>Puranas.</em><br />
Another distinction between the <em>Vedas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> is that although the <em>Puranas</em> are considered part of the <em>Brahma-yajna</em>, they are not used in the performance of Vedic sacrifices.<br />
Unfortunately, major problems also arise when trying to studsy the <em>Puranas.</em> Firstly, although the <em>Puranas</em> are much more accessible than the <em>Vedas</em> and more readily available, they too are not available in their entirety. The eighteen <em>Puranas</em> and eighteen <em>Upa-Puranas</em> are a vast body of literature and there are so many different versions that it is difficult to know which editions are complete and which texts have been interpolated. This is due to the fact that there are no current disciplic schools nor bona-fide commentaries for most of these works.<br />
Secondly, we can understand that independent study of the <em>Puranas</em> yields no fruit since each seems to establish a different deity as Supreme. By studying the <em>Puranas</em> without proper guidance, the result is only confusion. <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.65, 68-69) states –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>pancangam ca puranam syad akhyanam itarat smrtam<br />
sattvikesu ca kalpesu mahatmyam adhikam hareh<br />
rajasesu ca mahatmyam adhikam brahmano viduh<br />
tadvad agnes ca mahatmyam tamasesu sivasya ca<br />
sankirnesu sarasvatyah pitrnam ca nigadyate</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; A <em>Purana</em> consists of five elements, as opposed to an <em>Akhyana</em>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">6</span> The <em>sattvika</em> <em>Puranas</em> glorify Hari; the <em>rajasika Puranas</em> glorify Brahma, and the <em>tamasika</em> <em>Puranas</em> glorify Siva and Agni. <em>Puranas</em> dealing with mixed modes of nature glorify Sarasvati and the fore-fathers.&#8221; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">7</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The divisions of the eighteen <em>Puranas</em> is defined by Lord Siva to Uma in the <em>Padma Purana</em> (<em>Uttara Khanda</em> 236.18-21):</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>vaisnavanam naradiyam ca tatha bhagavatam subham<br />
garudam ca tatha padmam varaham subha-darsane</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>sattvikani puranani vijneyani subhani vai<br />
brahmandam brahma-vaivarta markandeyam tathaiva ca<br />
bhavisyam vamanam brahmam rajasani nibodha me<br />
matsyam kaurmam tatha laingam saivam skandam tathaiva ca<br />
agneyam ca sad etani tamasani nibodha me</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8221; O beautiful lady, one should know that the <em>Visnu, Naradiya, Bhagavata, Garuda, Padma</em> and <em>Varaha</em> are all in the mode of goodness. The <em>Brahmanda, Brahma-vaivarta, Markandeya, Bhavisya, Vamana</em> and <em>Brahma</em> are in the mode of passion. The <em>Matsya, Kurma, Linga, Siva, Skanda</em> and <em>Agni</em> are in the mode of ignorance.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sri Krsna has clearly expressed in <em>Bhagavad-gita</em> that goodness is superior to passion and ignorance. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">8</span> Similarly, Sri Suta Gosvami explains in the <em>Bhagavata</em>(1.2.24) that &#8220;Passion is better than ignorance because it can lead to realization of the Absolute Truth.&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">9</span> In this verse Suta speaks about which type of worship produces the ultimate benefit, and his conclusion is that one can only achieve the best result by worshipping Lord Visnu. The <em>sattvika Puranas</em> recommend the worship of Visnu / Krsna, whereas the <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas</em> advocate the worship of minor deities and therefore do not lead the aspirant towards the Absolute Truth.<br />
It is noteworthy that the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> commence with a questioner inquiring from a learned speaker about the nature of the Absolute. The speaker’s answers are clear, direct and unambiguous, leaving no room for misinterpretation. However, in the <em>tamasika</em> and <em>rajasika Puranas</em> questions are put to the speaker which do not pertain to the Absolute Truth. For example, in the <em>Linga Purana</em> the sages request Suta to speak about the glories of the Lingam form of Lord Siva. We may conclude from this that although Sri Suta Gosvami is learned in transcendental subject matters and expert in explaining them, the questions by the sages here restrict him from speaking on it. All <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika</em> <em>Puranas</em> contain this characteristic defect and therefore are not reliable sources of transcendental knowledge.<br />
One may ask at this point why Srila Vyasadeva wrote these <em>Puranas.</em> According to the various desires of the materially conditioned <em>jivas</em>, he arranged the <em>Puranas</em>. Nevertheless, all <em>Puranas</em> contain glorification of Lord Visnu. This was included by Vyasa in order that those in the lower modes of passion and ignorance will slowly develop interest in the Supreme Lord Hari while studying the <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas.</em> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">10</span>Therefore in the <em>Hari Vamsa</em> (3.323.34)it is said –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>vede ramayane caiva purane bharate tatha<br />
adav-ante ca madhye ca harih sarvatra giyate</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;In the <em>Vedas</em>, the <em>Ramayana, Puranas</em> and <em>Mahabharata</em>, from the very beginning to the end, as well as within the middle, only Hari, the Supreme Personality of Godhead, is explained.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yet it must be understood that although <em>rajasika</em> and <em>tamasika Puranas</em> do not speak extensively on the Absolute Truth, this does not mean that they give no valid knowledge at all. If this was the case why would <em>acaryas</em> such as Madhva cite from <em>Puranas</em> such as <em>Skanda, Brahma, Brahmanda, Brahma-vaivarta</em> etc which are not <em>sattvika</em> by nature? The <em>Puranas</em> in the lower modes may also give some insight into the Absolute Truth, although not to the same extent as the <em>sattvika Puranas.</em><br />
By this we may conclude that the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> are the ultimate <em>pramana</em>. This is also declared by the <em>Padma Purana &#8211; sattvika moksa-dah proktah: </em>&#8220;The <em>sattvika Puranas</em> give salvation.&#8221; Unfortunatly, as stated before, there are no current disciplic schools nor bona-fide commentaries for most of these works. Some of the <em>sattvika Puranas</em> recommend the path of <em>bhakti,</em> while others glorify the path of <em>jnana</em> or <em>yoga.</em><br />
One possibility to resolve this dilemma is to study the <em>Vedanta-sutra</em>. This work of Vyasadeva contains the essence of the <em>Vedas</em> and the <em>Puranas.</em> Still, the language of the <em>Vedanta-sutras</em> is ambiguous to say the least, and has therefore been interpreted in a number of ways by numerous scholars ( Madhva, Sankara, Ramanuja, Bhaskara, Bodhayana, Dramida, Guhadeva to name but a few). The foundations of many of the <em>sutras</em> lie in Upanisadic passages, yet Vyasa does not mention in his work as to which passages the particular <em>sutra</em> is commenting on. Thus both the student and the commentator must determine this for themselves. It is no wonder then that Vedavyasa felt discontent even after compiling the <em>Vedas</em>, <em>Puranas</em>, <em>Mahabharata</em> and <em>Vedanta-sutra &#8211;</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>tathapi bata me daihyo hy atma caivatmana vibhuh<br />
asampanna ivabhati brahma-varcasya sattamah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;I am feeling incomplete, although I am fully equipped with everything required by the <em>Vedas</em>.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 1.4.30)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The reason for his discontentment was then explained by Narada Muni –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>jijnasitam susampannam api te mahad-adbhutam<br />
krtavan bharatam yas tvam sarvartha-paribrmhitam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;You have completed your inquiries and your studies in the proper fashion, and you have written a great and wonderful work, the <em>Mahabharata</em>, which elaborately explains the different goals of life.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em> 1.5.3)</p>
<p class="verse"><em>bhavatanudita-prayam yaso bhagavato ’malam<br />
yenaivasau na tusyeta manye tad darsanam khilam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;You have not actually broadcast the sublime and spotless glories of the Personality of Godhead. That philosophy which does not satisfy the transcendental senses of the Lord is considered worthless.&#8221;</p>
<p class="verse"><em>yatha dharmadayas cartha muni-varyanukirtitah<br />
</em><em>na tatha vasudevasya mahima hy anuvarnitah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;O best of sages, since you have broadly described the four goals of human life beginning with religious performances, you have not described the glories of the Supreme Personality, Vasudeva.&#8221; (<em>Bhagavata</em>1.5.8-9)</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="dKlyYWY"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="180" height="257" class="size-full wp-image-7208  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f23feed43e2f.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> On the advice of Narada, Vyasa meditated and the <em>Bhagavata</em> was manifest to him. This is the natural commentary of Vyasa’s own <em>sutras</em> (<em>artho’yam brahma-sutranam</em>) and thus includes the purport of the entire <em>Vedic</em> literature (<em>vedartha-paribrmhitah</em>) It is free from the problems that we find with the <em>Vedas</em> and the other <em>Puranas</em> – it is available in it’s entirety, it has commentated upon by various Vaisnava <em>acaryas</em>, it is divinely composed and <em>Puranic</em> in nature. In it’s opening <em>sloka</em> it gives the essence of the <em>Vedas</em> since it begins with the holy <em>gayatri mantra·</em> (<em>gayatri-bhasya-rupo ’sah</em>) which is itself the essence of the <em>vedas.</em> This is also confirmed in the <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.20-22) and <em>Agni Purana</em> (272.6.7) &#8211;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>yatradhikrtya gayatrim vamyate dharma-vistarah<br />
vrtasura-vadhopetam tad bhagavatam istyate</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>likhitva tac ca yo dadyad dhema-simha-samanvitam<br />
prausthapadyam paurnamasyam sa yati paramam gatim<br />
asta-dasa-sahasrani puranam tat prakirtitam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;That <em>purana</em> is known as the <em>Bhagavata</em> which gives the highest religious principles, refers to the sacred <em>gayatri mantra</em>, and tells the story of the slaying of Vrtasura. This <em>purana</em> has 18,000 verses and whoever writes down the entire text and places it on a golden throne and gives it in charity to a qualified person on the day of the full-moon of the month of Bhadra will attain the Supreme abode.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Most importantly, the <em>Bhagavata</em> is the crowning glory of the divine author’s literary efforts, soothing his heart when he felt that his work remained incomplete.<br />
There are many verses that praise the <em>Bhagavata</em> above all the other <em>Puranas.</em> In the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (<em>Visnu-khanda</em> 6.4.3) it says –</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>srimad bhagavatasyatha srimad bhagavatah sada<br />
svarupam ekam evasti sac-cid-ananda-laksana</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> and the Supreme Lord are always of the same nature – possessed of eternal existence, knowledge and bliss.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the <em>Visnu Khanda</em> of the <em>Skanda Purana</em> (5.16.40-42, 44,33) –</p>
<p class="verse"><em>sataso &#8216;tha sahasrais ca kim anyaih sastra-samgrahaih<br />
na yasya tisthate gehe sastram bhagavatam kalau</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>katham sa vaisnavo jneyah sastram bhagavatam kalau<br />
grhe na tisthate yasya sa viprah svapacadhamah</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yatra yatra bhaved vipra sastram bhagavatam kalau<br />
tatra tatra harir yati tridasaih saha narada</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>yah pathet prayato nityam slokam bhagavatam mune<br />
asta-dasa-purananam phalam prapnoti manavah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;If the <em>Bhagavata</em> is not kept in one&#8217;s house in the Kali Yuga, of what avail are collections of other scriptures by the hundreds and thousands? How can he be condidered a Vaisnava who, in the Kali Yuga, does not keep the <em>Bhagavata</em> in his house? Even if he is a <em>brahmana,</em> he is lower than an outcaste. O Narada, O Sage, wherever the <em>Bhagavata</em> is found in the Kali-yuga, there Hari goes together with all the demigods. O Muni, that pius soul who daily recites a verse from the <em>Bhagavata</em> reaps the fruits of the eighteen <em>Puranas</em>.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the <em>Padma Purana</em> (<em>Uttara-khanda</em> 193.3)</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>puranesu tu sarvesu srimad bhagavatam param<br />
yatra prati-padam krsno giyate bahudharsibhih</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;Of all the <em>puranas</em>, the <em>Bhagavata</em> is the greatest. In every line the sages glorify Sri Krsna in various ways.&#8221;</p>
<p>Also in the <em>Padma Purana &#8211;</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>padau yadiyau prathama-dvitiyau trtiya-turyau kathitau yad-uru<br />
nabhis tatha pancama eva sasto bhujantaram dor-yugalam tathanyau</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>kanthas tu rajan navamo yadiyo mukharavindam dasamam praphullam<br />
ekadaso yas ca lalata-pattam siro’pi yad dvadasa eva bhati</em></p>
<p class="verse"><em>namami devam karuna-nidhanam tamala-varnam suhitavataram<br />
apara-samsara-samudra-setum bhajamahe bhagavata-svarupam</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The first and second cantos of the <em>Bhagavata</em> are Sri Krsna’s feet. The third and fourth cantos are His thighs. The fifth canto is His navel. The sixth canto is His chest. The seventh and eighth cantos are His arms. The ninth canto is His throat. The tenth canto is His beautiful lotus-face. The eleventh canto is His forehead. The twelth canto is His head.</p>
<p>I bow down to that Lord , the ocean of mercy whose color is like that of a <em>tamala</em> tree and who appears in this world for the welfare of all. I worship Him as the bridge for crossing the unfathomable ocean of material existence. The <em>Bhagavata</em> has appeared as His very Self.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In the <em>Garuda Purana &#8211;</em></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p class="verse"><em>artho ’yam brahma-sutranam bharatartha-vinirnayah<br />
gayatri-bhasya-rupo ’sah vedartha-paribrmhitah<br />
grantho ’stadasa-sahasrah srimad-bhagavatabhidhah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> is the authorized explanation of <em>Brahma-sutras</em>, and it is a further explanation of <em>Mahabharata</em>. It is the expansion of the <em>gayatri-mantra</em> and the essence of all Vedic knowledge. This <em>Bhagavata</em>, containing eighteen thousand verses, is known as the explanation of all Vedic literature.&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">11</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong> CONCLUSION:</strong> In this way we have shown through the <em>pramana</em> of the <em>srutis, smrtis, Itihasas</em> and <em>Puranas</em> that the <em>Mahabharata</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> are indeed considered to be the fifth <em>Veda</em>, and that they are of higher importance and significance in the age of Kali than the four <em>Vedas</em>. Of them, the highest is the the <em>Bhagavata</em>, the crest-jewel of all the Vedic literatures. For this reason the <em>Bhagavata</em>(1.3.43) says:</p>
<p class="verse"><em>krsne sva-dhamopagate dharma-jnanadibhih saha<br />
kalau nasta-drsam esa puranarko’dhunditah</em></p>
<p class="translation">&#8220;The <em>Bhagavata</em> is as brilliant as the sun. After Sri Krsna has left for His abode, accompanied by <em>dharma</em> and knowledge, it has arisen to save us from the darkness of the age of Kali.&#8221;</p>
<p>____________________________</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">1</span>&#8211; This is affirmed by Lord Krsna in the <em>Bhagavata</em> (11.3.44) – &#8220;<em>paroksa-vada vedo’yam&#8221;</em> (The <em>Vedas</em> speak indirectly).</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">2</span>&#8211; In the case of the <em>Bhagavata,</em> this itself is a contradiction from the point of view of the Madhva <em>sampradaya.</em> If the <em>Vedas</em> are considered a primary authority merely because they issued from the mouth of God Himself, the <em>Bhagavata</em> and <em>Mahabharata</em> should also fall into such a category since the author of these works was Veda Vyasa, whom the Tattvavadis consider to be a direct <em>avatara</em> of Narayana.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">3</span>&#8211; This verse from <em>Chandogya Upanisad</em> is also quoted by Madhvacarya in <em>Visnu Tattva Vinirnaya</em> (5). It is also worth noting that in Prof. K.T. Pandurangi’s work The <em>Principal Upanisads</em> (Dvaita Vedanta Studies and Research Foundation, Bangalore 1999) wherein he explains Madhvacarya’s <em>Upanisad</em> commentaries, the author gives the same meaning of this verse.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">4</span>&#8211; This is also confirmed in the <em>Bhagavata</em> (1.4.20):</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>rg-yajuh-samatharvakhya<br />
vedas catvara uddhrtah<br />
itihasa-puranas ca<br />
pancamo veda ucyate</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;The <em>Vedas</em> were divided into four, namely <em>Rg, Yajur, Sama</em> and <em>Atharva</em>. The <em>Itihasas</em> and the <em>Puranas</em> are said to be the fifth <em>Veda</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">5</span>&#8211; In his <em>tika</em> on the <em>Visnu Purana</em> 3.6.16, Srila Sridhara Svami explains these terms thus:</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>svayam-drstartha</em>&#8211;<em>kathanam prahur akhyanakam budhah srutasyarthasya<br />
kathanam upakhyanam pracaksate gathas tu pitr-prthivyadi gitayah</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;An <em>Akhyana</em> is a description of that which is witnessed by the speaker. An <em>Upakhyana</em> is a description of something the speaker has not seen, but merely heard about. A <em>Gatha</em> is a song dedicated to the forefathers and beings present upon the earth.&#8221;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">6</span>&#8211; The word <em>sankspitam</em> in this verse is important. This means ‘condensed’ and not ‘composed’. In other words Sri Vyasa condensed the already existing <em>Vedas</em>, then taking unused verses from that condensed portion, he compiled the <em>Puranas</em>. Thus, the <em>Puranas</em> must be understood to be equal to the <em>Vedas</em>.</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">7</span>&#8211; The five elements of a <em>Purana</em> are described in <em>Matsya Purana</em> (53.65) &#8211;</p>
<p class="verse note"><em>sargas ca pratisargas ca<br />
vamso manvantarani ca<br />
vamsyanucaritam caiva<br />
purana panca-laksanam</em></p>
<p class="translation note">&#8220;The five subjects which make up a <em>Purana</em> are creation (<em>sarga</em>), secondary creation (<em>pratisarga</em>), geneology of kings (<em>vamsa</em>), the description of the Manus (<em>manvantara</em>) and the activities of those kings (<em>vamsanucarita</em>). &#8220;</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">8</span>&#8211; In this verse the word ‘<em>agni</em>’ (fire) refers to the Vedic sacrifices wherein one offers oblations into various sacred fires. ‘<em>Kalpesu</em>’ means ‘scripture (in this case <em>Purana</em>) according to the definition given in the Medini Sanskrit dictionary 1.21.2 (<em>kalpa sastre vidhau nyaye samvarte brahmane dine</em> – the word <em>kalpa</em> means ‘scripture’, ‘rule’, ‘logic’, and ‘day of Brahma’.) The word ‘<em>ca</em>’ in the phrase ‘<em>sivasya ca</em>’ implies the consort of Lord Siva, namely Goddess Uma. ‘<em>Sankirnesu</em>’means ‘in the various <em>Puranas</em> which are in mixed modes of goodness, passion and ignorance. The word ‘<em>sarasvatyah</em>’ refers to the presiding deity of speech and, by implication, the various devas referred to in various scriptures which she embodies. <em>’Pitrnam’</em> refers to the <em>karma-khanda</em> rituals meant for attaining the heavenly planets of the manes (<em>karmana pitr-lokah</em>).</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">9</span>&#8211; <em>sattvat sanjayate jnanam<br />
</em> <em>rajaso lobhaeva ca<br />
pramada-mohau tamaso<br />
</em> <em>.bhavato’jnanam eva ca</em> (Bg 14.17)</p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">10</span>&#8211; <em>tamasas tu rajas tasmat<br />
</em><em>sattvam yad brahma-darsanam</em></p>
<p class="note"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">11</span>&#8211; Quoted by Sri Madhva in his <em>Bhagavata-tatparya.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/hindu-scriptures-battle-of-supremacy/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu Scriptures Battle of Supremacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
