<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>aurangzeb &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/aurangzeb/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 09:59:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 09:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivaji]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Probably not. And here are five reasons why. by Shoaib Danyal [Source: Scroll.in] As has been happening ever so often since Narendra Modi took power, history has burst out into modern-day politics. The New Delhi Municipal Corporation has proposed renaming &#8220;Aurangzeb Road&#8221; in Lutyen&#8217;s Delhi to &#8220;APJ Abdul Kalam Road&#8221;. The move had wide support &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:#333333;font-size:13pt;background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>Probably not. And here are five reasons why.<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><span style="color:#222222;font-size:13pt;"><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">by Shoaib Danyal [Source: Scroll.in] </span></span></span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/article-uzednshbdr-1441184122.jpg" alt="Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?" /></p>
<p><span id="more-815"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><span style="color:#222222;font-size:13pt;"><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">As has been happening ever so often since Narendra Modi took power, history has burst out into modern-day politics. The New Delhi Municipal Corporation has proposed renaming &#8220;Aurangzeb Road&#8221; in Lutyen&#8217;s Delhi to &#8220;APJ Abdul Kalam Road&#8221;. The move had wide support and both the Bharatiya Janata Party and the Aam Admi Party seem to have pitched for it, even as the Congress has maintained a studied silence. This also revived the long-standing Shiv Sena demand to rechristen Aurangabad in Maharashtra. Once the Mughal capital in the Deccan and founded by the Prime Minister (Peshwa) of the Ahmadnagar Sultanate, Malik Ambar, the city is set to be renamed Sambhaji Nagar, after Shivaji&#8217;s son.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Many people assume that history is an impersonal record of past events; a dull roll call of facts, events and figures. While raw data is certainly a component in the writing of history, there&#8217;s more to it in the way of how the historian interprets that data. In the words of EH Carr:</span><br />
<span style="font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="background:#fcfcfc;"><span style="color:#6f6f6f;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;">&#8220;History consists of a corpus of ascertained facts. The facts are available to the historian in documents, inscriptions and so on, like fish on the fishmonger&#8217;s slab. The historian collects them, takes them home, and cooks and serves them in whatever style appeals to him.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The final meal, then, depends not only on the fish available with the fishmonger, but also what the chef selects to cook and how he wants to cook it.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Most Indian state-written histories, for example, choose to elide the devastating <a href="http://tarikhpartarikh.blogspot.in/2014/03/the-maratha-invasion-of-bengal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">invasion</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of the Marathas into western Bengal in the 1740s. A majority of Indian narratives look at the Marathas as a &#8220;national&#8221; force and ignore the fact that (like any medieval army) they had no concept of nationalism and were mostly interested in loot. In a mirror image, Pakistan has named its missiles after Afghan king Mahmud of Ghazni, deliberately choosing to forget that the man made his fortune by mostly plundering what is current-day Pakistan.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">This is not to say that a history of Bengal that does not include the Maratha invasion is per se false. After all, any history of Bengal has to leave out something or the other in order to tell a cogent story. This example is just to introduce the concept of a narrative and its power in shaping our concept of history.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">With Aurangzeb, therefore, at least in the popular realm, a narrative has taken root which paints him as a Mughal Voldemort, so dreadful and tyrannical that even his name on a single road in the entire country could endanger the republic.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, it is impossible to disprove (or prove) such a narrative in an article. Nevertheless, here are five facts that at least don&#8217;t fit into it.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>1. Aurangzeb built more temples than he destroyed</strong></span><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The issue of temple destruction has taken on a particular hysteria after the violent mass movement in the 1980s and 1990s led by the Bharatiya Janata Party to destroy the Babri Masjid, based on the belief that the spot once housed a temple to the god Ram.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Ironically, there are almost no complaints of temple destruction by Mughal Hindu citizens in the medieval period itself, when these acts were actually supposed to have been carried out. Or even after Mughal power had waned in the 18th century (in case one would want to argue some sort of Mughal censorship). As the historian Richard Eaton has <a href="http://www.tehelka.com/2013/11/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">shown</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, destruction of temples by Muslim rulers in India was exceedingly rare and even when it did happen, it was a political act meant to chasten recalcitrant rulers and not a theological move.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In spite of his terrible reputation, Aurangzeb sticks to this template. Temples are rarely destroyed (Eaton puts the number of instances at 15 for Aurangzeb) and, if they are, the reason is political. For example, Aurangzeb almost never targetted temples in the Deccan, although that is where his massive army was camped for most of his reign. In the north, he did attack temples, for example the Keshava Rai Temple in Mathura. But the reason was political: the Jats of the Mathura region had revolted against the empire.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">For these same reasons of statecraft, Aurangzeb also patronised temples, since Hindus who remained loyal to the state were rewarded. In fact, as Katherine Butler Schofield from King&#8217;s College London <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayFulltext?type=1&amp;fid=573344&amp;jid=ASS&amp;volumeId=41&amp;issueId=01&amp;aid=573340" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">points</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> out, &#8220;Aurangzeb built far more temples than he destroyed.&#8221; Scholars such as <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/history/south-asian-history/architecture-mughal-india?format=HB" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">Catherine Asher</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, M Ather Ali and <a href="http://alkindi4.ideo-cairo.org/manifestation/168289" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">Jalaluddin</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>have pointed to numerous tax-free grants bestowed on Hindu temples, notably those of the Jangam Bari Math at Benares, Balaji&#8217;s temple at Chitrakoot, the Someshwar Nath Mahadev temple at Allahabad, the Umanand temple at Gauhati, and numerous others.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Also, temple destruction was a common part of Indian politics at the time and was not restricted to Muslims. In 1791, for example, the Maratha army raided and damaged the Shankaracharya&#8217;s temple in Sringeri because it was being patronised by Tipu Sultan, their enemy. Later on, Tipu renovated the temple and had the idol reinstalled.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>2. Music flourished in India during Aurangzeb&#8217;s reign</strong></span><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">A crucial part of the entire narrative of Aurangzeb as a tyrant is the parable that he banned music. It is a powerful tale and one that could really clinch the case. The only problem? It&#8217;s not true.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Far from being banned throughout India, as Katherine Butler Schofield comprehensively<a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayFulltext?type=1&amp;fid=573344&amp;jid=ASS&amp;volumeId=41&amp;issueId=01&amp;aid=573340" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">establishes</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, music wasn&#8217;t proscribed even in Aurangzeb&#8217;s court. The Emperor&#8217;s own coronation anniversaries were marked by both musicians and dancers. Not only that, his patronsiation of music meant that a number of dhrupads were composed in his name. Even further, he also seemed to be quite knowledgeable about it himself. In the <em>Mirat-e-Alam</em>, Bahktawar Khan wrote of the Emperor having a &#8220;perfect expert&#8217;s knowledge&#8221; of music. The<em>Rag Darpan</em>, a musical treatise by Mughal noble Faqirullah lists out Aurangzeb&#8217;s favourite singers and instrumentalists by name. Aurangzeb&#8217;s dearest son, Azam Shah went one step further and, during the lifetime of his father, became an accomplished musician.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In fact, it could even be said that music flourished under Aurangzeb&#8217;s. Schofield writes: &#8220;More musical treatises in Persian were written during Aurangzeb&#8217;s reign than in the previous 500 years of Muslim rule in India, and all of them make significant references to current music making.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In spite of his own love for it, later on in life, as Aurangzeb got more religious, he did stop listening to music himself. However, given the evidence, the assumption that this personal preference of Aurangzeb&#8217;s fashioned Mughal state policy seems incorrect.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>3. Aurangzeb employed more Hindus (including Shivaji) than any other Mughal<br />
</strong>It is a well-established fact that the number of Hindus employed by the Emperor&#8217;s administration was the highest ever in Mughal history up till then. In fact, the number of Hindu bureaucrats rose significantly during Aurangzeb&#8217;s rule, a statistic that, in the <a href="http://www.oup.co.in/product/oxford-india-paperback/history/medieval-india/232/the-mughal-nobility-under-aurangzeb-revised-edition/9780195655995" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">words</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of M Ather Ali, provides a &#8220;fine lawyer&#8217;s answer to any charge that Aurangzeb discriminated against Hindu mansabdars&#8221;.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The proportion of commanders, senior court officials and provincial administrators who were Hindu rose from 24% under Aurangzeb&#8217;s father, Shahjahan to 33% in the fourth decade of the Aurangzeb&#8217;s own rule.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">This trend actually becomes sharper as you move up the administration. A remarkably large number of Aurangzeb&#8217;s top generals were Hindu Rajputs. In fact, when Aurangzeb&#8217;s campaign against the Marathas or Sikhs is presented in a communal light, it is often forgotten that the actual Mughal army in the field was almost always led by a Rajput general.  Shivaji, himself, in fact, <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/co/academic/subjects/history/south-asian-history/marathas-16001818" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">served</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> in Aurangzeb&#8217;s army as a mid-level commander (mansabdar) at one time and, <a href="http://www.amazon.in/Shivaji-His-Times-Jadunath-Sarkar/dp/8125040269" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">writes</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Jadunath Sarkar, even expected to be made the Mughal Viceroy of the Deccan, but was refused by Aurangzeb, who could not gauge his military genius.</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://theindianmuslim.files.wordpress.com/2015/09/090315_0904_wasaurangze1.jpg" alt="" /><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>4. Aurangzeb&#8217;s mother tongue was Hindi<br />
</strong>Being unIndian is a charge levied not only at Aurangzeb but at almost any ruler who happens to be Muslim in medieval India. At one level, it is a puerile and, in fact, absurd test, given that there simply was no concept of &#8220;<a href="https://books.google.co.in/books?id=4mmoZFtCpuoC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">nationalism</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>&#8221; in 17th century India (or almost anywhere else).</span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Nevertheless, almost by any standards, Aurangzeb was a pukka upper-class Hindustani (a somewhat obvious point, since he <em>was</em> born and raised upper-class Hindustani). Patronising Braj Bhasha, a North Indian literary language for poetry and song, had been a long-standing Mughal tradition which continued into Aurangzeb&#8217;s rule. The patronage climate for Braj in Aurangzeb&#8217;s court was a &#8220;lively and encouraging one&#8221;, <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?aid=7179784&amp;fileId=S0026749X09990205" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">says</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> historian Allison Busch. Azam Shah, his son, was keenly interested in Braj poetry and patronised some of the biggest names in the language such as Mahakavi Dev. Vrind was another giant of Braj who was employed by Aurangzeb&#8217;s administration.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Moreover – again, this is obvious – the mother tongue of Aurangzeb and the other Mughals by then had become an early form of modern Hindi-Urdu. In a fascinating <a href="https://archive.org/stream/rukaatialamgirio00aurarich/rukaatialamgirio00aurarich_djvu.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">letter</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, written by Aurangzeb to his 47-year old son, Azam Shah, the Emperor gifts him a fort and orders that drums be beaten in his name. He then reminisces about Azam&#8217;s childhood, reminding him that he loved drums as a toddler and would often exclaim, &#8220;Babaji, dhun dhun!&#8221; to Aurangzeb in Hindi when he heard them.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, the Mughals still mostly wrote in Persian, which was the official language of the day. However, since you&#8217;re reading this in English, that shouldn&#8217;t be too much of an issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>5. The jizya tax wasn&#8217;t unusually discriminatory <em>for its time<br />
</em></strong>Controversial point, this, but let&#8217;s see it through.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Abolished by Akbar and reintroduced by Aurangzeb, the jizya was a tax levied on non-Muslims in the realm over and above all other duties. It functioned in three slabs depending on income and its rate ranged from 0.5% to 6%. It also had a number of exceptions built in and the poor, unemployed and disabled were not expected to pay. Moreover, Brahmans &#8220;as the <a href="https://books.google.co.in/books?id=Zpa8gyGW_twC&amp;redir_esc=y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">spiritual leaders</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of the Hindu community&#8221; were also exempt, as were bureaucrats.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The Muslim counterpart to the religious tax of jizya was the zakat, or alms tax, also to be paid over and above normal taxes. Aurangzeb, however, abolished the zakat.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">From the modern point of view, this is clearly discriminatory and modern nations do not (with minor exceptions such as the Hindu Undivided Family provision in India) impose taxes on groups based on identity.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Judging people in the 17th century with today&#8217;s morals, though, would result in an absurd situation: <em>everyone</em> would come out looking terrible. Taxation based on identity is an anachronism today but was not that much in Aurangzeb&#8217;s time. The Marathas, who went on to replace the Mughals in large parts of the Deccan, had a discriminatory taxation policy as well; a mirror image of Aurangzeb&#8217;s, in fact. They <a href="https://books.google.co.in/books/about/Beyond_Turk_and_Hindu.html?id=9ZhT5Ilq5kAC" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">collected</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> zakat from Muslims with no corresponding tax from Hindus.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">However, in many ways, both the Maratha zakat and Mughal jizya were, for their time, only mildly discriminatory, involving minor sums and a tiny percentage of the population (modern India&#8217;s income tax base is less than 3% of the population, so you can imagine how small it was for Mughal India). Unlike today, the main axis of India&#8217;s society at the time did not revolve around &#8220;Hindu&#8221; and &#8220;Muslim&#8221;. To see real 17th century discrimination, one needs to go to caste.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The Maharashtrian Mahar Dalit caste under the Peshwa rule, for example, had to hang a broom from their backs, which swept away their footsteps as they walked so as to not &#8220;pollute&#8221; the path, in case an upper caste person should happen to use it later. A pot had to be hung below their neck, to collect any saliva that should inadvertently fall out from their mouths, also to prevent &#8220;pollution&#8221;. Arms and education were, of course, banned and any Mahar breaking these caste laws was summarily put to death.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">So degrading was the condition of the Mahars under Peshwa rule that BR Ambedkar, also a Mahar, <a href="http://drambedkarbooks.com/2011/12/30/the-battle-of-bhima-koregaon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">celebrated</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> the victory of the British in the Anglo-Maratha wars – a practice that continues till today with the Mahars.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, our evaluation of tyranny in the past is not based on any objective reading of history (if such a thing were possible at all) but rests mostly on our modern prejudices and politics. This is why Aurangzeb&#8217;s jizya is discussed threadbare but the Maratha zakat or policy on caste is mostly swept under the carpet. And this is why Delhi&#8217;s Aurangzeb Road may soon be renamed.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Talibanism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 18:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atrocities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destruction of temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghaznavi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains and buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persecution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: MilliGazette ] &#160; Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan? &#160; &#160; Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: <a href="http://www.milligazette.com/Archives/15042001/Art06.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MilliGazette<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="color:#0070c0;">Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan?<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5643"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and Osmania universities, and Dr MS Jayaprakash, professor of history at Kollam &#8211; throw some deep insights into the dark history of India when Buddhism was systematically eliminated by Brahminical forces who control Hinduism, then and now.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Says Jayaprakash: &#8216;The ruthless demolition of Buddha statues by Taliban has courted severe criticism from different quarters of the world. Surprisingly, the BJP-led Indian Government, supported by all Hindutva forces, also condemned the Taliban action. It is a paradox that the forerunners of the present Hindutva forces in India had wantonly destroyed not only Buddhist statues but also killed Buddhists in India. Therefore, any impartial student of history would unequivocally say that these Hindutva forces have no moral right to criticize Taliban now.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He elaborates: &#8216;Hundreds of Buddhist statues, stupas and viharas have been destroyed in India between 830 and 966 AD in the name of Hindu revivalism. Both literary and archaeological sources within and outside India speak volumes about the havoc done to Buddhism by Hindu fanatics. Spiritual leaders like Sankaracharya and many Hindu kings and rulers took pride in demolishing Buddhist images aiming at the total eradication of Buddhist culture. Today, their descendants destroyed the Babri Masjid and also published the list of mosques to be targeted in future. It is with this sin of pride that they presently condemn Taliban.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin elaborates the selfish compulsions of Brahminism to wipe-out Buddhism: &#8216;Buddhism tried to create a dynamic society in ancient India. Jainism also contributed its share. As Buddhism spread, iron ploughs and implement were used for development of agriculture. As a result, new areas were cultivated and agricultural productivity increased, apart from developing trade centres and road links. Subsistence-level economy changed to a surplus economy with grain storage facilities, exchange of goods, trade and development of bureaucratic administration. This also created social change &#8211; from elans consisting several families to tribes consisting several elans of similar socio-economic conditions. The emphasis of Brahmins, on the other hand, was for receiving and giving alms and not on production of goods. Those who give and receive alms were close to Gods and those who produce were considered as inferior. According to Manusmriti, a Sudra should not have wealth of his own. In case he has any, a Brahmin as his master can take it over without any hesitation. &#8216;Rigveda&#8217; goes a step further to kill those who do not give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the Brahmins. In other words, someone has to produce goods so that others can give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the recipient Brahmins. It was against this system of &#8216;downgrading those who produce&#8217; that Buddhism came into being.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Recalls Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;The Hindu ruler Pushyamitra Sunga had destroyed 84,000 Buddhist stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. This was followed by the demolition of Buddhist centres in Magadha. Thousands of Buddhist saints were killed mercilessly. King Jalaluka destroyed the Buddha viharas within his jurisdiction on the ground that chanting of hymns by Buddhists disturbed his sleep! In Kashmir, King Kinnara demolished thousands of viharas and captured the Buddhist villages to please Brahmins. A large number of Buddha viharas were usurped by Brahmins and converted into Hindu temples where entry of &#8216;untouchables&#8217; was prohibited. Notably, Buddhist places were regularized as Hindu temples by writing Puranas, which were invented myths or pseudo history. The important temples at Tirupathi, Aihole, Undavalli, Ellora, Bengal, Puri, Badarinath, Mathura, Ayodhya, Sringeri, Bodhigaya, Saranath, Delhi, Nalanda, Gudimallam, Nagarjunakonda, Srisailam and Sabarimala are some of the striking examples of Brahminical usurpation of Buddhist centres.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Detailing the divergence in both orientation and essence between Buddhism and Hinduism, Prof. Bahauddin says: &#8216;Equality, compassion, non-violence, utilization of human abilities for general welfare, etc. were the cardinal principles of Buddhism. According to &#8216;Sathpatha Brahmanam (22-6, 3-4-14), on the other hand, the whole universe is controlled by God, God is controlled by Mantram and Mantram is with Brahmins and, therefore, Brahmins are God (on earth). They used Mantram and Sapam to instil fear in the people to obey them, while Buddhism encouraged people to observe visible facts, to apply reason to get out of fear. Buddhism also encouraged people to do good things, besides guiding Kings to look after the people&#8217;s welfare. Buddhism considers the general welfare of the people, while Brahminism considers that the whole world was created for them all along. And, there is bound to be conflict between these two opposite ways of thinking.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr Jayaprakash, Sakaracharya had played &#8216;a demon&#8217;s role&#8217; in destruction of Buddhist statues and monuments at Nagarjunakonda (in present-day Andhra Pradesh). &#8216;A. N. Longhurst, who conducted excavations at Nagarjunakonda, had recorded this in his invaluable book, Memoirs of the Archaeological Survey of India No. 54, The Buddhist Antiquities of Nagarjunakonda (Delhi, 1938, p. 6). The ruthless manner in which all the buildings at Nagarjunakonda have been destroyed is simply appalling and cannot represent the work of treasure-seekers alone since so many pillars, statues, and sculptures have been wantonly smashed to pieces. Local tradition relates that the great Hindu philosopher and teacher, Sankaracharya, came to Nagarjunakonda with a host of followers and destroyed the Buddhist monuments. The cultivated lands on which ruined buildings stand represent a religious grant made to Sankaracharya.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Quoting Dr. B. R. Ambedkar, Prof. Bahauddin says that the conflict against Brahmin supremacy had, in fact, started before Buddhist period, between Vasishta Muni, a Brahmin, and Viswamitra, a non-Brahmin. &#8216;The dispute was about the learning of &#8216;Vedas&#8217;, the right to conduct religious ceremony, to receive gifts, and to perform coronation of King. Vasishta Muni insisted that these were the exclusive privileges of Brahmins, while Viswamitra was opposed to such exclusive rights. This dispute lasted for long period, and even Kings joined in it (Writings and Speeches of Dr. Ambedkar, vol. 7, p. 148-155. It was won by Brahmins.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin lists the different stages of Brahmin hostility against Buddhism: &#8216;1) 483-273 BC: The period after Buddha&#8217;s death upto Ashoka&#8217;s rule when attempts were made to include Brahminical ideas in Buddhist ideology. 2) 273-200 BC: When Buddhism spread all over India and became a world religion. 3) 200 BC-500 AD: The period when all possible efforts were made to disintegrate Buddhism from within by adulterating Buddhist teachings with Brahminical ideas and also through physical annihilation from outside. As a result, Buddhism divided itself into 18 sects, of which Hinayana and Mahayana were prominent ones. 4) 500-700 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in North India and efforts began to drive out Buddhism and Jainism from South India. 5) 700-1100 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in South India and, with added vigour, it moved again to North India to obtain complete supremacy over Buddhism and Jainism. 6) 1100-1400 AD: Buddhism and Jainism were destroyed from the remaining Southern States of Karnataka and Kerala and, thus, total supremacy of Brahminism all over India was achieved.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;Within Kerala, Sankaracharya and his close associate Kumarila Bhatta, an avowed foe of Buddhism, organized a religious crusade against Buddhists. A vivid description of Sankaracharya&#8217;s pleasure of seeing people of non-Brahminic faith being burnt to death is available in &#8216;Sankara Digvijaya&#8217;. Kumarila instigated King Suddhanvan of Ujjain to exterminate Buddhists. The &#8216;Mricchakatika&#8217; of Sudraka describes how the King&#8217;s brother-in-law in Ujjain inhumanly tortured the Buddhist monks, by using them as bullocks by inserting a string through their nose and yoking them to the cart! The &#8216;Keralolpathi&#8217; documents the extermination of Buddhism from Kerala by Kumarila. About the activities of Sankaracharya, even Vivekananda had observed: &#8216;And, such was the heart of Sankara that he burnt to death lots of Buddhist monks by defeating them in argument. What can you call such action on Sankara&#8217;s part except fanaticism&#8217; (Complete works of Swami Vivekananda, Vol. III, p. 118, Calcutta, 1997).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, there are hundreds of places in Kerala having names &#8216;palli&#8217; either affixed or suffixed with them. &#8216;Karunagapalli, Karthikapalli, Pallickal, Pallippuram, Edappally, etc. are some examples of these places. The term &#8216;palli&#8217; means a Buddha vihara. Notably, Kerala had 1200 years of Buddhist tradition. Earlier, the schools in Malayalam were called as &#8216;Ezhuthupalli&#8217; or &#8216;Pallikoodam&#8217;. It is also worth noticing that the Christians and Muslims in Kerala use the term &#8216;palli&#8217; to denote their church and mosque alike. These &#8216;pallies&#8217; or viharas had been ruthlessly demolished by the Hindu forces under the leadership of Sankaracharya and Kumarila. They could exterminate 1200 years of Buddhist tradition and converted Kerala into a Brahminical state based on the &#8216;Chaturvarna&#8217; system. Original inhabitants of Kerala, like the Ezhavas, Pulayas, etc., were crushed under the weight of casteism. Many a viharas was transformed into temples and majority of people were prevented from entering temples under the pretext of caste pollution. It can also be noted that the name &#8216;Kerala&#8217; is the Sanskritised Aryan version of the Dravidian and Buddhist term &#8216;Cherala&#8217;. The Parasurama legend is nothing but an invented myth for regularizing the Brahminical &#8216;Kerala&#8217; hiding its glorious Buddhist traditions.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jainism, too, met with the same fate in South India. Prof. Bahauddin elaborates: &#8216;Very little information is available about growth of Jainism in South India during 300-400 AD. The Jain book, &#8216;Digambara Darsana&#8217;, recounts the starting of a Sangham at Madurai in 470 AD and Jainism became widespread and strong during 500-600 AD (Kumaraswamy Iyengar, &#8216;Studies in South Indian Jainism&#8217;, p. 51-58)….. The Jains used to instal the images of their saints in their religious places, a practice which was followed by Brahmins. Hindu temples appeared all over Tamilnadu probably after converting the Jain religious places. The idols of 63 Brahmin Sanyasis, who led destruction of Jainism, still adorn the walls of some Hindu temples in Tamilnadu. The remains of destroyed Jain idols, their abandoned religious and living places are scattered all over Tamilnadu to narrate their story. Frescos depicting the kings of Jains could be seen on the walls near the Golden Tank at Madurai Meenakshi Temple where, of the total 12 annual festivals, five depict the killing of Jains according to Kumaraswamy Iyengar (p. 78-79).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, a number of Buddha statues have been discovered at places like Ambalapuzha, Karunagapalli, Pallickal, Bharanikkavu, Mavelikara and Neelamperur in Kerala. &#8216;They are either in the form of smashed pieces or thrown away from viharas. Lord Ayyappa of Sabarimala and Lord Padmanabha at Thiruvananthapuram are the proxy images of Buddha being worshipped as Vishnu. Hundreds of Buddhists were killed on the banks of Aluva river. The term &#8216;Aluva&#8217; was derived from &#8216;Alawai&#8217; which means &#8216;Trisul&#8217;, a weapon used by Hindu fanatics to stab Buddhists. Similarly, on the banks of the Vaigai river in Tamilnadu, thousands of Buddhists were killed by the Vaishnava Saint, Sambanthar. Thevaram, a Tamil book, documents this brutal extermination of Buddhism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls the strong reasons to believe that a large section of Jains had embraced Islam: &#8216;The spread of Islam in Tamilnadu can be considered in three or four stages. Islam spread in Kerala and Tamilnadu when Jainism was under pressure (650-750 AD). The new religion was received without resistance…. Since Islam considers every human being with equality Jainism and Buddhism had no conflict with it. When Muhammad ibn Al-Qasim attacked Sindh, the Buddhists supported him because they were facing annihilation at that time. A similar situation was prevailing in South India during 650-750 AD…. Muslims in Tamilnadu are called Anchuvanthar, Labba (teacher), Rauthar, Marakar (sailor) or Jonakan (Yavankan). The Anchuvanam is the guild of traders and groups of artisans. The Muslim mohallas of &#8216;Anchuvan Vamsagar&#8217;, &#8216;Anchuvanathar&#8217;, etc. are scattered all over Tamilnadu and seem to be the en bloc conversion of Jain guilds engaged in different activities, especially weaving. Those who ran away from Tamilnadu settled down in Sravanabalagola and Gomatheswaram in Karnataka. And, those who could not leave due to their economic interests converted to Islam. If we analyze the body structure, food, language, dress, ornaments, customs and habits of Anchuvanthar, it could be see that those are a continuation of Jain way of living and customs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Till recently, the weavers in such Muslim mohallas will not eat at noon or night, and take only one meal before dusk. This was a continuation of Jain habits. There is a separate place in such villages called &#8216;Odukkam&#8217; where Jain Munist used to sit in prayer. On the last Wednesday of the month called &#8216;Odukkathae&#8217; Wednesday, the Muslims gather together to sing religious songs, which is also a Jain tradition. When religious functions like Maulood, Rathif, etc. are organized in the house, a white cloth with lotus symbol on it called &#8216;Mekett&#8217; is tied, which resembles the &#8216;Asmanagiri&#8217; of the Jains…. The architecture of Muslim stone mosques are completely of Jain architecture. The pillars of earlier mosques have practically no difference with the Jain temple pillars. The close relationship between traders and weavers had probably cemented by conversion to Islam. During 950-1200 AD, there were large number of Sufis, Fakirs, wandering poets, singing minstrels, etc. among Muslims all over Tamilnadu. Nadirshah with 500 disciples settled down in &#8216;Trichinopoly&#8217; during 1000 AD. Aliyar Shah and his disciples made Madurai as their centre. Baba Fakhruddin travelled all over Tamilnadu. Nagur became another Sufi centre. The Muslim religious literature of Tamilnadu of that period was least different from those created by Jains and Hindus during the &#8216;Bhakti&#8217; movement.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recounts the spread of Jainism and Buddhism in Kerala, thus: &#8216;Jainism spread in North Kerala around 200 BC. The Jain architectural remains in Canara and Malabar are not available anywhere else in South of Nepal. While Jainism entered North Kerala via Mangalore, Salem, Coimbatore and Wayanad, it entered Southern Kerala from Tirunelveli, Kanyakumari, Nagercoil, Chitharal, etc. The hill near Anamala, which was an important Jain centre, is still called &#8216;Jain Durgam&#8217;. The close-by Kurumala was also a Jain centre. From Anamala through Munnar, Devikulam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor, etc. they reached Neryamangalam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor and other places. The &#8216;Kallil Kshetram&#8217; in Perumbavoor is an important Jain monument as also the &#8216;Jainmedu&#8217; in Vadakethara village of Palakkad district. Kerala&#8217;s cave temples at Chitharal, Kallil, Trikur, Erunilamkode (Thrissur district) and Thiruveghapuram (Palakkad district) were constructed during the period of Jain King Mahendra Verman-I (610-640 AD). Temple records of Rameswaram, Sucheendram, Poothadi (Wayanad), Keenalur (Kozhicode) , etc. show that they were part of &#8216;Kunavai Koottam&#8217; during 10-11th centuries. &#8216;Koottam&#8217; is the place of living for Jain Sanyasis. Temple records show that all these present-day Hindu temples were Jain religious places till 11th century. Place names with Kallu, Poothan, Aathan, Kotha, Palli, Ambalam, etc. were all Jain centres. Spread all over Kerala, names of these places show that Buddhism and Jainism were widespread. The famous Kalpathi in Palakkad district was a Buddhist-Jain centre. The &#8216;Ratholsavam&#8217; there is akin to the &#8216;Kettukazhcha&#8217; of Buddhists. The present Bhagavati temples were also Jain temples. The group, &#8216;Adikal&#8217;, had a prominent position among Jains who became &#8216;Pisharadi&#8217; after absorption of Jainism in Hinduism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&#8216;Similarly, the Buddhist stoopa at Kodungallore, located in Methala village South-East of Thrikanamathilakam, is an important Buddhist ruin in Kerala…. Mahismathi was the capital of Chera King Satyaputran, which shows the relationship of Chera country (Kerala) with Buddhism. There is a reference in &#8216;Manimekhala&#8217; about a Buddhist Chaityam in Kerala. While Vadakkumnatha Temple at Thrissur and Kurumba Temple at Kodungallore were Buddhist temples, Buddha statues were discovered from Kollam, Alappuzha, Mavelikara, Pallikkal, Karumadi and other places…. Treating mental patients in Thiruvadi temple and leprosy patients in Thakazhi temple shows that they were Buddhist temples since these kind of humanitarian services were not rendered out from Hindu temples…. By 900 AD Buddhism and Jainism were almost wiped out from Tamilnadu. The second settlement wave of Brahmins in Kerala during 900 AD was with Pandyan Kings&#8217; support. Karnataka and Kerala were the only two states where Buddhism and Jainism were still surviving and the second immigration of Brahmins might have been for driving out these two religions from the remaining places.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls: &#8216;Very few people know that Buddhism and Jainism were the prominent religions of Kerala till 1200 AD. I was also under the impression that Hinduism was in Kerala from the very beginning. When facts were pieced together, a different picture emerged. Only from the end of 1800 AD the evidence became available about Buddha, Buddhism, Ashoka, etc. That fact itself is a pathetic story….&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash in conclusion: &#8216;This is what really happened in India, the land of Buddha. But our so-called eminent historians, except a few, are bent upon eclipsing the cruelty done to Buddhists in India. These pseudo historians have succeeded in creating an impression that India is a land of righteousness and toleration. The entire world has been duped by them. The deed on the part of Taliban can be justified on the ground that Islam does not permit idols. But one has to note that Islam does not allow the demolition of other people&#8217;s religious centres and images. Whatever may be the argument for and against Taliban action, the Hindu atrocities on Buddhism in India has no parallel in the entire world history of religious struggle. Let the world know the cruel and crooked face of the &#8216;Indian vulture without culture&#8217;!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
