<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>birth &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/birth/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 15:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Overpopulation</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overpopulation in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; by Sulaiman Razvi India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-7484" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg" width="382" height="322" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-300x253.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-768x647.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 382px) 100vw, 382px" /></p>
<p>by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% population would become majority couple of years. I fail to understand why Hindus are so scared of becoming minority? Aren’t Hindus living as minority in Muslim majority countries like Malaysia, Indonesia, UAE and Bangladesh without facing any sort of discrimination which non Hindus face in India? Are they scared that once the become minority they would be treated the same way they treat minorities and Dalits presently in India? On the one hand they spread fear mongering that Muslims would soon become majority but on the other hand they are indulged in changing demographics of states which sizeable Muslim population. Muslims were once a majority community in Jammu and were reduced to minority via ethnic cleansing in Jammu massacre by Kashmiri Hindus more particularly by the Dogra Hindus. Attempts are made to change demographics of Muslim majority Kashmir and same is happening with states like Bengal and Assam which has 30% each Muslim population, these states were excluded from Inner Line Permit which means Hindus coming from Bangladesh and Pakistan would not be settled in any North-Eastern states of India but in these two states Bengal and Assam. It was decided that people with more than 2 children would not get government jobs in Assam, this was cleverly implemented as Hindus as Total Fertility Rate less than 2 in Assam while Muslims have higher than 2. But such law was not implemented in states like Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, Rajasathan… where Hindu fertility rate is higher than 2. Assam Chief Minister from BJP Hemanta Biswa specifically <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/assam-implement-two-child-policy-avail-govt-schemes-cm-himanta-biswa-sarma-1817189-2021-06-20" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">appealed<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> to the Muslim immigrants to adopt family planning. Two Child norm has been implemented in Assam and people with more than 2 children will not be able to avail some government benefits, but this law is not applicable to some Hindu classes such as SC, ST and the Tea tribe. He says he want upliftment Muslims from poverty by implementing the two child policy norm.Family planning has been a issue since independence but Hindutvadis want to implement two child policy norm in states which has Hindu TFR less than national average, two child policy would probably be implemented when Hindu TFR falls below 2.</p>
<p>Without wasting anymore time let’s see what Hindu scriptures says about population control. It is mentioned in RigVed,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.85.45 O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. Vouchsafe to her ten sons, and make her husband the eleventh man. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="105" class="wp-image-7485" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p><span id="more-927"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.24.5 Grant, Agni, to the worshipper wealth rich in heroes, plenteous store, Make thou us rich with many sons. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="82" class="wp-image-7486" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Grihya Sutra,</p>
<p>Sankhayana Grihya Sutra 1.19.6 ‘Give birth to a male child; may after him (another) male be born; their mother shalt thou be, of the born, and (to others) mayst thou give birth…</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Upanishad,</p>
<p>Khandogya Upanishad, 1 Prapathaka, Kanda 5, verse 4. &#8216;Him I sang praises to, therefore art thou my only son,&#8217; thus said Kaushitaki to his son. &#8216;Do thou therefore sing praises to the breath as manifold, if thou wishest to have many sons.&#8217;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in the Purana that Hindu god Krishna had ten sons from each wife,</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagvat Purana) 10.61.1 Sukadeva Gosvami said: Each of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa&#8217;s wives gave birth to ten sons, who were not less than their father, having all His personal opulence.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse,</p>
<p>&#8221;Lord Kṛṣṇa had 16,108 wives, and thus this verse indicates that the Lord begot 161,080 sons&#8221; He also writes on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19</p>
<p>http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_10.61.1</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>He wrote,</p>
<p>&#8221;&#8230;The birth of a human being is a great science, and therefore reformation of the act of impregnation according to the Vedic ritual called Garbhādhāna-samskāra is very important for generating good population. The problem is not to check the growth of the population, but to generate good population on the level of Vidura, Vyāsa and Maitreya. There is no need to check the growth of population if the children are born as human beings with all precautions regarding their birth. So-called birth control is not only vicious but also useless.&#8221; A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>He also wrote,</p>
<p>“&#8230;In every state all over the world, such activities are encouraged by the government in the form of birth control. Women are supplied pills, and they are allowed to go to a clinical laboratory to get assistance for abortions. This is going on as a result of sense gratification. Actually sex life is meant for begetting a good child, but because people have no control over the senses and there is no institution to train them to control the senses, the poor fellows fall victim to the criminal offenses of sense gratification, and they are punished after death as described in these pages of Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam.” A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.30.21 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" data-wpel-link="internal"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-7487" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" alt="" width="2560" height="2208" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-300x259.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1024x883.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-768x662.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1536x1325.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-2048x1767.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></a></p>
<p>Shankaracharya Vasudevananda Saraswati of Badrikashram tells Hindu women to produce 10 children. <a href="http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>https://scroll.in/latest/825148/rss-backed-seer-asks-hindus-to-have-10-children-says-god-will-take-care-of-them-toi</p>
<p>Hindu religious and political leader Sakshi Maharaj asks Hindu women to produce 4 children. <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><br />
<a href="http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>‘Hindus should beget four children till Uniform Civil Code is implemented’, says senior priest Swami Govindadev Giriji Maharaj of Bharat Mata Mandir in Haridwar<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Prachi says asked Hindus to have 4 children, not 40 puppies<br />
<a href="http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How the Gita Press opposed birth control to shore up the Hindu population<br />
<a href="https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>To save religion, Hindus should follow &#8216;we 2, our 8&#8217; policy: religious guru Swami Prabodhananda Giri<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Pragya Thakur appeals Hindus to have more children, says she will take care of them.<br />
<a href="https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Now, Saffron leaders ask Hindus to have 10 kids to ensure survival of religion</strong><br />
seer Ramanandacharya Raghvachrya said Hindus were facing threat across the world. “Lord Krishna had 16,108 wives and he had 10 children from each of them. The world will be ruled by those who have maximum population. Lord Ram too had asked his brother Bharat to have more sons for protection of the religion“</p>
<p>Slogan of ‘hum do, hamare do’ will not work. Each Hindu family should have at least eight children,” said Kanhaiyya Das, a top priest from Ayodhya.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>Couple hands over 13th girl<br />
</strong> Kamli gave her 13th daughter to the Devarakonda Shishu Vihar.<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>One son, 13 daughters and counting — all for another boy</strong><br />
Kanu confesses that her body is now unable to bear the stress of pregnancies.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Every Hindu family with five children will get Rs 2 lakh: Shiv Sena<br />
Each family that has five kids between 2010 to 2015 will get Rs 2 lakh.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Produce more children, RSS tells Hindu couples<br />
<a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Make it 5 kids: BJP leader Shyamal Goswami from West Bengal to Hindu women<br />
<a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the same time, there are also demands by leaders like Giriraj Singh and Baba Ramdev to implement two-child policy. Confusing, isn&#8217;t it? Let me explain it to you. Firstly one needs to question them why there&#8217;s a demand for 2 child policy and not 1 child policy?</p>
<p>How much a community reproduces is reflected in the fertility rate. The fertility rate of Muslims is 2.6 while that of Hindus is 2.1. Hindu religious and political leaders are exhorting Hindus to have more babies so that their population may increase, they hope that Hindus will produce more babies if they urge Hindus to have more babies, whereas there are also leaders like Giriraj and Ramdev who don&#8217;t see the possibility of Hindus having more babies, hence they want to implement 2 child policy as Hindus are already producing 2.1 children on average. So basically 2 child policy won&#8217;t affect them and only Muslims would be affected with the implementation. Event was held in Delhi on world population day attended by Hindu leaders and made inflammatory speeches against Muslims, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnGuY2eFQr8" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Giriraj Singh said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> that &#8220;to tackle declining population of Hindus and to stop the increasing population of Non-Hindus we need a law.&#8221; From his statement, one can easily understand that he wants two-child policy because he is hopeless about Hindus producing more babies.</p>
<p>The day when Hindu fertility rate falls below 1.0 then demand for 1 child policy will grow. Hindu fanatics want others to produce less babies than them, they want others to eat what Hindus wants them to eat, they want others to learn what Hindus wants to teach them, in short, they are enforcing their religion on non-Hindus.</p>
<p>Hindu population in several Arab countries are going to more than double by 2050, imagine if Muslims harass Hindus there like Hindus are unnecessarily harassing Muslims using the bogus myth of Muslim population explosion. As per <a href="https://www.pewforum.org/2015/04/02/middle-east-north-africa/154-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">PEW Research<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, Hindu population in Muslim majority Middle East and North Africa is going to double.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="403" class="wp-image-7488" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-300x189.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s come to Pakistan and Bangladesh. Hindu population is consistently increasing in Bangladesh <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindu-population-in-bangladesh-increasing-sushma-swaraj-in-rajya-sabha-5266275/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/Bangladesh%E2%80%99s-Hindus-number-1.7-crore-up-by-1-p.c.-in-a-year-report/article14397035.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and Pakistan <a href="https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/india/hinduism-fastest-growing-religion-in-pakistan-saudi-arabia-51516.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/hindu-population-in-pakistan-has-grown-at-a-faster-pace-than-in-india-119032600520_1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> whereas Hindu fanatics in India are busy peddling fake data of declining Hindu population in Pakistan and Bangladesh. As per Newslaundry Hindus in Pakistan were <a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/2015/01/09/the-vanishing-hindus-of-pakistan-a-demographic-study-2" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1.3% in 1951<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> after mass migration which increased to 1.85% in 1998 as per <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20140402081116/http:/www.census.gov.pk/Religion.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Pakistan Government Census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, as per official census Hindu population in Pakistan in the year 1951 was 1.6%. According to the <a href="https://tribune.com.pk/story/2119692/1-pakistani-hindus-reject-indias-offer-citizenship/&amp;fbclid=IwAR1qaVQxi3WJOaJ57u4CRTPsxgSqMyi6d4_9CibaH8jKcyilmdNKhjwZ6Vg/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1961 census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, the non-Muslim population was recorded at 2.83%. A decade later in 1972, the census recorded non-Muslim population at 3.25% of the total population. That means, it increased by 0.42%. In the 1981 census, the non-Muslim population was 3.30%. In the next census carried out in 1998, it was recorded as 3.70% of the total population. Population after the mass migration should be taken into consideration not post Independence survey. The second wave of mass migration happened in Bangladesh after the 1971 Liberation war. There were approx 33% Muslims in Delhi, 57% in Punjab, 67% in Jammu (before Jammu massacre). Using these figures one cannot say that Muslim population has been reduced to 14%.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2232" height="2560" class="wp-image-7489" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg 2232w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-262x300.jpeg 262w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-893x1024.jpeg 893w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-768x881.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1339x1536.jpeg 1339w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1785x2048.jpeg 1785w" sizes="(max-width: 2232px) 100vw, 2232px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Abortion is clearly prohibited in Hinduism</strong>,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.105.48 &#8220;Willful abortion and hatred of the husband are great sins in women without any expiation. Hence, she shall be shunned from a distance.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Parasara Smriti 4.20 What sin is incurred in killing a Brahman, abortion causes a sin twice as great; there is no atonement for that sin. The abandonment of such a woman has been ordained by law.</p>
<p>Gautama Dharma Shastra 21.9. A woman becomes an outcast by procuring abortion, by connection with a (man of) lower (caste) and (the like heinous crimes).</p>
<p>Vasistha Samhita 28.7. Those versed in the sacred law state that there are three acts (only) which make women outcasts, (viz.) the murder of the husband, slaying a learned Brâhmana, and the destruction of the fruit of their womb.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now a days Hindus are mocking Muslims of having ten children which isn&#8217;t true, after reading this will they still criticize Muslims with such taunt? Maharishi Manu also had ten sons,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.2 …and the ten sons of the Manu will be Sukshetra, Uttarnaujas, Harisheńa, and others.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Devi Bhagvatam</p>
<p>Devi Bhagvatam 8.4.1-4 The Risi Narayana said :&#8211; The eldest son of Svayambhuva, Priyavrata served always his father and was very truthful. He married the daughter of the Prajâpati Vis&#8217;va Karma&#8230;He begat ten sons, very spiritual and well qualified and one daughter named Ûrjasvatî….</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Mahabharata,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.115 &#8220;Vaisampayana said, &#8216;Meanwhile, O Janamejaya, Dhritarashtra begat upon Gandhari a hundred sons, and upon a Vaisya wife another besides those hundred. And Pandu had, by his two wives Kunti and Madri, five sons who were great charioteers and who were all begotten by the celestials for the perpetuation of the Kuru line.&#8217;</p>
<p>Hindu god Shiva had eight children, Ganesha, Jalandhar, Kartikey, Ashok Sundari, Ayappa, Andhaka, Manasa, and Jyoti. So its not other religion but Hinduism which encourages couple to have more children. Hinduism considers women as a child production machine,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 5.39.67 &#8220;The fruits of the Vedas are ceremonies performed before the (homa) fire; the fruits of an acquaintance with the scriptures are goodness of disposition and conduct. The fruits of women are the pleasures of intercourse and offspring.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Narada Smriti 12.19 Women have been created for the sake of propagation, the wife being the field, and the husband the giver of the seed. The field must be given to him who has seed. He who has no seed is unworthy to possess the field.</p>
<p>Skanda Purana V.iii.103.9-16 “[Atri said]…It is cited by expounders of the Vedas that a woman is one who gives sexual pleasure and a son…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honor killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed &#160; Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show Satyamev Jayate has once again brought the issue to public attention. In the discussions that followed the verse &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7866 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png" alt="" width="359" height="239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" />Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show <em>Satyamev Jayate</em> has once again brought the issue to public attention.</p>
<p>In the discussions that followed the verse <strong>यत्र</strong> <strong>नार्यस्तु</strong> <strong>पूज्यन्ते</strong> <strong>रमन्ते</strong> <strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>देवता</strong>  (Devatas reside where women are worshipped) was used repeatedly. This painted a misleading picture of the ancient indian society suggesting that misogyny sprung up from nowhere. A closer examination reveals, however, that this verse from Manu Smriti has been divorced from its context and the word <strong>“</strong><strong>पूजन</strong><strong>” or “</strong><strong>पुजा”</strong> has been interpreted rather arbitrarily to suit a particular view. We reserve the discussion of this verse for future articles.</p>
<p><span id="more-856"></span></p>
<p>Earlier there were 40 accepted Vedic sanskar (sacraments), now however only 16 of these are conducted. The first of these 16 sanskar is that of “<strong>Garbahabhan</strong>” (conception), the second being “<strong>Punsavan</strong>”. Before coming to the main subject of the article, I would like to place before the reader a few facts about these sanskar (sacraments).</p>
<p><strong>Varna System or Death System?</strong></p>
<p>What follows is a brief analysis of these sanskar (sacraments) and the caste system. In Hinduism the evil of caste gets associated with the person from his birth itself. On the face of it Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj seem to reject the birth based caste system and accept a social system based on merit but do they practice what they preach? To investigate this let us consider the following three verses from Manu Smriti. The first two of these occur as they are in Swami Dayanand’s <em>Sanskar Vidhi</em> published by Arya Sahitya Prachar Trust (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7867" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png" alt="" width="549" height="267" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a.png 652w" sizes="(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px" /></p>
<p>(A)&#8221;Garbhan and other Sanskar (sacrament) of dwija should be performed with holy rites prescribed by the Veda. Because these sanctify the body and purify in this life and after death&#8221; ( Manu Smriti 2-26)</p>
<p>(B)&#8221;By womb related sacraments (Garbhadan, Punswan, Simantyan), Jatkarma, Chudakarma and Upanyan sanskar (sacraments) the defects related to the womb and the semen of the Dwijas is removed&#8221; (Manu Smriti 2-27).</p>
<p>(C)“Let (the first part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s name (denote something) auspicious, a Kshatriya&#8217;s be connected with power, and a Vaisya&#8217;s with wealth, but a Sudra&#8217;s (express something) contemptible.</p>
<p>(The second part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s (name) shall be (a word) implying happiness, of a Kshatriya&#8217;s (a word) implying protection, of a Vaisya&#8217;s (a term) expressive of thriving, and of a Sudra&#8217;s (an expression) denoting service.” [Manu Smriti 2/31-32]
<p>The third verse is not from the above mentioned book however the idea is mentioned in the book in following manner</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7869" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png" alt="" width="550" height="66" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a.png 611w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>“The male child born should be named thus &#8211; if the child is Brāhman &#8211; name him ‘Devsharmā’, if he is Kshatriya- name him ‘Devvarmā’, if he is Vaishya &#8211; name him ‘Devgūpta’,if he is a Shūdra name him ‘Devdās’.</p>
<p>Here it has been advised to name a child in the naming ceremony (10 days after birth) according to the above mentioned rules.</p>
<p>Whether such practices can remedy deficiencies of semen or womb is irrelevant but a number of questions arise after reading the above, why is this practice limited only to the Dwijas (Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaishya)? What is the basis of this distinction drawn between the Dwijas (referred to as ‘twice-born’ henceforth) on one hand and the Shudras on another? Certainly there is no difference in merit of 10 days old twice-born and Shudra, then why is a child born in Shudra family believed to be a ‘Shudra’ and has ‘das’ appended to his name? These people who keep insisting that Varna system is not based on birth but on merit have no answers to these questions.</p>
<p><strong>Punsavan Sanskar (Sacrament)</strong></p>
<p>What exactly is this Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament)? Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelkar while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ sukta from Atharvaved, in his commentary of Atharvaved writes,</p>
<p>“The birth of son is called ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ and birth of girl is called ‘<strong>Straishuya</strong>’”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar has named the section where he explains this sukta as “Certain birth of son” this in itself explains the term ‘Punsavan’. Swami Dayanand’s associate who later became the leader of Sanatan Dharma, Pandit Bhimsen Sharma while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ writes,</p>
<p><strong>उत्पत्स्यमानगर्भस्य</strong> <strong>बेजिकगार्भिकदोषपरिहारार्न्थ</strong> <strong>पुंरूपत्वसंपत्तये</strong> <strong>च</strong> <strong>पुंसवनम्</strong></p>
<p>(षोडशसंस्कारविधी, तृतीय संस्करण,1926, पृ. 72-73)</p>
<p>“Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament) is conducted to remove the semen and womb related deficiencies of the unborn child and to make it male”</p>
<p>In other words the sanskar (sacrament) is conducted so that a male child is born and if the unborn child is female then it should be transformed to a male child. This is the ancient Vedic way of getting rid of female foetuses. Even if we leave aside the question of effectiveness of such a procedure, the mentality operating behind such practices can be easily seen. If the female foetus itself is converted to male foetus then there is no question of birth of girls. This indicates that why even today people do not wish a girl child to be born to them.</p>
<p>While today, scientific methods are used to detect the sex of the foetus and to kill it if it is a girl, in Vedic times the foetus itself was transformed (at least people wished to do so) to a male foetus. The underlying mentality is same, only the methods have changed.</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand presents five proofs related to Punsavan Sanskar, without mentioning their meaning. However, the meanings given by other Arya Samaji Scholars make the picture clearer. Below is the meaning given by Ramgopal Vidyalankar in his book titled <em>Sanskar-Prakash Arthart Mahrshi Dayanand Sarsvati Parnit Sanskarvidhi</em> on pages 43-44</p>
<p><strong>पुमानग्निः</strong> <strong>पुमानिन्द्र</strong><strong>: </strong><strong>पुमान्देवो</strong> <strong>ब्रहस्पति</strong><strong>:  </strong><strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>पुत्रं</strong> <strong>विन्दस्व</strong> <strong>तं</strong> <strong>पुमाननु</strong> <strong>जायतां</strong> <strong>स्वाहा</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>मंत्रब्राह्मण</strong><strong> 1/4/9]</strong></p>
<p>“Agni, Indra, and learned scholar of diverse disciplines &#8211; give you strength. May you get a strong son and let even his descendent be strong.” [Mantra Brahman 1/4/9]
<p><strong>शमीमश्वत्थ</strong> <strong>आरूढ़स्तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवानं</strong> <strong>कृतम्</strong> <strong>तद्वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेद्नं</strong> <strong>तत्स्त्रीष्वाभरामसि</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/1]</strong></p>
<p>“’Punsavan is done after a man as virile as a horse conceives a woman calm by nature as it is the best solution to get a son. The sanskar (sacrament) is conducted on women.” [Atharvaved 6/11/1]
<p>Let me also mention the interpretation of Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelekar</p>
<p>“(<strong>अश्व</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>त्थ</strong><strong>: </strong>) Peepal tree (<strong>शमी</strong> <strong>आरूढ़</strong><strong>:</strong>) where it grows on Shami tree (<strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवनं</strong> <strong>कृतं</strong> ) Punsavan is done there. (<strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>) This ensures birth of a son (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रीषु</strong> <strong>आ</strong> <strong>भरामसि</strong>) we give this to women ”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains the procedure of this sanskar (sacrament) in his exegesis of this verse</p>
<p>“1. The Peepal tree that grows on the Shami tree makes the foetus in the womb take male form. That is if a woman takes the medicine prepared out of this then she will definitely give birth to a son. 2. Such a Peepal tree ensures the birth of a son. 3. The consumption of it ensures the birth of a son. 4. Women should be given the medicine prepared from such a Peepal tree to ensure the birth of a son.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar continues</p>
<p>“The peepal tree growing on a Shami tree should be powdered and should be consumed with honey or milk etc. This makes the woman’s womb capable of producing a son. This medicine should be given to a woman who gives birth only to girls. This changes their womb and may generate strength to produce a male child.”</p>
<p>Now let us take a look at the second verse of ‘Punsavan’</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar writes</p>
<p><strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>रेतो</strong> <strong>भवति</strong> <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियामनुषिच्यते</strong> <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong> <strong>तत्प्रजापतिरब्रवित्</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/2]</strong></p>
<p>“God Prajapati has said that semen definitely is in man, this is nurtured in the woman and thus a son produced.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains this as</p>
<p>(<strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वे</strong> <strong>रेतः</strong> <strong>भवति</strong>)Semen definitely is in the man (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियो</strong> <strong>अनु</strong> <strong>षिच्यते</strong>) it is nurtured in the women ( <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>)it is a means to get a son,( <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अब्रवित्</strong> ) this is said by Prajapati .</p>
<p>Let us turn to the 3rd verse.</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar &#8211;</p>
<p><strong>प्रजापतिरनुमतिः</strong> <strong>सिनीवाल्यचीक्लृपत्</strong><strong>  </strong><strong>स्त्रैषूमन्यत्र</strong> <strong>दधत्पुमांसमु</strong> <strong>दधदिह</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/3]</strong></p>
<p>“Prajapati, Anumati and Siniwali (Sanvatsar, Pournima and Amavasya) complete the foetus. The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere, the rules related to male are described here.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar writes &#8211;</p>
<p>“(<strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अनुमतिः</strong>) Father should be determined to get a son (<strong>सिनी</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>वाली</strong> <strong>अचीक्लृपत्</strong>) and the mother should be capable (of bearing a son) only if this happens (<strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>उ</strong> <strong>इह</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) a male foetus is formed (<strong>अन्यत्र</strong> <strong>स्त्रैषूयं</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) otherwise a female foetus is formed..”</p>
<p>Whatever has been said about this third verse of ‘Punsavan’ sukta of Atharvaved is quite clear except the second part which can have three meanings</p>
<p>The first and second are given these scholars</p>
<ol>
<li>The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere the rules related to men are described here.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation could have been accepted if the rules concerning the birth of females had been mentioned in the Vedas elsewhere but we have to say with great disappointment that perhaps this is not true. For this reason this interpretation is unacceptable. However, even with this interpretation the importance given to the birth of a son can be clearly seen.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Male foetus is formed (in the conditions mentioned above) otherwise a female foetus is formed.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation given by Shri Damodar is accepted but the implications of such an interpretation are noteworthy. If this interpretation is true then definitely birth of a son would be wished for since ‘Punsavan’ is performed by everyone.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Third interpretation would be – Let girl/female foetus be placed in some other womb and male fetus be placed in this womb. Even this meaning exposes the underlying mentality which wishes for a male child and rejects a female child.</li>
</ol>
<p>So, these are the verses used to prevent a female child from taking birth and ensuring the birth a male child. It would not be wrong to call this the ancient and Vedic version of female foeticide. The Hindu scriptures enjoining ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ fail to even mention the sanskar (sacrament) named “<strong>Straisuy</strong>”</p>
<p>As far as Vedas are concerned women are not allowed to give birth to a female child, there however, is the command to give birth to 10 sons. A verse from Rigveda reads</p>
<p><strong>इमां</strong> <strong>तवमिन्द्र</strong> <strong>मीढ्वः</strong> <strong>सुपुत्रां</strong> <strong>सुभगां</strong> <strong>कर्णु</strong> <strong>।</strong> <strong>दशास्यां</strong> <strong>पुत्राना</strong> <strong>धेहि</strong> <strong>पतिमेकादशं</strong> <strong>कर्धि</strong><strong> ||</strong> -ऋग्वेद 10/85/45</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand writes the meaning of this verse as follows</p>
<p>O majestic man capable of nurturing semen! Give a married woman or widow the best son and grant her good fortune. Produce 10 sons for a married woman and consider the 11th to be a woman.</p>
<p>This makes it clear that the birth of a girl is neither desired nor considered good since ancient times. However such verses can neither change the way sex is determined nor can they prevent the birth of a girl child. As such a girl once born has to be accepted. But nothing changes after this</p>
<p>In the ‘<strong>Harish-Narad dialogue</strong>’ in <em>Aitreya Brahman</em> which is an explanation of the Rigved, Narad says:</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>कृपणं</strong> <strong>ह</strong> <strong>दुहिता</strong></p>
<p>“Daughter leads to suffering and is a cause of misery”</p>
<p>While explaining this, scholar Sayancharya quotes an ancient verse</p>
<p><strong>संभवे</strong> <strong>स्वजनदुः</strong> <strong>खकारिका</strong> <strong>संप्रदानसमयेर्थदारिका</strong> <strong>योवनेपि</strong> <strong>बहुदोषकारिका</strong> <strong>दारिका</strong> <strong>ह्रदयदारिका</strong> <strong>पितुः</strong></p>
<p>“When a girl is born, she makes relatives unhappy; when she gets married she takes away wealth. She commits a lot of mistakes in her youth that is why it is said that she cleaves her father’s heart”</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya writes with respect to ‘daughter’ in his Nirukt</p>
<p>“Daughter is called Duhita because she is <em><u>Durhita</u></em> (one who does bad) and <em>Durehita</em> (it is better if she stays far away). She is <em>Dogdha</em> (one who sucks parent’s wealth)” – (Nirukt Adhayay 3, Khand 4)</p>
<p>In the next Adhyay of the same book, while explaining the word  ‘Kanya’ Acharya Yaska writes,</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>क्वेयं</strong> <strong>नेत्व्य</strong></p>
<p>(Nirukt Adhyay 4 Khand 15)</p>
<p>“Kanya is so called because as soon as she takes birth parents start worrying about her marriage”</p>
<p>These examples show the negative view associated with the birth of girl in Hindu culture and Hindu religious scriptures. It is this mentality which is criticized in the Qur’an in the following words &#8211;</p>
<p>And when one of them is informed of [the birth of] a female, his face becomes dark, and he suppresses grief. He hides himself from the people because of the ill of which he has been informed. Should he keep it in humiliation or bury it in the ground? Unquestionably, evil is what they decide. (Qur’an 16/58-59)</p>
<p>Allah, the Exalted puts an end to the discrimination between a boy and a girl in the Qur’an</p>
<p>To Allah belongs the dominion of the heavens and the earth; He creates what he wills. He gives to whom He wills female [children], and He gives to whom He wills males. (Qur’an 42/49)</p>
<p>A point worth noting is that in this verse daughters are mentioned before sons. Commenting on this verse Sayyidina Wathilah ibn Aska said, fortunate is the woman who has a daughter as her first child.</p>
<p>Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) said,</p>
<p>If anyone has a female child, and does not bury her alive, or slight her, or prefer his sons to her, Allah will bring him into Paradise. [Narrated by Abdullah ibn Abbas; Abu Dawud, Kitaab al-Adab, Hadith 5127)</p>
<p>To conclude, I would like to say that to put an end to the evil practice of female foeticide and the negative view associated with a girl child, the mentality operating behind these needs to be destroyed. How do we do that? Well,</p>
<p><strong>किं</strong> <strong>ग्राहृयमग्राहृयमिति</strong> <strong>कवयो</strong> <strong>नात्र</strong> <strong>मोहिताः</strong><strong>, </strong><strong>अज्ञस्तु</strong> <strong>मूढ़मतित्वात्सतृणमभ्यवहारी</strong> <strong>।।</strong></p>
<p>Deciding between the acceptable and unacceptable is not difficult. A wise person embraces the acceptable and rejects the unacceptable but a foolish person due to his foolishness believes a cow and donkey to be the same.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scientific Evidence For Reincarnation?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/836/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life after death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moksha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reincarnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scientific]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ultimate bliss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/836/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Abu Adeeba &#160; &#160; INTRODUCTION Scouring the Hindu forums, discussion boards and apologetic websites, one will almost invariably find juxtaposed to the subject of reincarnation [1] scientific research on past-life regression therapy, near death experiences (NDE), out-of-body experiences (OBE), etc. as evidence for its validity. More often than not, Hindu&#8217;s make recourse to the same &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/836/" data-wpel-link="internal">Scientific Evidence For Reincarnation?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Abu Adeeba<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<h1><strong>INTRODUCTION</strong></h1>
<p>Scouring the Hindu forums, discussion boards and apologetic websites, one will almost invariably find juxtaposed to the subject of reincarnation [1] scientific research on past-life regression therapy, near death experiences (NDE), out-of-body experiences (OBE), etc. as evidence for its validity.<br />
More often than not, Hindu&#8217;s make recourse to the same evidences trumpeted by all those who believe in and propagate the theory of reincarnation-transmigration.<br />
Initially, the large number of references cited from so-called experts and pawned off as scientific proof may at first seem convincing to the unmindful or biased mindset. However, in light of real scientific evidence to the contrary, it quickly becomes apparent to the critically minded that these alleged evidences are highly suspect with critics and debunkers aplenty.<br />
<span id="more-836"></span><br />
What this article intends to show, <em>insha&#8217;Allaah</em> (God-Willing), is that any and all suggestions of incontrovertible proofs for past-life experiences is rejected by the mainstream scientific community due to the huge bulk of empirical research and data accumulated over the past few decades. The ones who have attempted to peddle these highly dubious results only to be convincingly rebutted are a very small fringe group that connivingly associate themselves to the scientific community.<br />
Of course, this has not deterred the many Hindus and their co-sympathisers from unashamedly magnifying and hyperbolising any and all pseudo-scientific research in their desperate attempt to validate the patently unjust theory of reincarnation.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<strong>EVIDENCE AGAINST REINCARNATION</strong><br />
The &#8220;scientific research&#8221; of Dr Ian Stevenson is usually the primary reference cited by many past-life propagandists. However, what many of these enthusiasts do not realise is that after spending half his career investigating alleged reincarnation cases, the late doctor had to grudgingly accept the fact that he had miserably failed to convince his many colleagues in the mainstream scientific community:<br />
Dr Stevenson himself recognized one glaring flaw in his case for reincarnation: <strong>the absence of any evidence of a physical process by which a personality could survive death and transfer to another body</strong>&#8230; But with rare exception, mainstream scientists &#8211; the only group Dr Stevenson really cared to persuade &#8211; tended to ignore or dismiss his decades in the field and his many publications. Of those who noticed him at all, some questioned Dr Stevenson&#8217;s objectivity; others claimed he was credulous. Still others suggested that he was insufficiently versed in the cultures and languages of his subjects to do credible investigations. [2] (bold, underline ours)<br />
This is unsurprising considering that the doctor had been investigating this &#8220;paranormal&#8221; subject for the past 40 years and yet &#8220;to date, the only researchers who have verified Stevenson&#8217;s findings about children who remember past lives are people he has funded himself via the Department of Personality Studies&#8221; &#8211; hardly disinterested and unbiased verifiers. Perhaps this failure was down to the mysterious phenomenon where &#8220;the majority of cases documented by Stevenson were no longer &#8216;active&#8217; at the time of their investigation. That is, the subject of the case had ceased to have recollections of the supposed previous existence and thus the evidence consists mainly of retrospective accounts by other people (e.g., parents) of the experient&#8217;s statement about that existence&#8221;. [3]
Little wonder, then, regarding his reputation in the psychiatric community, that he honestly avowed: &#8220;Not a few psychiatrists suspected that I had become unhinged&#8221;. [4]
In light of what follows, however, one will understand why it was that Dr Stevenson failed to convince his peers.<br />
Maarten Peters and his colleagues of the Department of Experimental Psychology at Maastricht University in the Netherlands conducted research on patients of reincarnation therapists who were hypnotised to help them remember their alleged past lives. The results found that &#8220;<strong>people who believe they had previous lives are committing a <em>source-monitoring error</em></strong><em>,</em> or an error in judgment about the original source of a memory&#8230; This is important because <strong>source-monitoring mistakes are the first in a sequence of events that psychologists believe lead to false memories</strong>&#8220;. (bold, underline ours)<br />
False memory or confabulation is the <strong>confusion of imagination with memory</strong>, and/or the confusion of true memories with false memories in order &#8220;to fill in gaps in one&#8217;s memory with fabrications that one believes to be facts&#8221;. [5]
Peters goes on to say:<br />
Once familiarity of an event is achieved, this can relatively easily be converted into a belief that the event did take place.&#8221; He adds: &#8220;A next possible step is that <strong>individuals interpret their thoughts and fantasies about the fictitious event as real memories</strong>.[6] (bold, underline ours)<br />
Moreover, &#8220;in many cases of false memories, it is very difficult to determine whether or not the perceived events actually occurred &#8211; that is, the &#8216;ground truth&#8217; can not be established.&#8221; [7]
Distinguished Professor Elizabeth F. Loftus of psychology at the University of California, Irvine, has conducted extensive research into the area of memory. She states:<br />
Hundreds of studies have been published documenting memory distortion induced by exposure to misinformation&#8230; [a phenomenon] called the <strong><em>misinformation effect</em></strong> (Loftus &amp;  Hoff man, 1989). [8] (italicised bold ours)<br />
The development of false memories for implausible events has been suggested as follows:<br />
First, the event must be perceived as plausible.<br />
Second, individuals must acquire the autobiographical belief that it is likely to have happened to them.<br />
Third, individuals must interpret their thoughts and fantasies about the event as memories.[9]
There have also been studies that have &#8220;demonstrated that our personal beliefs are susceptible to the influences of imagination&#8230; Research also suggests that behaviour, as well as beliefs, can be modified through imagination&#8221;. [10]
A research paper, which looked into the shaping of people&#8217;s beliefs and behaviour through imagination, titled <em>How Self-Relevant Imagination Affects Memory for Behaviour</em>, concluded<br />
Imagination is indeed a powerful tool. Even when people are not particularly motivated to change behaviour, imagination does lead to reported behaviour change&#8230; The results from this study demonstrate that <strong>researchers and clinicians cannot rely on participants or clients to accurately recall past behaviours or other attributes after self-relevant imagination has been employed</strong>. On the basis of these results, one must conclude that <strong>imagination is a powerful tool of suggestion that may play a critical role in the representation of one&#8217;s personal history</strong>. (bold, underline ours) [11]
In fact, so powerful are the &#8220;tricks of memory&#8221; that people can even convince themselves of absurd events, such as, having been abducted by aliens. Harvard experimental-psychopathology, Professor Richard McNally who ran studies on alien abductees, put the experiences down to &#8220;a form of sleep paralysis known in the profession as hypnopompic episodes &#8211; essentially a state, experienced by up to 30 percent of the population at some point in their lives, when the body is physically asleep, part of the mind is still dreaming, but another part of the mind is conscious of being awake&#8221;.<br />
He said, however, that many of these people convinced of their abduction experience &#8220;did have a<strong>strong tendency toward beliefs outside of the mainstream</strong>&#8220;. (bold, underline ours) He added:<br />
They&#8217;re not lying&#8230; They&#8217;re really sincere. They are, however, characterized by a range of<strong>New Age beliefs</strong>, by magical ideation-<strong>they tend to believe in past lives, crystals,reincarnation</strong>, alternative medicines. Second, they&#8217;re high on absorption-they can become entranced by a sunset, absorbed in a novel, they had imaginary playmates as children. (bold, underline ours)<br />
He went on to say that most of these so-called abductees &#8220;did not actually remember, at the time of awakening from their hypnopompic episode, that they had been abducted. What they did feel was intense discomfort; many then sought the help of therapists or counselors [sic]-under whose tutelage they began to &#8216;remember&#8217; that they had been abducted and experimented upon while in this strange state. In a different cultural context, the same individuals would likely have recalled being visited by witches, ghosts or Satan&#8221;.<br />
He further states that under the suggestive questioning of clinicians: &#8220;These individuals&#8217; minds are generating very powerful explanatory frameworks-under the guise of memory-for their sleep paralysis. They&#8217;re very resistant to reinterpretation.&#8221; Once this takes place, these memories &#8220;become an integral part of the individual&#8217;s self-identity&#8221; to the extent that they even display physiological responses under certain suggestive conditions. For example, &#8220;when asked to relive their experiences, respond in much the same way (sweaty palms, racing heartbeat, facial muscle tensions) as do traumatized war veterans&#8221;. [12]
While Costandi comments:<br />
Other researchers have shown <strong>how easy it is to distort peoples&#8217; recollections of real events, or to coax people into &#8216;remembering&#8217; entire events that did not happen</strong>&#8230; Work by other research groups shows that memories of highly implausible events, and even impossible events, such as alien abduction and reincarnation, can be planted just as easily. [13] (bold, underline ours)<br />
There also exists the pseudoscience known as &#8220;<strong>past life regression therapy</strong>&#8220;, which is based on the premise that traumas that occurred in previous lives contribute to current psychological and physical symptoms.<br />
In 1988, psychiatrist Brian Weiss published a series of cases focusing on patients who were hypnotised and age regressed to &#8220;go back to&#8221; the origin of a present-day problem. When patients were regressed, they reported events that Weiss interpreted as having their source in previous lives.<br />
However, with memories being so plastic and changeable, more scientifically rigorous and credible research found that the actual &#8220;perceived expectations of the therapist/experimenter can affect the production of reports associated with FMS [False Memory Syndrome], and also the consequent belief that the false memory is in fact true&#8221;.<br />
Newman and Baumeister (1996) and Spanos, Menary, Gabora, DuBreuil, and Dewhurst (1991), found that subjects assign more credibility to their pseudomemory when the therapist or experimenter express a belief in the possibility that such phenomena actually do occur. Wilson (1982, cited in Spanos, Menary, et al. 1991) ascertained that the time lapse reported between past lives was consistent with the therapists&#8217; beliefs regarding the issue. <strong>If the therapist believed that past lives followed directly after each other with no gap, their clients were found also to report it</strong>. Conversely, if therapists believed there was a time lapse between such lives, their clients&#8217; reports also reflected it.[14] (bold, underline ours)<br />
As for the techniques and results used in an attempt to prove past-life experiences, then Psychologist Donald A. Eisner after citing the research of Spanos <em>et alia</em> observed:<br />
<strong>Rather than evidence of reincarnation, these studies support the notion of a socially created identity re-enactment</strong>. <strong>Information during these past-life sessions came from a multitude of sources including TV shows, novels and wish-fulfilling daydreams</strong>. &#8230;<br />
<strong>There are no controlled research studies that demonstrate the viability of the underlying concept of reincarnation</strong>. <strong>None of the field studies</strong> to date has confirmed that people who are age-regressed [15] to an alleged prior lifetime <strong>have veridical recollection</strong>. The use of suggestive techniques tends to taint the examination process and may produce artifactual responses. [16] (bold, underline ours)<br />
Other research conducted by Nicholas P. Spanos, Evelyn Menary, Natalie J. Gabora, Susan C. DuBreuil, and Bridget Dewhirst, of Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, found that highly hypnotised hypnotic subjects, and thus extremely susceptible to suggestion, had what are known as a &#8220;hidden self&#8221;. These &#8220;hidden self experiments indicate that contextual cuing can lead motivated, nonsimulating subjects to define themselves as having a secondary identity and to respond in a manner consistent with that self-definition&#8221; to the extent that  &#8220;hypnotic past-life identities are viewed as socially constructed fantasies that are cued by the demands of the hypnotic past-life suggestions. This conceptualization suggests that the intensity with which subjects experience past-life identities may be related to a general propensity for becoming absorbed in fantasy activity and imaginative role playing&#8221;. In detail, they stated:<br />
Contrary to the reincarnation hypothesis (Wambaugh, 1979), past<strong>-life reportersfrequently supplied inaccurate historical information</strong>, did not possess information that might reasonably be expected of a person who actually lived in the relevant historical period, and <strong>made historical errors</strong> that would have been impossible for a person who lived in the era in question. Our findings are consistent with the hypothesis that <strong>past-life reports are fantasies that subjects construct on the basis of their often limited and inaccurate historical information</strong> (Kampman, 1976; Wilson, 1982). In constructing these fantasies, subjects tend to choose historical periods and localities with which they are relatively familiar. To meet the demands of the hypnotic regression suggestion, they weave events, places, and persons from their own life experiences into a historical fantasy drama that they then describe in the form of an autobiographical narrative given by a past-life identity.<br />
Kampman and Hirvenoja (1978) obtained findings consistent with this hypothesis by hypnotizing their past-life reporters again and asking them for the sources of their past-life reports. These subjects reported that stories heard as children, books, and events <strong>in theirown lives were the sources of information used to build their past-life identities</strong>. &#8230;<br />
<strong>Subjects with a propensity for engaging in fantasy and imaginative role playing in everyday life were particularly adept at becoming so absorbed in their past-life fantasies that their awareness of their primary identity tended to fade into the background</strong>. These <strong>highly imaginative subjects</strong> also tended to experience particularly intense past-life experiences. These findings are consistent with a substantial body of theory and evidence (Sheehan &amp; McConkey, 1982; Shor, 1970; Spanos, 1971; Spanos &amp; Barber, 1974) indicating that absorption in the construction of suggestion-related imaginings is associated with a partial fading of current reality concerns and with experiencing the behavioral and subjective events called for by suggestions. [17] (bold, underline ours)<br />
They continue:<br />
<strong>Subjects learn to develop past-life identities that are consistent with the expectations of their therapist or hypnotist</strong>. Our results are also consistent with findings indicating that hidden observer reports are shaped by expectations transmitted by experimental instructions (Spanos &amp; Hewitt, 1980; Spanos et al., 1983), with numerous studies indicating that subjects incorporate information acquired prehypnotically into their hypnotic enactments (Lynn, Nash, Rhue, Frauman, &amp; Sweeney, 1984; Orne, 1959; Spanos, Cobb, &amp; Gorassini, 1985). [18] (bold, underline ours)<br />
And they conclude:<br />
The present findings provide <strong>no support for versions of the reincarnation hypothesis</strong>holding that past-life responders invariably provide historically accurate accounts&#8230; Instead, our findings, along with the work of Kampman (1976) and Wilson (1982) support the usefulness of viewing <strong>hypnotically induced past-life identities as contextually generated, rule-governed, goal-directed FANTASIES</strong>. According to this hypothesis, subjects construct these fantasies to meet the demands of the hypnotic regression situation. The suggestions employed in this situation require that subjects&#8217; fantasies be framed as autobiographical historical minidramas that are narrated by a first-person singular identity other than the subject (i.e., by a secondary personality). To meet these demands, subjects tend to choose historical times and places with which they are relatively familiar or in which they have a special interest. Within these constraints, they construct a life story that weaves together plot lines, details, and characters that are derived from a wide range of sources (e.g., personal experience, television shows, novels) and that is expressed as a first-person report&#8230; Both the anecdotal findings reported by Wilson (1982) and the findings of Studies 2 and 3 demonstrate that past-life responders shape their past-life fantasies to correspond to the expectations transmitted by the hypnotist. [19] (bold, underline, capitals ours)<br />
These fantasies can also be induced and encouraged by and during the actual process of hypnosis, as Dr Robert Baker puts it:<br />
For a long while it was believed that hypnosis provided the person hypnotized with abnormal or unusual abilities of recall. The ease with which hypnotized subjects would retrieve forgotten memories and relive early childhood experiences was astonishing&#8230;<br />
However, when the veridicality of such memories was examined, it was found that many of the memories were not only false, but they were even outright fabrications. Confabulations, i.e. making up stories to fill in memory gaps, seemed to be the norm rather than the exception. It seems, literally, that using &#8220;hypnosis&#8221; to revive or awaken a person&#8217;s past history somehow or other not only stimulates the person&#8217;s desire to recall and his memory processes, but it also opens the flood gates of his or her imagination. [20]
A classic example of these shortcomings was demonstrated by the infamous &#8216;Bloxham tapes&#8217;. The Cardiff-based hypnotherapist, Arnall Bloxham, who was the subject of a BBC documentary and subsequently featured in a book by Iverson (1976/77), forwarded one particular case, amongst others, of Welsh housewife Jane Evans. Evans apparently provided details of six previous incarnations, which included Allison, a maid who lived in the house of a wealthy French merchant named Jacques Couer in the 15th century.<br />
Although Iverson felt that the case for reincarnation was established, subsequent investigation by Harris (1986) proved him wrong. In fact, in both of these cases and others, there were significant errors in the accounts produced. For example, Jane Evans reported that Couer was single with no children. In fact, he was married with five children &#8211; something that most maids would notice. Such errors provided the clue to the source of the story. A novel by Thomas B. Costain entitled <em>The Moneyman</em> was based upon Couer&#8217;s life but the author had taken the literary liberty of deliberately omitting Couer&#8217;s family as they kept getting in the way of the plot development. It appears that Evans had read the book and then forgotten reading it. During the hypnotic sessions these details had re-emerged and had been taken to be real memories.<br />
In the case of Jane Evans and many other similar claims, it is generally believed that no deliberate hoax was involved. Instead, <strong>these are seen as being cases of CRYPTOMNESIA (literally, &#8216;hidden memories&#8217;; see Baker, 1992)</strong>. It is argued that an individual can store away information from a variety of sources during his or her life, such as from novels, films, history books, or wherever, without later being aware of the source of the information. When the information is later recalled under hypnosis, perhaps elaborated upon by the individual&#8217;s own fantasies, the memories can be taken to be veridical. [21](bold, underline, capital ours)<br />
Steven Jay Lynn and Judith W. Rhue, Professors of Psychology at Ohio University, found similarities between past-life regression subjects and patients suffering from Multiple Personality Disorder (MPD &#8211; also known as (DID) Dissociative Identity Disorder). After categorically rebutting the notion that &#8220;although some believers in reincarnation hold that people can be hypnotically regressed back past their birth to previous lives (e.g. Wambaugh, 1979), <strong>the available evidence provides no support whatsoever for this notion</strong>. Instead, the available data suggest that past-life experiences and enactments are fantasy constructions (Baker, 1992; Spanos, Menary, Gabora, DuBreuil, &amp; Dewhirst, 1991)&#8221;, (bold ours) [22] they state:<br />
Past-life constructions are important because they are similar in many respects to the multiple identities of MPD patients. Like MPD patients, those exhibited by past-life responders often display moods and personality characteristics that are different from the person&#8217;s primary self, have a different name than the primary self, and report memories that the primary self was unaware of. Just as MPD patients come to believe that their alter identities are real personalities rather than self-generated fantasies, many of the subjects who enact past lives continue to believe in the reality of their past lives after termination of the hypnotic procedures. [23]
But, what is MPD/DID diagnosed as? According to the American Psychiatric Association&#8217;s Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorder, MPD/DID, though controversial, is considered a <strong>mental illness/disorder</strong>.<br />
<b>CONCLUSION</b><br />
There is so much more evidence that could be presented. However, for the sake of brevity, this should be sufficient for the unbiased and critical mind to realise that past-life experiences, connected to reincarnation or otherwise, are nothing more than fantasy driven claims made by those who may just be suffering from mental illness.<br />
Hence, where does this bulk of evidence presented by mainstream science leave those Hindus desperate to prove the validity of reincarnation through hook or by crook?<br />
We believe they are in a catch-22 situation, for we have shown that:</p>
<ol>
<li>The so-called evidence of past lives is rejected by the mainstream scientific community due to the presence of an overwhelming volume of empirical proof accumulated over the past couple of decades.</li>
<li>No amount of proof can vindicate Hinduism from the charge that the karmic theory and the concept of reincarnation portrays God as inherently unjust and cruel.</li>
</ol>
<h6></h6>
<h6></h6>
<h6>Footnotes</h6>
<h6>[1] We have covered this topic in detail showing how untenable this concept is and how it theologically renders the Creator as inherently unjust:  <a href="/index.php/2013/01/25/no-reincarnation-no-moksha-no-mukti-in-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Reincarnation, No Moksha, No Mukti in the Vedas </a> <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014151753/http://islamhinduism.com/responses/answering-agniveer/222-does-vedic-god-of-agniveer-deserve-worship" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Does Vedic God of Arya Samaj deserve worship? <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> <a href="https://truthabouthinduism.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/reincarnation-reality-or-myth/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Reincarnation: Reality or Myth? <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></h6>
<h6>[2] T. Shroder (2007), <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/02/10/AR2007021001393.html?nav=hcmodule" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><em>Ian Stevenson; Sought To Document Memories Of Past Lives in Children</em><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> , (The Washington Post, 11 Feb).</h6>
<h6>[3] H. J. Irwin, C. Watt (2007), <em>An Introduction to Parapsychology</em>, (McFarland &amp; Company, Inc.), p.210.</h6>
<h6>[4] J. Arehart-Treichel (2004), <em><a href="http://pnhw.psychiatryonline.org/content/39/23/21.full" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Psychiatrist Explores World Beyond &#8216;Normal&#8217;<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Psychiatric News, Vol. 39 No. 23, American Psychiatric Association, 3 Dec), p.21.</h6>
<h6>[6] C. Mims (2007), <em><a href="http://www.sciam.com/article.cfm?id=previous-life-memories-due-to-bad-memory" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Remember a Previous Life? Maybe You Have a Bad Memory<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Scientific American, 30 Mar).</h6>
<h6>[7] M. Costandi (2007),<em> <a href="http://ieet.org/index.php/IEET/more/costandi20070417" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Alien Abduction, Reincarnation and Memory Errors<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Institute for Ethics &amp; Emerging Technologies, 11 Apr).</h6>
<h6>[8] E. F. Loftus (2003)<em>, <a href="http://faculty.washington.edu/eloftus/Articles/AmerPsychAward+ArticlePDF03%20(2).pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Make-Believe Memories<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> , </em>(American Psychologist, Nov), p.868.</h6>
<h6>[9] G. A. L. Mazzoni, E. F. Loftus, I. Kirsch (2001), <em><a href="http://faculty.washington.edu/eloftus/Articles/mazzloft.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Changing Beliefs About Implausible Autobiographical Events A Little Plausibility Goes a Long Way<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied, Vol. 7 No. 1, 51-59, by the American Psychological Association).</h6>
<h6>[10] A. K. Thomas, D. E. Hannula, E. F. Loftus (2007), <em><a href="https://webfiles.uci.edu/eloftus/ThomasHannulaLoftus_Imag_ACP07.pdf?uniq=-z3dhko" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">How Self-Relevant Imagination Affects Memory for Behaviour<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Applied Cognitive Psychology, 21:69-86; published online 10 July 2006 in Wiley InterScience), p.70.</h6>
<h6>[11] <em>Ibid.</em>, pp.83-4.<br />
[12] S. Abramsky (2004), <em>Memory &amp; Manipulation</em>, (OCWeekly, 9 Sept), pp.<a href="http://www.ocweekly.com/2004-09-09/features/memory-manipulation/5" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">5<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> &#8211;<a href="http://www.ocweekly.com/2004-09-09/features/memory-manipulation/6" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">6<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> .</h6>
<h6>[13] M. Costandi (2007), <em>op. cit.</em></h6>
<h6>[14] K. Gow (1998), <em><a href="http://www.massey.ac.nz/~trauma/issues/1998-3/gow1.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">The Complex Issues in Researching &#8220;False memory Syndrome&#8221;<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (The Australasian Journal of Disaster and Trauma Studies Vol. 1998-3).</h6>
<h6>[15] Age regression is a controversial aspect of hypnotherapy in which the patient returns to an earlier stage of life in order to explore a memory or to get in touch with some difficult-to-access aspect of their personality.</h6>
<h6>[16] D. A. Eisner (2000), <em>The Death of Psychotherapy: From Freud to Alien Abductions</em>, (Greenwood Publishing Group), pp.166.</h6>
<h6>[17] N. P. Spanos, E. Menary, N. J. Gabora, S. C. DuBreuil, B. Dewhirst (1991), <em><a href="http://construct.haifa.ac.il/~ofram/spanos_et_al.pdf" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Secondary Identity Enactments During Hypnotic Past-Life Regression: A Sociocognitive Perspective<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> </em>, (Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, vol.61 No.2), pp.311-12.</h6>
<h6>[18] <em>Ibid.</em>, p.313</h6>
<h6>[19] <em>Ibid.</em>, p.318</h6>
<h6>[20] R. Baker (1992), <em>Hidden Memories: Voices and Visions from Within</em>, (Prometheus Books, Buffalo, N.Y.), p.152.</h6>
<h6>[21] C. C. French (2003), <em>Fantastic Memories &#8211; The Relevance of Research into Eyewitness Testimony and False Memories for Reports of Anomalous Experiences</em>, (Journal of Consciousness Studies, Vol.10, No. 6-7), p.164.</h6>
<h6>[22] S. J. Lynn, J. W. Rhue (1994), <em>Dissociation: Clinical and Theoretical Perspectives</em>, (Guilford Press, NY), p.140.</h6>
<h6>[23] <em>Ibid.</em></h6>
<h6> Reprinted with slight changes and with kind permission of islam-sikhism.info. Original title: &#8216;<strong>Evidence&#8217; for Reincarnation DEBUNKED</strong>, by Abu Adeeba. Source: <a href="http://www.islam-sikhism.info/soter/debunk01.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.islam-sikhism.info/soter/debunk01.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></h6>
<h6></h6>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/836/" data-wpel-link="internal">Scientific Evidence For Reincarnation?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
