<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>inheritance &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/inheritance/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 11:05:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Responses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in vedas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi The writer has tried his level best to show Woman are highly revered in the Vedas. How can they claim that Vedas give equal status to women when Vedas are known for oppressing women, it says Women are devoid of intelligence, she shall not inherit, Women are like sly fox. Women &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>The writer has tried his level best to show Woman are highly revered in the Vedas. How can they claim that Vedas give equal status to women when Vedas are known for oppressing women, it says Women are devoid of intelligence, she shall not inherit, Women are like sly fox. Women in Vedas is nothing but a commodity, Yajur Veda 30.5 and 30.9 explicitly states that Ishwar has created women for sexual enjoyment. It doesn&#8217;t even pray for daughter let alone giving them equal rights, Veda only prays for the birth of Son, it says daughter should be born somewhere else, this asserts that women in Vedas is merely looked as a commodity. Some Hindu apologists instead of accepting  oppressive verses, has tried to show equal status of women in Vedas by misquoting them, through means of deceit.</p>
<p><span id="more-620"></span></p>
<p>When they couldn&#8217;t find verses that gives equal rights or praises women, they used the verses addressed to Vedic Goddesses to show women are highly revered in Vedas, they has also used verses which are to be recited during Marriage ceremony. Those verses can never be used to prove that women are given equal status in Vedas, if Vedas really praises women then Hindu apologists should furnish references from Vedas that gives equal inheritance, verses praying for birth of daughter etc. This is a response to a Hindu fanatic&#8217;s article. The reason behind making a response to his article is because he has misquoted the Vedic mantras and commentaries to suit is vested interest, to deceive the gullible people. The writer is being deceitful to propagate his religion as taught by his guru Mulshankar (Dayanand). He pretends to be quoting Arya Samaj Hindi translation but in fact he has mistranslated the Hindi translations also. This is why I will mostly be using Arya Samaj translation as well as orthodox translation of Shri Ram Sharma (Gayatri Parivar) for few verses.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajur 16.44</p>
<p>There should me a women army. Let the women be encouraged to participate in war.</p>
<p>(Book: Vagambhraniya, Author: Dr Priyamvada Vedbharti)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 16.44 &#8220;Food to the expert in deeds, and to the manager of cow-pens. Food to the efficient couch maker, and to him who lives peacefully in his house. Homage to him who is skilled in mental deliberations, and to him who is proficient in diving deep into intricate topics. Food to him who explores the mysteries of nature, and to him who dwells in inaccessible mountain caves.&#8221; Tr. Devi Chand (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 13.26: O woman, you do not deserve to be defeated by challenges. You can defeat the mightiest challenge. Defeat the enemies and their armies. You have valour of thousands. Please us all.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.26 Thou art Ashadha, Conquering One. Conquer our foemen, conquer thou the men who fain would-fight with us. A thousand manly powers hast thou: so do thou aid and quicken me.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="497" height="300" class="wp-image-7716" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71-300x181.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>Here the word Ashadha or Ishtika is translated as Brick, and earth or speech by some. It is a brick which the queen forms first. The Satapatha Brahmana briefly mentions about Ashadha,</p>
<p>Satapatha Brahmana 7.4.2.32-33. He then lays down the Ashadha (invincible brick),–the &#8216;invincible one&#8217; being this earth, it is this earth he thus lays down. He puts it on the fore-part (of the altar-site), for this earth was created first. And as to its being called Ashadha. The gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Pragapati, strove together. The gods saw this invincible brick, even this earth; they put it on (the altar); and having put it on, they conquered (and drove) the Asuras, the enemies, the rivals, from this universe; and inasmuch as (thereby) they conquered (asahanta), it is called Ashadha. In like manner the Sacrificer, after putting on that (brick), conquers (and drives) his spiteful rival from this universe (or, from everything here).</p>
<p>And there is one more verse from Brahmanas which is a commentary of the Vedic verse,</p>
<p>Satapatha Brahmana 7.4.2.39. &#8216;Thou art Ashadha, the conquering,&#8217; for the gods thereby conquered the Asuras,–&#8217;conquer the enemies! conquer the hostile!&#8217; as the text, so the meaning;–&#8217;thou hast a thousand energies: do thou speed me!&#8217; a thousand means</p>
<p>So this verse is not addressed to a women but to a Brick.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 20.85: Noble woman motivates us to be on path of truth, love and harmony.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 20.85 &#8220;Vedic text, the impeller of truthful speeches, the inspirer of perceptions, expatiates on God.&#8221; Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 2.41.16: O woman, you are the motherly force that provides direction to our life.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This verse is not addressed to a common woman, it&#8217;s about people offering prayer to the Goddess, the correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.14.16 Best Mother, best of Rivers, best of Goddesses, Sarasvati, We are, as &#8217;twere, of no repute and dear Mother, give thou us renown. <img decoding="async" width="625" height="118" class="wp-image-7717" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 6.61.2: The way a powerful river breaks down even strongest rocks and hills, in same manner an intelligent woman destroys the fraud propagated by perverted ones. May we bow to such intelligent women.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.61.2 She with her might, like one who digs for lotus-stems, hath burst with her strong waves the ridges of the hills. Let us invite with songs and holy hymns for help Sarasvati [Vedic Speech according to Arya Samaj] who slayeth the Paravatas.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="437" height="379" class="wp-image-7718" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp3.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73.png 437w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73-300x260.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 437px) 100vw, 437px" /></p>
<p>This verse is addressed to goddess Saraswati but according to the Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation it refers to Vedic Speech.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharvaveda 7.57.1: Whenever I am hurt emotionally or physically, woman – as a mother, wife, sister etc – provides healing touch and rejuvenates me. I bow in humble respect to her.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.57.1 Whatever trouble hath disturbed and shaken me–I speak with hope, I move, imploring, &#8216;mid the folk What harm my body in myself hath suffered, now let Sarasvati relieve with fatness.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="147" class="wp-image-7719" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp4.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74-300x71.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>According to the Shripad Damodar (Arya Samaj) Hindi translation above, this verse is also addressed to Hindu Goddess Saraswati. This is a prayer made to Saraswati.</p>
<p>The writer has quoted some verses about discrimination of women in Vedas and then tried to explain it. He again repeated the same trick i.e., to twist the verses and has given his own interpretation. I will reply to his mistranslated Vedic verses one by one.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that was prevalent in all societies and more so in Biblical and Quranic society. Bible, Quran an Hadiths are full of such references. But Vedas have no mention of Niyoga. People have interpreted Vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations. But neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society. On contrary, many a prophets of Christianity and Islam got children from slave-girls but never made them their wives! Prophet Abraham is supposed to have even attempted to abandon his slave-girl to death after having child from her. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria. God only knows the veracity of these stories and support for sex slavery in Bible and Quran. But as far as Vedas are concerned, any relation apart from one single wife/husband is clearly considered to be cause of miseries.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Readers are requested to go through these articles for evidence of Niyoga from Vedas and Arya Samaj scholars,</p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/05/11/niyoga-aur-naari/" data-wpel-link="internal">नियोग और नारी (Niyoga aur Naari)</a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Arya Samajis </a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/12/27/hinduism-lust/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Lust </a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a></p>
<p>Can the writer elaborate what are those &#8220;emergency&#8221; situations where prostitution would be required? Don&#8217;t such people have wives to relieve their desire? Seems like the Rishis created these Niyoga verses to satisfy their whims. The founder of Arya Samaj Dayanand Saraswati wrote</p>
<p>&#8220;Niyoga is clearly allowed by the Veda&#8221; Satyarth Prakash, Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 4, p.142, Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>When Dayanand (who is considered the greatest revivalist) says Veda sanction Niyoga then how can the author defy his Guru?</p>
<p>The writer is acting like a small kid who when caught tries to accuse others of doing the same thing. You can&#8217;t even compare having a child on slave with Niyoga, because Niyoga is a Vedic practice where the wife cohabits with other men to beget children or the Brahmin cohabits with several women to relieve his desires. He claims Quran is full of such (Niyoga) references but doesn&#8217;t cite any. As far as Prophet&#8217;s relation with Hazrat Mariya is concerned there are ample evidence to show that Prophet Muhammad (S.A.W) married Marriya al Qibtiyya r.a,</p>
<p>&#8220;The muqawqis, or King of the Copts, gave the Prophet (S) two wives as a gift. The Prophet (S) married one[i.e., Mariya], who became the mother of the Prophet&#8217;s son Ibrahim, and he gave the other one to Hassan as a wife&#8221;.</p>
<p>(Haythami said in Majma al-zawaid, &#8220;Tabarani in al-Aswat and al-Bazzar related it, and the narrators in al-Bazzar&#8217;s chain are all scholars of sound Hadith as stated by Hisham Kabbani in Encyclopedia of Islamic Doctrine: Remembrance of Allah and Praising the Prophet, p. 76 Vol. II)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>The reason why birth of a daughter became a curse in last 1000 years was due to the butchers from West and Central Asia coming in name of Islamic Jihad to kill men and rape women. The entire history of last 1000 years is full of resistance against these terrorists. Thus people wanted sons who could fight these terrorists or at least not be raped by them the way they used to rape women. Birth of daughter thus became a curse because safeguarding the dignity of a daughter was a challenging task. This is why purdah system came in India. This is why dowry system became prevalent – ensuring safety of women became a risky thing. And soon these evil practices became part of the culture. However Vedas are complete against all this and it is time we get back to Vedas.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>As usual the writer tries to blame Muslims for the evil Vedic practices. First of all I want to talk about the Dowry topic. He says all the evil practices became prevalent in India due to Muslims. Can he provide a single reference where Dowry is demanded from women in Islam? Dowry system exists only in Hinduism. Secondly If Muslim rulers were so powerful, cruel and religious bigots that Hindus killed their daughters due their fear then why didn&#8217;t the Muslim rulers establish a fully dominant Muslim empire? They could have easily converted all the Hindus by the force of Sword. But almost all the rulers treated Hindus and Muslims alike, never discriminated on the basis of religion and this is evident from the fact that Hindus still make 80% of the population in India, Even the bravest Hindu rulers were defeated by Muslim rulers, you can ascertain the strength of Muslims rulers by this fact.</p>
<p>In the entire article the writer couldn&#8217;t quote a single verse that prays for the birth of a daughter, on contrary Vedas say a daughter should be born somewhere else and only a son should be born. With such kind of verses Female infanticide became widely prevalent in Ancient India. A historian writes</p>
<p>&#8221;In ancient India approximately 1500 BC, there is evidence of nomadic Vedic Aryan tribes who invaded the land and introduced the custom of Female infanticide (Moor 1811). It was the customary that these tribes would pray for the birth of a male child and pray against the arrival of a female.&#8221; – Violence and Abuse in Society: Understanding a Global Crisis, p.121, Angela Brown Miller</p>
<p>He further writes</p>
<p>Edward Moor (1811), a British soldier reporting on female infanticide in ancient India, specified the reasons that made it a necessary practice. In his treatise advocating for female children, &#8220;Vedic Dark Ages&#8221;, he wrote &#8220;Obliterating female children was a convenient way to alleviate financial ruin; large dowries prescribed by the Vedas implied that female children were an economic burden; women were of little use to Aryan Warmachines.&#8221; In those cultures, the gruesome methods used to murder female infants included posioning, starvation, suffocation, smothering, drowning in a pit filled with milk, burying alive, throwing baby to the crocodiles in the Ganges River, cutting up the child and then feeding it to animals, and throwing the baby girl in the air and chopping her up with unsheathed swords as she fell.&#8221;-(ibid)</p>
<p>So these evil practices were introduced by none other than Hindu invaders themselves.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>The word &#8216;Putra&#8217; in Vedas is generic and does not necessarily mean a son but implies a child. This is same as &#8216;mankind&#8217; does not mean only men but all human beings. In most mantras of Vedas though, word &#8216;Praja&#8217; is used which again means children. As mentioned previously, there are mantras which desire specifically a daughter. For example, Rigveda 10.159.3, 8.31.8, 9.67.10, Yajurveda 22.22, Rigveda 4.32.23 and Atharvaveda 10.3.20. Thus all these claims of Vedas being male-centric is childish at the best.</p>
<p><strong>REPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.138 Because a son delivers (trayate) his father from the hell called Put, he was therefore called Putra (a deliverer from Put) by the Self-existent (Svayambhu) himself.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 7.9 The son saves his father from the hell called Put; therefore he was named &#8220;Putra&#8221;<br />
by the Self-existent himself.</p>
<p>Above verses clears all doubts over the term Putra. If the word Putra denotes Children then what does the word Putri mean? Moreover the term &#8220;Veer&#8221; is also used in Vedas to mean Son. The word &#8220;Veer&#8221; is a masculine word generally used for Warrior but in Vedas it&#8217;s been used for Son also. Other verses which the author quoted have been refuted. Its surprising to see that as per Hindu scripture the Son saves the father from hell while the daughter is a burden who does bad. Read <a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</a> for the refutation of the verses he quoted about Birth of daughters in Veda.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Punsawan Sanskar is recommended for aspirants of <strong>both sons and daughters</strong>. So there is no male bias here.</p>
<p>The mantra meaning has been distorted to suit the agenda. The mantra has a deep meaning. But simply put it means that: &#8220;By Grace of Ishwar, woman is able to have a womb and nurture the child therein. May the woman have a son if she desires and planned so ELSE she may have a girl. [Atharva Veda 6.11.3]&#8221;</p>
<p>Thus the mantra simply implies that if couple has planned for a boy, may boy be born else girl be born</p>
<p>What translators have done is to translate &#8216;Anyatra&#8217; as &#8216;Elsewhere&#8217; <strong>instead of &#8216;In other condition</strong> or else&#8217;.</p>
<p>The Vedic methods of procreation suggest ways of deciding either a boy or a girl. But regardless of the</p>
<p>case, Punsawan Sanskar is practiced by all Veda followers. Hence there is no gender bias here.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>It is mentioned in Grihya Sutras,</p>
<p>Sankhayana Grihya Surtra 1.19.6 …Pragapati has created him, Savitar has shaped him. Imparting birth of females to other (women) may he put here a man…</p>
<p>Now who will claim that the translation is incorrect as this verse from Grihya Sutra confirms the Vedic verse on Pumsavan Sanskar. The author himself is distorting the translation and blaming others. Shripad Damodar (Arya Samaj) writes in the commentary about Punsavan,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="313" height="95" class="wp-image-7720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp5.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75.png 313w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75-300x91.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 313px) 100vw, 313px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;The birth of a son is called &#8216;Punsavan&#8217; and birth of a girl is called &#8220;Straishuya&#8221;.</p>
<p>Arya Samaji scholar named Vaidyanath Shastri translates Atharva Veda 6.11.1 as follows,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 6.11.1 &#8220;Ashvatta rooted on the tree of Shami is medicine in conducting the ceremony of Pumsavan. It being used there to perform the Pumsavan, a male birth is certain. This is the means of finding a son. We the house-holders bring and use it in the woman.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>It is also mentioned in Garuda Purana,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.93.11-13 &#8220;Garbhadhana (conception) [is performed] after the menstruation, Pumsavana before throbbing of the child in the womb [with purpose to get a son]&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Vishnu Smriti,</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 27.2 The Pumsavana (ceremony to cause the birth of a male) must be performed before the embryo begins to move.</p>
<p>Read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> for more information on Punsavan and Female foeticide</p>
<p>The word &#8220;Anyatra&#8221; means somewhere, elsewhere, in another place. The author has derived the meaning &#8220;in other condition&#8221; from Jaydev&#8217;s translation, while giving the meaning from Jaydev&#8217;s translation it would have been better for him to quote complete translation of Jaydev Sharma (Arya Samaj),</p>
[Jaydev] Atharva Veda 6.11.3…In other conditions there is possibility to conceive a girl child but by this procedure the woman conceives a male child only. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="463" height="222" class="wp-image-7721" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp6.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76.png 463w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>This is a clear discrimination against birth of daughters. Another verse from Atharva Veda has a prayer to beget several sons,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 3.23.3 Bring forth a male, bring forth a son. Another male shall follow him. The mother shalt thou be of sons born and hereafter to be born.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="781" height="87" class="wp-image-7722" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp7.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.jpeg 781w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39-300x33.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39-768x86.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 781px) 100vw, 781px" /></p>
<p>If there is already a son then why does it pray for birth of sons again and again? It is somehow understandable if Vedas pray for one son as daughters don&#8217;t have the right to perform Vedic tasks which can be performed only by a son. But Vedas praying for sons again and again is a discrimination which has lead the Indian society to adopt the evil practice called female infanticide.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.33.17 Do not try to rule over the thought process of woman. She can think very fast and in multiple dimensions.</p>
<p>This is also true. Women can think and connect at emotional levels that is impossible for men. That is why women can nurture children in ways men cannot even think of. What translators have done is to distort &#8216;Ashasyam&#8217; to mean &#8216;cannot be taught&#8217;while it means &#8216;cannot be ruled&#8217;. Then they translated &#8216;Raghum&#8217; to mean &#8216;little&#8217; while it actually means &#8216;agile&#8217;or &#8216;able to move rapidly in variety of locations&#8217;or &#8216;dynamic&#8217;. That is why Raghu of Raghukul to which Ram belonged was named so.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This writer is distorting his own Vedas, he is deliberately mistranslating the verse, the correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.33.17 Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline, Her intellect hath little weight.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="208" class="wp-image-7723" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77-300x125.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Above is a Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation, and I am quoting two other much more clear Hindi translations by Shri Ram Acharya and Pundit Ram Govind Trivedi,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="556" height="75" class="wp-image-7724" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp9.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78.png 556w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78-300x40.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 556px) 100vw, 556px" /></p>
<p>Pundit Ram Govind Trivedi&#8217;s Hindi translation,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="431" height="139" class="wp-image-7725" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp10.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79.png 431w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px" /></p>
<p>Mahrishi Manu writes</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.18 For women no (sacramental) rite (is performed) with sacred texts, thus the law is settled; women (who are) destitute of strength and destitute of(the knowledge of) Vedic texts, (are as impure as) falsehood (itself), that is a fixed rule.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.95.15 &#8220;Do not run away from your duties due to indulgence in a woman. Do not share confidential details of country with anyone. They may be wolves in garb who want to destroy you and your country. A woman befriended for sensual purposesis a wolf in disguise. Hence stay away from sensual vices to protect the country.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thus the particular mantra can be interpreted variously. The particular mantra is part of an allegorical conversation between Pururava and Urvashi. Pururava has several meanings like Cloud, Air and Person. Urvashi means electricity, speech or a woman. Thus the mantra, rather Sukta, provides deep insights. Let us try to understand the context by taking it as conversation. Interestingly this mantra is uttered by the woman herself!</p>
<p>The deep meanings of mantra also unravel that all those women indulged in luring people by glamor – read actresses, models etc – are basically wolves in disguise. So far the country keeps adoring the Aishwarya Rais and Kareenas and Katrinas and ignoring Rani Laxmis and Ahilya Bais and Rani Karnavatis, we simply cannot prosper. Glam-girls are wolves in disguise. And when political leadership starts getting close to them, nothing can be better recipe for national disaster. This mantra thus asserts that considering women as objects for sensual pleasure is not advisable.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This is the same author who is quoting verses out of context and now asking everyone to read it in context. Below is the correct translation along with Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.95.15 Nay, do not die, Pururavas, nor vanish: let not the hideous wolves devour thee. Female friendships do not exist. With women there can be no lasting friendship: hearts of hyenas are the hearts of women.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="490" height="206" class="wp-image-7726" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp11.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80.png 490w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80-300x126.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" /></p>
<p>So where in this verse does it say that it refers to women who lures? This verse refers to women in general, it&#8217;s not confined to particular type of women, people like the author should stop giving their own interpretation. Yaska Acharya in his book Nirukta 5.13 writes that Urvashi is the name of a Nymph. Further this verse is explained in Srimad Bhagawatam/Bhagwad Purana,</p>
<p>Bhagawad Purana 9.14.36-38: &#8220;Urvasi said: My dear King, you are a man, a hero. Don&#8217;t be impatient and give up your life. Be sober and don&#8217;t allow the senses to overcome you like foxes. Don&#8217;t let the foxes eat you. In other words, you should not be controlled by your senses. Rather, you should know that the heart of a woman is like that of a fox. There is no use making friendship with women. <strong>Women as a class</strong><br />
<strong>are merciless and cunning.</strong> They cannot tolerate even a slight offense. For their own pleasure they can do anything irreligious, and therefore they do not fear killing even a faithful husband or brother. Women are very easily seduced by men. Therefore, polluted women give up the friendship of a man who is their well-wisher and establish false friendship among fools. Indeed, they seek newer and newer friends, one after another&#8221;.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON writes in the commentaries of these verses</p>
<p>&#8220;Canakya Pandita has advised, visvaso naiva kartavyah strishu raja-kuleshu ca: &#8220;Never place your faith in a woman or a politician.&#8221; Unless elevated to spiritual consciousness, everyone is conditioned and fallen, what to speak of women, who are less intelligent than men. Women have been compared to sudras and vaisyas (striyo vaisyas tatha sudrah). On the spiritual platform, however, when one is elevated to the platform of Krishna consciousness, whether one is a man, woman, sudra or whatever, everyone is equal. <strong>Otherwise, Urvasi, who was a woman herself and who knew the nature of women, said that a woman&#8217;s heart is like that of a sly fox</strong>. If a man cannot control his senses, he becomes a victim of such sly foxes. But if one can control the senses, there is no chance of his being victimized by sly, fox like women. Canakya Pandita has also advised that if one has a wife like a sly fox, he must immediately give up his life at home and go to the forest…<strong>Urvaśī frankly explained the nature of a woman</strong>. Because of her nature, a woman can respond to even a slight offense from her husband by not only leaving him but even killing him if required….Because women are easily seduced, the Manu-samhita enjoins that they should not be given freedom. A woman must always be protected, either by her father, by her husband, or by her elderly son. If women are given freedom to mingle with men like equals, which they now claim to be, they cannot keep their propriety. The nature of a woman, as personally described by Urvasi, is to establish false friendship with someone and then seek new male companions, one after another, even if this means giving up the company of a sincere well-wisher&#8221;. Source for commentaries of verses <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.36" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">36<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.37" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">37<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.38" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">38<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>So according to Srimad Bhagawatam and the commentary by such great scholar of Hinduism, this Vedic verse refers to &#8220;Women as a Class&#8221; not to women like Kareenas, Katrinas, And that all women are like sly fox, cunning, polluted.</p>
<p>The Rishi and Rishika as well as the Deities of this hymn are Urvashi and Puruava, which means their conversation and all that they are saying is a divine inspiration/commandment. So how can some Hindus claim it is Urvashi&#8217;s personal views, thus they are not divine words? The deities of this hymn are Puruava and Urvashi which is enough to prove my point.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>&#8216;Yajur Ved (Taitriya Sanhita)- &#8220;Women code says that the women are without energy. They should not get a share in property. Even to the wicked they speak in feeble manner&#8221; [Yajur Ved 6/5/8/2]
<p>Shatpath Puran, preachings of the &#8216;Yajur Veda&#8217; clubs women, &#8216;shudras&#8217; (untouchables), dogs, crows together and says falsehood, sin and gloom remain integrated in them. [14/1/1/31] In &#8216;Aiterey Puran&#8217;, preaching of the &#8216;Rig Veda&#8217; in Harsih Chandra – Narad dialogue, Narad says: &#8220;The daughter causes pain&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>1. The first reference is not clear. In any case Taitriya Samhita is not original Yajurveda. Kindly provide a reference from actual Yajurveda (Madhyandina Shukla Yajurveda Samhita to be specific, which is the actual Veda Samhita).</p>
<p>2. There is no text called Shatpath Puran and Aiterey Puran. They are Shatpath and Aitereya Brahmans. In any case, again these references are not from Vedas. Further we request the author of these allegations to provide the exact verse</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>Well, it&#8217;s not our fault if there are so many corrupted Vedas available, even the Vedas which you claim to be original is not authentic at all nor can you prove it&#8217;s authenticity. But can you show a reference from your &#8220;Original&#8221; Vedas that talks about equal inheritance? That verse is from Krishna Yajur Veda and is believed by orthodox Hindus (Mainly south Indians) to be correct/Authentic Vedas along with Shukla Yajur Veda. But the most authentic Smriti of Arya Samaj the Manu Smriti also makes no mention of equal inheritance, it rather says</p>
<p>Manu 8:416. A wife, a son, and a slave, these three are declared to have no property; the wealth which they earn is (acquired) for him to whom they belong.</p>
<p>Further Rig Veda also says that a woman will not inherit the property. Refer to my article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Inheritance for Women in Vedas</a>,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.31.2 &#8221;The son does not transfer paternal wealth to his sister. He makes her receptacle of the embryo of her husband. When parents procreate children of either sex, one (the male) becomes the performer of holy rites (he is the legal inheriter), the other (the female) is to be enriched with gifts.&#8221; Tr. Satyaprakash Saraswati (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>There is no polygamy in Vedas, Vedas strictly prohibit Polygamy. Vedas stands only for monogamy.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Where is the reference, We As far as Polygamy in Vedas is concerned there are numerous verses which talks about multiple wives of a man, I will quote few of them</p>
<p>7.18.2 For like a King among his wives<br />
thou dwellest: with glories, as a Sage, surround and help us…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="122" class="wp-image-7727" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp12.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81-300x67.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p>Above Hindi translation is of Gayatri Parivar.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.116.10…who was without kindred, and made him the husband of many maidens. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="588" height="133" class="wp-image-7728" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp13.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82.png 588w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82-300x68.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 588px) 100vw, 588px" /></p>
<p>For more information read <a href="/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hindu Dharma</a> for more details.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>The Aryans in those days used to attack the original inhabitants of this place, or other tribe within their own race, loot them and snatch away their women. Thus, these militant, wicked men had more wives. This custom of polygamy helped a great deal in bringing down the women. Rig Ved 10/59 says that Lord Indra had many queens that were either defeated or killed by his principal wife.</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Any evidence, manuscripts or any vague reference to hypothesis of either Aryan invasion theory or Aryans being a race or even any tribe claiming to be Arya killing or plundering anyone? Please cite a single reference to this most stupid hoax of Aryan Invasion.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Here is the reference</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 What do the cattle for thee among the Kikatas, they yield no milk to mix with the Soma, they need not the vessel (for the libation) Bring thou to us the wealth of Pramaganda; give up to us, O Maghavan, the low caste. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="509" height="270" class="wp-image-7729" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp14.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83.png 509w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83-300x159.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /></p>
<p>Manu Smriti 7.96 Chariots and horses, elephants, parasols, money, grain, cattle, women, all sorts of (marketable) goods and valueless metals belong to him who takes them (singly) conquering (the possessor).</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Our challenge is open to all – Cite one single verse in all 4 Vedas that justify Sati Pratha, or support polygamy, or insult women, or justify sex-slavery and we shall quit Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>Let us add one more allegation referring to Rigveda 10.18.7 which Hindu-haters translate to mean &#8220;widow woman should go into fire&#8221;. However what the shameless haters have done is to change the word &#8220;Agre&#8221; in the mantra (which means going ahead) to &#8220;Agne&#8221; which means fire. The mantra by the way has nothing about widow. It means that: In matters of household management, wife should be the leader.</p>
<p><strong>Allegation:</strong></p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda opines that even at that time women used to have sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. The hymn says:&#8221;O woman, get up and adopt the worldly life again. It is futile to lie with this dead man. Get up and become the wife of the man who is holding your hand and who loves you. [Rig Ved 10/18/8]. Apparently this shows that woman is considered to be a property. Whenever and whosoever desired, could become her master.</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Opinion of Vivekananda or practice of &#8216;that&#8217; time is none of our concern. Many Hindus go to worship graves or even support Jihadi terrorists of Kashmir. That does not make this a practice sanctioned by Vedas or Hinduism.</p>
<p>2. The meaning of this mantra provided has been slightly distorted and misinterpreted to suit one&#8217;s mindset of hatred. Actual meaning is: &#8220;O woman, get up from here and come back to the world of living ones. Do not waste your life in grief of one who is dead. You have the children of the person who had held your hand and became your husband, to take care of.&#8221;</p>
<p>3. The next mantra (where this mantra comes in Atharva Veda 18th Chapter) refers to a childless widow. It says: &#8220;I have seen a young widow rising up from grief of dead to marry again and start her life again away from gloom and darkness.&#8221;</p>
<p>4. Thus the mantras give the noble lesson that a widow should not continue repenting on dead one but start life afresh and continue with her responsibilities. These mantras form the foundation in which widow remarriage is encouraged and Sati Pratha is discouraged. And fools quote these very mantras to showcase the entirely opposite stand!</p>
<p>I agree that condition of widows has been miserable for several centuries. This has been primarily because the first targets of all butchers who invaded from West Asia in name of Islam was to rape women – be it army of Qasim, Ghazni, Ghori, Khilji, Lodhi, Babur, Akbar or whosoever. Thus widows would have no one to even fight and lay their life for their dignity. Thus widowhood started being regarded as a curse. And soon it became a evil practice. Thanks to efforts of 19th century reformers especially Arya Samaj, this is no more the case with Hindu society that knows Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>4. But the plight of women in Pakistan is extremely horrible. With no rights for divorce and the shameful Hudood ordinance, it has been a nightmare being a woman in a Muslim dominated country.</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Those verses are mistranslated by the writer. The writer himself should quote the reference as a refutation and then explain it. The correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.18.7 Let these unwidowed dames with noble husbands adorn themselves with fragrant balm and unguent. Decked with fair jewels, tearless, free from sorrow, first let the dames go up to where he lieth</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.18 .8 Rise, woman, (and go) to the world of living beings : come, this man near whom thou sleepest is lifeless: beget children from this appointed husband [through Niyoga], the suitor who took thee by the hand.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="506" height="222" class="wp-image-7730" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp15.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84.png 506w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84-300x132.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /></p>
[This verse is translated into English from Hindi Bhasya]
<p>The verse Rig Veda 10.18.8 is much more worse than one can imagine, this verse is spoken by the dead husband&#8217;s brother, this is mentioned in Aswalayana Griha Sutra 4.2.</p>
<p>As per the Vedic rule, after the death of the husband, the dead husband&#8217;s bother or any other man is considered Devar i.e., he can have intercourse with the widow at anytime to fulfill his desire and to beget sons.</p>
<p>Arya Samaj commentary on the Rig Vedic verse 10.18.8, page 512 states: &#8220;When a woman capable of conceiving a child becomes widow then she may contract Niyoga with the Appointed Husband to beget childre&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="541" height="98" class="wp-image-7731" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp16.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85.png 541w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></p>
[Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/rugveda_v5/pages/p512.gif" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/rugveda_v5/pages/p512.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>The author says remarriage is strongly encouraged in Vedas but cites no reference for it. As per the Vedic law, a widow should either live a life of austerity i.e., not wearing colorful clothes, jewellery, not laughing etc., or else should enter the pyre of her Husband. She can&#8217;t desire to have sex with other men, but other men without any hesitation can have it with her. it is mentioned in</p>
<p>Parasara Smrti 4.32 If a woman follows her departed lord, by burning herself on the same funeral pile, she will dwell in heaven for as many years as there are hairs on the human frame, which reach the number of three crores and a half.</p>
<p>So a woman should either remain widow or ascend the pyre, but why should a woman have this option? Why not make this same rule applicable for men also? As per Hindu scripture a man can marry after the death of his wife but if a husband dies then the wife should either ascend her husband&#8217;s pyre or live a life of celibacy. Niyoga is clearly sanctioned by Maharishi Manu in Manu Smriti 9.81. Swami Dayanand Saraswati also discouraged widow remarriage and also said that it is prohibited. Then how can the author go against the teachings of his Guru.</p>
<p>Looks like the author has vowed to blame Islam and Muslims for all the evil practices sanctioned by the Vedas. Women are war booty in Vedic Dharm</p>
<p>As far as Divorce is concerned, a Woman can never ask for divorce</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 5. 154. Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife.</p>
<p>Hindu reformist organization like Arya Samaj did nothing for the betterment of women as the Vedas opposes it. Arya Samajis supports castiesm and Niyoga so how can the author claim such crap. The author writes</p>
<p>&#8221; Thus widows would have no one to even fight and lay their life for their dignity. Thus widowhood started being regarded as a curse.&#8221;</p>
<p>Didn&#8217;t the writer just say that remarriage is strongly encouraged in Vedas? if it is so then why these widows were not remarried so that their Husbands may protect them? Isn&#8217;t it the duty of Brother or Son as well to protect the widow? Maharishi Manu writes,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.65 In the sacred texts which refer to marriage the appointment (of widows) is nowhere mentioned, nor is the remarriage of widows prescribed in the rules concerning marriage.</p>
<p>But in case when there is a remarriage of women, the remarried woman, her husband and her son will be isolated, this is what Maharishi Manu says</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.160 …the son begotten on a re-married woman, the son self given, and the son of a Sudra female, (are) the six (who are) not heirs, (but) kinsmen.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti .166 …the husband of a remarried woman, and a carrier of dead bodies, (all these) must be carefully avoided.</p>
<p>Sati Pratha was existent in India before the advent of Muslims. Does the writer mean to say that Mudri the wife of Pandu and wives of Hindu god Krishna practiced Sati Pratha due to the fear of Muslim invaders? As there is evidence from Hindu scriptures to show that Sati Pratha was a Vedic custom practiced by some women,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.38 &#8220;The 8 queens of Krishna, who have been named, with Rukmini at their head, embraced the body of Hari, and entered the funeral fire. Revati also embracing the corpse of Rama, entered the blazing pile, which was cool to her, happy in contact with her lord. Hearing these events, Ugrasena and Anakadundubhi, with Devaki and Rohini, committed themselves to the flames.&#8221;</p>
<p>For more information read the article <a href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a>. The evil practice of Sati Pratha came into existence not because of Muslims, instead the Muslim rulers tried to stop this evil Vedic practice</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Though Mughals tried to impose restrictions on Sati Pratha but could not stop this evil practice. The position of a widow was miserable in the Hindu society. They were not allowed to use ornaments.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Muslim women had property right of their Husband and father but Hindu women had no property right. The Hindu female had her right only on ornaments and precious articles.&#8221;- Pratiyogita Darpan, p.133, by Upkar Prakashan.</strong></p>
<p>It has become habit of Hindu fanatics to start talking about other countries just to cover the ugly part of Hinduism. Islam gives women the right to divorce unlike Hinduism which doesn&#8217;t allow women to divorce and even says that widow should either ascend pyre of her husband or live her entire life in simplicity and chastity and chastity here includes obscene practice called Niyoga. Practices like Sati, Niyoga, Dev Daasi, female infanticide shows which religion is oppressive to women. There has been 500% increase in rape of Dalit women. The Indian court had to ban many inhumane Vedic practices and the writer in his hypocrisy crediting Arya Samaj.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Allegation</strong>:</p>
<p>In Rig Veda there are references to slave girls being given in charity as gifts. After killing the men-folk of other tribes, particularly of the native inhabitants, their women were rounded up and used as slave girls. It was custom to present slave girls to one other as gifts. The kings used to present chariots full of slave girls to their kith and kin and priests (Rig Veda 6/27/8). King Trasdasyu had given 50 slave girls. It was custom to present slave girls to Saubhri Kandav (Rig Veda 8/38, 5/47/6).</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Not again! The mantra in 6.27.8 has a &#8216;Vadhu&#8217; word which has been misquoted blatantly and foolishly. The sukta refers to national security. The actual mantra means: &#8220;May the wise king appoint a council of 20 able dynamic persons to create strategies to defend the nation from enemies.&#8221; The word &#8220;Vadhumatah&#8221; means one who is capable and dexterous in handling multiple situations smartly.</p>
<p>2. The reference to King Trasadasyu has been wrongly given again showcasing that no one even bothered to check the references. But whatever be the case, Tradasyu means one who defeats terrorists and criminals and hence ensures peace and progress. Saubhari means a noble person who takes care of students well. The actual mantra in Rigveda 8.19.36 means: &#8220;The king who is very philantrophic and protector of noble ones, who has defeated the terrorists has provided me 50 Vadhus.&#8221;</p>
<p>3. Now question is that what does Vadhu mean? Vadhu means anything that brings strength, vitality, protection or bliss. Since Vedic philosophy believes that women are source of all happiness that come in a society, Vadhu refers to a new bride who enters home of in-laws. Thus it can refer to a daughter-in-law or wife or a bride in general. It can also mean an armed force that protects the nation. Thus in no way the mantra refers to slave girls. If you take literal meaning of bride, then it means that King gave 50 already wed women to a teacher. Obviously it then means that he arranged for marriage of his graduating students. But a more sensible meaning would be that the king gave a battalion of 50 to a general to protect the country. But no way, can it refer to a slave girl.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>How can someone give &#8220;already wedded women&#8221;? A bride is not presented to anyone, only a slave girl is presented. The author has mistranslated the verses, below are the verses with correct Hindi translation of Shri Ram Acharya,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.27.8 The opulent supreme sovereign Abhy Avartin, the son of Chayamana, presents, Agni, to me two damsels riding in cars, and twenty cows</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="510" height="106" class="wp-image-7732" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp17.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86.png 510w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86-300x62.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 510px) 100vw, 510px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.19.36 A gift of fifty female slaves<br />
hath Trasadasyu given me, Purukutsa&#8217;s son, Most liberal, kind, lord of the brave.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="558" height="91" class="wp-image-7733" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp18.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87.png 558w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87-300x49.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 558px) 100vw, 558px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.126.3 Ten chariots drawn by bay steeds, and carrying women, stood near me, given me by Swanaya and a thousand and sixty cows… <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="541" height="98" class="wp-image-7734" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp19.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88.png 541w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></p>
<p>If these verses are referring to Bride/Wife then can Hindu tell us How can wives be presented to someone? Is it Niyoga or some other obscene Vedic practice? A slave is a commodity which can be sold, purchased or gifted and that&#8217;s what we read in Vedas here, the Woman were gifted to others. The Arya Samaj translation says,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.52.3 Eat, Indra, our (offered) cakes and butter; derive enjoyment from our praises, as a lover from women.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="509" height="281" class="wp-image-7735" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp20.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89.png 509w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89-300x166.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /></p>
<p>The Arya Samaj translation has translated the word Vadhu as Stree (Woman) in this verse, further the commentary states,</p>
<p>&#8220;…Like the man longing for a woman is blissed by getting her…&#8221;</p>
<p>The sentence here in this verse &#8220;Vadhuyur yoshanaam&#8221; means one fond of women. The word Vadhu also means Woman, even the author writes</p>
<p>&#8221; Even the most modern Amarkosh 3.102 simply states &#8220;Vadhurjaya Snusha Stree Cha&#8221; or &#8220;Vadhu means Wife, Daughter-in-law or Woman&#8221;</p>
<p>Maharishi Manu writes about types of slaves in the most authentic Smriti of Arya Samaj the Manu Smriti,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 8.415 There are slaves of seven kinds, (viz.) he who is made a captive under a standard, he who serves for his daily food, he who is born in the house, he who is bought<br />
and he who is given, he who is inherited from ancestors, and he who is enslaved by way of punishment.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Upanishad that,</p>
<p>Brihadayanaka Upanishad 6.2.7 He said: &#8216;You know well that I have plenty of gold, plenty of cows, horses, <strong>slaves</strong>, attendants, and apparel; do not heap on me what I have already in plenty, in abundance, and superabundance.&#8217;</p>
<p>So it is evident that Slavery was prevalent in Vedic period and sanctioned by the Vedic texts.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>As for intercourse without marriage, Vedas strictly recommend against it. They recommend a relationship between man and woman that is based on commitments and for a purpose. Hidden relationships or goalless relationships are both rejected</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Mr Reference forgot to mention the reference, Can he cite a single reference that prohibits it? Vedas permits extra martial sex and adultery, read my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>As for incest (brother-sister or father-daughter relationship), Vedas recommend harshest punishment</p>
<p>that sets example for society. Further, wine drinking is considered a foolish act</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Where is the reference for this? I don&#8217;t think it is very difficult to mention the source for what you say, you just have to type it. Or at least give the reference wherein Ishwar prohibits incest? If there isn&#8217;t any then why defend it?</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Let us first provide meaning of Atharva Veda 20.96.15. It says: &#8220;We shall destroy the person who molests/rapes a woman or kills her children posing as her brother or protector&#8221;. This mantra justifies why punishment for rape is death sentence as per Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>Now let us provide meaning to actual mantra being alleged to have intercourse between father and daughter. This is Rig Veda 1.164.33. The mantra explains the process of food/herb generation through rainfall. It says: Sunlight is like my father because he provides me nourishment and the earth is like my mother because she supports and feeds me. Sun and Earth face each other as if two armies stand against each other. Clouds impregnate the earth with rainfall so that food and herbs are produced that provide us nourishment. Thus this mantra describes a natural phenomenon through allegory and nowhere states that incest is recommended.</p>
<p>Please also note that &#8216;Duhita&#8217; means one obtained from churning. Thus the mantra also implies that earth is formed from a part of sun that separated out in a process similar to churning. Astro-physicists can corroborate if this process of creation of earth from sun is indeed correct or not.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>The correct translation for this verse is,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.15 May we exterminate from hence, who in the form of brother, husband, or paramour, approaches thee, and seeks to destroy thy offspring.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="194" class="wp-image-7736" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp21.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90-300x118.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>I have provided Arya Samaj Hindi translation also, so where does it say Ishwar destroys the person who &#8220;Rapes/Molests Women&#8221;, This verse is talking about Ishwar protecting the embryo in womb. This is clearly mentioned in Rig Veda 10.96 the entire hymn speaks about this. I wonder didn&#8217;t the writer read previous verses of Atharva Veda 20.96.15 or he deliberately distorted the meaning of this mantra to present it for his interests. Those verses will clear the doubt,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.12-13 …The malady of evil name that hath attacked thy babe and womb. That which destroys the sinking germ, the settled, moving embryo, That which would kill the babe at birth, even this will we drive far away.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="450" height="364" class="wp-image-7737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp22.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91-300x243.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>As far as Rig Veda 1.164.33 is concerned, the writer has mistranslated that verse also, If Vedas really prohibit incest then why doesn&#8217;t he quote the verse? The fact is Vedas directly or indirectly promotes incest but doesn&#8217;t prohibit it. Read my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya gives the following meaning for the word Duhita,</p>
<p>&#8220;Daughter is called Duhita because she is Durhita (one who does bad) and Durehita (it is better if she stays far away). She is Dogdha (one who sucks parent&#8217;s wealth)&#8221; -Nirukt 3.4</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>In the name of &#8216;beejdan&#8217; (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of the women was not safe. The so called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with other man&#8217;s wife. From &#8216;Niyog pratha&#8217; it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that women were looked upon as mere child producing machines. In The Position of women in Hindu Civilization, Dr. B. R. Ambedkar writes: &#8220;Though women is not married to man, she was considered to be a property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only son could be successor to the property.&#8221; Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says [Arya Niti Ka Bhadaphor, 5th ed., p. 14]: &#8220;No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic man could not keep even the relations brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery/adultery named &#8216;Niyog&#8217;. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognize neither their sister nor their daughter and also did not keep the relations with them in mind. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what a miserable plight of women was society in then.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S</strong><br />
<strong>RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Once more vague allegations and no reference. Once more my request: Cite authentic references from Vedas to claim anything for Hinduism and not some historical allegations.</p>
<p>2. Ambedkar is not an authority on Hinduism. He admits in his writings that he has no knowledge of</p>
<p>Sanskrit and has referred only to western authors in translations of Vedas.</p>
<p>3. And who is this Gajdhar Prasad Baudh? Yet another Prophet or reincarnation of some old prophet that his words are taken so seriously?</p>
<p>4. As for incest (brother-sister or father-daughter relationship), Vedas recommend harshest punishment that sets example for society. Further, wine drinking is considered a foolish act. In fact anything that dumbs mind – wine, lust or anger – is considered foolishness in Vedic custom. But may be this new Prophet has come with some new revelations! We request your new Prophet to cite specific references instead of vague allegations. (I know this statement is getting repetitious but we have no other option)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati (Mulshankar) the founder of Arya Samaj wrote in his book</p>
<p>&#8220;Those, however, who cannot control their passions may beget children by having recourse to Niyoga.&#8221; By Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Satyarth Prakash, Ch 4, p.130, Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>He also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife and she is pregnant, he may contract Niyoga with a (widow) and beget offspring on her…&#8221; – Satyarth Prakash, Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 4, pg140 Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>As we can see, it states that if a man (particularly Brahmin) is unable to control his lust then he can have sex with the widow in the name of Niyoga or Beejdan you can say. This guy is busy making his own sect, his beliefs contradict the teachings of his guru Mulshankar, and also he does not view scholars like Vivekananda as authoritative. Whenever such claims are made which the Veda sanctions Mr. Reference insists for references but Mr. Reference doesn&#8217;t provide the reference from Vedas where incest is prohibited. Can Mr. Reference furnish the evidence from Vedas wherein Ishwar recommends harsh punishments for incestuous acts? Vedas does not prohibit incest but it promotes incest in several verses. For more details on obscenity read to my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Read Part 2 of this article </strong><a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Responses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Make sure you read the first part of this article, Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part 1 CLAIM: VEDAS PRAY FOR BIRTH OF DAUGHTERS It is true that the birth of the son was celebrated from last 100 years. But this was not because of a Vedic injunction. This is because of the Jihadis who were killing &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Make sure you read the first part of this article, </strong><a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part 1</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM: VEDAS PRAY FOR BIRTH OF DAUGHTERS</strong></p>
<p>It is true that the birth of the son was celebrated from last 100 years. But this was not because of a Vedic injunction. This is because of the Jihadis who were killing men and raping the women, so Sons were wished to defend from these Jihadis and to prevent rape. <strong>On contrary, there are specific verses in Vedas that pray for begetting daughters! Refer Rigveda 10.159.3</strong>, Rigveda 8.31.8, Yajurveda 22.22, Rigveda 4.32.23 and Atharvaveda 10.3.20.</p>
<p><span id="more-596"></span></p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:<br />
</strong></p>
<p>The interesting thing to note is some Hindus always blame Muslims for the Vedic verses oppressing women and treating them like third class citizens. Woman in Vedas is merely seen as a commodity. There are verses that prays only for the birth of a Son and doesn&#8217;t wish for Daughter, in fact the Vedas even says that a girl should be born somewhere else and 10 Sons should be born in this womb (this is the context of the hymn), this is the reason why the writer is talking about the so called Vedic verses wishing for Daughters.</p>
<p>In reality there isn&#8217;t a single verse which says so, Vedas pray for the birth of a Son in many passages like the entire hymn of Atharva Veda 6.11. and 7.48 are dedicated for the birth of a son and several verses like Atharva Veda 14.1.22, 12.3.47, 2.36.3, 14.2.72, Rig Veda 3.31.1, 10.85.42-45 and so on pray for the birth of a Son only but I don&#8217;t find a single verse that wishes for daughter.</p>
<p>All the verses the writer has quoted are mistranslated although he claims to be using &#8220;Authentic&#8221; translation. I will mostly be using Arya Samaj translations and also orthodox Hindi translations of renowned Hindu scholars like Shri Ram Acharya, Swami Karpatri and Pundit Ram Govind Trivedi.</p>
<p>The first verse he quoted about Daughter&#8217;s birth is Rig Veda 10.159.3, first let&#8217;s see what he wrote in another article</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 21</p>
<p>Rig 10.159</p>
<p>A women speaks after waking up in morning, &#8220;My destiny is as glorious as the rising sun. I am the flag of my home and society. I am also their head. I can give impressive discourses. My sons conquer enemies. My daughter illuminates the whole world. I myself am winner of enemies. My husband has infinite glory. I have made those sacrifices which make a king successful. I have also been successful. I have destroyed my enemies.&#8221;</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>He claimed that Rig Veda 10.159.3 prays for birth of a daughter but according to his own translation we can&#8217;t find any sentence where the birth of a daughter is wished. Here is the correct translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.159.3-6My Sons are slayers of the foe, my Daughter is a ruling Queen… and rid me of each rival wife. Destroyer of the rival wife, Sole Spouse, victorious, conqueror. The others&#8217; glory have I seized as &#8217;twere the wealth of weaker Dames.…I have subdued as conqueror these rivals, these my fellow-wives, That I may rule this Hero and the folk.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="449" height="175" class="wp-image-7742" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-92.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-92.png 449w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-92-300x117.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 449px) 100vw, 449px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="453" height="357" class="wp-image-7743" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-93.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-93.png 453w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-93-300x236.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /></p>
<p>These verses doesn&#8217;t pray for the birth of a daughter rather this is a prayer of a greedy Queen who wants to get rid of her co-wives so that she may rule the kingdom. His last sentence is correct to an extent</p>
<p>The context of this verse is that a Queen has many co wives, and she is praying for the destruction of her co-wives so she may have control over all the wealth and rule the kingdom. It even states that she destroyed her rival wives. Can this verse which depicts a woman as greedy, wealth monger, killer of innocent rival wives be used to show that Women are praised in Vedas?</p>
<p>The correct translation for the next verse the writer has quoted is,</p>
<p>Yajurveda 22.22 &#8220;warrior ; the cow giving abundant milk, the ox good at carrying burden ; the swift courser ; the woman skilled in domestic affairs, May this sacrificer be blessed with sons&#8221;. Tr. Devi Chand. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="508" height="188" class="wp-image-7744" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-94.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp3.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-94.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-94-300x111.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></p>
<p>This verse also prays for the birth of a son only, and says that Women (Stri not daughter) should be skilled in domestic work, it doesn&#8217;t say that daughter should be born. This verse rather projects a woman as a slave who is used only for domestic work.</p>
<p>Rigveda 4.32.23 Like two slight images (puppets) of girls, unrobed, upon a new-wrought post, So shine the Bay Steeds in their course.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="85" class="wp-image-7745" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-95.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp4.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-95.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-95-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>This verse is used by some Orthodox Hindus to prove Idol worship in Vedas. This verse doesn&#8217;t talk anything about begetting a daughter.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.3.20 As glory dwelleth in a maid, and in this well-constructed car, So may the Charm, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="115" class="wp-image-7746" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-96.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp5.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-96.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-96-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.31.8</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="535" height="212" class="wp-image-7747" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-97.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp6.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-97.png 535w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-97-300x119.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 535px) 100vw, 535px" /></p>
<p>The above verse is translated as &#8220;The man and woman who obeys Ishwar and who does good deeds gets good Son…&#8221;</p>
<p>This verse do not speak of birth of a daughter, as we see here, other translations states that &#8220;They are blessed with sons&#8221;, the Arya Samaj Hindi translation also speaks of a Son born to parents who obeys Ishwar, So does that mean Ishwar will curse the people who do not follow him by giving them a Daughter? Griffith&#8217;s translation also doesn&#8217;t mention anything about begetting sons or daughters.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.67.10 May Pusan, drawn by goats, be our protector, and on all his paths Bestow on us our share of maids.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="93" class="wp-image-7748" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-98.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp7.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-98.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-98-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>This verse does not pray for the birth of a daughter rather it is longing for WOMAN and praying to get women for carnal purpose. The Sanskrit word is Kanya which is translated as Maiden or Lady. Arya Samaj translations like Satyaprakash and Tulsi also does not mention anything about bestowing daughters.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.47.6 mentions that: &#8220;<strong>Those educated women who happily choose their husbands and then give birth to noble children, plan and train their life and those of children in same manner as one weaves a cloth from threads slowly and steadily.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.47.6 &#8220;For him worshippers lengthen praises and works of adoration, and for him mothers (cosmos) sew garments of rays. Rejoicing in the contact of their impregnation, the rays, the consorts, of the sun, come to our presence by the path of the sky, to meet him.&#8221; Tr. Saty Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>It does not talk about the &#8220;Educated Women&#8221;, rather this verse talks about a Woman weaving garment for her Son (according to Shri Ram Acharya translation).</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 5.10: O woman, realize your potential. You are a lioness who can destroy criminals, ignorance and vices and protect the noble ones.</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is.</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 5.10 &#8220;O speech, thou pronouncest words and overawest foes, attain to the learned. O speech, thou art the dispeller of ignorance, and remover of evils, purify the religious-minded people. O speech, thou art the destroyer of ignoble character and the subduer of mean demeanour, aborn thyself for the well-behaved learned persons.&#8221;- Tr. Devi Chand (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="467" height="368" class="wp-image-7749" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-99.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-99.png 467w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-99-300x236.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>This verse is not even addressed to a woman, secondly it talks about the Vedic speech. The verse is in femininity because the addressee is Ved<br />
Vani (Vedic Speech/words) which are feminine in Hindi and Sanskrit language.</p>
<p><strong>TRANSLATION BLUNDER OF THE WRITER</strong></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Atharva 14.1.20</strong></p>
<p>Hey wife! Become the queen and manager of everyone in the family of your husband.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Similar meaning</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 660)</p>
<p><strong>He mentioned this same verse in the same article with different translations</strong>,</p>
<p><strong>Atharva 14.1.20</strong> Oh wife! Give us discourse of knowledge</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>The bride may please everyone at her husband&#8217;s home through her knowledge and noble qualities.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 660)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.20 Let Bhaga take thy hand and hence conduct thee: let the two Asvins on their car transport thee. Go to the house to be the household&#8217;s mistress, and speak as lady to thy gathered people.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="202" class="wp-image-7750" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-100.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp9.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-100.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-100-300x123.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>This verse does not ask the wife to give knowledge, nor it says to become the queen, this verse talks about a Bride and Bridegroom. The author should quote the 22<sup>nd</sup> verse which prays for Sons and Grandsons.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.22… With sons and grandsons<br />
sport and play, rejoicing in your happy home.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="474" height="133" class="wp-image-7751" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-101.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp10.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-101.png 474w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-101-300x84.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 474px) 100vw, 474px" /></p>
<p>Read the article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a> for English translation of Arya Samaj.</p>
<p><strong>REPEATED TRANSLATION BLUNDER OF THE WRITER</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://agniveer.com/women-in-hinduism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Yajurveda<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> 10.26: O woman, you provide bliss and stability to world. You are source of valour.</p>
<p>Before I continue, I want to quote the same verse that this same fanatic quotes in his other article,</p>
<p><a href="http://agniveer.com/women-in-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Yajur<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Veda 10.26</p>
<p>In this mantra it is enforced that the wife of ruler should give education of politics to the others. Likewise the king do justice for the people, the queen should also justify her role.</p>
<p>(Book: Vagambhraniya, Author: Dr Priyamvada Vedbharti)</p>
<p>His translation differs on the same verse, so how can we the trust such person. The correct translation is,</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 10.26 Fair art thou, good to sit on, womb of kingship. Sit on the fair one, sit on that which offers a pleasant seat: sit in the womb of kingship.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="475" height="291" class="wp-image-7752" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-102.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp11.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-102.png 475w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-102-300x184.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 13.18: O woman, you are as strong as earth and are on very high pedestal. Protect the world from path of vices and violence.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.18 Thou art the earth, the ground, thou art the all-sustaining Aditi, she who supporteth all the world. Control the earth, steady the earth, do thou the earth no injury.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="120" class="wp-image-7753" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-103.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp12.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-103.png 567w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-103-300x63.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" /></p>
<p>This verse is addressed to Earth and Aditi (a goddess).</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 4.14.3: O brilliant woman, remove ignorance with your bright intellect and provide bliss to all.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.47: O woman, may you be strong and powerful like a rock. May you gain brilliance of sun and have a long prosperous life that benefits all.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.47 I place upon the lap of Earth the Goddess, a firm auspicious stone to bring thee children. Stand on it, thou, greeted with joy, resplendent: a long long life may Savitar vouchsafe thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="478" height="222" class="wp-image-7754" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-104.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp13.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-104.png 478w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-104-300x139.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.14.3 Red Dawn [Usha] has come, riding with brightness onward, distinguished by her beams, gay-hued and mighty. Dawn [Usha] on her nobly-harnessed car, the Goddess, awaking men to happiness, approacheth.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="440" height="344" class="wp-image-7755" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-105.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp14.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-105.png 440w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-105-300x235.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 440px) 100vw, 440px" /></p>
<p>This deity in this verse is Usha the Goddess of Dawn and it is addressed to her not to a common woman.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 20.84: May the scholarly woman purify our lives with her knowledge, noble actions and guidance.</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Actually this verse is addressed to the Hindu goddess Saraswati, but Arya Samajis considers it to be Vedic speech, So here the verse is addressed to Vedic speech not to women as per the Arya Samaj translation,</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 20.84 May Vedic speech, our purifier, powerful through the force of diverse forms of knowledge, with wisdom and riches acquired through enterprise, beautify our Yajna&#8221;. Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="455" height="179" class="wp-image-7756" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-106.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp15.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-106.png 455w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-106-300x118.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px" /></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 7.46.3 Teach the husband ways of earning wealth</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>Protector of children, having definite knowledge, worth thousands of prayers and impressing all directions, O women, you accept prosperity. O wife of desrving husband, teach your husband to enhance wealth.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 1, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 804)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Here is the Hindi translation of the verse by a Arya Samaji scholar,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="392" height="322" class="wp-image-7757" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-107.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp16.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-107.png 392w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-107-300x246.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /></p>
<p>According to Tulsi Ram&#8217;s and Griffith&#8217;s translation this verse is addressed to Sinivali (A Goddess), read the first verse of this hymn which is addressed to the Goddess moreover the husband here is the Hindu god Vishnu. This is also a payer made to Goddess requesting her husband to bestow riches. Your doubts will be cleared if you read all 3 verses of this hymn,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.46.1-3 O broad-tressed Sinivāli, thou who art the sister of the Gods, Accept the offered sacrifice, and, Goddess, grant us progeny. Present the sacrifice to her, to Sinivāli, Queen of men, Beautiful-fingered, lovely-armed, prolific, bearing many a child. Thou who as Queen of men art Indra&#8217;s equal, a Goddess coming with a thousand tresses, To thee our sacrifices are performed, O Consort of Vishnu Goddess, urge thy Lord to bounty!</p>
<p>The Commentary and Hindi translation of Kshemkarandas Trivedi is also distorted, His translation is same as I quoted above and below is his commentary,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="68" class="wp-image-7758" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-108.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp17.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-108.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-108-300x34.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Women being clever in domestic work, saving the money earned by their husbands should nurture the children.&#8221;-Commentary by Kshemkaran Das Trivedi, Atharva Veda Hindi Bhasya, page 804.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 11.5.18 In this mantra of Brahmcharya Sukta, it is emphasized that girls too should train themselves as students and only then enter into married life. The Sukta specifically emphasizes that girls should receive the same level of training as boys.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 8</p>
<p>Girls should train themselves to become complete scholars and youthful through Brahmcharya and then enter married life.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya, Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 413-414)</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.5.18 &#8220;A maiden living in chastity by controlling her senses wins for her husbandship a young bachelor of similar qualifications. Even bulls, horses and beasts nourish themselves with fodder and keep their sexual appetit in control.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>This verse does not state that girls should educate themselves. The word Brahmacharya here denotes self-restraint, not about getting education, if it is about getting education then can the writer please explain which school educates Bull and Horse? This is why Griffith whose translation is based on Hindu scholars also translates it as &#8220;by Self-restraint&#8221;.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.5.18 &#8220;By self-restraint a maiden finds a youth to be her wedded lord. By self-restraint the ox and horse seek to win fodder for themselves.&#8221; Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Garuda Purana,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.49.31 &#8220;…Brahmacarya is refraining from sexual intercourse…&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Atharva 7.47.1</strong> Oh woman! You are the keeper of knowledge of all types of actions (karma).</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>O woman, you provide us wealth and prosperity.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 1, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 804)</p>
<p>Similar meaning:</p>
<p>(Book: Atharvaved ka subodh bhashya (7-10 chapters), Author: Sripad Damodar Satvalekar, Page 98)</p>
<p><strong>Atharva 7.47.2</strong> Oh woman! You know everything. Please provide us strength of prosperity and wealth</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>O woman! You enhance our wealth and prosperity</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 1, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 805)</p>
<p>Similar meaning:</p>
<p>(Book: Atharvaved ka subodh bhashya (7-10 chapters), Author: Sripad Damodar Satvalekar, Page 98)</p>
<p>He also quotes</p>
<p><strong>Atharva 7.48.2</strong> Oh woman! Please provide us with wealth through your intellect</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>Scholarly, respectful, thoughtful, happy wife protects and enhances wealth and bring happiness in home.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 1, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 806)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.47.1 Oft in this sacrifice with favoured cry I call Kuhu, beneficent Goddess, skilled in all her works. May she vouchsafe us wealth with every boon, and give a, hero meet for praise who gives a hundred gifts.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="464" height="278" class="wp-image-7759" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-109.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp18.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-109.png 464w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-109-300x180.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Ved 7.47.2 Oft in this sacrifice with favoured cry I call Kuhu, beneficent Goddess, skilled in all her works. May she vouchsafe us wealth with every boon, and give a hero [Son]meet for praise who gives a hundred gifts.</p>
<p>(Hindi Shri Ram Acharya translation)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="497" height="110" class="wp-image-7760" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-110.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp19.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-110.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-110-300x66.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.48.2 All thy kind favours, Raka! lovely in their form, wherewith thou grantest treasures to the man who gives, With these come thou to us this day benevolent, O blessed one, bestowing wealth of thousand sorts.</p>
<p>(Hindi Shri Ram Acharya translation)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="120" class="wp-image-7761" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-111.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp20.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-111.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-111-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>The writer has translated the names of goddesses Raka and Kuhu as woman, but actually these are the names of the Hindu goddesses,</p>
<p>Bhagawad Purana 4.1.34: Angira&#8217;s wife, Sraddha, gave birth to four daughters, named Sinivali, Kuhu, Raka and Anumati.</p>
<p>Nirukta 11.28 &#8220;Anumati and Raka are two wives of gods&#8221;</p>
<p>Nirukta 11.33 &#8220;Simvali and Kuhu are two wives of gods&#8221;</p>
<p>Offerings were made to these goddesses</p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 5.6.18 &#8220;To Aditi are (to be offered) three ruddy-spotted; to Indrani three black-spotted; to Kuhu three red-spotted; three calves to Raka; three heifers to Sinivali; the red-spotted hornless ones are for Agni and Visnu.&#8221;</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s clear that these verses refer to Hindu goddesses not to common women. Kuhu is the goddess of the new moon day. The Atharva Veda 7.47 is a hymn for gaining wealth and Son. The verses addressed to Goddesses can not be used to portray women are highly revered in Vedas, readers can go through this article to know why Goddesses are praised <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/why-did-the-brahmins-dethrone-the-gods-and-enthrone-the-goddesses/" data-wpel-link="internal">Why did the Brahmins dethrone the Gods and enthrone the Goddesses?</a></p>
<p>for the sake of the argument even if I accept his translation to be correct, it doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean that the wife is a good luck charm that will bring wealth. A woman in Hinduism brings wealth with her as a Dowry, even after the marriage she has to keep bringing money from her parent&#8217;s house, so this is how she brings wealth, Dayanand Saraswati writes,</p>
<p><strong><em>&#8216;</em></strong>&#8216;If the bride&#8217;s people do not live very far from her husband&#8217;s home, there is a possibility of her parents becoming poor<strong><em>, as whenever she visits her parents, they will have to give her something or other by the way of a present.&#8221;-</em></strong>Satyarth Prakash ch 4, p84.</p>
<p>Further the Hymn of Atharva Veda 7.48 is also a prayer to get wealth and a SON. The author should have honestly quoted the previous verse also,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.48.1 …may beget sons…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="546" height="127" class="wp-image-7762" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-112.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp21.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-112.png 546w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-112-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 546px) 100vw, 546px" /></p>
<p>Vedas doesn&#8217;t say woman brings prosperity, but prosperity here only means the birth of a son, Rig Veda and the hymn of Atharva Veda 7.48 is entirely dedicated for birth of a son and prosperity. Another verse states that</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.63.15 Vouchsafe us blessing in our paths and desert tracts, blessing in waters and in battle, for the light; Blessing upon the wombs that bring male children forth</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.3.47 …A youthful world, a son hath been begotten. Begin a life that brings success and triumph.</p>
<p>Similarly the woman who has no son was looked down in the Vedic period, it is mentioned in the Brahmana,</p>
<p>Satapatha Brahmana 5.3.1.13 And on the following day he goes to the house of a discarded (wife), and prepares a pap for Nirriti;–a discarded wife is one who has no son…hail!&#8217; For a wife that is without a son, is possessed with Nirriti (destruction, calamity)…</p>
<p>So in the Vedic scripture the woman brings prosperity only by giving birth to a son, if she doesn&#8217;t she is discarded, looked down, rejected, cursed.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 14.1.64 Oh woman! Utilize your vedic intellect in all directions of our home!</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>O bride! Reach the home of scholars and bring bliss and happiness by ruling your home</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 678)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 8,9</p>
<p>When girls ignore external objects and develops foresight and vibrant attitude through power of knowledge, she becomes provider of wealths of skies and earth. Then she should marry an eligible husband.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya, Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 654)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This verse is recited before the bride enters her in law&#8217;s house, it does not say anything like the bride should utilize her Vedic intellect it says that Vedas should be chanted (by the priest).</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.64 &#8220;Let Brahma, the Vedic prayer with Vedic verses be offered before, and after, let the Vedic verses be chanted in the middle and let the Ved mantras be pronounced all around. O bride! reaching the portal of magnificient home, without under-going any trouble and shine being gentle and auspicious in the house of your husband.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 1.14.3 Oh groom! This bride will protect your entire family</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 13</p>
<p>O groom! This bride is protector of your entire family. May she dwell in your home for a period and sow seeds of intellect.</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 1, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 80-81)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 1.14.3. This woman shall be the keeper of thy house, O king (Yama), and her do we make over to thee! May she long sit with her relatives, until (her hair) drops from her head!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="483" height="234" class="wp-image-7763" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-113.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp22.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-113.png 483w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-113-300x145.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></p>
<p>The speaker in this verse is not God, it&#8217;s the father. The Arya Samaj translation does not say that the &#8220;Woman/Bride shall be the protector of your family&#8221;. This verse is spoken by the father to his daughter&#8217;s in laws. Usually parents only speak the goodness of their children.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 2.36.3 May this bride become the queen of the house of her husband and enlighten all.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.36.3 This woman shall obtain a husband, since king Soma makes her lovely! May she, begetting sons, become a queen; may she, going to her husband, shine in loveliness!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="475" height="241" class="wp-image-7764" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-114.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp23.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-114.png 475w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-114-300x152.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /></p>
<p>The writer is quoting half-baked verses, he correctly quoted that the Bride may become the queen of her husband&#8217;s house but didn&#8217;t say how she could become  queen. It&#8217;s simple, by Begetting a Son. If begetting a son makes a woman the queen of the house then begetting a daughter might make her the housemaid. It also does not state that she should enlighten all but it says she shines in lovliness.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 14.1.61</p>
<p>Hey bride! You shall bring bliss to all and direct our homes towards our purpose of living</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 14</p>
<p>Similar meaning</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 677)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.1.61 &#8220;O bride! you mount on this chariot which is decorated with good flowers, which have various colours, which is goldenhued which is strongly bound, good wheeled and which moves comfortably. Mount the Loka, the house-hold life which is the source of immorality and make the marriage auspicious for your husband and other members of the family.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="85" class="wp-image-7765" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-115.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp24.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-115.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-115-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>Above is Damodar&#8217;s (Arya Samaj) Hindi translation. It only asks the bride to make the marriage auspicious.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 14.2.74</p>
<p>This bride is illuminating. She has conquered everyone&#8217;s hearts!</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 14</p>
<p>May the bride be victorious and prosperous!</p>
<p>Similar meaning</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 709)</p>
<p>Atharva 14.2.71</p>
<p>Hey wife! I am knowledgeable and you are also knowledgeable. If I am Samved then you are Rigved.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 14</p>
<p>Similar meaning</p>
<p>(Atharvaveda-Hindi Bhashya Part 2, Author: Kshemkarandas Trivedi, Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, Delhi, Page 708)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>These verses are to be recited during the marriage ceremony, This verse does not say that the Bride has conquered everyone&#8217;s heart, or the bride be prosperous.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.2.74 Her who first guided by a rein came hither, giving the bride, here offspring and possessions, Let them convey along the future&#8217;s pathway. Splendid, with noble children, she hath conquered.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="490" height="255" class="wp-image-7766" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-116.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp25.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-116.png 490w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-116-300x156.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 14.2.71-72 I am this man, that dame art thou I am the Samved and thou the Rigved. I am the heaven and thou the earth. So will we dwell together here, parents of children yet to be. Unmarried men desire to wed; bountiful givers wish for sons. Together may we dwell with strength unscathed for high prosperity.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="131" class="wp-image-7767" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-117.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp26.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-117.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-117-300x63.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>First of all the speaker here is a man wishing for a Bride, secondly the Arya Samaj translation does not state that &#8220;I&#8217; am knowledgeable so are you&#8221;. Next verse of this hymn prays for begetting a Son, So again there is a discrimination against birth of Daughter. The Upanishad explains this verse,</p>
<p>Brihadaranyaka Upanishad 6.4.20 &#8220;Then he embraces her, repeating the following mantra:I am the vital breath and you are speech. You are speech and I am the vital breath. I am Saman and you are Rig; I am heaven and you are earth. Come, let us strive together so that we may have a male child.&#8221;</p>
<p>The next verses of this Brihadaranyaka Upanishad are too vulgar, it explicitly tells sex positions. So I won&#8217;t be quoting it here, readers can check those verses in the article <a href="/index.php/2014/12/27/hinduism-lust/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Lust</a>. The writer is quoting verses which are to be recited at the time of marriage or when the Bride enters the house, she brings lot of wealth with her as dowry and is wished only for begetting sons so how can these verses be used to show women are revered in Vedas? Even a horse or bull which is slaughtered in the Yajna is mentioned in similar way in the Vedas. If the writer wants to show equal status of women in Vedas then he should quote verses giving them equal inheritance, praising common women (Not goddesses), permitting them to get education, allowing them to do trade and commerce etc.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva 7.38.4 and 12.3.52</p>
<p>Women should take part in the legislative chambers and put their views on forefront.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 23</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>The verse does not state that women can take part in the legislative chamber, this hymn is a Charm to Secure love, the speaker here is a woman who is praying to get back her Husband.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.38.1-2 I dig this Healing Herb that makes my lover look on me and weep; That bids the parting friend return and kindly greets him as he comes. This Herb wherewith the <strong>Asuri drew Indra downward from the Gods</strong>, With this same Herb I draw thee close that I may be most dear to thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="781" height="252" class="wp-image-7768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp27.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40.jpeg 781w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40-300x97.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40-768x248.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 781px) 100vw, 781px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.38.4-5 &#8220;Not only I desire in this august assembly O husband! but thou also admitted so. Thou then, be exclusively mine and should not and would not talk of other women. If you, O husband or wife! are far away from the men of family, if you are far away beyond the river, this herb may seem to bind you fast and bring you back to me.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>According to Sayana this hymn is a Vashikaran (Black magic) Hymn. According to the Atharva 12.3.52 which the author has quoted says that both the Man and the Woman had spoken falsehood in the assembly,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.3.52 &#8220;O ye men and women! whatever lie you tell in plays, whatever in meeting, and whatever untruth you speak in desiring wealth let all this dirt be left out in the lie or untruth itself. You always dress your self with common dress.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig 10.85.7</p>
<p>Parents should gift their daughter intellectuality and power of knowledge when she leaves for husband&#8217;s home. They should give her a dowry of knowledge.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p>Atharva 14.1.6 Parents should gift their daughter intellectuality and power of knowledge when she leaves for husband&#8217;s home. They should give her a dowry of knowledge.</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>These verses are not about the dowry of knowledge but the actual dowry which the bride brings to her in laws. The evil roots of Dowry system in India originated from Vedas. There is a detailed article on Dowry in Hinduism written by Mushafiq Sultan <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/the-menace-of-dowry-and-its-origin/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Menace of Dowry and its Origin</a></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Chapter 1: Women in Vedic Dharma, Page 9</p>
<p>Rig 3.31.1</p>
<p>The right is equal in the fathers property for both son and daughter</p>
<p>(Book: Mera Dharma, Author: Priyavrat Vedavachaspati, Gurukul Kangri University)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.31.1 WISE, teaching, following the thought of Order, the sonless gained a grandson from his daughter. Fain, as a sire, to see his child prolific, he sped to meet her with an eager spirit.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="350" class="wp-image-7769" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-118.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp28.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-118.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-118-300x213.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.31.1 &#8220;The disciplined and wise father, relying on the sanction of natural rights, honours his grandson, the son of his daughter, with valuable gifts. The father trusting to the impregnation of the daughter consoles himself with cheerful mind.&#8221; Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>This verse shows the eagerness to get a son, this verse is about a man who was sonless and gained a grandson from her daughter. Further this verse no where talks about equal share of property, Pandit jaydev writes in the commentary</p>
<p>&#8220;The grandson shall be the legal heir of his grandfather&#8217;s property&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="462" height="286" class="wp-image-7770" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-119.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp29.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-119.png 462w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-119-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 462px) 100vw, 462px" /></p>
<p>So where is the equal inheritance here? It is more biased, Several question arises from this commentary, Why does a grandson become the heir when the sonless man already has a daughter? Isn&#8217;t there equal inheritance for woman? Why does the Man need to adopt his grandson when he already has a daughter? Swami Dayanand Saraswati says that a sonless Man can contract Niyoga to get sons even if he has a Daughter. Why this partiality against daughters?</p>
<p>And how can Arya Samajis claim that Vedas give inheritance right to women when none of their scripture says? Vedas does not entitle woman to inherit, only the sons enjoys the right of inheritance. The Hindu law is that the women shall not inherit her father&#8217;s property and if the Father is sonless only then his grandson (from his daughter) should inherit his property, as it is recorded in Bhagwad Puran</p>
<p>Bhagwad Puran 10.57.37 &#8220;Since Satrajit had no sons, his daughter&#8217;s sons should receive his inheritance. They should pay for memorial offerings of waler and pinda, clear their grandfather&#8217;s outstanding debts and keep the remainder of the inheritance for themselves.</p>
<p>So if one has a son, then there is no chance for the daughter&#8217;s son to inherit his Grandfather&#8217;s property. For more details read my article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Inheritance for Women in Vedas</a></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig ved 1.164.41</p>
<p>One ved, two ved, or four ved along with ayurved, dhanurved, gandharved, aarthved etc in addition with education, kalp, grammar, nirukt, astrology, meters i.e the six vedaang should be attained by the clear-minded woman, which is equivalent to the crystal-clear water and spread this diversified knowledge among the people.</p>
<p>(Book: Vagambhraniya, Author: Dr Priyamvada Vedbharti)</p>
<p>O men and women! A scholarly woman who has practiced or teaches one, two or four Vedas or four Vedas and four upavedas, along with grammar, etymology etc and spreads knowledge to whole world and removes ignorance of people is source of happiness for entire world. A woman who studies and teaches all parts of Vedas brings progress to all human beings</p>
<p>(Book: Rigveda Bhashyam, Part III, Author: Dayanand Saraswati,Vedic Yantralaya, Page 382,383)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.164.41 The Speech has been uttered, fabricating the waters, and being one-footed, two footed, four-footed, eight-footed, nine-footed, or infinite in the highest heaven.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="471" height="432" class="wp-image-7771" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-120.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp30.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-120.png 471w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-120-300x275.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 471px) 100vw, 471px" /></p>
<p>According to the Arya Samaj Jaydev&#8217;s and Shri Ram Acharya&#8217;s Hindi translations this verse is addressed to Vedic Speech.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig ved 10.85.46</p>
<p>Like wise in so many other mantras a woman has been presented to play an essential role in family and as wife. Similarly she has been given the lead stage in society works, in governmental organizations, and for ruling the nation is also mentioned in Vedas.</p>
<p>(Book: Vagambhraniya, Author: Dr Priyamvada Vedbharti)</p>
<p>Rigevda contains several Suktas containing description of Usha as a God. <strong>This Usha is representation of an ideal woman</strong>. Please refer &#8220;Usha Devata&#8221; by Pt Sri Pad Damodar Satvalekar as part of &#8220;Simple Translation of Rigveda (Rigved ka subodh bhashya)&#8221;. Page 121 to 147 for summary of all such verses spread across entire Rigveda. In summary:</p>
<p>Women should be brave (Page 122, 128)</p>
<p>Women should be expert (Page 122)</p>
<p>Women should earn fame (Page 123)</p>
<p>Women should ride on chariots (Page 123)</p>
<p>Women should be scholars (Page 123)</p>
<p>Women should be prosperous and wealth (Page 125)</p>
<p>Women should be intelligent and knowledgeable (Page 126)</p>
<p>Women should be protector of family and society and get in army(Page 134, 136)</p>
<p>Women should be illuminating (Page 137)</p>
<p>Women should be provider of wealth, food and prosperity (Page 141- 146)</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This is what the writer is trying to do in the whole article, when he can&#8217;t find any verse which praises women, he just twisted the verses attributed to Hindu Goddesses and said it speaks about common Women. All those verses are prayers to Vedic Godesses, they doesn&#8217;t praise common women. This translation is not fully correct. Usha was physically assaulted in Veda, I&#8217; am using Shri Ram Acharya&#8217;s Hindi translation for this verse below,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.30.8-11 And this heroic deed of might thou, Indra, also hast achieved, That thou didst smite to death the Dame, Heaven&#8217;s Daughter, meditating ill. Thou, Indra, Mighty One, didst crush Usas, though Daughter of the Sky. When lifting up herself in pride.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="576" height="156" class="wp-image-7772" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-121.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp31.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-121.png 576w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-121-300x81.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /></p>
<p>According to some scholars Indra raped Usha, while according to others this is an allegorical verse and has a different meaning. However I&#8217; am not talking about the context of this verse, the purpose is only to show that Usha does not represent the &#8220;Ideal Woman&#8221; in Vedas as the author claims. Usha is a goddess representing the sky and is considered the daughter of the sky. So my question to the author is If Usha represents the Ideal Woman then why did Indra (sometime translated as Ideal Man by Arya Samaj) assault Usha? Who is the ideal person here? Moreover this verse also gives a wrong impression of physical abuse on women.</p>
<p>As far as the verse Rigved 12.85.46 is concerned, the term Usha is not mentioned there, it&#8217;s referring to bride. He did not show the reason as to why the woman is getting special treatment, whole context can be understood by reading previous verses,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.85.42-45 … With sons and grandsons sport and play, rejoicing in your own abode. …Not inauspicious enter thou thy husband&#8217;s house … Loving the Gods, delightful, bearing sons [Hero]… O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. Vouchsafe to her ten sons, and make her husband the eleventh man.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="426" height="251" class="wp-image-7773" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-122.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0701_testingresp32.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-122.png 426w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-122-300x177.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 426px) 100vw, 426px" /></p>
<p>This verse prays for begetting 10 sons but doesn&#8217;t state anything about birth of even one daughter. This verse is about the bride and is recited before the bride enters the house. And the evils of this hymn is that this hymn of Rig Veda Mandal 10 Sukt 85 is about Dowry, where the bride brings wealth with her. Status of Women in Hinduism is no better than a prisoner, Read the articles to know about the position of Women in Vedas/Hinduism</p>
<p><strong>Also read </strong><a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part 1</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Women and the Vedic Dharm</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and the Vedic Dharma</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma. In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color:#333333;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p style="color:#333333;">The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. Nowhere is a prayer or charm recited to be granted a daughter. For exmaple,</span></span></p>
<p><span id="more-848"></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">1. O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. <strong style="font-style:inherit;">Vouchsafe to her ten sons</strong>, and make her husband the eleventh man. [Rigved Mandal 10, Sookt 85, Mantra 45]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_rig_10_85_45.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">2. This is thy Soma draught, O bright Âditya: take delight therein. To this mine utterance, O ye men, give credence, what good the man and wife obtain by praying: <strong style="font-style:inherit;">A manly son is born and gathers riches</strong>, and thrives for ever sinless in the dwelling. [Yajurved Adhyay 8, Mantra 5]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_yajur_8_5.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">3. Fathers, bestow on me a babe, <strong style="font-style:inherit;">a boy </strong>enwreathed with lotuses, so that there may be here a man. [Yajurved Adhyay 2, Mantra 33]</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/son_yajur_2_33.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">All prayers for being granted a boy and none for a girl.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Speaking of marriage Swami Dayanad Saraswati says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“In Sanskrit a daughter is called </span><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">duhitri</span></em><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> (from Du – distant, Hit – good), because the marriage of a girl to a man who comes from a distant country or distant part of the same country is productive of good.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">“If the bride’s people do not live very far from her husband’s home, there is a possibility of her parents becoming poor, as whenever she visits her parents, they will have to give her something or other by the way of a present.” </em>[Satyarth Prakash Chapter 4, The advantages and disadvantages of distant and near marriages, Page 85]</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Rigved Mandal 8, Sookt 33, Mantra 17 says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline,</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Her intellect hath little weight</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">.”</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_brain_rig_8_33_17.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">At another place, it is written:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">There cannot be any friendship with a woman. Her heart is</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> like</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> that of a hyena.</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Rig Veda, 10/95/15</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_hayenas_rig_10_95_15.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda says:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Women are without energy. They should not get a share in the property. Even to the wicked, they speak in a feeble manner. </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">  vi. 5. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">8</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">2</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A wife has no claim to property of her husband. The wealth that she earns is not her but her husband’s. [Manu Smriti  Chapter 8, Sholka 416]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A girl without a brother is called <em style="font-weight:inherit;">Abhratr</em> and it is prohibited to marry such a girl.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The Atharva Ved says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Those maidens there, the veins, who run their course in robes of ruddy hue, must now stand quiet, reft of power, like sisters who are brotherless. [Atharva Ved Kaand 1, Sookt 17, Mantra 1]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/brotherless_ath_1_17_1.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Explaining this word, Nirukt, which is the oldest Indian treatise on Etymology, </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Philology and Semantics, says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">They stand like women who have no brother, and whose path is  obstructed with regard to procreation and the offering of the sacrificial cake. With these words the simile implies the prohibition of marrying a brotherless maiden.[Nirukt 3:4]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Shatpath Brahman, preachings of the ‘Yajur Veda’ says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He (the Adhvaryu) then mixes it with the residue (of ghee) which is left in the prakaranî spoon. Now other libations he completes by mixing, but this one he diminishes; for ghee is a thunderbolt, and by that thunderbolt, the ghee, the gods smote the wives and unmanned them, and thus smitten and unmanned they neither owned any self nor <strong style="font-style:inherit;">did they own any heritage</strong>. And in like manner does he now, by that thunderbolt, the ghee, smite the wives and unman them; and thus smitten and unmanned, they neither own any self<strong style="font-style:inherit;"> nor do they own any heritage</strong>. [Shatpath Brahman; Kaand 4, Adhyay 4, Brahaman 2, Kaandika 13]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The same Shatpath Brahman says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“And whilst not coming into contact with Sûdras and remains of food; for this Gharma is he that shines yonder, and he is excellence, truth, and light; <strong style="font-style:inherit;">but woman, the Sûdra, the dog, and the black bird (the crow), are untruth: he should not look at these, lest he should mingle excellence and sin, light and darkness, truth and untruth</strong>. [Kaand 14, Adhyay1, Brahman1, Kaandika 31]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">A woman can never ask for divorce, even if her husband ill treats her. Manu says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife. [Manu Smriti 5:154]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Swami Dayanand Saraswati is teaching us in Satyarth Prakash how to choose a perfect wife. Listen to him.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let a man never marry one who is pale and anaemic, nor one who is altogether a bigger and stronger person than himself or has a redundant member, nor one who is an invalid, nor one either with no hair or too much hair or too much hair, nor one immoderately talkative, nor one with red eyes.” MANU 3: 8.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Nor one with the name of star,of a tree,or of a river, or of a mountain.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">So Hindu men should not marry women who are named Ashvini, Ganga, Saraswati, Himalaya, etc.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let him choose for his wife, a girl who has a graceful figure without any deformity, who has a pretty name, who walks gracefully like a swan or an elephant, who has fine hair and lovely teeth, and whose body is exquisitely soft.” MANU 3: 10</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Satyarth Prakash, Pages 89, 90]</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He forgets to teach how to choose a husband.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The ‘Vedas,’ also talk about ‘Niyog’ the custom of childless widow or woman having sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. In simple words ‘Niyog’ means sending a married woman or widow to a particular man for sexual intercourse so that she gets a son. Indication of this custom is available in Rig Veda.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> In ‘Aadiparva’ of ‘Mahabharata’ (chapters 95 and 103), it is mentioned that Satyawati had appointed her son to bestow sons to the queens of Vichitrvirya, the younger brother of Bhishma, and as a result of which Dhartrashtra and Pandu were born. Pandu himself had asked his queen, Kunti, to have sexual intercourse with a Brahmin to get a son (Aadi Parva,’ chapters 120 to 123).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">It has been said in ‘Aadi Parva’ (chapters 64 and 104), that when Parshu Ram started killing the Kshatriyas, thousands of female Kshatriyas started going to Brahmins to get sons. Similar references are found at other places in ‘Mahabharata’ also. With regard to ‘Niyog’, there are detailed discussions at a number of places in other religious books.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In Nirkut, the meaning of ‘dewar’ that is, husband’s younger brother, has been given as ‘Duvitya Var’ that is, the second husband (Nirukt 3:15).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">An ancient commentator of ‘Manu Smriti’ (Manu’s Code), Meghatithi has clearly accepted the existence of ‘Niyog‘ (quoted from ‘Dharam Shastra Ka Itihas’, by Bharatratan Mahamahopdhyay, Dr P.V. Kane, Part I, page 341).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the last century, Swami Dayanand Saraswati had claimed to have written a commentary free from defects in the interpretation, of the ancient commentators on the ‘Vedas.’ Dayanand had not only accepted the prevalence of ‘Niyog’ but also on the basic of ‘smritis’ (codes of traditional Hindu laws), discussed ‘Niyog’ in great detail in the language of the ‘Veda mantras’ (Vedic hymns). According to him there was a law that a woman or a man could have sexual intercourse with eleven persons. If no child was born from the one, then a woman could go to another. If even then she was unable to beget a child, then she could go to the third and so on till she had intercourse with eleven men (Dayanand’s commentary on Rig Veda, 10/85/45).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Woman was sometimes even forced to have sexual intercourse with men in the custom of ‘Niyog’. ‘Devtas, Rishis, Munis’ and ‘Brahmins’ used to participate in ‘Niyog’ (see ‘Mahabharata Aadi Parv; chapters 64,95,103, 104).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Chastity of woman was not safe</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the name of ‘beejdan’ (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of women was not safe. The so-called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with another man’s wife. From ‘Niyog pratha’, it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that the women were looked upon as mere child-producing machines.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In ‘The Position of Women in Hindu Civilization’, Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar writes: “<em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though woman was married to a man, she was considered to be the property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only the son could be the successor to property.”</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says: <em style="font-weight:inherit;">“No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic men could not keep even the relations between brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery / adultery named ‘Niyog’. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognise neither sister nor daughter and also they did not keep in mind their relations with them. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what the miserable plight of women was in the society then. (Refer ‘Arya Niti Ka Bhandaphor’, 5th edition page 14).</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Till such a time as these teachings have an overwhelming influence, the improvement in the position and status of the women is next to impossible.</span></span></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
