<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>loot &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/loot/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:17:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Killing Infidels in Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 05:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[answering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavarta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beheading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahmadvish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayananad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disbelievers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extremism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinduism exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innocent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ISIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jihad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kafir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kikata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murdering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non believers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plunder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puranas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaughtering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthabouthinduism.wordpress.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthofhinduism.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ved nindak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war booty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Also read new article Killing Infidels in Hinduism Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7331" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg" alt="" width="517" height="384" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1024x760.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-768x570.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1536x1141.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-2048x1521.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /></p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Also read new article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Hinduism</a></p>
<p>Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as a result of the violent passages in Vedas. As per Vedas, you must kill a person who rejects Vedas, who hates Vedas and Ishwar, who does not worship, who does not make offerings to ishwar, who insults god (Blasphemy), one who oppresses a Brahmin etc. There are several passages in Vedas which calls for death of disbelievers. I am mostly using Arya Samaji translations of Satya Prakash Saraswati, Satyakam Vidyalankar, Devi Chand, Vaidyanath Shastri, Kshemkarand Das Trivedi, Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Shripad Damodar Satvalekar, and orthodox translations of Swami Karpatri and Shri Ram Sharma Acharya (Gayatri Parivar) and I will be using Griffith’s translation as well followed by Hindi translation of Hindu scholars. In the Vedas you will find numerous words to denote non-Hindus such as Adeva, Adevayu which means Godless, anindra which means against Indra, Ayajyu, Ayajvan which means unsacrifcing, Abrahman, Anyavrata which means followers of other gods, apavrata, avrata which means riteless, devanid which means haters of gods, Brahmadvish which means haters of devotion and those who denounce Vedas.</p>
<p><span id="more-746"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.13.9 “May you (O love divine), the beholder of the path of enlightenment, purifying our mind and destroying the infidels who refuse to offer worship, come and stay in the prime position of the eternal sacrifice.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.6.3 “May the fire divine chase away those infidels, who do not perform worship and who are uncivil in speech. They are niggards, unbelievers, say no tribute to fire divine and offer no homage. The fire divine turns those godless people far away who institute no sacred ceremonies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.63.5 ”Augmenting the strength of resplendent self, urging the waters and rejuvenating all noble acts and destroying the infidels.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p><strong>One who does not offer Sacrifice is inhuman</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.70.11 “May your friend, the cloud, hurl that infidel down from heaven who differs from us in rites and rituals, is inhuman, who does not observe fire sacrificials, and who does not show reverence to Nature’s bounties.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.97.9 “O Lord of knowledge, this laudation is for you…destroy the godless and the malice of our enemy.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Killing Avrata,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.73.8 &#8220;&#8230;he, the all-wise, looks over all worlds; he censures those who are hostile in action, and who do not offer sacrifices and render no public good.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.84. 8 When will he trample, like a weed, the man [Infidel] who hath no gift for him…</p>
<p>Yaska writes,</p>
<p>Nirukta 5.17 When, with his foot, will he trample the unworshipping man like a mushroom</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.64.1-2 “May our hymns please you; O lord of resolute will power, please display your bounty. May you drive off the infidels. May you crush with your foot the niggard churls who offer no homage. You are powerful; there is none so powerful as you are.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.2.10 “May you roaring flames, O adorable Lord, be manifest in the sky as sharp weapons, to destroy infidels. In his exhilaration may his shining splendour inflict destruction. The godless hands try to bind him from all sides but do not succeed.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.79.10 “The powerful flowing elixir…It is the conferer of wealth, the king of vigour; It crushes malignities and harasses the enemies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.76.11 “Both the heaven and earth shudder when you, O the resplendent Lord, uttering your fearful roar, crush down the infidel.” Tr. Satya Prakash Sarawati</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.21.3 ‘Let this war drum made of wood, muffled with leather straps, dear to all the persons of human race and bedewed with ghee, speak terror to our foemen.”Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="464" height="205" class="wp-image-7290" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi1.png?w=464" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png 464w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x133.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.19.6 ‘May you bring near to us those who stand aloof; may you strike terror into our foes; o pure flowing elixir, please transfer their riches to us.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati and Satyakam Vidyalankar</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 17.33 “He is an ideal commander of the army, who is swift, keeps his arms sharpened, fearless like a strong bull, a zealous killer of foes, strikes terror in men…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 4.31.7 “Let the King [Varuna] and Manyu, the warm emotion give us the wealth of both kinds-earned and gathered. Let our enemies overwhelmed with terror in their mind and spirit and defeated in their design run away.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya also writes about terror,</p>
<p>Nirukta 10.21 …These are hemistichs. Like a spear hurled, it inspires terror (among enemies) or courage (among friends)…</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.36 “We learned persons accept as our ruler, thee, the introducer of new plans for our advancement, the master of loyal subjects, the embodiment of virtue, the most advanced in noble qualities and acts, the queller of the irreligious…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.44 “…This fourth warrior, full of delight, should subdue the irreligious foes.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.12 “O king, make progress in thy duty of administration, extend happiness to the virtuous. O terrible chastiser, burn down the irreligious foes. O splendid person, humiliate and consume utterly like dried up stubble, him, who encourages our foe.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.23 He who dwells fixed in the atmosphere, smiting the blasphemers of the god that do not sacrifice, to him be reverence with ten sakvarî−stanzas!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="59" class="wp-image-7291" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi2.png?w=601" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x29.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Killing Women and Children</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.21 Do not covet our cattle, our men, our goats and sheep! Bend thy course elsewhere, O strong god (ugra), slay the offspring of the blasphemers! <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="602" height="111" class="wp-image-7292" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi3.png?w=602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png 602w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.20.4-5 “Let this war-drum victorious in the battle, loudly roaring and becoming the means of seizing whatever may be seized, be seen by all. Let this war-drum utter wonderful voice and let the army-controlling man capture the possessions of the enemies. Amid the conflict of the deadly weapons let the woman of enemy waked by the roar and afflicted run forward in her terror hearing the resounding and far reaching voice of the wardrum, holding her son in her hand.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="577" height="107" class="wp-image-7293" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi4.png?w=577" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.118.8 So, Agni, with thy glowing face burn fierce against the female fiends, Shining among Uruksayas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="508" height="100" class="wp-image-7294" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi5.png?w=508" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4-300x59.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>VEDIC GOD STEALS</strong></p>
<p><strong>GOD STEALING LIKE A THIEF</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “To him, who is the performer of all deeds, the possessor and giver of strength, the truly powerful Lord, we offer devotional prayers. He a highwayman, snatches wealth from the godless exploiters and gives it to honest devotees.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Griffith’s translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “…The Hero, watching like a thief in ambush, goes parting the possessions of the godless.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.93.4 Agni and Soma, famed is that your. prowess wherewith ye stole the kine, his food, from Paṇi…<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="513" height="96" class="wp-image-7295" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi6.png?w=513" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png 513w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.61.25 “The elixir of divine love flows onward, chasing the malignant, and driving off the withholders of wealth and thus it proceeds to the holy abode of the resplendent Lord.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.19.9 ‘O bounteous Lord, pious devotees, skilled in reciting hymns, sing their songs to you for your adoration. May you select us also to join them who by their homage to you, have become entitled to appropriate the riches of infidels‘. Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.75.12 ‘Leave us not in this conflict as a bearer of load; snatch up the wealth of infidels and give it to us.’ Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.4.5 “…May you come to bless our fire ritual. May you having scattered all our adversaries, bring to us the possessions of our foeman.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Here god is prayed to eliminate the rivals and to bring their wealth. Yaska writes on this verse,</p>
<p>Nirukta 4.5 “Having destroyed all assailants, bring to us the treasures of our enemies, i.e. having destroyed the forces of our adversaries, bring to us the treasures or the food from the homes of our enemies.”- Nirukta 4.5</p>
<p><strong>ALL NON HINDUS ARE DEMONS, BARBARIANS.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="417" height="523" class="wp-image-7296" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/tolerance-hinduism-buddhism-jainism-zoroastrianism-false-religions-untitld.jpg?w=417&amp;h=523" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg 417w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole-239x300.jpeg 239w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px" /></p>
<p>The reason it is important to know who are Demons in Hinduism is because Hindu apologists find no problem with violent verses in the Veda because it says to kill ‘Demon’, they just say that these verses are referring to Demons and not to non-Hindus and try to get rid of the argument. As I said earlier Hindu apologists usually takes violent verses in lighter vein because it says to kill demons. Vedas are said to be eternal, now the question is if those verses were applicable only to Demons then it means that those verses have become useless now. So why God revealed such verses for limited period of time in the eternal book?</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote,”The Dwijaas( the twice-born) – Braahmanaas, Kshatriyas, Vaishyaas are called Aryas, while the Shudras are called Anaryas, or Non-Aryas.”ATHARVA VEDA 19:62. In the face ofthese Vedic authorities how can sensible people believe in the imaginary tales of the foreigners. In the Devaasurawars, Prince Arjuna and King Dashrathaand others of Aryavarta used to go to the assistance of the Aryas in order to crush the Asuras. This shows that the people living outside Aryavarta were called Dasyus and Malechhaas… Besides, Manu also corroborates our position. He says, “The countries other than Aryavarta are called Dasyus and Malechha countries.” MANU 10:45, 2:23. The people living in the north-east, north, north-west were called Rakshasas.” Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>Dasyu and Rakshasa mean demon. Here Swami Dayanand quoting Manu Smriti says that all people living outside Aryavrata and those who do not belong to four castes are demons (Rakshasa, Dasyu) and barbarians (Mleccha). According to Hindu Dharma all the non Hindus are demons and barbarians. Here is the full translation of Manu Smriti,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 10.45 All those tribes in this world, which are excluded from (the community of) those born from the mouth, the arms, the thighs, and the feet (of Brahman), are called Dasyus, whether they speak the language of the Mlekkhas (barbarians) or that of the Aryans.</p>
<p>Now some say that this doesn’t refer to Non-Hindus but to caste Hindus who lost their status on account of their neglecting their religious rites which lead them to loss of caste. They aren’t convinced even after providing explanation by their own scholar. Maybe they didn’t read verse 43 of this chapter 10 which says that by neglecting sacrifices the Dvijas made their successive generation fell to the status of Shudra not Dasyu. If Brahmins, Kshatriya, Vaishya and Shudra losing their caste made them Dasyu, the question is why they aren’t regarded as outcaste but as Dasyu? Because verse 43 and 45 aren’t correlated. Verse 45 is plain and clear that those tribe outside the pale of four Varnas are Dasyu and non-Hindus aren’t included in the four castes. Manu Smriti 10.45 also refutes the claim of apologists who claim that Dasyu means non-Human beings since Manu 10.45 states that Dasyu can be from four castes also who has abandoned their Vedic religion (if we go by the explanation of apologists) since they claim that Dasyu refers to demons only. Hindu scriptures from Veda to Purana mentions demon, so where are all those demons now? Dayanand Saraswati wrote,</p>
<p>“You can still see that the description of Raakshasas given therein tallies with the ugly appearance of the negroes of today.” <strong>Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</strong></p>
<p>So he is comparing Rakshasa with present day Negroes (black people) we can ascertain from this line that people living in north east and north west were not really monsters but were native people who are described in such racist manner. Swami Prabhupada also wrote,</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes: “…An atheist is called a demon, and it is a fact that even a person born of good parents can turn into a demon by bad association…” <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.3.6</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>An Indologist wrote about Dasyu,</p>
<p>“The picture of the dasyu that emerges from these passages is quite different from that of the raksas. There is nothing about taking the form of a bird and flying by night, no mention of disrupting sacrifices, and no connection with black magic. The dasyus seem to be human beings of a different race from the Aryans and of a different (adevic and abrahamanic) religion. The mention of the proper names of various dasyus who are defeated for (or by) certain Aryan princes (e.g. Dabhiti) also makes the dasyu sound more like historical figures. There are occasional mentions of taking land from the dasyus (RV 4.38.1). The mention of dasyus in connection with fortresses (pur-) is also a characteristic which is in contrast to the raksases. Raksases do not build fortresses and fight from them. It seems quite safe to agree with the general conclusion of Vedic scholars that dasyu refers to the indigenous people of the land whom the invading Aryans conquered or absorbed.” <strong>by Wash Edward Hale, p.154, Asura in Early Vedic Religion, Published by Motilal Banarsidass Publisher, 1986.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Moreover the Aryans were engaged in battle against the Dasyus and the reason given is Dasyus sings no [Vedic] hymns; Dasyus are riteless, Dasyus have alien laws; Dasyus differs from rites and rituals and doesn’t observe fire sacrifices; Dasyus are faithless, niggars, without belief, sacrifice and worship. The main reason given to fight them is that Dasyus do not offer any gifts to Vedic deities and Indra was often invoked to wage a war against the Dasyu. Refer my article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing infidels in Hinduism</a> for references. Dasa and Dasyu has been synonymously used in the Vedas. The Persian word <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dahae" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Dahae<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> maybe related to the Dasyu tribe mentioned in the Vedas. “The Dahae were a Scythian people of ancient Central Asia. A confederation of three tribes – the Parni, Xanthii and Pissuri – the Dahae lived in an area now comprising much of modern Turkmenistan. The area has consequently been known as Dahestan, Dahistan and Dihistan” [end quote]. The word Parni is also believed to be the Iranian word for Panis tribe. The Panis and Dasyu may be have been closely related to each other that’s the reason they are mentioned together in Rig Veda 7.6.3; 5.34.6. Many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dasa" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Indologists<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> have also opined that Dasa were a tribe of humans not demons. Apologist pathetic response would be that Dasyu in the Veda are described as having numerous eyes and hands which is a proof that they were demons. Even Rishis who are said to be humans are described in some texts as of having three heads, Vedic deities as of having face of horse, animal getting pregnant after drinking semen of Rishis, does that prove that Rishis and Vedic deities were also demons? Hindus have a long history of using epithets against other religions, the Aryans used to consider Dasyu as Anasa which literally translates to noseless but it actually means flat nosed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to Panis tribe. Panis too are described as Demons, but Yaska in Nirukta also calls them Merchant (Nirukta 2.17). Panis tribe were rich traders and they were consistently attacked by Aryans to plunder them since they did not patronize the priests who then invoked Vedic gods to attack Panis. Apologists gives lame excuse, when defending verses about killing and plundering Panis tribe, all that they say is Panis were demons and doesn’t explain the part where Aryans plundered them and were the first to fight the Panis tribe. If they were demons then why Aryans were so eager to get their donations? Veda reiterates that Panis brings no gifts to Vedic deities, so why crave for their wealth if they were so demonic in nature? Veda also mentions a member of Panis community named Bribu who is praised in Rig Veda 6.45.31 because he is said to have gifted many cows to Rishi Bhardwaj (Manu Smriti 10.107) in which he is referred to as a carpenter. Now all of a sudden a Panis member is praised, what’s the reason? Because the reason to kill and plunder them is clearly given in Atharva Veda 20.93.2 that the Panis brings no gifts, had they given donations like Panis Bribu then they would’ve been spared and would’ve also been praised in the Vedas. Panis were rich merchants, they also had carpenters they used to rear cattle, engaged in trade and amassed wealth. These are the characteristics of humans not demons.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kikata too were plundered like Dasyu and Panis tribes because they didn’t observe Vedic rituals and didn’t make donations to Vedic deities. Veda also mentions Zoroastrians and calls them demons (Asura). The Asuras mentioned in Vedas are non other than Zoroastrians. They are actually Ahura worshippers (Zoroastrians). Vedic religion and Zoroastrianism are roughly of the same age they have many similarities like Vedic Yagna is called Yasna in Zoroastriniasm, Soma is Homa, Deva in Veda are positive while Daeva in Zoroastrianism is neutral to negative, Zoroastrian text also mentions Aryans. From Rig Veda Mandal 1 to 7, Vedic deities are also called as Asur but the definition when applied to Vedic deities is ‘Mighty’. When the Aryans moved from Central Asia to India they brought with them the memories, thus the word Asura is used till Rig Veda Mandal 7 as a praiseworthy word. And then it was turned negative and was also used later to describe enemies residing in eastern part of India such as Bengal and Assam like Asura king Naraka of Pragiyotisapura in Assam or Mahishasura. There’s also a tribe in India named <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/meeting-the-asurs-a-marginal-tribe-in-eastern-india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Asur people<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> who claim themselves to be descendants of Mahishasura.</p>
<p>People of Lanka in Ramayana has been described as Demons. Hanuman burned hundreds of demons inhabiting Lanka for no fault of their when Ram’s enmity was towards Ravana and not towards inhabitants of Lanka. Ramayana makes no mention of humans residing in Lanka but refers to the people of Lanka as demons. Go to Sri Lanka and tell me how many demons you found there or at least try to find their bones.</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to the Puranas, which is the most important point here. Many Puranas especially Vishnu Purana book 3 chapters 17 &amp; 18 states that demons embraced Buddhism and Jainism. The reason I quote Vishnu Purana again and again is because two chapters of this scripture are dedicated in denigrating Buddhism and Jainism and gives a picture of how Hinduism perceives other religions. Hindu text says that demons embraced Buddhism. Their disciples and disciples would continue to preach this religion. Now as you may know Buddhism’s history is not unknown like Hinduism’s. We know who its founder was and when Buddhism was founded, we know that its founder really existed and was not a mythological figure. Buddhism was founded in the 6<sup>th</sup> century B.C. It was a time when humans had started recording history. So you tell me did any Greek, Roman or any traveller ever recorded that demons used to live in India and they embraced Buddhism as stated in Hindu scriptures? So what Hindus did is nothing but demonization of their enemies. Hinduism recognizes many tribes and Dasyus, Panis, Yavana… were among them and they have been demonized because as mentioned in Manu (10.45) all those who do not belong to four castes are Dasyu and Malechas. Now some also justify violent verses of Vedas saying that all violent verses about killing godless, riteless, those who do not offer gifts actually refers to demons and not to human beings and that demons were averse to humanity. An Asura named Rambha who was the father of Mahishasur was a devotee of Vedic deity Agni. Vishnu Purana bk 3 ch 17-18 states that demons were Vedic followers who couldn’t be killed unless they apostatizes from Vedic Dharma and embraces other religions like Buddhism and Jainism. So what these incidents prove is that even demons could follow Vedic religion but still that wouldn’t make them Hindus or Humans since Hinduism believes in birth based and only those belonging to four castes can be considered Vedic followers. So this refutes the claim that demons were averse to Devas or Humanity.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Sutras,</p>
<p>Apastamba Sutra, Prasna I, Patala 9, Khanda 27.11 The expression Krishna Varna, ‘the black race,’ is truly Vedic. In the Rig-veda it usually denotes the aboriginal races, and sometimes the demons.</p>
<p>Vedas also states that the one who offers no worship is inhuman, wicked, evil, miser etc.,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.20.5 “Preserve us from the reproach of every one, who makes no offerings, is vicious and wicked and who utters ill words, so that we may be free (from anxiety).” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Shouldn’t Ishwar be friendly with entire creation? Why Ishwar is friendly only with those who make offerings? Was it invented by Rishis to get wealth in the name of god? What about the poor people who don’t even have money to feed their children. Will Ishwar forgive them or punish them as he commands to kill those who doesn’t pour gifts.</p>
<p><strong>Beheading the Demons (Non Hindus)</strong></p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.2.10 “…Here do I cut off the neck of the Raksas, who hateth us, and whom we hate’, he says; there are two people, he whom he hates and he who hates him; verily straightway he cuts their necks…”</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 1.7.7 O Agni, bring thou hitherward the Yatudhanas bound and chained. And afterward let Indra tear their heads off with his thunder-bolt.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="102" class="wp-image-7297" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi7.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x49.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 5.26 By impulse of God Savitar I take thee with arms of Asvins, with the hands of Peahen.Thou art a woman. Here I cut the necks of Rakshasas away. Barley art thou. Bar off from us our haters, bar our enemies…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="554" height="210" class="wp-image-7298" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi8.jpg?w=554" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg 554w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x114.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.26.3 Thou didst impel the sage to win the daylight, didst ruin Śuṣṇa for the pious Kutsa.The invulnerable demon’s head thou clavest when thou wouldst win the praise of Atithigva.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7299" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi9.jpg?w=612" width="505" height="123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg 612w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x73.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.14.13 With waters’ foam thou torest off, Indra, the head of Namuci, Subduing all contending hosts.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7300" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi10.jpg?w=625" width="514" height="88" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x51.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>DEATH TO THOSE WHO DOESN’T POUR GIFTS TO ISHWAR</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.44.11 “Give us not, O showerer of benefits, to the wicked. Relying upon your friendship, O Lord of riches, may we remain unharmed. Many are the boons you distribute amongst men; may you demolish those who make no libation, and root out those who present no offerings.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.176.4 Slay everyone who pours no gift, who, hard to reach, delights thee not. Bestow on us what wealth he hath: this even the worshipper awaits.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="94" class="wp-image-7301" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi11.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p><strong>PLUNDERING THE PROPERTIES OF PEOPLE WHO DO NOT OFFER GIFTS</strong></p>
<p>Ishwar commands to plunder the property of people who do not offer gifts and then to kill them.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.81.9 …Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="161" class="wp-image-7302" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi12.png?w=500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.2 Crush with thy foot the niggard churls who bring no gifts. Might art thou: There is not one to equal thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="512" height="104" class="wp-image-7303" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi13.png?w=512" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png 512w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8-300x61.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 “Thou, Soma, boldest wealth in kine which thou hast seized from niggard churls: Thou calledst forth the outspun thread.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>English translation by Arya Samaji scholar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 &#8220;O elixir of bliss, you hold the wealth of kine which you win from the greedy persons; you are the force behind the extended thread (of creation).&#8221; Tr. Svami Satya Prakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>This verse refers to the Panis tribe, according to some scholars the Panis tribe were also part of the Vedic society but were plundered and killed because they made no offerings to Ishwar, this is why they are considered Niggards. But Yaska gives a different meaning, Yaska writes that Panis tribe were Demons. One is not to be deluded by the usage of the word Demon here as Demons and Barbarians are those who does not follow the Veda or who lives beyond the boundaries of Aryavarta. The Vedic followers are commanded here to crush the Panis tribe only because they make no offerings to Vedic Gods. There are more evidences to show that tribes were plundered and killed just because they made no offerings to Vedic gods.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.56.6 These people, Indra, keep for thee all that is worthy of thy choice. Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="470" height="193" class="wp-image-7304" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi14.png?w=470" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png 470w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9-300x123.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px" /></p>
<p><strong>Plundering Godless (Adeva)</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.138.4 He boldly cast down forts which none had e’er assailed: unwearied he destroycd the godless treasure-stores. Like Sun and Moon he took the stronghold&#8217;s wealth away, and, praised in song, demolished foes with flashing dart.</p>
<p>Following is the Hindi translation by Arya Samaji scholar Shripad Damodar Satwalekar</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1101" height="197" class="wp-image-7305" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg 1101w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-300x54.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-1024x183.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-768x137.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1101px) 100vw, 1101px" /></p>
<p><strong>Dark races</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;Through your fear, O universal fire, the dark evil forces, though of many minds, come under a control, having abandoned their possessions. Adorable Lord, may you shine upon all men and blaze, consuming the cities of their foes.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Another clear translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;For fear of thee forth fled the dark-hued races, scattered abroad, deserting their possessions, When, glowing, O Vaiśvānara, for Pūru, thou Agni didst light up and rend their castles.&#8221; Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p><strong> Ishwar Behaving like a Thug</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.93.5 “When two large, mutually defiant hosts, emulous in corporal vigour, contest, may you destroy the godless in favour of the god fearing and in favour of the person who pours out devotional sentiments.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.25.7 (Indra), the drinker of the effused Soma, contracts no friendship with the wealthy trader who offers not any libation ; he takes away his wealth ; destroys him when destitute; but he is a special (friend) to him who presents the libation and oblation.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="463" height="148" class="wp-image-7306" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi15.png?w=463" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png 463w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.34.8 When Indra, the possessor of opulence, discriminates between two men, both wealthy, and exerting themselves (against each other) for the sake of valuable cattle, he takes one of them [The one who performs Yajna] as his associate, causing (his adversaries) to tremble, and the agitator (of the clouds), together with the Maruts, bestows upon him herds of cattle.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="121" class="wp-image-7307" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi16.png?w=548" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11-300x66.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p>Other verses shows that Ishwar provides protection to those who make offerings to him, but Ishwar slays the person who doesn’t worship or make offerings. Why is Ishwar behaving like a thug? Shouldn’t Ishwar be equal and friendly to everyone irrespective of their offerings? All the verses I quoted above orders to kill those who make no offerings, there are several instances in Vedas wherein tribesmen were killed just because they made no offering to Ishwar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O bounteous Lord, of what avail are the cattle of infidels to you. Neither they yield milk nor do these faithless persons kindle sacred fire. May you bring wealth of these unbelievers to us and give us possession of people of low mortality and crush them.” Tr. SayaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>This verse is referring to the Kikata tribe who were plundered by Vedic heroes and killed. Maharishi Yaska explains this as,</p>
<p>Nirukta 6.32 What are the cows doing in Kikata? Kikata is the name of a country where the non-Aryans dwell. Non-Aryan tribes are (so called because it is said),’What have they done? Or their assumption is that religious rites are useless. They neither get the milk to mix with the soma, nor kindle fire.</p>
<p>Here the Vedic god is invoked to plunder the cows of of Kikata people and to plunder the wealth of the king of Kikata tribe. As I said earlier, many tribes were plundered and looted by Vedic gods just because they made no offering to Ishwar, Kikata and Panis tribes are few examples. Here is another translation by Arya Samaj,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O learned king! you possess admirable wealth, what do the cattle do among the atheists because they have no faith in the Vedic teachings and rites or in place inhabited by them. They yield no milk to mix with the Soma, and do not perform the Yajna with the ghee of the cows. Therefore, bring them to us, so that we may use them for hospitality (giving the milk mixed with Soma) to teachers and preachers. Give us wealth taken away from the wicked persons for the use of those who hailing from a good family come to us. Remove far away from us a man who uses his power for doing mean or inglorious acts or keep him under us.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p><strong>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote on this verse</strong>, “As the cows do not grow among the wicked atheists, in the same manner, Dharma and other virtues do not grow among the persons lacking faith. Among the enlightened persons atheists can never have the upper hand. Therefore, good scholars should blot out atheism.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO HATE ISHWAR AND WHOM ISHWAR  HATES</strong></p>
<p>The entire hymn of Atharva 2.19 is dedicated in burning those who hate Ishwar and to whom Ishwar hates,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.19.1 Burn thou, O Agni, with that heat of thine against the man who hates us, whom we hate.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="189" class="wp-image-7308" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi17.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12-300x110.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.15 “…By him we attack on him who hates us and whome we abhor. We overthrow and slay him through this knowledge, through this act and through this fatal weapon.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.25 …from earth we bar him who hates us and whom we hate.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="515" height="137" class="wp-image-7309" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi18.png?w=515" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png 515w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13-300x80.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="483" height="316" class="wp-image-7310" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi19.png?w=483" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png 483w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14-300x196.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Arya Samaj commentary states that a, ‘Man [Brahmin] should satisfy himself by killing his enemies with the miraculous powers given by God’.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="457" height="79" class="wp-image-7311" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi20.png?w=457" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png 457w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 457px) 100vw, 457px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.21 “O resplendent Lord, brave and opulant, protect us this day against our foes with many and excellent defences, may the vile wretch who hates us fall before us; May the breath of life depart from him whom we hate.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 15.15 This one in front, golden-tressed, with sunbeams; the leader of his host and his chieftain are Rathagritsa and Rathaujas, and Puñjikasthalâ: and Kratusthalâ his Apsarases. Biting animals are his weapon, homicide his missile weapon; to them be homage: may they protect us, may they have mercy upon us. In their jaws we place the man whom we hate and who hates us.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="539" height="204" class="wp-image-7312" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi21.png?w=539" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png 539w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16-300x114.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 539px) 100vw, 539px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.3.3 This charm shall conquer and cast down thy foemen. <strong>Be thou the first</strong> to slay the men who hate thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="248" class="wp-image-7313" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi22.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17-300x145.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Is it right to kill someone just because they hate you or Ishwar? What kind of God is Ishwar who commands to kill the person who just hates him. The above verse explicitly says to be the first one to kill those who just ‘Hate’ you. Is this justifiable? If you just oppress a Brahmin you are liable to be killed according to Vedas, but the Brahmin can kill you, deprive you of your property, there is no sin in this, but oppressing a Brahmin is a grave sin in Vedas,</p>
<p>‘Atharva Veda 13.3.1 ‘…O Rohita (King) agitate destroy and entangle in snares the man doing wrong to Brahman.” , Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="427" class="wp-image-7314" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi23.png?w=494" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18-300x259.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.52 Rend, rend to pieces, rend away, destroy, destroy him utterly. Destroy Angirasi! the wretch who robs and wrongs the Brahmans, born.</p>
<p>Poor Shudra’s fate is to be oppressed by Brahmins,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 8.417 A Brahmana may confidently seize the goods of (his) Sudra (slave); for, as that (slave) can have no property, his master may take his possessions.</p>
<p>Maharishi Manu says that a Brahmin can even kill anyone who hurts him without bringing notice to the King,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.31-33 A Brahmana who knows the law need not bring any (offence) to the notice of the king; by his own power alone be can punish those men who injure him. His own power is greater than the power of the king; the Brahmana therefore, may punish his foes by his own power alone. Let him use without hesitation the sacred texts, revealed by Atharvan and by Angiras; speech, indeed, is the weapon of the Brahmana, with that he may slay his enemies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO REJECT AND HATE VEDAS</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.62 “Rend, rend to bits, rend through and through, scorch and consume and burn to dust, the one who rejects the Vedas”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="493" height="118" class="wp-image-7315" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi24.png?w=493" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png 493w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 493px) 100vw, 493px" /></p>
[This verse is translated from the Hindi Bhasya]
<p>Arya Samaj commentary states:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="442" height="58" class="wp-image-7316" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi25.png?w=442" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png 442w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20-300x39.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px" /></p>
<p>“Godly persons shall always be ready to kill irreligious people”</p>
[Kshemkarandas Trivedi (Arya Samaj) on Atharva Veda 12.5.62, page 576]
[Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>He writes on Atharva Veda 12.5.54</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="455" height="145" class="wp-image-7317" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi26.png?w=455" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png 455w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px" /></p>
<p>‘‘Vedic followers should destroy infidels“- Kshem Karan Das Trivedi on Atharva Veda 12.5.54, page 574 [Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Hindu god Vishnu says,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.17 When the glorious Vishnu heard their prayers he emitted from his person an illusory form wliich he gave to the celestials and said. “This illusory form shall so deceive the Daityas, so that being led astray from the path of the Vedas, they may be put to death ; for all gods, demons and others, who shall transgress the authority of the Veda, shall perish by my prowess which I exercise for the preservation of the universe. Go then ; be not affraid ; this illusory form shall go before you. celestials, it shall be of great service to you, this day.</p>
<p>Veda also commands to kill the enemies of Vedas,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.12.6 …Burn down the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="469" height="248" class="wp-image-7318" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi27.png?w=469" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png 469w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22-300x159.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" /></p>
<p>Griffith has translated the word Brahmadvish as “Haters of Prayer/devotion” which is also correct but the definition “Those who hate Vedas” is precisely correct, other correct definition is ‘Enemies of Vedas’. Dayanand Saraswati founder of Arya Samaj gives the following meaning,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="185" height="26" class="wp-image-7319" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-23.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi28.png?w=185" /></p>
<p>“Brahmadivsh = The enemies of Vedas and Ishwar.</p>
[Rig Veda Dayanand Saraswati Hindi Bhasya, Mandala 2, page 323]
<p>Vidya Martanda also endorsed his Guru’s definition,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="503" height="148" class="wp-image-7320" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi29.png?w=503" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png 503w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24-300x88.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 503px) 100vw, 503px" /></p>
[Rig Veda, By Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda, Vol 3, p.469, Published by Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, April 2002 Reprint]
<p>Satya Prakash Saraswati defines Brahmadvish as,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="565" height="87" class="wp-image-7321" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi30.png?w=565" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png 565w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25-300x46.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 565px) 100vw, 565px" /></p>
[Rig Veda Samhita, by Satya Prakash Saraswati and Vidyalankar, Vol 4, page no 1294, Published by Veda Pratishthana, New Delhi, 1977]
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON gives the following meaning,</p>
<p>‘‘One who is envious of the Vedas, of a qualified Brahmana or of the Brahmana caste is called Brahma-dvis”</p>
[Krishna The Supreme Personality of Godhead: A Summary Study of Srimad-Bhagavatam’s Tenth Canto, Part 2, by A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada, page 304, Publisher Bhaktivedanta Trust, 2003 Edition]
<p>Besides Pandit Jaydev Sharma also translates it as ‘The enemies of Vedas’, Almost every commentator and translator has given the same meaning.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.4 “O God and learned person! you take the people to the target through the path of religion and justice and protect them. If you commit a sin, the soul or God is not infested with it. Those who denounce the Vedas and God, you cast your anger on them. Therefore, we should admire your greatness.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda (Arya Samaj).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="222" class="wp-image-7322" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi31.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26-300x130.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.1 …destroy the enemies of Vedas</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="502" height="185" class="wp-image-7323" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi32.png?w=502" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png 502w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27-300x111.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8 …burn down the enemies of God, Vedas and the malice…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="481" height="248" class="wp-image-7324" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi33.png?w=481" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png 481w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28-300x155.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 481px) 100vw, 481px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.52.3 …cast your destroying weapon for the destruction of the enemies of Veda, wealth and crops.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="497" height="352" class="wp-image-7325" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi34.png?w=497" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.4 …he slays, unasked, the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="505" height="243" class="wp-image-7326" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi35.png?w=505" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png 505w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8; 6.52.3, Atharva veda 20.96.4; 2.12.6 are translated into English from the Hindi Bhashya.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THE BLASPHEMERS</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.72.1 …ye killed all darkness and the Gods’ blasphemers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="479" height="93" class="wp-image-7327" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi36.png?w=479" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png 479w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 479px" /></p>
<p>It is mentioned in Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam)</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam 4.4.17 Sati continued: If one hears an irresponsible person blaspheme the master and controller of religion, one should block his ears and go away if unable to punish him. But if one is able to kill, then one should by force cut out the blasphemer’s tongue and kill the offender, and after that one should give up his own life.</p>
<p>ISKCON scholar writes on this verse,</p>
<p>“If possible she should have cut out Daksha’s tongue because he blasphemed Lord Siva. In other words, since Lord Siva is the protector of religion, a person who vilifies him should be killed at once, and after killing such a person, one should give up one’s life…The instruction set forth here in Srimad-Bhagavatam is that one should not tolerate at any cost the activities of a person who vilifies or blasphemes an authority. If one is a Brahmana he should not give up his body because by doing so he would be responsible for killing a Brahmana; therefore a Brahmana should leave the place or block his ears so that he will not hear the blasphemy. If one happens to be a Kshatriya he has the power to punish any man; therefore a Kshatriya should at once cut out the tongue of the vilifier and kill him. But as far as the Vaisyas and Sudras are concerned, they should immediately give up their bodies.” [<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"> http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17 <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.61.3 Thou castest down, Sarasvati, those who scorned the Gods…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="478" height="120" class="wp-image-7328" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi37.png?w=478" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png 478w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32-300x75.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.14 Burn up the demons with thy fiercest flaming brand, those who have scorned thee in thy manifested might…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="147" class="wp-image-7329" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi38.png?w=492" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33-300x90.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>Recommended reading <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/vedas-and-world-peace-part-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas and World Peace part 2</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Were Buddhists persecuted by Hindus?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/were-buddhists-persecuted-by-hindus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destroy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invaders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mughal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vihara]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/were-buddhists-persecuted-by-hindus/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed Intolerance towards Buddhists The Brahmanical hostility towards Buddhism was a major reason of the decline of Buddhism in India, the place of its birth. It is quite true that at a later date the Brahmins accepted Buddha as one of the avataras but it was just another srewd Brahmin way of &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/were-buddhists-persecuted-by-hindus/" data-wpel-link="internal">Were Buddhists persecuted by Hindus?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed</p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Intolerance towards Buddhists</h3>
<p>The Brahmanical hostility towards Buddhism was a major reason of the decline of Buddhism in India, the place of its birth. It is quite true that at a later date the Brahmins accepted Buddha as one of the avataras but it was just another srewd Brahmin way of showing contempt towards the Buddha. The Hindus never really showed any friendly attitude towards the followers of the religion of the Buddha, as it shown from various historical records. The Bramins first sowed the seeds of hatred towards the Buddhists in their scriptures to gain the sympatheis of the common people in slaughtering Buddhists.<br />
<span id="more-854"></span><br />
In the Ayodhya Kaanda of Valmiki Ramayana, a Buddhist was compared to a thief and the Tathagatas to atheists (Naastiks). It said:<br />
<b>यथा </b><b>हि </b><b>चोर </b><b>स्स </b><b>तथा </b><b>हि </b><b>बुद्ध-<br />
</b><b>स्तथागतं </b><b>नास्तिकमत्र </b><b>विद्धि।</b></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>As a thief, so is Buddha. Know that Tathagatas are atheists. [Sarga 109; shloka 34]</blockquote>
<p>The Yajnavalkya Smriti says that the very sight of a monk with red robes and shaven head (referring to Buddhists), even in a dream, is a bad sign. [Yajnavalkya SmritiI/272-273]
The Agni Purana[16/1-3] and Vishnu Purana[18/13-18] refer to Buddha as an embodiment of Grand Deception (māyamohasvarup) and that he deluded the people from the Vedic Religion.  His path is a sure ticket to hell.<br />
The great philosopher of Hinduism, Shankaracharya, said that the Buddha was suffering from what we know as schizophrenia. Shankaracharya said that</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“<strong>he (Buddha) was a man given to make incoherent assertions or else that hatred of all beings</strong> induced him to propound absurd doctrines by accepting which they would become thoroughly confused.–So that–and this the Sûtra means to indicate–Buddha’s doctrine has to be entirely disregarded by all those who have a regard for their own happiness.”<br />
[Shankar Bhashya on Brahmasutra 2/2/32]</blockquote>
<p>The writer of <em>Saankhyakaarika</em>, Vachaspati Mishra, uses the words <strong>‘Mleccha (filthy)’, Purushaapsad (low people) and PashuPraay (Animal like) </strong>for Buddhists, Jains, etc. He writes:<br />
<b>आप्तग्रहणेनाs</b><b>युक्ताः  </b><b>शाक्यभिक्षुर्नि </b><b>ग्रन्थकसंसारमो </b><b>चकादीनामागमाभासाः </b><b>परिहृता </b><b>भवन्ति . </b><b>अयुक्तत्वं </b><b>चैतेषां </b><b>विगानात्, </b><b>विच्छन्न </b><b>मूलत्वात्, </b><b>प्रमाणविरुद्धार्थाभिधानात् </b><b>कैशिचदेव </b><b>मलेच्छादिभिः </b><b>पुरुषापसदैः </b><b>पशुप्रायैः </b><b>परिग्रहाद् </b><b>बोद्धव्यम् .</b></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“By saying ‘true revelation’, all pretended revelations such as those of Shaakya, Bhikshu (Buddha),etc have been set aside. The invalidity of these systems is due to their making unreasonable assertions, to want of sufficient basis, to their making statements contradictory to proofs, and lastly to their being accepted only by <strong>Mlecchas, or by mean men or by animal like people</strong>. “</p></blockquote>
<h3>Were Buddhists persecuted by Hindus? Yes, they were</h3>
<p>Buddhism suffered a great decline owing to the hostile activities of some philosphers of Brahminical thought and preachers of South India. Kumarila Bhatta was regarded as the fiercest critic of Buddhism. He was the strongest protagonist of Vedic ritualism. Kumarila is said to have been a Brahmin of Bihar who raged with the ardour to preach against Buddhism. The <em><strong>Shankar Digvijaya</strong></em>of Madhava (earliest authentic biography of Shankaracharya) refers to Malayali King Sudhanva’s brutal extermination of Buddhists at the instigation of Kumarila Bhatta.</p>
<h3>Intolerance towards Buddhists</h3>
<p>The Brahmanical hostility towards Buddhism was a major reason of the decline of Buddhism in India, the place of its birth. It is quite true that at a later date the Brahmins accepted Buddha as one of the avataras but it was just another srewd Brahmin way of showing contempt towards the Buddha. The Hindus never really showed any friendly attitude towards the followers of the religion of the Buddha, as it shown from various historical records. The Bramins first sowed the seeds of hatred towards the Buddhists in their scriptures to gain the sympatheis of the common people in slaughtering Buddhists.<br />
In the Ayodhya Kaanda of Valmiki Ramayana, a Buddhist was compared to a thief and the Tathagatas to atheists (Naastiks). It said:<br />
<b>यथा </b><b>हि </b><b>चोर </b><b>स्स </b><b>तथा </b><b>हि </b><b>बुद्ध-<br />
</b><b>स्तथागतं </b><b>नास्तिकमत्र </b><b>विद्धि।</b></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>As a thief, so is Buddha. Know that Tathagatas are atheists. [Sarga 109; shloka 34]</blockquote>
<p>The Yajnavalkya Smriti says that the very sight of a monk with red robes and shaven head (referring to Buddhists), even in a dream, is a bad sign. [Yajnavalkya SmritiI/272-273]
The Agni Purana[16/1-3] and Vishnu Purana[18/13-18] refer to Buddha as an embodiment of Grand Deception (māyamohasvarup) and that he deluded the people from the Vedic Religion.  His path is a sure ticket to hell.<br />
The great philosopher of Hinduism, Shankaracharya, said that the Buddha was suffering from what we know as schizophrenia. Shankaracharya said that</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“<strong>he (Buddha) was a man given to make incoherent assertions or else that hatred of all beings</strong> induced him to propound absurd doctrines by accepting which they would become thoroughly confused.–So that–and this the Sûtra means to indicate–Buddha’s doctrine has to be entirely disregarded by all those who have a regard for their own happiness.”<br />
[Shankar Bhashya on Brahmasutra 2/2/32]</blockquote>
<p>The writer of <em>Saankhyakaarika</em>, Vachaspati Mishra, uses the words <strong>‘Mleccha (filthy)’, Purushaapsad (low people) and PashuPraay (Animal like) </strong>for Buddhists, Jains, etc. He writes:<br />
<b>आप्तग्रहणेनाs</b><b>युक्ताः  </b><b>शाक्यभिक्षुर्नि </b><b>ग्रन्थकसंसारमो </b><b>चकादीनामागमाभासाः </b><b>परिहृता </b><b>भवन्ति . </b><b>अयुक्तत्वं </b><b>चैतेषां </b><b>विगानात्, </b><b>विच्छन्न </b><b>मूलत्वात्, </b><b>प्रमाणविरुद्धार्थाभिधानात् </b><b>कैशिचदेव </b><b>मलेच्छादिभिः </b><b>पुरुषापसदैः </b><b>पशुप्रायैः </b><b>परिग्रहाद् </b><b>बोद्धव्यम् .</b></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“By saying ‘true revelation’, all pretended revelations such as those of Shaakya, Bhikshu (Buddha),etc have been set aside. The invalidity of these systems is due to their making unreasonable assertions, to want of sufficient basis, to their making statements contradictory to proofs, and lastly to their being accepted only by <strong>Mlecchas, or by mean men or by animal like people</strong>. “</p></blockquote>
<p>Kumarila is said to have been a Brahmin of Bihar who raged with the ardour to preach against Buddhism. The <em><strong>Shankar Digvijaya</strong></em>of Madhava (earliest authentic biography of Shankaracharya) refers to Malayali King Sudhanva’s brutal extermination of Buddhists at the instigation of Kumarila Bhatta.</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>The king (Sudhanva) commanded his servants “kill all Buddhists from Himalaya to Rameshvaram, <strong>even children and elderly</strong>. Whosoever will not kill them, will be killed at my hands.” [93]
At the instigation of Kumarila Bhatta, the king killed the Buddhists, the opponents (of the Hindu religion) just like a Yogi destroys the disturbances. [95]
<strong>[Madhava-Vidyaranya, Sankara Digvijaya Sarg 1; shlokas 93-95]
</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>This was about Kumarila’s brutal persecution of Buddhists. Now let us turn to Adi Shankaracharya, the Brahmin of South India, who did  a great job of glorifying the <em>Vedas </em>and the <em>Advaita Vedanta</em> philosophy. He was vigorously anti-Buddhism. I have already quoted his remarks on Buddha, which show his ‘regard’ for the Buddhist religion (Refer Shankar Bhasya on Brahmasutra 2/2/32). With regards to the Sringeri matha built by Shankaracharya, Sir Charles Eliot in his book <em>Hinduism and Buddhism</em> (1921 Ed. Page 211) says,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“There is some reason to suppose that the Matha of Sringeri was founded on the site of a Buddhist Monestary”</p></blockquote>
<p>The 15th Sarga of his biography <em>Madhava-Vidyaranya Sankara Digvijay </em>refers to his campaigns against the Buddhists, being escorted by King Sudhanvan’s army wherever he went from the Himalayas to the India Ocean. Owing to his anti Buddhist activities, Buddhism fell on its evil days.<br />
This royal persecution of Buddhists by some Brahminic rulers was the most potent factor which contributed to bring the decline of Buddhism in India. The <strong><em>Budaun Stone Inscription</em> </strong>of Lakhanapaala refers to one <strong>Varamasiva, a Saiva ascetic, </strong>who destroyed an idol of Buddha in the South (Dakshinapatha) before his arrival in Vodamayuta (<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=epigraphia%20indica%20vol.1&amp;author1=burgess,%20jas.&amp;subject1=tribes,%20india&amp;year=1892%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=540&amp;barcode=99999990010481&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=luzac&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=ignca&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20archaeological%20library,%20%20asi&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=NULL&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=OUT_OF_COPYRIGHT&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=tagged%20image%20file%20format%20&amp;url=/data6/upload/0144/640" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">Epigraphia Indica vol.1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, Page 63)<br />
A <strong>Chalukya Inscription</strong> of 1184 A.D. refers to a feudatory chief,<strong> Mahaamandaleshvara Viruparasadeva</strong>, who is described as a’forest-fire to the Jain religion’, a ‘destroyer of the Buddha religion’, a ‘demolisher of Jain basadis’ and ‘establisher of the Sivalinga-Simhaasana (Shiva Linga Throne).He destroyed several <i>samayas </i>at Pariyalige, Anilevada (Anhilwad), Unukallu (Unkal), Sampagadi (Sampagaon), Ibbaluru (Ablur?), Marudige (Maradigi), Anampur (Alampur), KaTahada (Karad), Kembhavi, Bammakuru and other places. [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=Annual%20report%20of%20the%20archaeological%20survey%20of%20India%201929-30&amp;author1=Sahni,%20Daya%20Ram&amp;subject1=Annual%20Report%20-%20India%20-%20Archaeological%20Survey&amp;year=1935%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=272&amp;barcode=99999990229624&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=Manager%20of%20Publication,%20Delhi&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=Banasthali%20University&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=Central%20Library,%20University%20of%20Rajasthan%20&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=Digital%20Library%20of%20India&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=2009-10-06&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=Copyright%20permitted&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=Tagged%20Image%20File%20Format%20&amp;url=/data3/upload/0083/855" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">Annual report of the archaeological survey of India 1929-30<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Page 171]
We know from the record of the Nalanda Inscription of Vipulasrimitra, that a <strong>Vangala </strong>army killed a Buddhist monk named<strong>Karunasrimitra</strong> of <strong>Somapura </strong>and burnt down his house, which was actually a monastery. [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=epigraphia%20indica%20vol.21&amp;author1=sastri,%20hirananda&amp;subject1=indic%20language,%20dialects&amp;year=1931%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=431&amp;barcode=99999990010841&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=truber&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=ignca&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20archaeological%20library,%20%20asi&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=NULL&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=OUT_OF_COPYRIGHT&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=tagged%20image%20file%20format%20&amp;url=/data6/upload/0145/000" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">Epigraphia Indica vol.21<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Page 97]
Another fierce Hindu king who showed his great hostility towards Buddhism was <strong>Shashanka, the King of Gauda</strong>. He was a notable example of anti-Buddhist Brahminical fanaticism. He is said to have uprooted the sacred Bodhi-Tree at Bodh-Gaya but in order to destroy it totally, he burnt its remains. A Buddha image from a temple east of the Bodhi tree was removed by him and in its place, he installed an image of Siva. [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=On%20Yuan%20Chwang%27s%20Travels%20In%20India%20%20vol.%202&amp;author1=Watters,%20Thomas&amp;subject1=GEOGRAPHY.%20BIOGRAPHY.%20HISTORY&amp;year=1905%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=368&amp;barcode=4990010212648&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=V.%20B.%20Librarian&amp;publisher1=Royal%20Asiatic%20Society,%20London&amp;contributor1=Smith,%20Vincent%20A.,%20ill.&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=cdack&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=CENTRAL%20LIBRARY,%20VISVA-BHARATI&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=Digital%20Library%20Of%20India&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=2006-03-30&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=In%20Public%20Domain&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=Tagged%20Image%20File%20Format%20&amp;url=/data3/upload/0066/800" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">On Yuan Chwang&#8217;s Travels in India vol. 2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> by Thomas Watters, 1905, Pages 115,116]
This is corroborated by <em>The Life of Hiuen Tsiang by the Shaman Hwui Li</em> who mentions that a certain <strong>Kumaara-Raja</strong> threatened the monks of Nalanda with a behaviour similar to Shashanka, and with the destruction of the whole monastery unless Hiuen Tsang was sent to his court. Kumara-Raja wrote in his letter,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“I have again sent a messenger with a written request: If he (Hiuen Tsang) does not  come, your disciple will then let the evil portion of himself prevail. In recent times Shanshanka-Raja was equal still to the destruction of the law and uprooted the Bodhi tree. Do you, my Master, suppose that your disciple has no such power as this? If necessary then I will equip my army and elephants, and like the clouds sweep down on and trample to the very dust that monastery of Nalanda. These words <i>(are true) </i>as the sun!” [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=The%20Life%20Of%20Hiuen-Tsiang&amp;author1=Shaman%20Hwui%20Li&amp;subject1=GEOGRAPHY.%20BIOGRAPHY.%20HISTORY&amp;year=1911%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=272&amp;barcode=4990010212716&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=V.%20B.%20Librarian&amp;publisher1=Kegan%20Paul,%20Trench,%20Trubner%20and%20Co.,%20London&amp;contributor1=Cranmer-Byng,%20L.&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=cdack&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=CENTRAL%20LIBRARY,%20VISVA-BHARATI&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=Digital%20Library%20Of%20India&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=2006-03-30&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=In%20Public%20Domain&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=Tagged%20Image%20File%20Format%20&amp;url=/data3/upload/0066/868" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><em>The Life of Hiuen Tsiang by the Shaman Hwui Li</em><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ; Translated by Samuel Beal; 1911;  Pg. 171]</blockquote>
<p>Another cruel persecutor of Buddhism was <strong>Mihirakula</strong>, who had occupied the throne of Kashmir. <strong>Kalhana Pandit</strong>, the famous chronicler of Kashmir and the author of <strong><em>Rajatarangini</em></strong>, says that for his atrocities he was like Yama, the god of death. Kalhana describes further: “One’s tongue would become polluted if one attempted to record his cruelties and evil deeds in detail” [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=kalhana%27s%20rajtarangini%20a%20chronicle%20of%20the%20kings%20of%20kashmir&amp;author1=stein,%20m.a.&amp;subject1=kashmir%20history&amp;year=1900%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=580&amp;barcode=99999990253849&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=archibald%20constable%20and%20co.%20ltd.&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=uod,delhi&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20library,%20delhi%20university&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=NULL&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=not%20available&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=book%20&amp;url=/data4/upload/0106/653" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong><em>Rajatarangini </em></strong><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>I, 289,290 and 304; Translated by M. A. Stein]. From his account it is known that Mihirakula played an important role in the development of Brahmanism. He was a worshipper of Shiva and built a Shiva temple in Srinagara [<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=kalhana%27s%20rajtarangini%20a%20chronicle%20of%20the%20kings%20of%20kashmir&amp;author1=stein,%20m.a.&amp;subject1=kashmir%20history&amp;year=1900%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=580&amp;barcode=99999990253849&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=archibald%20constable%20and%20co.%20ltd.&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=uod,delhi&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20library,%20delhi%20university&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=NULL&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=not%20available&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=book%20&amp;url=/data4/upload/0106/653" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><em>Rajatarangini</em><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> I, 306; M. A. Stein]. The view that he was a Shaivite is upheld by M. A. Stein as he writes,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“The impression which this tradition retained of Mihirakula’s religious propensities, is in full accord with the evidence of his coins which, in the emblems of bull and trident and in the legends of jayatu vrsa, jayatu vrsadhvaja, display a distinct leaning towards Shaivism.”<br />
[<a><strong>Rajatarangini</strong></a>; M. A. Stein; Footnote to I, 289]</blockquote>
<p>Mihirakula oppressed the Buddhists and behaved with them cruelly. At his instigation not only were many Buddhists murdered but many Stupas, Caityas, Vihaaras, and other Buddhist establishments were destroyed in Punjab and Kashmir. The description of his cruelties as described in the <em>Rajatarangini </em>is corroborated by the description given by Hiuen Tsang in his book <strong><em>Si-Yu-Ki</em></strong>. He writes,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“He exterminated the royal family and the chief minister, overthrew stupas, destroyed the sangharamas, altogether one thousand six hundred foundations.”<br />
[<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=si-yu-ki.%20buddhist%20records%20of%20the%20western%20world&amp;author1=tsiang,%20hiuen%20and%20beal,%20samuel&amp;subject1=europe,%20description%20and%20travel&amp;year=1969%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=734&amp;barcode=99999990040816&amp;author2=&amp;identifier1=&amp;publisher1=oriental%20books%20reprint%20corporation&amp;contributor1=&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20archaeological%20library,%20%20asi&amp;scannerno1=&amp;digitalrepublisher1=&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=&amp;unnumberedpages1=&amp;rights1=OUT_OF_COPYRIGHT&amp;copyrightowner1=&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=&amp;format1=tagged%20image%20file%20format%20&amp;url=/data8/upload/0238/099" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">Si-Yu-Ki. Buddhist Records of the Western World<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Tr. Samuel Beal, 1969; Book iv, Page 171]</blockquote>
<p>Mihirakula’s hostility towards the Buddhist was shared by the Shaivite Brahmins. Kalhana comments in the <em>Rajatarangini </em>on the greed of the Brahmins who eagerly accepted grants of land from Mihirakula.</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“Brahmins from Gandhara, resembling himself in their habits and verily themselves the lowest of the twice-born, accepted Agraharas from him.”<br />
[<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=kalhana%27s%20rajtarangini%20a%20chronicle%20of%20the%20kings%20of%20kashmir&amp;author1=stein,%20m.a.&amp;subject1=kashmir%20history&amp;year=1900%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=580&amp;barcode=99999990253849&amp;author2=NULL&amp;identifier1=NULL&amp;publisher1=archibald%20constable%20and%20co.%20ltd.&amp;contributor1=NULL&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=uod,delhi&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=central%20library,%20delhi%20university&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=NULL&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=0000-00-00&amp;numberedpages1=0&amp;unnumberedpages1=0&amp;rights1=not%20available&amp;copyrightowner1=NULL&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=0000-00-00&amp;format1=book%20&amp;url=/data4/upload/0106/653" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><em>Rajatarangini</em><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> I, 307; M. A. Stein]</blockquote>
<p>This shows that the Brahmins were hand in glove with his slaughter of Buddhists and the destruction of the Buddhist establishments. So, the fake polemics of some Hindu writers that Mihirakula was not a Hindu or that his destruction of Buddhists establishments cannot be tied to Hindus are unfounded.<br />
Another hateful persecutor of Buddhists was Pushyamitra Sunga, founder of the Sunga Dynasty. Several Chinese and Japanese historians mention Pushyamitra’s name at the head of the list of persecutors. Buddhist writers portray Pushyanitra as a cruel persecutor of the religion of Sakyamuni (Buddha). Pushyamitra, a militant follower of Brahminism, assassinated the last Mauryan Emperor Brhadratha, capturing the throne of Magadha and founded the Sunga Dynasty. It ruled for a period of one hundred and twelve years.  Pushyamitra had to justify his position as head of the Brahmanic reaction by persecuting the Buddhists and destroying Buddhist monasteries on the one hand and restoring the sacrificial ceremonies of the Brahmanic faith on the other, for which his principal helpers were Patanjali and also perhaps Manu, the author of the <i>Manusmriti. </i>who was also his contemporary according to some scholars. The persecution of the Buddhists by Pushyamitra, was a logical sequence of the Brahmanic reaction and the political <em>coup d’etat</em>. The Buddhist text <em>Divyavadana </em>mentions the persecutions of Pushyamitra and his destruction of Buddhist stupas and monasteries. Hindutva apologists such as Dr. Koenraad Elst have tried to refute these charges on Pushyamitra, saying that they are “rendered improbable by external evidence”. Elst then claims that “he (Pushyamitra) allowed and patronized the construction of monasteries and Buddhist universities in his domains, as well as the still-extant stupa of Sanchi.” Although he gives no reference for this claim, it is possible that he was referring to the epigraph on the <strong>gateway of Barhut,</strong> which mentions its erection “during the supremacy of the Sungas“. The inscription uses the words <strong>सुगनं रजे</strong> (During the reign of Sungas). It does not necessarily include the reign of Pushyamitra. It only means ‘during the reign of Sungas’. The gateway was constructed during the reign of his successors who were more tolerant to Buddhism than the founder of the dynasty and leader of the Brahmanic reaction. That the gateways were erected long after the time of Pushyamitra is also the opinion of eminent archaeologists like Mr. N. G. Mazumdar, who writes,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“The Sungas referred to in this inscription formed a dynasty which was founded by the general (Senapati) Pushyamitra, succeeding the Mauryas about 180 B.C. <strong>The gateways, however, appear to have been set up about a century later, towards the close o the Sunga period</strong>.”<br />
[<a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.new1.dli.ernet.in/cgi-bin/metainfo.cgi?&amp;title1=A%20Guide%20To%20The%20Sculptures%20In%20The%20Indian%20Museum,Pt.I%20&amp;author1=Majumdar,N.G.&amp;subject1=GEOGRAPHY.%20BIOGRAPHY.%20HISTORY&amp;year=1937%20&amp;language1=english&amp;pages=150&amp;barcode=4990010056058&amp;author2=&amp;identifier1=VB%20Librarian&amp;publisher1=Manager%20Of%20Publications,%20Delhi&amp;contributor1=&amp;vendor1=NONE&amp;scanningcentre1=cdack&amp;slocation1=NONE&amp;sourcelib1=CENTRAL%20LIBRARY,%20VISVA-BHARATI&amp;scannerno1=0&amp;digitalrepublisher1=Digital%20Library%20Of%20India&amp;digitalpublicationdate1=2011-11-21&amp;numberedpages1=&amp;unnumberedpages1=&amp;rights1=In%20Public%20Domain&amp;copyrightowner1=&amp;copyrightexpirydate1=&amp;format1=Tagged%20Image%20File%20Format%20&amp;url=/data8/upload/0253/341" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">A Guide To The Sculptures In The Indian Museum, Pt.I<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> N. G. Mazumdar, 1937 Ed., Page 13]</blockquote>
<p>Dr. Elst also quotes the historian of Buddhism, Etienne Lamotte, who wrote, “To judge from the documents, Pushyamitra must be acquitted through lack of proof”. [History of Indian Buddhism, Institut Orientaliste, Louvain-la-Neuve 1988/1958, p.109] Firstly, this reference is incorrect as the page number is 392. Even then, let me provide the complete quote of Etienne Lamotte. He writes,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“To judge from the documents, Pushyamitra must be acquitted through lack of proof. Nevertheless, as was remarked by H. Kern, in view of the varied opinions, <strong>it is possible that, in some localities, there may have been pillages of monasteries, perhaps with the tacit permission of the governors</strong>. “</p></blockquote>
<p>Prominent Indian historian, professor Romila Thapar writes,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“Buddhist sources claim that they (Sungas) persecuted the Buddhists and destroyed their monasteries and places of worship. This could have been an exaggeration, but archaeological evidence reveals that Buddhist monuments in the Sunga domain were at this time in disrepair and being renovated. However, if the chronology of these monuments shifts forward as is now being suggested, then this would make them post-Sunga renovations. Nevertheless, even if some renovations were of a later date, the damage to the stupa at Sanchi, and to the monastery at Kaushambi dates to Shunga times. Added emphasis is given to this from Pushyamitra having performed <em>ashvamedhas</em>, or horse sacrifices. This is sometimes viewed as indicating support of Vedic Brahmanism and a disapproval of heterodox sects.”<br />
[The Penguin History of Early India from the origins to AD 1300, Romila Thapar, 2002 Edition, Pg. 210]</blockquote>
<p id="pjWJziA"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="294" height="203" class="size-full wp-image-7363  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f2509e59a02f.png" alt="" /></p>
<p> This view of Professor Thapar was confirmed when <strong>Deorkothar Stupas</strong>were excavated by P. K. Mishra (Archaeological Survey of India) in 1999 till 2000. The story about this Stupa was published by P. K. Mishra on the official website of the <em>Archaeology</em> magazine, a publication of the Archaeological Institute of America. P. K. Mishra wrote,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>“The ancient Buddhist text <em>Divyavadanam </em>speaks of the death and destruction brought about by Pushyamitra Sunga, who ruled in the first quarter of the second century B.C., in a bid to glorify Hinduism. During his reign, Buddhist monuments were wantonly destroyed. Although archaeological evidence is meager in this regard, it seems likely that the Deorkothar stupa was destroyed as a result of Pushyamitra Sunga’s fanaticism. The exposed remains at Deorkothar bear evidence of deliberate destruction datable to his reign. The three-tiered railing is damaged; railing pillars lie, broken to smithereens, on stone flooring. Twenty pieces of pillar have been recovered, each fragment itself fractured. The site offers no indication of natural destruction.”<br />
[SOURCE: <a href="http://archive.archaeology.org/online/news/deorkothar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://archive.archaeology.org/online/news/deorkothar/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]</blockquote>
<p>Etienne Lamotte wrote his book in 1958, when he did not have the new archaeological findings before him. To hang on to his quote is an example of a drowning man clutching at straws.<br />
Further Reading<br />
Buddhist scholars have also laid claim to many Hindu temples being original Buddhist Shrines. A book written by Dr. K. Jamnadas was titled <em>‘Tirupati Balaji was a Buddhist Shrine’</em>. In this book, the author has given huge stock of evidence to prove that the temple which is today sacred to Hindus was once a Buddhist Shrine. Readers are advised to make up their own mind after reading the book themselves and verifying the proofs.The book can be downloaded from the link <a style="color: #9f9f9f;" href="http://www.ambedkar.org/Tirupati/Tirupati.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.ambedkar.org/Tirupati/Tirupati.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/were-buddhists-persecuted-by-hindus/" data-wpel-link="internal">Were Buddhists persecuted by Hindus?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
