<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>hajre aswad &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/hajre-aswad/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 12:45:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What is Shivling?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2022/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 06:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Immorality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analyse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[definition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history of shivling linga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[is shivlingam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lingam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning of shivling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mecca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phallus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what is shivling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Analysis of Lingam (updated) &#160; Written by Sulaiman Razvi The meaning of Shiva Ling or Lingam has become a subject of controversy in recent times. Hindus revere the Shiv Ling. Hindu god Shiva is considered “The Destroyer” part of Trimurti and he is also considered the Ascetic god. The early scholars of Hinduism didn’t lay &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2022/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Shivling?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: arial black, sans-serif;">Analysis of Lingam (updated)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>The meaning of Shiva Ling or Lingam has become a subject of controversy in recent times. Hindus revere the Shiv Ling. Hindu god Shiva is considered “The Destroyer” part of Trimurti and he is also considered the Ascetic god. The early scholars of Hinduism didn’t lay stress on the meaning of Shivling, it was only in recent times when Hinduism was exposed to foreigners that some Hindu scholars started giving their definitions. Hindus insist that Shivling isn’t a male genital organ despite Hindu scriptures defining Shivling as Shiva’s penis, it&#8217;s obvious that Hindus are embarrassed by this definition of Shivling. When dealing with such issues we have to look deep into its history. Shiva Lingam actually a Phallic (male erected generative organ) emblem is considered a symbol by present-day Hindu scholars. We can find traces of Phallus or Shiva Lingam worshipers in the Rig Veda which is the oldest scripture of Hinduism, Rig Veda Mandal 7, Sukta 21, verse 5 mentions Shishnadeva which is literally translated as Penis worshippers (Sishna+Deva), we read that the ancient Aryans were hostile towards these worshipers. However, its meaning is obscure as some scholars consider the word Shishandeva to be “lewd people” or “unchaste people”, it could be that those people were considered unchaste on account of them being Phallus worshippers. When you tell any Hindu that Shivling is penis, he would reply that the Sanskrit word Shisan is generally used for penis and not Ling, but they would deny that Shishandeva mentioned in Rigved is penis worshippers as they have unending excuses to defend their Dharm.</p>
<p><span id="more-756"></span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">The meaning of Ling</span></strong></h1>
<p><img decoding="async" width="601" height="84" class="wp-image-8795 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-601w84h.png" alt="C:\Users\Hassan Razvi\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Word\apte penis ling.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-601w84h.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-601w84h-300x42.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /><br />
[Student’s Sanskrit English Dictionary 1893 edition, By V.S Apte, page 311]
<p>ISKCON scholars give the following meaning,</p>
<p>“lingam — phallic symbol which is used in the worship of Lord Śiva.” [Source: <a href="http://www.prabhupada-books.de/gita/glossary/glossary_L.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.prabhupada-books.de/gita/glossary/glossary_L.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">It is mentioned in Mahabharata,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Mahabharata Anushasana Parva 13, section, 14, verses 230-1 …all creatures bear the signs that mark Mahadeva and his spouse. Hence, all creatures must be regarded as belonging to Maheswara. All creatures of the feminine sex, have sprung from Ulna’s nature as their cause, and hence it is they bear the mark of femininity that distinguishes Uma; while all creatures that are masculine, having sprung from Siva, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">bear the masculine mark that distinguishes Siva</span>…” Tr. K.M. Ganguly</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">So what is that masculine mark that distinguishes a male person? It’s obviously the male organ (penis). And it is that which distinguishes Siva also. The pedestal of Shivling is Yoni which translates as Vagina. The meaning of Ling and Yoni itself should dispel doubt about Shivling not being a </span><span style="font-size: 11pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;">male genital organ.</span> </span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">Rishis cutting o</span><span style="color: initial;">f</span><span style="color: initial;">f Bhikshatan’s (Shiva) Penis in Darunavam forest </span></strong></h1>
<p>There are mainly two versions of Shivling origin. One which proves Shivling as a male organ and another one appear as a measureless cosmic pillar, this too has a story which proves Shivling to be penis. But the Shivling as penis version is emphasized in the Hindu scriptures which is why this version has a group of stories on the origin of the Shivling. But the most repeated story is that of Shiva going to Darunvanam forest in his Bhikshatana avatar which is his “Supreme Beggar” form and is depicted as a nude man. Rishis resided in Daruvanam forest with their families, Shiva went to Darunavam forest fully nude holding a begging bowl in hand and as per some text he appeared there in front of the wives and daughters of Rishis with an erected penis, he enchanted the wives and daughters of Rishis which according to me is nothing but molestation. No person in the right mind would appear naked with an erected penis in front of women, in the modern world the person would be behind bars on sexual harassment charges. Coming to the point, this angered the Rishis who started beating up Shiva (Bhikshatana) and cut off his penis, as per some version the penis fell down due to the curse by sages, that penis grew larger and wreaked havoc on the earth, and Rishis went to Brahma to stop it but he recommended Rishis to propitiate Shiva. As advised by Brahma, the Rishis begged Shiva to withdraw his Ling, Shiva agreed on one condition that Rishis make a pedestal akin to Parvati’s vagina which will hold the Ling, and that the Rishis should start worshipping it. Rishis did as told by Shiva and that’s how Shivling came to be worshipped. Let’s go through Hindu texts and read about different versions on the origin of Shivling.</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Kotirudra Samhita 4, chapter 12, verses 8-51 “Once the leading Brahmin devotees of Siva engrossed in the meditation of Siva went into the forest for bringing sacrificial twigs. In the meantime Siva himself assuming a very hideous form came there in order to test their devotion. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">He was very brilliant but stark naked</span>. He had smeared ashes all over his body as the sole ornament. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Standing there and holding his penis he began to show all sorts of vicious tricks</span>. It was with a mind to do something pleasing to the forest-dwellers that Siva, favourite of the devotees, came to the forest at his will. The wives of the sages were extremely frightened at this sight. The other women excited and surprised approached the lord. Some embraced him. Others held his hands. The women were engrossed in struggling with one another…When the naked sage did not reply, the great sages told that terrible Puruṣa. “You are acting pervertedly. This violates the Vedic path. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Hence let your penis fall on the ground</span>.” When they said thus, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">the penis of that Avadhūta, who was Śiva of wonderful form, fell down instantly. That penis burnt everything in front; wherever it went it began to burn everything there</span>. It went to Pātāla; it went to heaven; it went all over the earth; it never remained steady anywhere. &#8220;When the naked sage did&#8230;Brahmā said:— Let the gods propitiate goddess <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Pārvatī and pray. If she can assume the form of the vaginal passage that penis will become steady</span>&#8230;The penis shall be drenched with that water, O great sages. When the sprinkling is made with Śatarudrīya mantras it will become stable. Pārvatī in the form of the Vaginal passage and an auspicious arrow shall form as the pedestal wherein the phallus shall be installed in accompaniment of the Vedic mantras&#8230;After propitiating Pārvatī and the bull-bannered lord and performing the rites mentioned before, the excellent penis became static&#8230; Śiva became delighted and so also Pārvatī, the mother of the universe. That phallus was held by her in that form then.&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Following is another translation of this passage by Shiva Sharan (Alain Daniélou),</p>
<p><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">Shiva Purana, Kothi Rudra Samhita 4.12.17-46</span> <span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">“</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">Shocked by the appearance and behaviour of Shiva, the sages of the forest said to him, ‘You have acted perversely. That is contrary to the scriptures. </span><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000; background-color: #ffffff;">Your sexual organ will fall to the ground’. When they had thus spoken, the sexual organ of this messenger of Heaven, who was none other than Shiva of the marvellous forms, at once fell to the ground</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">. The phallus burned everything before it; wherever it went, all was consumed. It travelled through the under-world, in heaven and on the earth, never staying in one place. All the worlds and their inhabitants lived in anguish. The sages were struck with dismay. The gods, and the sages knew neither peace nor pleasure any more. [all the sages then went to God Brahma] and Brahma continued, ‘As long as this Phallus is not in a fixed position, no good can come to any of the three worlds. </span><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000; background-color: #ffffff;">In order to calm its wrath, you must sprinkle this divine sexual organ with holy water, build a pedestal in the form of a vagina and shaft (symbol of the goddess), and install it with prayers, offerings, prostrations, hymns and chants accompanied by musical instruments</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">. Then you shall invoke the god, saying, ‘You are present in everything that exists. The universe is but the form of yourself. O benevolent One! calm yourself and protect the world’. The sages therefore reverently approached Shiva who said to them, </span><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000; background-color: #ffffff;">‘The world shall not find peace until receptacle is found for my sexual organ. No other being except the Lady of the Mountain [ie., Parvati] may seize hold of my sexual organ</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">. If she takes hold of it, </span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">it will immediately become calm</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">.</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">”</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;"> Tr.</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;"> Shiva Sharan</span> <span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">(</span><span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">Alain </span>Daniélou)</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">This story is further supported by various other Puranas which I have mentioned below,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Kurma Purana II.38.52 “The sages said: A certain highly brilliant person has entered the holy Daruvana along with his wife, who was very beautiful in all her limbs. But he was naked. The lordly person fascinated our entire women and daughters, with his charming personality. While his beloved defiled our sons. We heaped various imprecations and curses on him but they were defied and set at nought. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">He was beaten soundly by us. His Linga was struck down</span>.” Tr. Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Kurma Purana, Part II, chapter 39, verses 1-3 states,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Kurma Purana II.39.1-3 &#8220;[The sages said:] O lord of all immortal beings, tell us, how we can see the Pinaka-bearing lord once again. You are the saviour of those who seek refuge. [Brahma said:] <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Make an excellent Linga of the Lord resembling the Linga which was seen by you all and struck down on to the ground</span>, and observing celibacy, worship it with respect along with your wives and sons, through the varios Vedic observances.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Brahmanda Purana, Part I, Anusanga Pada 2, chapter 27, verse 45 states,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Brahmanda Purana I.2.27.45 “He [Shiva] was scolded and beaten. <span style="color: #ff0000;">His Linga (?penis) was taken out</span>. It is to alleviate his anger that we have sought refuge in you.” Tr. G.V. Tagare </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">There is also a mixture of the two versions of Shivling origin, following verses from Vamana and Skanda Purana mention the Darunavam story but with the fusion of the penis and cosmic pillar stories. When the penis became endless, Vishnu assumed the form of a boar and digs the earth to find its beginning and Brahma becomes a swan and flies upwards (according to some he flies in his lotus plane) to find its end, on failing to find the beginning or end they return to the same place and accepts Shiva to be the superior god and worships Shiva. There’s also a twist, as per some text Brahma decided to cheat, saying that he had reached the top of the Linga and brought Ketaki flower as proof. Following is Skanda Purana I.1.6.25-44, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana Māheśvara-khaṇḍa 1, Kedāra-khaṇḍa 1, chapter 6, verses 2-34 &#8220;Lord Śaṃbhu wandered about in the forest Dāruvana for the sake of begging alms. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">The sole lord of the worlds with quarters for his garments (i.e. naked)</span>, having the cluster of his matted hair loosened&#8230;At midday the sages, O brāhmaṇas, went to the sacred places (for bath) from their hermitages. At that very time, all the wives of those sages came there. On seeing Śaṃbhu they spoke to one another, “Who is this personage of uncommon appearance, who has come here in the form of a mendicant? We along with our friends shall give him alms.” Saying, “So be it”, they went home and joyously brought various kinds of food as alms&#8230;In this manner all young women gathered together at the place where Śaṅkara was (standing). The alms-bowl of Śaṃbhu was filled with cooked food of very good quality. Four types of foodstuffs with all the six tastes filled his bowl. When Śaṃbhu was desirous of returning to the Kailāsa mountain, all those wives of brāhmaṇas joyously followed him forsaking their domestic duties. With their minds attached to him, they walked on and on (after him)&#8230;When all those wives (of sages) had left thus, the excellent sages reached their hermitages and found them empty and vacant. They spoke to one another, “Where have all these women (our wives) gone? We do not know by what damned fellow they have been abducted.” Pondering and deliberating thus they searched here and there. Thereupon they saw that they had been following Śiva. On seeing Śiva, the sages angrily closed in upon him. Standing in front of Śiva, all of them said with impetuosity, “What has been done by you, O Śaṃbhu (who profess to be) detached and noble-souled? You are no doubt the kidnapper of the wives of others, i.e. of us, the sages.” Although rebuked thus, Śiva silently went on towards his mountain. Then that immutable Mahādeva was overtaken by the sages. (They then cursed him thus:) “<span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Since you are the abductor of (our) wives, be instantaneously a eunuch.” Thus cursed by the sages, his penis fell down on the ground</span>. As soon as it reached the ground, it became very large immediately and it increased in size (enormously). From beneath and above, the Liṅga covered the seven Pātālas in an instant. Then it pervaded the entire earth and enveloped the firmament. All the heavens were covered. Then it rose beyond the heavens&#8230;Viṣṇu and the Lotus-bora god Brahmā both of whom were (gods) of exalted fortune, heard this. Viṣṇu went to the nether worlds and Brahmā went to heaven.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">A similar story is mentioned in Vamana Purana chapter 6, verses 57-84 which states that Kama (Cupid) was going to strike Shiva so he went to Daruvanam forest, as Shiva had seduced wives of sages so they cursed him, as a result of the curse Shiva’s penis fell off, Shiva disappeared from the place, all people were terrified, terrible omen ensued.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Vamana Purana 6.57- 84 &#8220;Going there too <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Cupid saw Sankara, and Hara finding him ready to strike, fled from that place</span>. Then pursued by Cupid, Hara entered the frightful pine forest where Rsis were settled with their consorts&#8230;Seeing him enter, the wives of Bhargavas and Atreyas felt excited and completely lost their self control, excepting the unique Arundhati and the lady Anasuya&#8230;Wherever Sankara went women became agitated and with their passion excited, they followed him. Leaving their own hermitages vacant, the wives of the sages followed him, in the same way as the she-elephants follow the he-elephants. O sage, enraged at this sight the Rsis, Bhargavas and Angirasas said, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">&#8216;May his Linga drop down on the earth</span>.&#8217; <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Subsequently the Linga of the deity dropped down</span> rending the earth and the trident-holding Sankara invisible. Thereafter cleaving the earth, the Linga fell down, entered the lower world instantly and rent the universe at the top. Then Hari viewing the measureless Linga and mounting the chief of birds entered the nether world, wonderstruck. O Brahman, making an all round survey from above on his lotus plane Brahman could not reach its end, and returned amazed. O great sage, the Visnu&#8230;visited the seven regions under the earth and later came out, but did not reach its end. Approaching the Linga of Hara both Visnu and Brahman began to propitiate the god with hands folded before him&#8230;The gods said &#8216;O Sankara, withdraw the Linga of yours which was hurled down on the earth. O Lord, for this do we propitiate you. Hara said, &#8216;O Exalted gods, if the gods worship my Linga, then I can take it back and in no other manner.&#8221; Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">A similar story is mentioned in Linga Purana also but it doesn’t mention the bobbitising of Shiva, but the story does say that Shiva went to the forest intending to seduce them as well as to test them, Shiva seduced women of sages by his erotic gestures, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Linga Purana, Section I, chapter 29, verses 5-36 &#8220;In order to propitiate the lord of Devas, the sages performed a terrible penance in the Daru forest. They were accompanied by their wives, sons and sacrificial fires&#8230;Rudra, wanted to test the sincerity of the dwellers of the Daru forest&#8230;Thus in order to test their faith, and sportively too, he assumed a deformed but attractive appearance. He had three eyes and two hands. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">He was nude</span>, and dark in complexion. Even in this form he was extremely handsome. He was smiling and singing, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">with seductive play of his eyebrows, thereby creating feelings of love in the hearts of women</span>. He the destroyer of cupid, the lord of extremely handsome features increased their sexual feelings On seeing a man of deformed features, black-red (in colour), even the chaste women followed him with great enthusiasm&#8230;One of them, on seeing him did not know that her upper and lower garments had stripped off. Others in their excitement could not distinguish between their kinsmen and the multi-branched trees though they were familiar&#8230;Due to the Maya of Rudra even the chaste ladies fell down in an awkward posture with their clothes loosened and their tresses dishevelled, in the very presence of their husbands…On seeing the crowd of women and Rudra in this situation the brahmins, leading sages began to say harsh words. Their powers of austerity were ineffective against Rudra&#8230;Thus deluded the sages of Daruvanam did not understand Rudra. They spoke harsh words to Rudra who thereupon disappeared. In the morning all those sages with perplexed minds and blurred thinking went from Daruvana to Brahma of noble soul&#8230;they informed him about what had happened in that holy Daru forest&#8230;He stood up with palm joined in reverence and bowed to Rudra. He then spoke hurriedly to the sages who had their abodes in Daru forest. Fie upon you all who had attained excellent treasure, O brahmins, but had unluckily wasted it. The man with a Linga who had been seen by you all without Lingas, the person of deformed features was the supreme lord himself.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edied by J.L. Shastri</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Here the line &#8220;without Linga&#8221; means impotent men. Mahabharata 13.14.157 states that Shiva had sex with the daughters and wives of Rishis, I assume this is alluding to the Darunvama forest story, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Mahabarata, Anusasana Parva 13, section 14, verse 157 <span style="color: #353535; background-color: #ffffff;">“He sports with the daughters and wives of the Rishis. His hair is long and erect. He is perfectly nude for he has the horizon for his dress. He has terrible eyes.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Nilkantha Chaturdhara the commentator of Mahabharata wrote,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">“It is known that Siva entered the Pine Forest naked in order to entice the wives of the sages.” Nilkantha Chaturdhara on Mahabharata XIII.17.42, Tr. Wendy Doniger</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">In the Skanda Purana I.i.34.116-129, Parvati the wife of Shiva says that Shiva went to Daruvanam forest nude only to seduce women of sages on the pretext of begging alms, Parvati had denuded Shiva in front of gods and their servants after Shiva lost bet in the game of dice, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana, Part 1, Mahesvarakhanda book 1, Kedarkhanda section 1, chapter 34, verses 11-129 &#8220;After saying thus, Parvati, the goddess, beloved of Sankara, became furious. She held Sankara by the hand. The lady of slender limbs took away the serpent Vasuki from his neck. Similarly she removed many other ornaments also. The infuriated lady hurriedly took away the ornaments of Sambhu. His crescent moon and his excellent elephant hide removed. The serpents Kambala and Asvatara tha thad been worn by Mahesa as ornaments were removed by the great goddess laughingly with tricky words. Even his loincloth was taken away laughingly with the utterance of tricky words. At that time the Ganas and the friends (of Parvati) felt embarrassed and ashamed. (The friends and others) turned their faces away. Bhrngi of great oenance, Candi, Munda, Mahaloman, Mahodara and many other Ganas became miserable. On seeing them in that plight, Mahesa became ashamed. Sankara who became angry spoke these words to Parvati: &#8216;All these sages are laughing satirically. Similarly Brahma, Visnu and these Devas, Indra and others all of them laughing (at me)&#8230;On being told thus by Sambhu, the Yogin, Parvati, the chaste lady of charming face, laughed and spoke these words: <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">&#8216;What have you to do with a loincloth</span>? You are a sage of sanctified soul. (Some time back) <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">you wandered through Daruvana with the cardinal points alone for your garment (i.e. you were naked). Under the pretext of begging for alms, the wives of the sages were enchanted</span>. While you were going, you were greatly adored by them. Your loincloth fell down (penis?) there&#8230;&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Dharmasamhita of Shiva Purana states that on not getting sexual pleasure from his wife Gauri he went to pine forest with an erect penis, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Shiva Purana, Dharmasamhita 10.187; 10.78-80 “When Siva failed to be satisfied by making love to Gauri, his wife, he then went naked into the Pine forest in the guise of madman, his linga erect, his mind full of desire, wishing to obtain sexual pleasures with the wives of the sages.” Tr. Wendy Doniger</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana VI.258.1-20 version also states that Shiva was infuriated with the urge to have sexual intercourse but Parvati was doing penance so he tried to calm himself by pouring water on his body, by taking dips in rivers and streams but to no avail, he then went to the abode of sages and seduced women of sages, the sages in anger cursed Shiva’s penis to fall off, the penis fell down instantly due to which blood was oozing out from Shiva. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana, Nāgara-khaṇḍa 6, Tīrtha-māhātmya section 1, chapter 258, verses 1-20 &#8220;When the Daughter of Mountain became engrossed in a great and terrible penance, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Hara who had been overwhelmed by Kandarpa (god of Love)</span> roamed over the earth in the Tirthas, cool shades of trees, rivers, streams everywhere. Mahesvara indulged in sprinkling his body with water. Still the Lord oppressed by Kama, did not attain happiness anywhere&#8230;Mahesa adopted a handsome form and (roamed about on her banks)&#8230;As he passed through the abode of sages at will, he displayed fickle and rash movements of his limbs&#8230;Even as he roamed about thus, the wives of the sages became infatuated and mentally fancied him in the form of their husbands&#8230;The handsome features of the Lord enraged them further. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">They shouted &#8216;Let this fellow be held and beaten</span>. Who is this wicked fellow that has come here?&#8217; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Uttering thus, they took up wooden sticks and rushed at him. Afraid of those noble sages, he fled away</span>&#8230;When they all could not catch hold of Mahesvara, the angry <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Brahmanas cursed Siva thus: &#8216;It was on account of your Linga (penis) that you came to the hermitages like a thief. Since you have abducted other men&#8217;s wives, let your Linga fall on the ground</span>. O Tapasa (ascetic), this terrible curse will affect you immediately.&#8217; As soon as this (curse) was uttered, the tremendous fire of the curse adopted an adamantine form, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">cut off the Linga of Dhurjati and made it fall on the ground. The almightly Lord swooned with his body smeared with blood</span>.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</span></p>
<p>The above passage is also a good response to those who like to play with words. It states that blood was flowing from his body after his Linga (penis) was cut off by sages through the curse, which suggests that the Linga mentioned here is Shiva’s penis and not symbol as claimed by Hindu apologists. Skanda Purana VII.iii.39.5-15 narrates another version which states that Shiva got the urge to have sex after his first wife Sati passed away, then Shiva went to the hermitage of Valakhilya,</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana, book 7 Prabhasa Khanda, Section 3 Arbuda Khanda, chapter 39, verses 5-15 &#8220;When due to humiliation of Dakṣya for not being invited to Yajña, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Satī&#8230;got consumated by death</span>, Kāmadeva taking his bow and arrow of flowers in hand arrived there swiftly. Seeing the invincible Kāmadeva, Śiva then put him as an arrow onto his bow. Apparently out of fear Śiva disappeared. Then he, i.e., Kāmadeva moving about here and there, reached the hermitage of Vālakhilya which was bearing a beautiful look with a good tree outside it. Vālakhilya’s wives then got a glimpse of the handsome Kāmadeva. The group of same women began to embrace the worshipable Liṅga following it up with kissing and repeated touching&#8230;The Sage saw change in the women manifesting all the possibility of their going wayward. Unaware as he was, the great soul simply got enraged with Mahādeva. Heated up with distress, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">he (i.e., the Sage) therefore, to save his wives took out his curse on the worshipable Liṅga of Śiva saying ‘let this worshipable Liṅga fall down</span> for having caused such evils/sins’. A mere sight of the worshipable Liṅga which is reason enough for causing deceit among women is an immediate enemy of the body. Hence, there should be a downfall for this and let this Liṅga fall down.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">Bhrigu cursing Shiva</span></strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Srimad Devi Bhagavatam 4.20.36-37 narrates the story of Shiva having sexual intercourse in the forest and was spotted by sage Bhrigu who cursed Shiva, as a result, Shiva’s penis fell off, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Srimad Devi Bhagavatam book 4, chapter 20, verses 36-37 “O King! When Mahâdeva, being infatuated with Kâma, went into the forest of Bhrigu and becoming naked, began to copulate, the ascetic Bhrigu, seeing him in that state, exclaimed “O You are very shameless” and cursed Him thus:- <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Let your penis drop off just now</span>. Mahâdeva, then to satisfy his thirst for passion, began to drink the water of the lake Amrita Vapî, dug by the Dânavas.” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Padma Purana VI.255.26-40 has a slight variation, it states that Bhrigu went to the abode of Shiva to meet him but Shiva was too busy having sex with his wife, moreover Nandi spoke harsh words to Bhrigu which angered Bhrigu, who then cursed Shiva that his form shall be that of Ling in the clitoris. The pedestal of Shivling is Yoni which is vagina/clitoris.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Padma Purana Uttara Khanda 6, chapter 255, verses 26-40 Having gone near the door of the house of the magnanimous Śaṅkara and seeing very fierce Nandin with a spear in his hand, he said (to him): “I, the brāhmaṇa Bhṛgu, have come to see Hara, the best god. Quickly announce me (i.e. my arrival) to the magnanimous Śaṅkara.” Hearing the words of him, Nandin, the lord of (Śiva’s) attendants spoke harsh words to the great sage of an unlimited splendour: “The lord is not in the vicinity. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Śaṅkara is sporting with goddess (Pārvatī)</span>. O best sage, go back if you desire to live.” Thus repudiated by him the (sage) of a great penance remained there, at the door of the great lord, for many days. “<span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Since he, arrogant due to the company of a woman, thinks lightly of me, he shall have the form of clitoris</span>. Approached (i.e. overcome) by vice he slights me, a brāhmaṇa! Reduced to an impious state, he will not be adored by brāhmaṇas. Therefore, all the food, water, flowers and oblations offered to him will undoubtedly be useless.” The very lustrous one, having thus cursed Śaṃkara honoured by the world, said to the very fierce attendant, Nandin, holding a spear, O king: “May Śiva’s devotees, having ash, phallus and bones be impious and out of the Vedic fold.” The sage, having thus cursed Rudra, Tripura’s killer, went to Brahmā’s world&#8230;&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande</span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">Self-Castration</span></strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">There’s also a story that shows that Shiva himself let his penis fall down. There is a correlating story mentioned in Dharmasamhita of Shiva Purana and Mahabharata which states that Brahma asked Rudra/Shiva to create living beings after which Shiva plunged himself into the water, Brahma waited for a long time, Brahma ran out of patience and then he created living beings, Shiva came out of the water and upon learning that Brahma created all living beings he in anger cast off his penis as it was no longer necessary. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Mahabharata Sauptika Parva 10, section 17, verses 17-26 “After the creatures had multiplied and the Grandsire had become well pleased, the first-born rose from the water and beheld the living creation. He saw that diverse kinds of creatures had been created and that they had multiplied by their own energy.<span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;"> At this sight, Rudra became angry and caused his procreative limb to disappear in the bowels of the Earth</span>. The unfading Brahma, soothing him by soft words, said unto him, “O Sharva, what wert thou doing so long within the water? For what reason, also hast thou caused thy <span style="color: #ff0000;">limb of generation to disappear in the bowels of the Earth?</span>” Thus questioned, that lord of the universe wrathfully answered the lord Brahman, “<span style="color: #ff0000;">Somebody else has created all these creatures! What purpose then would be served by this limb of mine</span>? I have by my austerities, O Grandsire, created food for all these creatures. These herbs and plants also will multiply like those that will subsist upon them!” Having said these words, Bhava went away, in cheerlessness and rage, to the foot of the Menjavat mountains for practising severer austerities.” Tr. Kisari Mohan Ganguly</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Shiva Purana, Dharmasamhita 49:23b-46, 74-86 “He agreed to this and laughed, for he was secretly amused, and he said to Brahma, ‘<span style="color: #ff0000;">There</span><span style="color: #ff0000;"> is no good use for this Linga </span><span style="color: #ff0000;">except for the creation of progeny</span>.’ <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">And as he said this he broke it off and threw it upon the surface of the earth</span>. The Linga broke through the earth down to the subterranean hell and went to the very sky. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Vishnu sought the end of it below, and Brahma flew upwards, but they did not find the end of it</span>, for all their vital effort. Then a voice arose out of the sky as the two of them sat there, and it said, ‘If the Linga of the god with braided hair is worshipped, it will certainly grant all desires that are longed for in the heart.’ When Brahma and Vishnu heard this, they and all the divinities worshipped the Linga with devotion, with their hearts set upon Rudra (Shiva).” Tr. Wendy Doniger</span></p>
<p>A Hindu scholar named Swami Parmeshwaranand wrote,</p>
<p>“According to the account given in the Dharmasamhita of the Shiva Purana, during the ekarnava state before creation, Brahma approached Shiva-Rudra and beseeched him to create the universe, Shiva agreed and entered into the vast ocean in order to prepare himself for the enormous task. However, he did not come out of the ocean for a considerably long time. In the meantime, Brahma became fretful; he could not wait any longer and therefore brought about his own creation. When, later, Shiva-Rudra emerged out of the water, he found that the creation had already accomplished. He, there, cut off his generative organ as it was no longer necessary and threw it down on the earth. Since then the Linga became the form in which Shiva came to be worshiped.”- <strong>Encyclopaedic Dictionary of Puranas, Vol 1, By Swami Parmeshwaranand, page 1239</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">Some verses on importance of Shivling worship</span></strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Padma Purana states the importance of Shiv’s Lingam worship, it says that Gayatri turned the curse into a boon,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Padma Purana, Sṛṣṭi-khaṇḍa 1, chapter 17, verses 262-265. &#8220;Then Gāyatrī, the giver of boons said to Rudra: “<span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Those, men, who will worship your genital organ (in the form of phallus) even though it had fallen</span>, being purified and earning merit thereby, will share (i.e. enjoy) heaven. That state which men get by worshipping your genital organ (in the form of phallus), cannot be had in (i.e. by) maintaining sacred fire or offering oblations into it. Those who will, in the early morning worship your genital organ (in the form of phallus) with a bilva-leaf, will enjoy the world of Rudra.” Tr. by N.A. Deshpande</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">The context of the story is that Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva were cursed by Savitri as Shiva and Vishnu got a woman married to Brahma, infuriated wife of Brahma cursed them in the following way mentioned in Skanda Purana VII.I.165.87-89,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Skanda Purana, Prabhāsa Khaṇḍa 7, Prabhāsa-kṣetra-māhātmya section 1, chapter 165, verses 87-89 &#8220;Similarly the angry lady spoke to Rudra: &#8216;O Hara, while you are in Daruvana, the infuriated sages will curse you (as follows). &#8216;Oh! Kapalika, O insignificant one, you desire to carry off our wives. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">Hence this accursed Linga (penis) of yours, O Rudra, will fall on the ground.&#8217; Bereft of manliness</span>, you shall be afflicted with the curse of the sages. Your wife stationed on the banks of Ganga will console you.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">In the following Shiva Purana verse, Shiva’s male organ is considered his symbol,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Shiva Purana, Vidyesvara Samhita 1, chapter 16, verses 104-107 &#8220;The phallus is united with vagina and vagina is united with phallus. For the sake of perpetual enjoyment here and hereafter the devotee shall worship the phallic emblem which is lord Śiva Himself. He is the sun giving birth and sustenance to the worlds. His symbol is justified in the coming into existence of things. Persons should worship Śiva, the cause of birth, in his phallic form. <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">That which makes the Puruṣa known, is called Liṅga, the symbol.</span> The unification and fusion of the symbols of Śiva and Śakti is thus called Liṅga.&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Linga Purana, Section II, chapter 21, verses 1-3 &#8220;&#8230;Obeisance to you, O deity of holy rites, of infinite splendour&#8230;the trident-bearer, of excellent penis deserving worship, the staff-holder and of dry and arid semen.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Shiva Purana, Vidyeshwara Samhita 1, chapter 9, verses 43-44 “The phallic symbol and the symbolised Śiva are non-different. Hence this phallic emblem is identical with me. It brings devotees quite near to me. It is worthy of worship therefore. O dear sons, if phallic emblem of this sort in installed I can be considered installed, though my idol is not installed.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Another translation for the above verse,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Shiva Purana, Vidyeshwara Samhita 1,9.43-44 “Shiva said, &#8216;I am not distinct from the Phallus. The Phallus is identical with me. It draws my faithful to me, and therefore must be worshipped. My well beloved! Wherever there is an upright male organ, I myself am present, even if there is no other representation of me.” Tr. Shiva Sharan (Alain Daniélou)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Srimad Devi Bhagawatam 9.41.48 “Laksmi always remains there with the greatest gladness where conch-shells are blown, where there are conchsells, the S&#8217;alagrama stone, the Tulasi leaves and the service and meditation of Laksmi are daily done. Where the phallic emblem of Siva is worshipped… &#8221; Tr. Swami Vijnananda</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Varaha Purana 72.10 &#8220;People who seek pleasures sacrifice to me in my form as linga (phallus)&#8230;.&#8221; Tr. Venkitasubramonia Iyer, edited by J.L. Shastri</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Yoni (Vagina) worship can also be found in the Upanishad, it is mentioned,</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Brihadaranyaka Upanishad 6.4.2-3 “Prajapati said to Himself: “Well, let Me make a firm basis for it (semen).” So He created woman. Having created her, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">He worshipped her bottom portion. Therefore one should worship the bottom portion of a woman</span>. He (Prajapati) extended His organ that projects and with it impregnated her.”</span></p>
<h1><strong><span style="color: initial;">Pictures of s</span><span style="color: initial;">ome Shivlings bearing striking resemblance to Penis</span></strong></h1>
<p>Some of these Shivlings are ancient.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img decoding="async" width="318" height="434" class="wp-image-8796 size-full aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/An-ancient-lingam-found-at-Aradhanarishwara-Temple-at-Indabettu-village-in-Dakshina-Kannada-district.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/An-ancient-lingam-found-at-Aradhanarishwara-Temple-at-Indabettu-village-in-Dakshina-Kannada-district.jpeg 318w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/An-ancient-lingam-found-at-Aradhanarishwara-Temple-at-Indabettu-village-in-Dakshina-Kannada-district-220x300.jpeg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" />An ancient lingam 200 B.C old found at Aradhanarishwara Temple at Indabettu village in Dakshina Kannada district. Source: <a href="http://www.thehindu.com/todays-paper/tp-national/tp-karnataka/professor-spots-ancient-lingam/article4205939.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">TheHindu.com<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="318" height="390" class="wp-image-8797 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Gudimallam-Lingam.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Gudimallam-Lingam.jpeg 318w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Gudimallam-Lingam-245x300.jpeg 245w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /><br />
Divinely sculpted: A second century BC idol of Lingodbhava cult of Lord Shiva, the first of its kind found in South India, at Gudimallam temple in Chittoor district. Source: <a href="http://www.thehindu.com/todays-paper/tp-national/tp-andhrapradesh/venerated-since-ages/article4493900.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">TheHindu.com<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="180" height="549" class="wp-image-8798 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Ek-Mukha.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Ek-Mukha.png 180w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Ek-Mukha-98x300.png 98w" sizes="(max-width: 180px) 100vw, 180px" /><br />
Ek Mukha Lingam, Aghapura, Bharatpur, Rajasthan. First Century A.D</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="229" height="344" class="wp-image-8799 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-229w344h.jpeg" alt="C:\Users\Hassan Razvi\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Word\Rishikesh Shivlingam.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-229w344h.jpeg 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-3-229w344h-200x300.jpeg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br />
Rishikesh Shivling</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="403" height="227" class="wp-image-8800 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-6-403w227h.jpeg" alt="Devipuram Shivling Andhra Pradesh" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-6-403w227h.jpeg 403w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-6-403w227h-300x169.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 403px) 100vw, 403px" /><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Devipuram Shivling, Andhra Pradesh</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="260" height="348" class="wp-image-8801 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-7-260w348h.jpeg" alt="Khmer style Shivling Cambodia" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-7-260w348h.jpeg 260w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-7-260w348h-224x300.jpeg 224w" sizes="(max-width: 260px) 100vw, 260px" /><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Khmer style Shivling, Cambodia</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="324" height="433" class="wp-image-8802 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-8-324w433h.jpeg" alt="Gaya Shivlingam" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-8-324w433h.jpeg 324w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Picture-8-324w433h-224x300.jpeg 224w" sizes="(max-width: 324px) 100vw, 324px" /><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Believed to be Shivling, Vishnupad temple in Gaya</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-8803 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-stone-pillar-of-the-Fu-Nan-period-6th-century-CE.jpeg" width="392" height="584" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-stone-pillar-of-the-Fu-Nan-period-6th-century-CE.jpeg 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-stone-pillar-of-the-Fu-Nan-period-6th-century-CE-201x300.jpeg 201w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-stone-pillar-of-the-Fu-Nan-period-6th-century-CE-768x1144.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-stone-pillar-of-the-Fu-Nan-period-6th-century-CE-1031x1536.jpeg 1031w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /><br />
The stone pillar of the Fu Nan period, 6th century CE. It is at the Museum of Vietnamese History, Hochi Minh city, Vietnam. Source: <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/features/friday-review/stonespeak-column-this-vietnamese-lingam-has-a-face/article7329318.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">TheHindu.com<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2022/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Shivling?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Kaaba a Hindu temple?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 17:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ishalayam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makkeshwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Inside Kaaba 786 is not ॐ and ॐ is not Vedic !!!!! Refutation of P.N. Oak’s Claims Against The Ka’bah Did Brahma Built The Kaaba Then ? Exposing the reality of “‘Sayar-ul-Okul’” ! A Jaw Breaking Response to P N Oak And His Lies! Exposing the reality of “King Vikramaditya”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/" data-wpel-link="internal">Is Kaaba a Hindu temple?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/inside-kaaba/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">Inside Kaaba</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/786-is-not-%e0%a5%90-and-%e0%a5%90-is-not-vedic/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">786 is not ॐ and ॐ is not Vedic !!!!!</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/refutation-of-p-n-oaks-claims-against-the-kabah/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">Refutation of P.N. Oak’s Claims Against The Ka’bah</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/did-brahma-built-the-kaaba-then/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">Did Brahma Built The Kaaba Then ?</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-sayar-ul-okul/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">Exposing the reality of “‘Sayar-ul-Okul’” !</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/a-jaw-breaking-response-to-p-n-oak-and-his-lies/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">A Jaw Breaking Response to P N Oak And His Lies!</a></p>
<p class="entry-title"><a href="/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/" rel="bookmark" data-wpel-link="internal">Exposing the reality of “King Vikramaditya”</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/" data-wpel-link="internal">Is Kaaba a Hindu temple?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/24/is-kaaba-a-hindu-temple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exposing the reality of &#8220;King Vikramaditya&#8221;</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 16:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Imran Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaaba hindu temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makkeshwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiv lingam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Imran Khan Who is King Vikramaditya ?  A Comic Hero. Vikramaditya (Sanskrit: विक्रमादित्य) (102 BCE to 15 CE) was a legendary emperor of Ujjain, India, famed for his wisdom, valour and magnanimity. The title &#8220;Vikramaditya&#8221; was later assumed by many other kings in Indian history, notably the Gupta King Chandragupta II and Samrat &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/" data-wpel-link="internal">Exposing the reality of &#8220;King Vikramaditya&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Imran Khan</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Who is King Vikramaditya ? </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">A Comic Hero.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="background:#f8fcff;"><span style="font-size:12pt;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium alignleft" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/096cf-vikram_aur_betaal.jpg" width="178" height="247" />Vikramaditya</strong> (<a title="Sanskrit language" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanskrit_language" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Sanskrit</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>: </span><span style="font-family:Mangal;">विक्रमादित्य</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;">) (102 BCE to 15 CE) was a legendary emperor of <a title="Ujjain" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ujjain" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Ujjain</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a title="India" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/India" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, famed for his wisdom, valour and <a title="Magnanimity" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnanimity" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">magnanimity</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. The title &#8220;Vikramaditya&#8221; was later assumed by many other kings in Indian history, notably the Gupta King <a title="Chandragupta II" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chandragupta_II" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Chandragupta II</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and <a title="Samrat Hem Chandra Vikramaditya" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samrat_Hem_Chandra_Vikramaditya" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Samrat Hem Chandra Vikramaditya</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> (popularly known as &#8216;<a title="Hemu" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hemu" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Hemu</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>&#8216;).<br />
</span></span></p>
<p><span id="more-639"></span></p>
<p style="background:#f8fcff;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The legendary Vikramaditya is a popular figure in both Sanskrit and regional languages in India. <span style="background-color:yellow;">His name is conveniently associated with <strong>any event or monument whose historical details are unknown,</strong> though a whole cycles of tales have <strong>grown around him</strong></span>. The two <span style="background-color:yellow;">most famous ones in Sanskrit are <a title="Vetala Panchvimshati" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vetala_Panchvimshati" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;"><em>Vetala Panchvimshati</em></span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> or &#8216; (&#8220;The 25 (tales) of the Vampire&#8221;)</span> and <em>Simhasana-Dwatrimshika</em> (&#8220;The 32 (tales) of the throne&#8221;<em>). These two are found in varying versions in Sanskrit and also in the regional languages.</em><br />
</span></p>
<p style="background:#f8fcff;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The tales of the vampire (<a title="Vetala" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vetala" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Vetala</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>) tell twenty-five stories in which the king tries to capture and hold on to a vampire that tells a puzzling tale and ends it with a question for the king. In fact, earlier the king was approached by a Sadhu to bring the vampire to him but without uttering a word, otherwise the vampire would fly back to its place. The king can be quiet only if he does not know the answer, else his head would burst open. Unfortunately, the king discovers that he knows the answer to every question; therefore the cycle of catching the vampire and letting it escape continues for twenty-four times till the last question puzzles Vikramaditya. A version of these tales can be found embedded in the <a title="Kathasaritsagara" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kathasaritsagara" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Katha-Saritsagara</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><span style="color:red;"><strong><em>The name Vikramaditya&#8211;Sun of Valour&#8211;is probably not a proper name, but a title like Pharaoh or Tsar. No doubt Kalidasa intended to pay a tribute to his patron, the Sun of Valour, in the very title of his play, Urvashi won by Valour.</em></strong></span><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>THE MYSTERIOUS ORIGINAL KING VIKRAMADITYA</strong></span></span></p>
<p><em>V.S.Gopalakrishnan</em></p>
<p>Whoever may not have heard of the &#8220;<strong>Vikram-Betal</strong>&#8221; stories, the fascinating tales about the great King Vikramaditya and Betal, the vampire? Was he a real king or was he only a legendary, imaginary figure? If anything gets my goat, it is the seamless intertwining of the two, the truth and fiction. Let us take this guy under our microscope. After all, very few human beings are known as creators of eras named after them! We all know about <strong>Vikram Samvat</strong>.</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Somewhere in wikipedia, you find the date of King Vikramaditya as 102 BC to 15 AD, but in the same sentence it is mentioned that he was a <strong>legendary</strong> emperor of <strong>Ujjain</strong>, India, known for his wisdom, valour and magnanimity! Where does history end and legend start? I am flummoxed!<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However, the Vikram Era that starts from <strong>56 BC </strong>is not legend but is historical, and is real even today. That year marks the defeat of the invading <strong>Sakas</strong> (powerful Central Asian Tribes) by King Vikramaditya when Ujjain was invaded. The Vikram Samvat calendar is popular in Northern India and in Western India. It is a lunar calendar and the year starts with the day after the new moon in Chaitra. While the Government of India has adopted the <strong>Saka Calendar (starting 78 AD)</strong> for official purposes, the Government of Nepal has been officially following the Vikram Samvat, which they call Bikram Samvat. One must remember that the Saka Era (starting 78 AD) is a misnomer in a sense since really speaking it also celebrates the defeat of Sakas, at the hands of the Satavahana King <strong>Shalivahana in the year 78 AD</strong>. The Saka era is also called Shalivahana era.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The Saka people (also called Scythians) of Central Asia did however settle down in North India from 2<sup>nd</sup> century BC to 4<sup>th</sup> century AD, and they gave rise to <strong>Indo-Scy</strong>t<strong>hians</strong>. Sakas occupied and ruled Western India too and the rulers were called <strong>Western Satraps</strong>. Large sections of the Rajasthanis (kshatriyas) are descendants of the Sakas. There is an amazing combination of foreign blood in the Hindus. Similarly, sections of Rajasthanis and Gujaratis are also considered the descendants of the fierce, formidable and cruel <strong>Huna tribe</strong> (also called the <strong>Huns</strong>) of Central Asia which over-ran and ruled North India, under their leader <strong>Toramana</strong> and later his son<strong> Mih</strong>ir<strong>akula</strong> in the 5<sup>th</sup> and 6<sup>th</sup> centuries AD. The two father and son Hun rulers were cruel to the subjects and particularly destroyed Buddhist cities, monuments etc. Mihirakula became a Hindu towards the end of his life.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>KATHA-SARIT-SAGARA</strong>:<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Coming back to the ancient King Vikramaditya, we find accounts about him in &#8220;Katha-Sarit-Sagara&#8221; (meaning Ocean of Tales) written in Sanskrit by a Kashmiri Pundit called <strong>Soma Deva Bhatta </strong>in the middle of the 12<sup>th</sup> century AD. Soma Deva wrote it for the entertainment of Queen <strong>Suryamati,</strong> wife of King <strong>Anantdeva</strong> of Kashmir. It is said that it consisted of 350 stories in 18 books, 124 chapters, 21000 verses and prose too! This is the biggest compilation of Indian tales ever.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Accounts and stories about King Vikramaditya that are found in the Katha-Sarit-Sagara were written <strong>1200 years </strong>after his time, and the problem will be one of what is history and truth and what is fiction and legend. There sure must be some admixture of both! The 25 stories of Vikram-Betal form part of the work, as also accounts of Vikramaditya&#8217;s life.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>HIS LIFE:</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">As per Katha-Sarit-Sagara, Vikramaditya was the son of King <strong>Mahendraditya</strong> of the <strong>Paramara</strong> Dynasty. However, the Paramara (also known as Pawar) Dynasty came into being around 800 AD only, founded by <strong>Upendra.</strong> The most significant Paramara Ruler was Bhoja I and the capital city was Dharanagara (present <strong>Dhar</strong>). Thus, the Ocean seems to be off the mark. However, the Betal story in the Katha-Sarit-Sagara does go with the original Vikramaditya of the first century BC!<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>BHAVISHYA PURANA</strong>:<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8220;Bhavishya Purana&#8221; in verse form has a lot to say about the life of Vikramaditya. It is one of the major 18 Puranas and is said to have been written by Vyasa several centuries before Christ. The work literally means &#8220;History of the Future&#8221;. The Purana starts with the greatness of Shiva, Vishnu, Surya etc. It has uncannily predicted, believe it or not, the following – Jesus Christ, Muhammad, fall of Sanskrit, Chandragupta, Ashoka, Chaitanya, Akbar, Jaichandra, British Rule, Hitler etc. The events are written as having already taken place.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The following account owes itself to the &#8220;Bhavishya Purana&#8221; as for Vikramaditya, whom we may call Vikram here for brevity. Vikram&#8217;s father was <strong>Gandharvasena</strong>, son of Lord<strong> Indra</strong>. Are we not into myths here? Once, while Apsara <strong>Mohini</strong> was on her way to meet Siva on Mount Kailasa, Gandharvasena (Vikram&#8217;s father) happened to obstruct her way. Enraged at this, Lord Indra cursed him (his own son Gandharvasena) and turned him into a donkey with certain riders. We may omit portions regarding the donkey becoming a human again. Vikram was only 5 years old when he entered a penance for 12 years. He was bestowed with extraordinary power and insights. His elder brother Bhartuhari renounced his throne and the kingdom came to Vikram. King Vikram was known for justice, sagacity, wisdom, valour, charity and generosity.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">I will not go into any aspect of the twenty five Vikram-Betal stories known as &#8220;<strong>Vetala Panchavimshati</strong>&#8221; which are fascinating to say the least. Some years ago, Doordarshan telecast the stories in a serial. I shall try to attempt a separate blog about the stories. There are also 32 stories relating to Vikramaditya Simhasan (throne) and they are called &#8220;<strong>Simhasana Dwatrimshika</strong>&#8220;. King <strong>Shalivahana of Paithan </strong>after whom Saka era is named, is said to be Vikram&#8217;s grandson.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>KAABA AND KING VIKRAM:</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Of late, an excitement has been aroused among the people with the alleged discovery of King Vikram&#8217;s inscription inside the <strong>Kaaba at Mecca</strong>. It is alleged that there is a Shiva lingam inside the Kaaba. Thus, Arabia came under the vast extent of King Vikram&#8217;s empire. Prophet Mohammad, it is said, took the crescent moon emblem for Islam from Shiva&#8217;s adornment. There are quite a few articles in the Net on this subject. However, the Net is hardly the place where you get to really read scientific or highly scholarly papers. I am personally unable to judge the authenticity of all the claims about Kaaba. The readers may throw light on this giving links.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>OTHER VIKRAMADITYAS</strong>:<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The title &#8220;Vikramaditya&#8221; was adopted by some well-known kings of India in later times. Notable examples are the <strong>Gupta King Chandragupta the second Vikramaditya </strong>and <strong>Samrat Hem Chandra Vikramaditya (also known as Hemu). </strong>The former, the great Gupta King, who was the son of Samudragupta, and who ruled from 375 to 413 AD, defeated the last king Rudrasimha III of the Shaka Satrap Dynasty in Gujerat and annexed that kingdom to his vast territory. Hemu (1501-56), the son of a Brahmin priest, became a trusted Army Chief and Prime Minister under the Suri Dynasty (Afghans). The Afghans (Suris) and Mughals (Babar and Humayun) were at loggerheads for the Delhi Throne. Hemu benefited by this and took the Delhi throne in 1556 for a short time and ruled as a Hindu Emperor after 350 years of rule by Muslims.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">As far as Vikramaditya was concerned, the fiction part could be that he was Lord Indra&#8217;s grandson and that his father was turned into a horse for some time. Also, despite the loveliness of the Betal tales, the Betal communicating with Vikram is certainly an impossibility. </span></p>
<p>I took out my copy of &#8220;An Advanced History of India&#8221; by RC Majumdar and two others. It is a standard and advanced textbook used by History PG students. This is what the book says (at p.112, 4th edition):</p>
<p>QUOTE<br />
&#8220;Some scholars attribute to Azes I the foundation of that reckoning commencing 58 BC which afterwards came to be known as Vikrama samvat., but the matter cannot be regarded as certain.Indian tradition ascribes to it an Indian origin. It (tradition) was handed down by the Malava tribe, and in the post-Gupta period came to be associated with the great Vikramaditya, the destroyer of the Sakas&#8221;.<br />
UNQUOTE</p>
<p>For me the above skeletal passage is so disappointing! (Azes was a foreigner and how can Azes establish a Vikram era????)</p>
<p>So, Majumdar has totally neglected King Vikramaditya of the first century BC! He talks about indigenous origin, since Azes was a foreigner. This is the poor way our history is written!<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Then I took out my copy of the &#8220;Oxford History of India&#8221; by Vincent Smith. On p.167 (4th edition), Smith says;</p>
<p>QUOTE<br />
&#8221; Later in life, he (Chandragupta II ) took the additional title Vikramaditya (&#8220;Sun of Prowess&#8217;), which is associated by tradition with the Raja of Ujjain who is believed to have defeated the Sakas and established the Vikrama era in 58-57 BC. It is possible that such a Raja may really have existed, <span style="background-color:yellow;">although the tradition has not been verified by the discovery of inscriptions, coins or monuments</span>&#8220;.<br />
UNQUOTE</p>
<p>I find Smith to be vastly better than Majumdar!</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p style="background:#f8fcff;"><span style="color:darkblue;font-family:Arial;font-size:13pt;">Is Kutub Minar (in Delhi) king Vikramadiya&#8217;s tower commemorating his conquest of Arabia.???</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Kutub Minar did not EXIST at the time of Vikramiditya!<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;">The Qutb Minar (also spelled Qutab or Qutub, Urdu: </span><span style="font-family:Arial;">قطب</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span><span style="font-family:Arial;">منار</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;">), a tower in Delhi, India, is at 72.5 meters the world&#8217;s tallest brick minaret. Construction commenced in 1193 under the orders of India&#8217;s first Muslim ruler Qutb-ud-din Aibak, and the topmost storey of the minaret was completed in 1386 by Firuz Shah Tughluq. The complex is listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. It is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Delhi, and was also India&#8217;s most visited monument in 2006, as it attracted 3.9 million visitors, even more than the Taj Mahal, which drew about 2.5 million visitors more than the MAHA KUMBH mela.<br />
</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If Kutub Minar was a Hindu atrominical tower as Oak claimed what about, the other towers present in undivided India ???<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Inspired by the Minaret of Jam in Afghanistan and wishing to surpass it, Qutbuddin Aibak, the first Muslim ruler of Delhi, commenced construction of the QutbMinar in 1193, but could only complete its base. His successor, Iltutmish, added three more stories and, in 1386, Firuz Shah Tughluq constructed the fifth and the last story. The development of architectural styles from Aibak to Tughluq is quite evident in the minaret. Like earlier towers erected by the Ghaznavids and Ghurids in Afghanistan, the Qutb Minar comprises several superposed flanged and cylindrical shafts, separated by balconies carried on Muqarnas corbels.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The purpose for building this monument has been variously speculated upon. It could take the usual role of a minaret, calling people for prayer in the Quwwat-ul-Islam mosque, the earliest extant mosque built by the Delhi Sultans. Other possibilities are a tower of victory, a monument signifying the might of<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Islam, or a watch tower for defense.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"> Oak says: </span><span style="color:darkblue;font-family:Arial;font-size:13pt;">Firstly, the inscription on the iron pillar near the so-called Kutub Minar refers to the marriage of the victorious king Vikramaditya to the princess of Balhika. This Balhika is none other than the Balkh region in West Asia. It could be that Arabia was wrestled by king Vikramaditya from the ruler of Balkh who concluded a treaty by giving his daughter in marriage to the victor.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">BUT Balhika/ bahlika has nothing to do with either King Vikramaditya or Kutub Minar, it predates both. Bahlika finds mention in Atharvaveda, Mahabharata, Ramayana, Puranas, Vartikka of Katyayana, Brhatsamhita, Amarkosha etc and in the ancient Inscriptions. The inhabitants of Bahlika were known as the Bahlikas. The other variations of Bahlika are Bahli, Balhika, Vahlika, Valhika, Bahlava, Bahlam/Bahlim, Bahlayana and Bahluva etc.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">According to the Puranic traditions, Dhrshta was one of the nine sons of Manu. From him came a number of clans called Dharshtakas who were reckoned as Kshatriyas. According to Shiva Purana the Dharshtaka princes became rulers of Bahlika.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Satapatha Brahmana knows of a king named Bahlika Pratipeya whom it calls Kauravya (=Kaurava) . It has been pointed out that this Kaurava king is identical with Bahlika Pratipeya of Mahabharata.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">According to Mahabharata evidence, the king of Bahlika was present at Syamantapanchaka at Kurukshetra on the occasion of a solar eclipse. Also the name &#8216;Bahlika Desa&#8217; originates from the name of the middle son of King Pratipa of Hastinapura, Bahlika, who devoted his life to conquer these old Aryan territories in the Uttarapatha. Hence, being the elder to King Santanu, Bahlika was the paternal uncle of Bhishma and pre-dates him.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The King of Bahlika presented to Yudhishtra a golden chariot yoked with four white Kamboja studs at the time of Rajsuya ceremony (2.53.5).<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="color:darkblue;font-family:Arial;font-size:13pt;">OAK says; Secondly, the township adjoining the so called Kutub Minar is named Mehrauli after Mihira who was the renowned astronomer-mathematician of king Vikram&#8217;s court. Mehrauli is the corrupt form of Sanskrit &#8216;Mihira-Awali&#8217; signifying a row of houses raised for Mihira and his helpers and assistants working on astronomical observations made from the tower.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Mehrauli, Which was earlier known as Mihirawali means Home of Mihir, was founded by the King Mihir Bhoja of the Gurjara-Pratihara Dynasty. Mehrauli is one of the seven ancient cities that make up the present state of Delhi. The Lal Kot fort was constructed by the Gurjar Tanwar chief Anangpal I around AD 731 and expanded by AnangPal II in the 11th century, who shifted his capital to Lal Kot from Kannauj. The Gurjar Tanwars were defeated by the Chauhans in the 12th century. Prithviraj Chauhan further expanded the fort and called it Qila Rai Pithora. He was defeated in 1192 by Mohammed Ghori, who put his general Qutb-ud-din Aybak in charge and returned to Afghanistan. Mehrauli remained the capital of the Kanas dynasty which ruled until 1290. During the Khilji dynasty, the capital shifted to Siri.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
</span><span style="font-size:18pt;"><strong>I Challenge to show me a single proof from any authentic and proved historical database the existence of an Vikramaditya&#8217;s empire outside the Indian subcontinent as claimed by Mr P N Oak!</strong></span></span></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
<a href="http://www.lost-civilizations.net/ancient-civilizations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">http://www.lost-civilizations.net/ancient-civilizations.html</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_history" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_history</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.gloriousindia.com/history/gupta_empire.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">http://www.gloriousindia.com/history/gupta_empire.html</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;<br />
For those Interested in reading the fairy tales of Vikram and Betala here are the links :-</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bharatadesam.com/literature/stories_of_vikram_betal/vikram_and_betal.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">http://www.bharatadesam.com/literature/stories_of_vikram_betal/vikram_and_betal.php</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><a href="http://www.blogger.com/goog_462225646" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;"><br />
</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><br />
<a href="http://www.sacred-texts.com/goth/vav/index.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">http://www.sacred-texts.com/goth/vav/index.htm</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/" data-wpel-link="internal">Exposing the reality of &#8220;King Vikramaditya&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/24/exposing-the-reality-of-king-vikramaditya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 14:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aravsthan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bow down]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circumambulate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idol worship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idolater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lingam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makkeshwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims worship the kaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shave head beard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sulaiman razvi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ujjain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vikramaditya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi [This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time] The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Written by Sulaiman Razvi<br />
</span></p>
[This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time]
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for prayer. However some Islamophobes especially some Hindus allege that Muslims worship the Kaaba or the Black Stone and they accuse Muslims of being idolaters. First of all they have to know what exactly is Idol worship, only then they should accuse Muslims of Idolatry. Idol worship is a veneration or worship of the Idol of any God. Islam is known for its staunch monotheistic stand. Islam prohibits Idol worship, It is mentioned in the Qur&#8217;an,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span id="more-161"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">22:30 &#8221;…so shun the abomination of idols, and shun the word that is false.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">14:35 Remember Abraham said: &#8220;O my Lord! make this city one of peace and security: and <span style="text-decoration:underline;">preserve me and my sons from worshipping idols</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">5:90 O ye who believe! Intoxicants and gambling, <span style="color:red;">(dedication of) stones</span>, and (divination by) arrows, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">are an abomination― of Satan&#8217;s handiwork</span>: eschew such (abomination), that ye may prosper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Hadith,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Abu Dawood (Kitab Al-Aqdiyah) [24:3592] Narrated Khuraym Ibn Fatik: The Apostle of Allah (peace be upon him) offered the morning prayer. When he finished it, he stood up and said three times: False witness has been made equivalent to attributing a partner to Allah. He then recited: &#8220;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">So avoid the abomination of idols</span> and avoid speaking falsehood as people pure of faith to Allah, not associating anything with Him.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba or Black Stone to be God. Kaaba is a direction,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…when a person making supplication (du&#8217;a) faces the sky–just as those performing the prayer (Salat) face the Ka&#8217;bah, since the sky is the qiblah of those who supplicate, as the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Ka&#8217;bah is the qiblah of those who perform the prayer</span>…&#8221;-(Sahih Muslim bi Sharh al-Nawawi. 18 vols. Cairo 1349/1930. Reprint (18 vols. in 9). Beirut: Dar al-Fikr, 1401/1981, 5.24)<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8216;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8216;Allah&#8217;s direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah</span>. (And if thou shouldst follow their desires) their religion and direction of prayer (after the knowledge which hath come unto thee) that the Religion of Allah is Islam and His direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah&#8221;– Tanwir al Miqbas min Tafsir ibn Abbas 2:120<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">People used to stand on the Kaaba and give Azaan. Kaaba has been rebuilt several times, it was brought down by the Sahabas. Can any Hindu even think of destroying idol of their god? Ibn Az Zubayr brought Kaaba down to rebuild it and later it was again brought down and rebuilt by Ibn Hajjaj,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;he (Ibn Az Zubayr) decided to bring the Ka`bah down. The people hesitated to bring it down, fearing that the first person to climb on the House would be struck down. A man went on top of the House and threw some stones down, and when the people saw that no harm touched him, they started doing the same. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">They brought the House down to ground level</span>…`Abdul-Malik wrote back, `We do not agree with Ibn Az-Zubayr&#8217;s actions. As, for the Ka`bah&#8217;s height, leave it as it is. As for what he added from the Hijr, bring it down, and build the House as it was before and close the door.&#8217; <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Therefore, Al-Hajjaj brought down the House and rebuilt it as it was</span>.&#8221;- Tafsir Ibn Kathir [<a href="http://www.qtafsir.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=303&amp;Itemid=36" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Source<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Idolaters won&#8217;t stand on their idols nor they will destroy their Idols. How can such claims be made that Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone when Quran and Hadiths clearly prohibit any form of Idol worship? Hazrat Umar R.A said,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…No doubt, I know that you are a <strong>stone</strong> and can neither benefit anyone nor harm anyone. Had I not seen Allah&#8217;s Apostle kissing you I would not have kissed you.&#8221; Sahih Bukhari, Kitab al Hajj 26, Hadith no 667.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be God. Muslims do not worship the Kaaba. When some Hindus are told these facts they say,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:#c00000;font-size:12pt;">&#8221;They too, whom you call Idol worshippers, do not regard the image as God. They profess to worship God behind the Idol/image&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">How true it is, let&#8217;s analyse. Hindu scriptures clearly states that &#8216;You should establish an Idol of God and worship it for the Idol is God himself&#8217;. Whatever we or the Islamophobes says carries no weight unless it is backed by some evidence, let&#8217;s have a look at what Hindu scripture have to say about it because if they are accusing us of Idolatry then our way of worship must be similar with idol worshippers.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Garuda Purana 12.17 Then the son should place upon the <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">bed a golden image, and having worshiped it</span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.24.19 O sinless one! <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Establish my image in this city and worship it</span><br />
</span>three times, morning, mid-day and evening carefully and with devotion<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.13.49 These Saktis, capable of bestowing all the desires, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">will be worshipped in Pratimas(images of clay, etc.)</span> in the whole of India.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Vishnudharmottara Purana, Kanda 3, Adhyay 93, 2 in the former three ages, Krta, Treta, and Dvapara men were able to see a god directly but in the Kali age ment have lost that faculty; <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">therefore they have to worship them (the gods) in an image</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 11.23.21-33 … one is to worship one&#8217;s own Deity <span style="color:red;"><strong>in front</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">of fire or the </span><strong>image of any god</strong></span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">This shows that the Idol must be in front of the worshipper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">BhrGhSuPari Grihasutra 2.14.2 <span style="color:red;">Having prepared the image of the god and worshipping it </span>with the unbroken rice and flowers as available&#8230;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;It (clay) should be washed well and pasted with scented poweder and milk. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The idol should be made</span> with the hands on a raises platform. All the limbs, joints, etc. should be perfectly shaped with the respective weapons of the deity concerned. It should be seated on Padmasana (lotus pose) <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">and worshipped respectfully</span>&#8221;.-Shiva Purana 1.1.16.6-7, Tr. J.L. Shastri<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;O my child, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">one should worship the beautiful and universally auspicious idol (of Devi) </span>which is the destroyer of great demons placing it on a car (chatior)&#8221;.-Devi Purana 30.6cd-7ab, Tr. R.S. Bhattacharya<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Harivamsa Purana, Vishnu Parva 2.74.52 Those who <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">make my idol with stones taken from you and worship [it]</span> daily with devotion shall eventually attain my path.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">These verses clearly commands Hindus to worship the Idol of their god, but Quran nor any Hadith tells us to worship the Kaaba. Hindu texts and Scholars say that Idol is God himself. Pratima means Idol, image, picture of god but Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKON translates Pratima as Deity Form or Deity because he considers the Idol to be another form or incarnation of God. This fact is enough to prove that Muslims do not worship the Kaaba as Quran, Hadiths nor Muslims says Kaaba is Allah (S.W.T). Let me quote few verses from Hindu scriptures and passages written by Hindu scholars on this issue,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…think of the name as Brahman, and meditate upon it, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">just as people worship the idol, thinking it to be Vishnu Himself</span>.- Chandogya Upanishad Commentary by Shankarcharya on 12.1.4 ,The Upanishads and Sri Sankara&#8217;s Commentary, Volumes 4-5, p.200.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagavad Purana),<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">dravyaiḥ prasiddhair mad-yāgaḥ <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>diṣv amāyinaḥ bhaktasya ca yathā-labdhair hṛdi bhāvena caiva hi<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11.27.15 <span style="color:red;">One should worship Me in My Deity forms [Pratima/Idol]</span> by offering the most excellent paraphernalia. But a devotee completely freed from material desire may worship Me with whatever he is able to obtain…</span><span style="font-size:14pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">śailī dāru-mayī lauhī lepyā lekhyā ca saikatī mano-mayī maṇi-mayī <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>ṣṭa-vidhā smṛtā<br />
</span></p>
<p><a href="http://vedabase.com/en/sb/11/27/12" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="font-size:12pt;"> (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.12 <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The Deity form[Idol] of the Lord is said to appear in eight varieties</span> — stone, wood, metal, earth, paint, sand, the mind or jewels.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī explains that certain Deity forms, such as those made of sand, are manifested for a brief time to fulfill a personal desire of the worshiper. Those, however, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">who desire to attain pure love of God should worship the permanent form of the Deity (made, for instance, of marble, gold or brass)</span>, and they should maintain continual worship. In Kṛṣṇa consciousness there is no scope for neglecting the worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagwat Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.48 <span style="color:red;">Whenever one develops faith in Me in <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>My form [Idol] as the Deity</strong></span> or in other bona fide manifestations one should <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>worship Me in that form</strong></span></span>. I certainly exist both within all created beings and also separately in My original form, since I am the Supreme Soul of all.<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: The Supreme Personality of Godhead is worshiped according to the faith of a particular worshiper. The Deity form, arcā, is specifically mentioned here because Deity worship is essential for spiritual progress. <span style="color:red;">Śrīla Bhaktisiddhānta Sarasvatī Ṭhākura mentions that inexperienced persons may think that the Deity [Idol] is meant for the sense gratification of the worshiper, since superficially the Deity [Idol] is made of external substances such as marble or brass</span>. But through the process of installing the Deity by <span style="color:red;"><strong>chanting of authorized mantras, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">one invites the Supreme Personality of Godhead to enter the Deity form [Idol]</span>.</strong></span> By regulated, faithful worship one gradually <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>understands that the Deity [Idol] is completely nondifferent from the Supreme Lord Himself</strong></span>…<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;But, greater is the difficulty of those whose minds cling to the Unmanifested; for the goal of the Unmanifested is hard for the embodied being to reach.&#8221; Gita 12:5<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse &#8221;Therefore, the bhakti-yogi accepts the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity of Krishna as worshipable</span> because there is some bodily conception fixed in the mind, which can thus be applied. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">Of course, worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead in His form within the temple is not idol worship</span>. There is evidence in the Vedic literature that worship may be saguna and nirguna—of the Supreme possessing or not possessing attributes. Worship of the Deity in the temple is saguna worship, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">for the Lord is represented by material qualities</span>. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But the form of the Lord, though represented by material qualities such as <span style="color:red;">stone, wood or oil paint, is not actually material. That is the absolute nature of the Supreme Lord</span></span>…God has an authorized <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">representation in the Deity form [Idol]</span>, which is called arca-vigraha. This arca-vigraha is an incarnation of the Supreme Lord&#8221;.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 4.30.27:<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The form of the Lord as worshiped in the temples is called arca-vigraha or arcavatara, the worshipable form [Idol Worship],</span><br />
<span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">the Deity incarnation</span>. This facility is offered to neophyte devotees so that they can see the real form of the Lord face to face and offer their respectful obeisances and sacrifices in the form of arca. Through such facilities the neophytes gradually invoke their original Krsna consciousness. <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity worship in the form of temple worship is the most valuable benediction </span><strong>given by the Lord to beginners</strong></span>. All neophytes must therefore engage in the worship of the Lord by keeping the arca-vigraha (arcavatara)[Idol] at home or in the temple.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another Hindu scholar named Swami Sivananda writes,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;<span style="color:red;">Though the image is worshipped</span>, <span style="color:red;">the devotee feels the presence of the Lord <span style="text-decoration:underline;">in it</span></span> and pours out his devotion unto it.…<span style="color:red;">When you worship an image</span>, you do not say: &#8220;This image has come from Jaipur. It was brought by Prabhu Singh. Its weight is 50 lbs. It is made of white marble. It has cost me Rs. 500/-.&#8221; <span style="color:red;"><strong>You superimpose all the attributes of the Lord on the image and pray</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">: &#8220;</span><strong>O</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Antaryamin (Inner Ruler)! </span><strong>You are</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> all-pervading. You are omnipotent, omniscient, all-merciful. You are the source for everything. You are self-existent. You are Sat-Chit-Ananda. </span><strong>You</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> are eternal, unchanging. You are the Life of my life, Soul of my soul! Give me light and knowledge! Let me dwell in Thee for ever.&#8221;</span></span> When your devotion and meditation become intense and deep, you do not see the stone image. You behold the Lord only who is Chaitanya. <span style="color:red;">Image-worship is very necessary for beginners</span>…For a beginner, Pratima is an absolute necessity. <span style="color:red;"><strong>By worshipping an idol</strong>, Isvara is pleased</span>…<span style="color:red;">Even so, the Lord is highly pleased when a small portion of His Virat (cosmic) body is worshipped. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">An idol is a part of the body of the Lord</span></span>. The whole world is His body, Virat form. The devotion goes to the Lord<span style="color:red;">. The worshipper superimposes on the image the Lord and all His attributes</span>. He does Shodasopachara for the idol, the sixteen kinds of paying respects or service to the Lord…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The idol speaks. It will answer your questions and solve your problems</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">. The God in you has the power to awaken the latent </span><strong>Divinity in the idol</strong></span>…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The awakened Divinity in the idol</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;">acts as a guardian angel blessing all, conferring the highest good on those who bow to it…</span><br />
<span style="color:red;">The image in the temple at Tirupati assumed human form and gave witness in the court to help His devotees</span>.- All About Hinduism, By Sri Swami Sivananda, p.70-4<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;To the worshipper <span style="text-decoration:underline;">who believes the symbol, any kind of image is the body of the Lord under the form of stone, clay, brass, picture, Saligrama, etc. Such worship can never be idolatry</span>. <span style="color:red;">All matter is a manifestation of God. God is present in everything which exists</span>. Everything is an object of worship, for all is a manifestation of God who is therein worshipped.&#8221; – All About Hinduism, By Swami Sivananda, p.72<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be Allah nor do we adore the Kaaba as the Hindus does to their Idols thinking it to be god himself,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"> Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11:30:7 There we should bathe for purification, fast, and fix our minds in meditation. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">We should then worship the demigods by bathing their images</span>, anointing them with sandalwood pulp, and presenting them various offerings<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">So it is evident from all these verses that the Idolaters indeed think their Idols to be God. Another bogus claim made by some Hindus is that Kaaba was actually a Hindu temple and the Black Stone is actually Shiva Lingam. There is nothing to refute as there is no evidence which proves their point. There is absolutely no evidence at all. This hoax was started by a self-proclaimed historian (popularly known as Mythistorian by experts) who believed that all religious monuments and religions are corrupted form of Hinduism and that Christianity is altered version of Kishna Neti and Islam is the altered version of the Sanskrit word Ishalayam. He gave fake reference from an imaginary book created by him. Surprisingly Hindus believes this book exis and even quote, well, Islam is such a beautiful religion that anyone would like to link their religion with it. The Mythistorian&#8217;s work is full of mistakes and does not contain a single fact. He was ignorant of history. He made such poor remarks on other religions, for example he claimed that the Muslim&#8217;s Namaz is originally a Sanskrit word called Namah. I wonder whether he did some research or just wrote his frustrations. The Arabic word for prayer is Salah. Namaz is an Urdu word originated from Farsi, the word Namaz is used by Muslims of Indian subcontinent for prayer. He and his claims have been refuted by Imran Khan in his Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba Is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. Readers can go through the blog and see the idiotic claims made by Hindu nationalist. Shri Shri Ravi Shankar had also made such claims but later in a debate with Dr. Zakir Naik he honestly acknowledged that his claims are incorrect. There is no evidence at all that could suggest the Kaaba was a Hindu temple. There is also no preserved history which could suggest that Hindus lived in Makka or went there. Even a Muslim can make such claims. For example,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;Hindu God Ram was a normal Muslim, his name is altered version of the Arabic word Akram. His brother Luxman was also a Muslim his original name was Luqman, and his close disciple was Humam Bajar Ali which was changed to Hanuman Bajrang Bali. The Hindu God Krishna was also a Muslim his real name was Karim Shah. Shiva was also a Muslim his original name was Shuaa&#8221;. </span></p>
<p>So does it make them Muslims?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another bogus claim made by Hindus is that the Black Stone is Shiva Lingam. How can this be so when both these have different meanings and their own origin. The meaning and origin of Shiva Lingam is discussed briefly in the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">An Analysis of Lingam</a>. As far as Black Stone is concerned. The Arabic word is Hajre Aswad. Hajr means stone, Aswad means black. While Lingam means make erected organ and Yoni denotes female genital organ. According to the tradition, the Hajre Aswad (Black Stone) was white and was sent from heaven,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Al Tirmizi Sayyidina Book of Hajj 9, Hadith 878 &#8221;Ibn Abbas narrated that Allah&#8217;s Messenger (SAW) said, &#8220;The <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Black Stone was sent down from Paradise</span> and it was more <span style="text-decoration:underline;">white than milk</span>, but the sins of the children of Adam turned it black.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Hindus try to link Yoni (Literally female genital which is the base of Shivling) with the silver frame of Hajre Aswad. They are not aware of the fact that the silver frame was not present during the time of Prophet Muhammad (P.B.U.H). When the Black Stone was broken into pieces during a war, Its fragments were cemented into a silver frame by Abd Allah Ibn Zubayr. The Black Stone is from Heaven (Tirmizi 878) whereas Yoni (Female genital or Shivling&#8217;s base) worship was initiated after the curse. There are two stories concerning its origin. First one is when the Sage Bhrigu was dishonoured by Shiva as Shiva was busy with his wife Parvati so Bhrigu cursed him to be worshipped in Linga and Yoni form which he desired the most, another story is that Shiva was cursed by the sages to be worshipped in Penis form for seducing their wives, Shiva&#8217;s male organ fell down to earth and burned everything, Shiva told Brahma and Vishnu that it will become calm only when Parvati takes hold of it in Yoni (female genital) form. For more information, read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">Analysis of Lingam</a>. So how can some people claim Black Stone is Hindu Idol when both these have their own origin and definition? Some Hindu brothers are easily deceived by Islamophobes. One should not blindly follow what the person is saying. It is incorrect to liken Shivling with Black Stone because ShivLingam is risen out from the Vulva shaped base known as Yoni whereas Black Stone is not and Shiva Lingam is not cemented into the walls of temple like the Black Stone. There is no evidence of Lingam worship in Arabia nor there is a mention of such Idol. I request the readers to read the Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> as I don&#8217;t want to add any repetitive refutations.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:13pt;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></span><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>:-</strong> It is inappropriate to say that Muslims worship the Kaba or Black stone since Idol worship means worshipping the Idol thinking it to be God himself. Kaba is only a direction for worship. Quran nor the Hadith tell us to worship the Kaaba, Islam strictly prohibits idol worship.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
