<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>women &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/women/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 11:05:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</title>
		<link>/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immolation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infanticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niyoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pyre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Sati Pratha is a Hindu practice where the wife ascends the funeral pyre of her husband and gives up her life. The word Sati may have been derived from the name of Shiva&#8217;s wife. Sati, also called Dakshayani, was one of the daughters of Prasuti and Daksha. She loved Shiva, but &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Sati Pratha is a Hindu practice where the wife ascends the funeral pyre of her husband and gives up her life. The word Sati may have been derived from the name of Shiva&#8217;s wife. Sati, also called Dakshayani, was one of the daughters of Prasuti and Daksha. She loved Shiva, but her father Daksha forbade her marriage to Shiva. She married Shiva anyway, and Daksha got revenge by not inviting Shiva to a festival during his absence. Sati killed herself by self-immolation on a fire. After Shiva returned and found Sati’s body, he killed and decapitated Daksha, later replacing his head with a goat’s. Sati Pratha was widespread during the Early Brahmanic Dark Ages (1500 BC &#8211; 500 BC). It was later enforced by the Brahmins on their usurpation of power during the Later Brahmanic Dark Ages (500 BC &#8211; 1000 AD). Sati Pratha can be found in almost every Hindu scripture.<br />
<span id="more-1671"></span><br />
There have been some cases of Sati Pratha in Independent India,</p>
<p>16/1/19 In Shahbazpur UP, kin and locals stop woman from performing ‘Sati’<br />
<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kanpur/in-up-kin-and-locals-stop-woman-from-performing-sati/articleshow/67550770.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kanpur/in-up-kin-and-locals-stop-woman-from-performing-sati/articleshow/67550770.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>21/11/18 On way to perform &#8216;sati&#8217;, woman Laungshree Devi resident of Angautha village dragged from pyre<br />
<a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/national/way-perform-sati-woman-dragged-704033.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.deccanherald.com/national/way-perform-sati-woman-dragged-704033.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>1 April 2015 Maharashtra: Woman&#8217;s body found from husband&#8217;s pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-maharashtra-woman-s-body-found-from-husband-s-pyre-2073728" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-maharashtra-woman-s-body-found-from-husband-s-pyre-2073728<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Dec 15 2014: In Bihar, 65-year-old woman jumps into husband&#8217;s funeral pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.firstpost.com/india/bihar-65-year-old-woman-jumps-husbands-funeral-pyre-1849693.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.firstpost.com/india/bihar-65-year-old-woman-jumps-husbands-funeral-pyre-1849693.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>9 Sep 2009 Indian women still commit ritual suicides<br />
<a href="https://www.rt.com/news/india-ritual-suicide-sati/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.rt.com/news/india-ritual-suicide-sati/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>14 October 2008 Relatives arrested after widow burns to death on funeral pyre<br />
<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/oct/14/india" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/oct/14/india<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>22 September 2006 Brothers arrested for throwing 95-year-old mother on funeral pyre<br />
<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-406471/Brothers-arrested-throwing-95-year-old-mother-funeral-pyre.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-406471/Brothers-arrested-throwing-95-year-old-mother-funeral-pyre.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>22 August 2006 India wife dies on husband&#8217;s pyre<br />
<a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/south_asia/5273336.stm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/south_asia/5273336.stm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>An unusual occurence in Bihar<br />
&#8220;In 1987, 18-year-old Roop Kanwar was immolated in Rajasthan in front of the whole village. Hers was the fortieth case in independent India, and the 28th in Rajasthan. In this case too it was glorified as the ultimate religious act of a married woman. Public pressure forced the government to enact the Rajasthan Sati Prevention Ordinance on October 1, 1987. Rajasthan Chief Minister Vasundhara Raje Scindia had maintained a stony silence on whether her government will appeal against the judgment. And it had to be filed before March 31. This would have meant going against her mother’s professed views supporting sati. It would also have meant going against the Hindu revivalists in the BJP. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Incidentally, VHP Vice-President Acharya Dharmendra was the master of ceremonies at the first death anniversary of Roop Kanwar</span></span>.&#8221;<br />
<a href="http://archive.tehelka.com/story_main1.asp?filename=Ne040304bihar.asp" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://archive.tehelka.com/story_main1.asp?filename=Ne040304bihar.asp<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Widow burning was also celebrated as evident from archaeological evidence and structures built to honor women who gave up their lives after the death of their husbands,</p>
<p>“<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/chikkamagaluru-500-year-old-sculpture-found-inside-3000-year-old-stone-age-structure/articleshow/91629828.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Mastigallu<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> or maha sati kallu, similar to veeragallu (hero stone) sculptures, were erected for women who gave up their lives after their spouses. Karnataka&#8217;s mastigallus are from the period between 5th century CE and the 18th century.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN MAHABHARATA</strong></span></p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.125.33 &#8220;Vaisampayana continued, &#8216;Having said this, the daughter of the king of Madras, the wedded <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">wife of Pandu, ascended the funeral pyre of her lord</span></span>, that bull among men.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.126.30 &#8221; <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">His wife Madri, beholding him placed in the funeral pyre and about to be consumed, herself ascended the same pyre</span>, and sacrificing her life thus, hath gone with her lord to the region reserved for chaste wives.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.95.63-64 &#8220;And (one day) Pandu, beholding Madri decked with ornaments, had his desire kindled. And, as soon as he touched her, he died. <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Madri ascended the funeral pyre with her lord</span>.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 16.7.24-26 &#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The four wives of that heroic son of Sura ascended the funeral pyre and were consumed with the body of their lord</span></span>. All of them attained to those regions of felicity which were his.<span style="color: red;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">The son of Pandu burnt the body of his uncle together with those four wives of his</span>, using diverse kinds of scents and perfumed wood. As the funeral pyre blazed up</span>, a loud sound was heard of the burning wood and other combustible materials, along with the clear chant of Samans and the wailing of the citizens and others who witnessed the rite.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN RAMAYANA</strong></span></p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Ayodhya Kanda 3.66.12 &#8220;Today itself, I too in devotion to my husband, will meet my appointed end. I shall enter the fire, duly embracing this body of my husband.” Shri K.M.K. Murthy</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN PURANAS<br />
</strong></span><br />
Devi Bhagavatam 6.25.35-50 &#8230;Once Madri, full of youth and beauty, was staying alone in a solitary place and Pa<span style="text-decoration: underline;">nd</span>u seeing her embraced her and due to the curse, died. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">When the funeral pyre was ablaze, the chaste Madri entered into the fire and died a Sati</span></span>&#8230;</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 2.6.53-71 &#8230;Then those Munis, practising great vows, knew that Pandu was dead and performed duly, on the banks of the Ganges, the ceremony of burning the dead. At that time Madri gave over to Kunti the charge of her two sons and <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">followed the Sati practice along with her husband to go to Satyaloka</span>&#8230;</p>
<p>Agni Purana 222.19-23 &#8221;&#8230;The widow who practices self-control and austerities after the death of her husband, goes to heaven&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">the widow who burns herself on the same funeral pire wth her husband also goes to heaven</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Kurma Purana 2.34.108b-109 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A woman who enters the funeral pyre along with her husband</span></span>, shall uplift him even if is a Brahmana-slayer, an ungrateful fellow or one defiled by great sins. learned men know this to be the greatest expiation for women.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri.</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.38.1-11 &#8220;The 8 queens of Krishna, who have been named, with Rukmini at their head, embraced the body of Hari, and entered the funeral fire. <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Revati also embracing the corpse of Rama</span>, entered the blazing pile, which was cool to her, happy in contact with her lord. Hearing these events, <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Ugrasena and Anakadundubhi, with Devaki and Rohini, committed themselves to the flames</span>&#8230;&#8221; Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, KotiRudra Samhita 4.10. 23-24 &#8221;The Brahmin lady desirous of entering the pyre in order to follow her husband cursed the Raksasa king. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The chaste lady entered fire</span></span>&#8230;&#8221;<br />
Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 4.28.50 She then prepared a blazing fire with firewood and placed the dead body of her husband upon it. When this was finished, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">she lamented severely and prepared herself to perish in the fire with her husband</span></span>.<span style="font-size: 12pt;">&#8216;</span></p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse,<br />
&#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">It is the long-standing tradition of the Vedic system that a faithful wife dies along with her husband</span></span>. This is called saha-maraṇa. In India this system was prevalent even to the date of British occupation. At that time, however, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">a wife who did not wish to die with her husband was sometimes forced to do so by her relatives</span></span>. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Formerly that was not the case — the wife used to enter the fire voluntarily</span></span>. The British government stopped this practice, considering it inhuman. However, from the early history of India we find that when Mahārāja Pāṇḍu died, he was survived by two wives — Mādrī and Kuntī. The question was whether both should die or one should die. After the death of Mahārāja Pāṇḍu, his wives settled that one should remain and the other should go. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Mādrī would perish with her husband in the fire</span></span>, and Kuntī would remain to take charge of the five Pāṇḍava children. Even as late as 1936 we saw a devoted wife voluntarily enter the fire of her husband.’’ A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana 4.28.50 [Source: <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.28.50" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.28.50 <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p>He also wrote,<br />
‘’<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">I</span><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">n the Vedic culture there is a system known as satī or saha-maraṇa, in which a woman dies with her husband. According to this system, if the husband dies, the wife will voluntarily die by falling in the blazing funeral pyre of her husband</span></span>. Here, in this verse, the feelings inherent in this culture are expressed by the wife of the brāhmaṇa. A woman without a husband is like a dead body. Therefore according to Vedic culture a girl must be married. This is the responsibility of her father. A girl may be given in charity, and a husband may have more than one wife, but a girl must be married. This is Vedic culture. A woman is supposed to be always dependent—in her childhood she is dependent on her father, in youth on her husband, and in old age on her elderly sons. According to Manu-saṁhitā, she is never independent. Independence for a woman means miserable life. In this age, so many girls are unmarried and falsely imagining themselves free, but their life is miserable. Here is an instance in which a woman felt that without her husband she was nothing but a dead body.’’<strong>Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana 9.9.32</strong> [Source: <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.9.32" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.9.32<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Bhagwad Purana 9.9.36 After this way cursing Mitrasaha [&#8216;indulgent toward friends&#8217; or Saudâsa] she, being devoted to be with her husband, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">found her destination by stepping into the fire that burned the bones of her husband</span></span>.</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 11.31.19-20<span class="views-field views-field-field-translation"> <span class="field-content">Tormented by separation from the Lord, His parents gave up their lives at that very spot. My dear Parīkṣit, the wives of the Yādavas then climbed onto the funeral pyres, embracing their dead husbands.</span></span> <span class="views-field views-field-field-translation"><span class="field-content">The wives of Lord Balarāma also entered the fire and embraced His body, and Vasudeva’s wives entered his fire and embraced his body. The daughters-in-law of Lord Hari entered the funeral fires of their respective husbands, headed by Pradyumna. And Rukmiṇī and the other wives of Lord Kṛṣṇa — whose hearts were completely absorbed in Him — entered His fire.</span> </span></p>
<div class="views-row views-row-18 views-row-even"></div>
<div class="views-row views-row-18 views-row-even"></div>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.107.29 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A Wife who dies in the company of her husband</span></span> shall remain in heaven as many years as there are hairs on his person&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Garuda Purana II.4.88-97 &#8220;&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A woman who has been chaste and faithful to her husband should mount on the pyre after bowing to her (deceased) husband before the funeral rites start</span></span>. One who gets away from the pyre due to fainting should observe the vow named prajapatya. One who ascends the pyre and follows up her husband stays in heaven for a period equal to the number of hair on the body, three and a half crore. Just as the snake-charmer takes out the snake from the hole so also she takes out her husband from hell and enjoys with him in paradise. She who ascends the pyre goes to heaven. She is praised by the celestial nymphs and enjoys with her husband so long as the fourteen Indras rule in heaven successively. Even if the man has killed a brahmana or a friend or any other person of noble conduct he is purified of sins by his wife who ascends his pyre. A woman who enters fire after the death of her husband prospers in the heaven like Arundhati. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Until and unless the woman burns herself after her husband&#8217;s death she is never released from the bond of her sex</span></span>. A woman who follows her husband purifies the three families on her mother&#8217;s side, the three families on her father&#8217;s side and the three families on her husband&#8217;s side.&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Another verse mentioned in Garuda Purana translated by Ernest and Subrahmanyam shows how a widow repented,<br />
Garuda Purana 2.40 &#8221;Not knowing my duty I did not serve my husband, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">nor after his death enter the fire</span></span>. Having become widowed I performed no austerities;&#8211;O Dweller in the Body, make reparation for whatever you have done!&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.42 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">When a woman burns her body with her husband&#8217;s</span></span>, the fire burns her limbs only, but does not afflict her soul&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.45-46 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Likewise she who has joined her husband is never burnt. her inner soul becomes unified with that of her husband</span></span>, by death. The woman who does not burn herself in the fire, on her husband&#8217;s death, is certainly never released from feminine bodies.&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V. Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 10.48 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">The Woman who ascends the funeral pyre, when her husband is dead, becomes equal to Arundhati, and attains the heaven</span></span>. [50] She who goes with her husband purifies three families her mother&#8217;s, her father&#8217;s, and that into which she was given.&#8221; Tr. Ernest Wood and S.V. Subrahmanyam, Edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p>Brahma Purana Gautami Mahatmya 10.75 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Dying Immediately after the husband is the greatest duty of women</span></span>. This is the path laid down in the Vedas. [77] The woman who follows her husband shall stay in heaven for as many years as there are hairs in a man&#8217;s body, viz. three and a half crores of years.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.30.39 &#8221;By entering this burning pyre, I will be slightly after a long time, the dear guest of my husband in the world of the Pitrs (Manes)[41] After saying these words with firm decision, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Renuka decided to follow her husband by entering the fire</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 46.4-22 A king died childless, and his wife wept bitterly and embraced his corpse until a bird told her that she would have seven sons if <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">she mounted her husband&#8217;s funeral pyre</span></span>. She obeyed, and as she entered the fire the king arose and flew into the sky with her, by his power of yoga. When the queen entered her fertile period the king felt it his duty not to neglect her. He made love to her in the air, and his seed fell down from the sky. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Then he went with her to the world of Brahma to dwell eternally</span></span>. But the wives of the Seven Sages saw the cloud like seed falling from the sky into a flower, and they thought it was Soma. Wishing to be young forever, they bathed ritually, honoured their own husbands, and drank the king&#8217;s seed. The moment that they drank it [having thus unconsciously violated their chastity] they lost their holy lustre, and all their husbands abandoned them immediately as sinners. They gave birth to the seven Maruts (Storm Gods).</p>
<p>Padma Purana V.106.60 &#8221;Having raised her, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Narada said to the pure one about her dead (husband)</span>: &#8221;O innocent one of large eyes, please go to your husband. O you of large eyes, your husband, abandoned by his kinsmen, is dead. O auspicious one, you should not weep. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Enter fire (i.e. funeral pyre of your husband)</span></span>.&#8221;[65-68] If you will go to (i.e. desire to enter) fire there, then do not weep . O daughter, if you have committed a sin like enjoying another man (than your husband) then make an expiation to purify that. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">On entering into the fire your minor sins will perish</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Padma Purana VI.252.89-90 &#8221;Rukmaputri with Pradyumna, Usa with Aniruddha and all Yadava ladies <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">honoured the bodies of their husbands and entered fire</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande<br />
Skanda Purana III.i.12.115-116 &#8221;Ere long thereafter, King Manojava abandoned his body and went to the world of Siva, due to the power of that Tirtha. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">O Brahmanas, his wife Sumitra embraced his body then and ascended his funeral pyre</span></span>. She too attained the same world.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana V.i.53.38-41 &#8221;&#8230;The beautiful woman gathered fuel and twigs together and <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">kindled the funeral pyre which she ascended along with her husband</span></span>. She was mentally pleased in doing so&#8230;&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana III.ii.7.53-56 &#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A chaste woman who follows her husband from the house to the cremation ground for self-immolation undoubtedly attains the merit of a horse-sacrifice at every step</span></span>. Just as a snake-catcher forcibly retrieves a snake from its hole, so also a chaste woman retrieves her husband from the messengers of Yama and goes to heave. On seeing a chaste woman the messengers of Yama flee. On seeing the splendour of a chaste woman even the sun feels burning sensation, even the fire gets burnt and all other luminaries begin to tremble. A chaste woman sportingly enjoys heavenly pleasures along with her husband for as many crores and ten thousand years as there are hairs on her body.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare<br />
Narada Purana, Uttarabhaga 16.85-89 &#8220;She sold off her bangle and brought a great deal of fuel. She prepared the funeral pyre. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">After placing her dead husband on it, she poured ghee over the pyre (fuel). She too climbed on the funeral pyre</span></span> joining her face to his face, her heart near his heart and O gentle lady, her buttocks near his buttocks. With her foot she dragged the fire. The auspicious lady of charming limbs set fire to the ailing body of the husband along with her body. As the fire blazed brightly, she cast off her body and went to the world of the Devas taking her husband with her after annihilating many of his sins by means of her holy rites very difficult to be performed.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Narada Purana, Uttarabhaga 30.87 &#8220;With a great deal of merits the woman goes to the region of Visnu alongwith her husband if her body is cremated alongwith him. But a woman greedy of wealth and of her body (?) attains Yama&#8217;s torture and the affliction of being born in base wombs of lower species.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 46.51-53 &#8220;&#8230;Then after a long time that beloved slender-bodied queen of the king had pregnancy from that best of kings. During the pregnancy of the wife the king died. She, loyal to her husband, while desiring to get upon (the funeral pyre of) her husband, was prevented by the ministers, but could not be stopped.&#8221; Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>There is another fake story circulated on internet that, Wives of kings used to immolate themselves only if the Kings went into battle with Muslims, Jauhar wasn&#8217;t practiced when rival king was Hindu. Let&#8217;s not indulge in history and check what scripture says,<br />
Vishnu Purana 3.18.51-55 &#8220;It is related that there was formerly a king named Śatadhanu, whose wife Śaivyá was a woman of great virtue. She was devoted to her husband, benevolent, sincere, pure, adorned with every female excellence, with humility, and discretion&#8230;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">After a time the Rájá, triumphant over his enemies, died; and the princess ascended the funeral pile of her husband</span></span>.&#8221; Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>There is no reference that King Satadhanu lived in the period of Muslims and here we read that the wife of the king ascended funeral pyre of her husband after he died in (or after) the battle. So this refutes the claim of people who tries to blame others for all evil practices of their religion. If self-immolation with husband is such a great virtue then why don&#8217;t Hindu scripture says the same about men? But not all women are suppose to practice Sati Pratha, Brahmin women are barred from practicing it as it will be Brahmin slaughter, other than Brahmin women, following women are also exempted from ascending the funeral pyre of their husbands,</p>
<p>Narada Purana I.7.52 &#8220;O blessed princess! The following (ladies) do not ascend funeral pyre, viz. those with infant children (depending on them), pregnant women, those whose monthly course has not yet started and women in the menses.&#8221; Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Shiva Purana narrates story of Shiva who in the form of a merchant went to his devotee who was a prostitute to test her, he had sexual relation with her and asked her to be his wife for 3 days and a night, this can also be considered as temporary marriage or fornication since the story doesn’t narrate rituals pertaining to marriage. So after having sex with her, Shiva decided to give up his life and asked the prostitute Mahananda to lit funeral pyre, the prostitute too decided to ascend the funeral pyre as she had vowed to be the merchant’s wife for three days.</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Satarudra Samhita 3, Chapter 26, verses 38-51 “O my beloved, when the phallic image is smashed and burnt I do not desire to live. I am telling you the truth. There is no doubt in this. O gentle lady, prepare a pyre for me immediately through your servants. With my mind fixed in Śiva, I shall enter the fire… Then the merchant who was only Śiva himself went round the blazing fire. Desirous of knowing her intentions he entered the fire firmly… Taking the gemset bangle I had taken the pledge that I shall be the avowed wife of this merchant for three days… As she was going to jump in the fire with her mind fixed in his feet, Śiva, the soul of the universe, appeared in front and stopped her.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>IN SMRITIS</strong><br />
</span><br />
Parasara Smriti 4.28 &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">A widow, who immolates herself on the same funeral pile with her deceased husband, resides in heaven</span></span> for ten millions of years, which is the number of hairs on the human body.&#8221; Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Brihaspati Smriti 24.11 A wife is considered half the body (of her husband), equally sharing the result of his good or wicked deeds; whether she ascends the pile after him, or chooses to survive him leading a virtuous life, she promotes the welfare of her husband.<br />
Vishnu Smriti 25.14 &#8221;After the death of her husband, to preserve her chastity, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">or to ascend the pile after him</span></span><span style="color: #000000;">.&#8221; Tr. Various Oriental Scholars</span></p>
<p>Atri Samhita 1.209 &#8220;The woman, who falls down from the funeral pyre, [of her husband], or who gets no menses on account of a disease, becomes purified by a Prajapatya and feeding ten Brahmanas.&#8221; Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Daksha Samhita 4.19 &#8220;A woman, who, after the demise of her husband, ascends the funeral pyre, becomes of good conduct and lives gloriously in the celestial region.&#8221; Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Vijnanesvara writes in Mitakshara on Yajnavalkya Smriti verse 88</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>‘’Moreover, though &#8221;deprived of her husband,&#8221; or bereft of her husband, she should not be without her father, &amp;c, Because, being without their protection, she &#8221;becomes infamous,&#8221; becomes blameworthy. This is (the rule, in case the widow wishes to pass her life) as a Brahmachari or celebate. Because it is ordained in the Vishnu Smriti (Ch. XXXV. 14):- &#8221;After the death of her husband (the widow should adopt one of these two courses) either to preserve her chastity (Brahmacharya) or to ascend the pile after him.&#8221; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">There is great virtue in Anvarohana (or self-immolation along with the deceased husband.)</span></span><br />
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">Vyasa has shown the same thing, in the form of the parable of the she-pigeon:- &#8221;Devoted to her husband, she entered the raging fire</span></span>, and thereafter she obtained her (dead) lord who was adorned with a variegated bracelet. Then afterwards the bird went in company with his wife to heaven, and enjoyed it with her being honored with all acts (of service.)&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No Inheritance for Woman in Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 18:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance for woman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A Short Analysis on Women&#8217;s Inheritance in Vedas Written by Sulaiman Razvi It was due to the influence of other religions like Islam that some Hindu revivalist found the need to reform Hindu society. Hindu scholars fail to furnish any Hindu text which entitles a woman to inherit her father&#8217;s property, this is because there &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Inheritance for Woman in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>A Short Analysis on Women&#8217;s Inheritance in Vedas</h3>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi<br />
<span id="more-627"></span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">It was due to the influence of other religions like Islam that some Hindu revivalist found the need to reform Hindu society. Hindu scholars fail to furnish any Hindu text which entitles a woman to inherit her father&#8217;s property, this is because there isn&#8217;t a single authoritative text which allows a woman to inherit paternal property. It is mentioned in Vedas,<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Krishna Yajur Veda 6.5.8.1 </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Women are powerless, have no inheritance, </span>and speak more humbly than even a bad man.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">It is mentioned in Baudhayana in the inheritance section,</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Baudhayana Dharma Shastra 2.2.3.46 The Veda declares, &#8216;Therefore women are considered to be <span style="color: #ff0000;">destitute of strength </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">and of a portion</span></span>.&#8217;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">In the Rig Veda,<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Rig Veda 3.31.2 </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">&#8216;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#8216;<span style="color: red;">The son does not transfer paternal wealth to his sister</span></span>. He makes her receptacle of the embryo of her husband. When parents procreate children of either sex, <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">one (the male) becomes the performer of holy rites (he is the legal inheriter)</span>, the other (the female) is to be enriched with gifts.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Saraswati</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Below is the Hindi translation by Shri Ram Sharma,<br />
</span></p>
<p id="oPSjcNZ"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="548" height="121" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7639 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25742e208e6.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25742e208e6.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25742e208e6-300x66.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">This verse is further elaborated by Yaska,<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Nirukta 3.6 &#8216;<span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Na Jamaye&#8217; means not for the sister</span>. Jamih (sister) is (so called because) others beget &#8216;Ja&#8217;, i.e. offspring, on her, or the word may be derived from (the root) jam, meaning to go : she has mostly to go (to the husband&#8217;s family). The legitimate, i.e. one&#8217;s own son, left, i.e. gave, wealth. He made her the place of depositing the seed of her husband, i.e. the man who accepts her hand. <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">If the mothers have engendered Vahni, i. e. a son, and Avahni, i.e. a daughter, one of them, i.e. the son and the heir, becomes the procreator of children</span>, and the other, i.e. the daughter, is brought up and given away (in marriage) to another person.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">The verse speaks for itself. This is enough to prove whether women could inherit her paternal wealth or not. Svami Satya Prakash Saraswati wrote in the brackets of the verse that the son is the legal inheritor &#8221;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> (he is the legal inheriter)</span>&#8221; Below is the snapshot from his book<br />
</span></p>
<p id="MvlOfQp"><img decoding="async" width="394" height="115" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7640 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25743d853b7.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25743d853b7.png 394w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25743d853b7-300x88.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 394px) 100vw, 394px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">The Hindu law is governed by Mitakshara and Dayabhaga schools of law. In the Hindu Undivided Family (HUF) the head of the family is known as Karta. Usually Karta is a male member and only male members enjoy coparcener&#8217;s interest. After the death of the Karta the eldest son takes the property (as per Manu Smriti), although property can be divided in the presence of Karta as Maharishi Manu himself divided his property among his sons while he was alive.</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Krishna Yajur Veda 3.1.9 Manu divided his property among his sons.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">A daughter can inherit property only if she has no brother that too only if her father makes her the Appointed Daughter. If the daughter begets a Son then the son becomes the legal heir and is adopted by his maternal grandfather. Yaska states,<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Nirukta 3.5 <span style="text-decoration: underline;">One should not marry a brotherless maiden</span>, <span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">for his (the husband&#8217;s) son belongs to him (to the father of the girl)</span>. From this, the prohibition of marrying a brotherless maiden and the father&#8217;s right to appoint his daughter as a son are evident. When a father selects a husband for his unmarried daughter, he unites himself with a tranquil mind.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Pandit Jaydev Sharma (Arya Samaj) writes on Rig Veda 3.31.1<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;"> &#8221;The grandson shall be the legal heir of his grandfather&#8217;s property&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p id="CQlHipI"><img decoding="async" width="477" height="295" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7641 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25744c9cd56.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25744c9cd56.png 477w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f25744c9cd56-300x186.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 477px) 100vw, 477px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">It is mentioned in Purana,<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">Bhagwad Puran 10.57.37 &#8220;<span style="color: red; text-decoration: underline;">Since Satrajit had no sons, his daughter&#8217;s sons should receive his inheritance</span>. They should pay for memorial offerings of waler and pinda, clear their grandfather&#8217;s outstanding debts and keep the remainder of the inheritance for themselves.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-size: 12pt;">It&#8217;s clear that Vedas does not give rights of inheritance to women, Vedas nor the Brahmanas enables the daughter to inherit property. Even an appointed daughter can&#8217;t hold her father&#8217;s property after she begets a son. Inheritance in Hinduism is the exclusive right of Sons only.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Inheritance for Woman in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Responses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in vedas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi The writer has tried his level best to show Woman are highly revered in the Vedas. How can they claim that Vedas give equal status to women when Vedas are known for oppressing women, it says Women are devoid of intelligence, she shall not inherit, Women are like sly fox. Women &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>The writer has tried his level best to show Woman are highly revered in the Vedas. How can they claim that Vedas give equal status to women when Vedas are known for oppressing women, it says Women are devoid of intelligence, she shall not inherit, Women are like sly fox. Women in Vedas is nothing but a commodity, Yajur Veda 30.5 and 30.9 explicitly states that Ishwar has created women for sexual enjoyment. It doesn&#8217;t even pray for daughter let alone giving them equal rights, Veda only prays for the birth of Son, it says daughter should be born somewhere else, this asserts that women in Vedas is merely looked as a commodity. Some Hindu apologists instead of accepting  oppressive verses, has tried to show equal status of women in Vedas by misquoting them, through means of deceit.</p>
<p><span id="more-620"></span></p>
<p>When they couldn&#8217;t find verses that gives equal rights or praises women, they used the verses addressed to Vedic Goddesses to show women are highly revered in Vedas, they has also used verses which are to be recited during Marriage ceremony. Those verses can never be used to prove that women are given equal status in Vedas, if Vedas really praises women then Hindu apologists should furnish references from Vedas that gives equal inheritance, verses praying for birth of daughter etc. This is a response to a Hindu fanatic&#8217;s article. The reason behind making a response to his article is because he has misquoted the Vedic mantras and commentaries to suit is vested interest, to deceive the gullible people. The writer is being deceitful to propagate his religion as taught by his guru Mulshankar (Dayanand). He pretends to be quoting Arya Samaj Hindi translation but in fact he has mistranslated the Hindi translations also. This is why I will mostly be using Arya Samaj translation as well as orthodox translation of Shri Ram Sharma (Gayatri Parivar) for few verses.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajur 16.44</p>
<p>There should me a women army. Let the women be encouraged to participate in war.</p>
<p>(Book: Vagambhraniya, Author: Dr Priyamvada Vedbharti)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 16.44 &#8220;Food to the expert in deeds, and to the manager of cow-pens. Food to the efficient couch maker, and to him who lives peacefully in his house. Homage to him who is skilled in mental deliberations, and to him who is proficient in diving deep into intricate topics. Food to him who explores the mysteries of nature, and to him who dwells in inaccessible mountain caves.&#8221; Tr. Devi Chand (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 13.26: O woman, you do not deserve to be defeated by challenges. You can defeat the mightiest challenge. Defeat the enemies and their armies. You have valour of thousands. Please us all.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.26 Thou art Ashadha, Conquering One. Conquer our foemen, conquer thou the men who fain would-fight with us. A thousand manly powers hast thou: so do thou aid and quicken me.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="497" height="300" class="wp-image-7716" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-71-300x181.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>Here the word Ashadha or Ishtika is translated as Brick, and earth or speech by some. It is a brick which the queen forms first. The Satapatha Brahmana briefly mentions about Ashadha,</p>
<p>Satapatha Brahmana 7.4.2.32-33. He then lays down the Ashadha (invincible brick),–the &#8216;invincible one&#8217; being this earth, it is this earth he thus lays down. He puts it on the fore-part (of the altar-site), for this earth was created first. And as to its being called Ashadha. The gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Pragapati, strove together. The gods saw this invincible brick, even this earth; they put it on (the altar); and having put it on, they conquered (and drove) the Asuras, the enemies, the rivals, from this universe; and inasmuch as (thereby) they conquered (asahanta), it is called Ashadha. In like manner the Sacrificer, after putting on that (brick), conquers (and drives) his spiteful rival from this universe (or, from everything here).</p>
<p>And there is one more verse from Brahmanas which is a commentary of the Vedic verse,</p>
<p>Satapatha Brahmana 7.4.2.39. &#8216;Thou art Ashadha, the conquering,&#8217; for the gods thereby conquered the Asuras,–&#8217;conquer the enemies! conquer the hostile!&#8217; as the text, so the meaning;–&#8217;thou hast a thousand energies: do thou speed me!&#8217; a thousand means</p>
<p>So this verse is not addressed to a women but to a Brick.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Yajurveda 20.85: Noble woman motivates us to be on path of truth, love and harmony.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Correct translation is</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 20.85 &#8220;Vedic text, the impeller of truthful speeches, the inspirer of perceptions, expatiates on God.&#8221; Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 2.41.16: O woman, you are the motherly force that provides direction to our life.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This verse is not addressed to a common woman, it&#8217;s about people offering prayer to the Goddess, the correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.14.16 Best Mother, best of Rivers, best of Goddesses, Sarasvati, We are, as &#8217;twere, of no repute and dear Mother, give thou us renown. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="118" class="wp-image-7717" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-72-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 6.61.2: The way a powerful river breaks down even strongest rocks and hills, in same manner an intelligent woman destroys the fraud propagated by perverted ones. May we bow to such intelligent women.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.61.2 She with her might, like one who digs for lotus-stems, hath burst with her strong waves the ridges of the hills. Let us invite with songs and holy hymns for help Sarasvati [Vedic Speech according to Arya Samaj] who slayeth the Paravatas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="437" height="379" class="wp-image-7718" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp3.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73.png 437w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-73-300x260.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 437px) 100vw, 437px" /></p>
<p>This verse is addressed to goddess Saraswati but according to the Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation it refers to Vedic Speech.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Atharvaveda 7.57.1: Whenever I am hurt emotionally or physically, woman – as a mother, wife, sister etc – provides healing touch and rejuvenates me. I bow in humble respect to her.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.57.1 Whatever trouble hath disturbed and shaken me–I speak with hope, I move, imploring, &#8216;mid the folk What harm my body in myself hath suffered, now let Sarasvati relieve with fatness.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="147" class="wp-image-7719" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp4.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-74-300x71.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>According to the Shripad Damodar (Arya Samaj) Hindi translation above, this verse is also addressed to Hindu Goddess Saraswati. This is a prayer made to Saraswati.</p>
<p>The writer has quoted some verses about discrimination of women in Vedas and then tried to explain it. He again repeated the same trick i.e., to twist the verses and has given his own interpretation. I will reply to his mistranslated Vedic verses one by one.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that was prevalent in all societies and more so in Biblical and Quranic society. Bible, Quran an Hadiths are full of such references. But Vedas have no mention of Niyoga. People have interpreted Vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations. But neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society. On contrary, many a prophets of Christianity and Islam got children from slave-girls but never made them their wives! Prophet Abraham is supposed to have even attempted to abandon his slave-girl to death after having child from her. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria. God only knows the veracity of these stories and support for sex slavery in Bible and Quran. But as far as Vedas are concerned, any relation apart from one single wife/husband is clearly considered to be cause of miseries.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Readers are requested to go through these articles for evidence of Niyoga from Vedas and Arya Samaj scholars,</p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/05/11/niyoga-aur-naari/" data-wpel-link="internal">नियोग और नारी (Niyoga aur Naari)</a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Arya Samajis </a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/12/27/hinduism-lust/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Lust </a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a></p>
<p>Can the writer elaborate what are those &#8220;emergency&#8221; situations where prostitution would be required? Don&#8217;t such people have wives to relieve their desire? Seems like the Rishis created these Niyoga verses to satisfy their whims. The founder of Arya Samaj Dayanand Saraswati wrote</p>
<p>&#8220;Niyoga is clearly allowed by the Veda&#8221; Satyarth Prakash, Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 4, p.142, Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>When Dayanand (who is considered the greatest revivalist) says Veda sanction Niyoga then how can the author defy his Guru?</p>
<p>The writer is acting like a small kid who when caught tries to accuse others of doing the same thing. You can&#8217;t even compare having a child on slave with Niyoga, because Niyoga is a Vedic practice where the wife cohabits with other men to beget children or the Brahmin cohabits with several women to relieve his desires. He claims Quran is full of such (Niyoga) references but doesn&#8217;t cite any. As far as Prophet&#8217;s relation with Hazrat Mariya is concerned there are ample evidence to show that Prophet Muhammad (S.A.W) married Marriya al Qibtiyya r.a,</p>
<p>&#8220;The muqawqis, or King of the Copts, gave the Prophet (S) two wives as a gift. The Prophet (S) married one[i.e., Mariya], who became the mother of the Prophet&#8217;s son Ibrahim, and he gave the other one to Hassan as a wife&#8221;.</p>
<p>(Haythami said in Majma al-zawaid, &#8220;Tabarani in al-Aswat and al-Bazzar related it, and the narrators in al-Bazzar&#8217;s chain are all scholars of sound Hadith as stated by Hisham Kabbani in Encyclopedia of Islamic Doctrine: Remembrance of Allah and Praising the Prophet, p. 76 Vol. II)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>The reason why birth of a daughter became a curse in last 1000 years was due to the butchers from West and Central Asia coming in name of Islamic Jihad to kill men and rape women. The entire history of last 1000 years is full of resistance against these terrorists. Thus people wanted sons who could fight these terrorists or at least not be raped by them the way they used to rape women. Birth of daughter thus became a curse because safeguarding the dignity of a daughter was a challenging task. This is why purdah system came in India. This is why dowry system became prevalent – ensuring safety of women became a risky thing. And soon these evil practices became part of the culture. However Vedas are complete against all this and it is time we get back to Vedas.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>As usual the writer tries to blame Muslims for the evil Vedic practices. First of all I want to talk about the Dowry topic. He says all the evil practices became prevalent in India due to Muslims. Can he provide a single reference where Dowry is demanded from women in Islam? Dowry system exists only in Hinduism. Secondly If Muslim rulers were so powerful, cruel and religious bigots that Hindus killed their daughters due their fear then why didn&#8217;t the Muslim rulers establish a fully dominant Muslim empire? They could have easily converted all the Hindus by the force of Sword. But almost all the rulers treated Hindus and Muslims alike, never discriminated on the basis of religion and this is evident from the fact that Hindus still make 80% of the population in India, Even the bravest Hindu rulers were defeated by Muslim rulers, you can ascertain the strength of Muslims rulers by this fact.</p>
<p>In the entire article the writer couldn&#8217;t quote a single verse that prays for the birth of a daughter, on contrary Vedas say a daughter should be born somewhere else and only a son should be born. With such kind of verses Female infanticide became widely prevalent in Ancient India. A historian writes</p>
<p>&#8221;In ancient India approximately 1500 BC, there is evidence of nomadic Vedic Aryan tribes who invaded the land and introduced the custom of Female infanticide (Moor 1811). It was the customary that these tribes would pray for the birth of a male child and pray against the arrival of a female.&#8221; – Violence and Abuse in Society: Understanding a Global Crisis, p.121, Angela Brown Miller</p>
<p>He further writes</p>
<p>Edward Moor (1811), a British soldier reporting on female infanticide in ancient India, specified the reasons that made it a necessary practice. In his treatise advocating for female children, &#8220;Vedic Dark Ages&#8221;, he wrote &#8220;Obliterating female children was a convenient way to alleviate financial ruin; large dowries prescribed by the Vedas implied that female children were an economic burden; women were of little use to Aryan Warmachines.&#8221; In those cultures, the gruesome methods used to murder female infants included posioning, starvation, suffocation, smothering, drowning in a pit filled with milk, burying alive, throwing baby to the crocodiles in the Ganges River, cutting up the child and then feeding it to animals, and throwing the baby girl in the air and chopping her up with unsheathed swords as she fell.&#8221;-(ibid)</p>
<p>So these evil practices were introduced by none other than Hindu invaders themselves.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>The word &#8216;Putra&#8217; in Vedas is generic and does not necessarily mean a son but implies a child. This is same as &#8216;mankind&#8217; does not mean only men but all human beings. In most mantras of Vedas though, word &#8216;Praja&#8217; is used which again means children. As mentioned previously, there are mantras which desire specifically a daughter. For example, Rigveda 10.159.3, 8.31.8, 9.67.10, Yajurveda 22.22, Rigveda 4.32.23 and Atharvaveda 10.3.20. Thus all these claims of Vedas being male-centric is childish at the best.</p>
<p><strong>REPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.138 Because a son delivers (trayate) his father from the hell called Put, he was therefore called Putra (a deliverer from Put) by the Self-existent (Svayambhu) himself.</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 7.9 The son saves his father from the hell called Put; therefore he was named &#8220;Putra&#8221;<br />
by the Self-existent himself.</p>
<p>Above verses clears all doubts over the term Putra. If the word Putra denotes Children then what does the word Putri mean? Moreover the term &#8220;Veer&#8221; is also used in Vedas to mean Son. The word &#8220;Veer&#8221; is a masculine word generally used for Warrior but in Vedas it&#8217;s been used for Son also. Other verses which the author quoted have been refuted. Its surprising to see that as per Hindu scripture the Son saves the father from hell while the daughter is a burden who does bad. Read <a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</a> for the refutation of the verses he quoted about Birth of daughters in Veda.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Punsawan Sanskar is recommended for aspirants of <strong>both sons and daughters</strong>. So there is no male bias here.</p>
<p>The mantra meaning has been distorted to suit the agenda. The mantra has a deep meaning. But simply put it means that: &#8220;By Grace of Ishwar, woman is able to have a womb and nurture the child therein. May the woman have a son if she desires and planned so ELSE she may have a girl. [Atharva Veda 6.11.3]&#8221;</p>
<p>Thus the mantra simply implies that if couple has planned for a boy, may boy be born else girl be born</p>
<p>What translators have done is to translate &#8216;Anyatra&#8217; as &#8216;Elsewhere&#8217; <strong>instead of &#8216;In other condition</strong> or else&#8217;.</p>
<p>The Vedic methods of procreation suggest ways of deciding either a boy or a girl. But regardless of the</p>
<p>case, Punsawan Sanskar is practiced by all Veda followers. Hence there is no gender bias here.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>It is mentioned in Grihya Sutras,</p>
<p>Sankhayana Grihya Surtra 1.19.6 …Pragapati has created him, Savitar has shaped him. Imparting birth of females to other (women) may he put here a man…</p>
<p>Now who will claim that the translation is incorrect as this verse from Grihya Sutra confirms the Vedic verse on Pumsavan Sanskar. The author himself is distorting the translation and blaming others. Shripad Damodar (Arya Samaj) writes in the commentary about Punsavan,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="313" height="95" class="wp-image-7720" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp5.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75.png 313w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-75-300x91.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 313px) 100vw, 313px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;The birth of a son is called &#8216;Punsavan&#8217; and birth of a girl is called &#8220;Straishuya&#8221;.</p>
<p>Arya Samaji scholar named Vaidyanath Shastri translates Atharva Veda 6.11.1 as follows,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 6.11.1 &#8220;Ashvatta rooted on the tree of Shami is medicine in conducting the ceremony of Pumsavan. It being used there to perform the Pumsavan, a male birth is certain. This is the means of finding a son. We the house-holders bring and use it in the woman.&#8221; Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>It is also mentioned in Garuda Purana,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.93.11-13 &#8220;Garbhadhana (conception) [is performed] after the menstruation, Pumsavana before throbbing of the child in the womb [with purpose to get a son]&#8221; Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Vishnu Smriti,</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 27.2 The Pumsavana (ceremony to cause the birth of a male) must be performed before the embryo begins to move.</p>
<p>Read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> for more information on Punsavan and Female foeticide</p>
<p>The word &#8220;Anyatra&#8221; means somewhere, elsewhere, in another place. The author has derived the meaning &#8220;in other condition&#8221; from Jaydev&#8217;s translation, while giving the meaning from Jaydev&#8217;s translation it would have been better for him to quote complete translation of Jaydev Sharma (Arya Samaj),</p>
[Jaydev] Atharva Veda 6.11.3…In other conditions there is possibility to conceive a girl child but by this procedure the woman conceives a male child only. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="463" height="222" class="wp-image-7721" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp6.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76.png 463w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-76-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>This is a clear discrimination against birth of daughters. Another verse from Atharva Veda has a prayer to beget several sons,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 3.23.3 Bring forth a male, bring forth a son. Another male shall follow him. The mother shalt thou be of sons born and hereafter to be born.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="781" height="87" class="wp-image-7722" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp7.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.jpeg 781w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39-300x33.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39-768x86.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 781px) 100vw, 781px" /></p>
<p>If there is already a son then why does it pray for birth of sons again and again? It is somehow understandable if Vedas pray for one son as daughters don&#8217;t have the right to perform Vedic tasks which can be performed only by a son. But Vedas praying for sons again and again is a discrimination which has lead the Indian society to adopt the evil practice called female infanticide.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.33.17 Do not try to rule over the thought process of woman. She can think very fast and in multiple dimensions.</p>
<p>This is also true. Women can think and connect at emotional levels that is impossible for men. That is why women can nurture children in ways men cannot even think of. What translators have done is to distort &#8216;Ashasyam&#8217; to mean &#8216;cannot be taught&#8217;while it means &#8216;cannot be ruled&#8217;. Then they translated &#8216;Raghum&#8217; to mean &#8216;little&#8217; while it actually means &#8216;agile&#8217;or &#8216;able to move rapidly in variety of locations&#8217;or &#8216;dynamic&#8217;. That is why Raghu of Raghukul to which Ram belonged was named so.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This writer is distorting his own Vedas, he is deliberately mistranslating the verse, the correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.33.17 Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline, Her intellect hath little weight.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="208" class="wp-image-7723" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-77-300x125.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Above is a Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation, and I am quoting two other much more clear Hindi translations by Shri Ram Acharya and Pundit Ram Govind Trivedi,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="556" height="75" class="wp-image-7724" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp9.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78.png 556w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-78-300x40.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 556px) 100vw, 556px" /></p>
<p>Pundit Ram Govind Trivedi&#8217;s Hindi translation,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="431" height="139" class="wp-image-7725" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp10.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79.png 431w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-79-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px" /></p>
<p>Mahrishi Manu writes</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.18 For women no (sacramental) rite (is performed) with sacred texts, thus the law is settled; women (who are) destitute of strength and destitute of(the knowledge of) Vedic texts, (are as impure as) falsehood (itself), that is a fixed rule.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.95.15 &#8220;Do not run away from your duties due to indulgence in a woman. Do not share confidential details of country with anyone. They may be wolves in garb who want to destroy you and your country. A woman befriended for sensual purposesis a wolf in disguise. Hence stay away from sensual vices to protect the country.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thus the particular mantra can be interpreted variously. The particular mantra is part of an allegorical conversation between Pururava and Urvashi. Pururava has several meanings like Cloud, Air and Person. Urvashi means electricity, speech or a woman. Thus the mantra, rather Sukta, provides deep insights. Let us try to understand the context by taking it as conversation. Interestingly this mantra is uttered by the woman herself!</p>
<p>The deep meanings of mantra also unravel that all those women indulged in luring people by glamor – read actresses, models etc – are basically wolves in disguise. So far the country keeps adoring the Aishwarya Rais and Kareenas and Katrinas and ignoring Rani Laxmis and Ahilya Bais and Rani Karnavatis, we simply cannot prosper. Glam-girls are wolves in disguise. And when political leadership starts getting close to them, nothing can be better recipe for national disaster. This mantra thus asserts that considering women as objects for sensual pleasure is not advisable.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>This is the same author who is quoting verses out of context and now asking everyone to read it in context. Below is the correct translation along with Arya Samaj&#8217;s Hindi translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.95.15 Nay, do not die, Pururavas, nor vanish: let not the hideous wolves devour thee. Female friendships do not exist. With women there can be no lasting friendship: hearts of hyenas are the hearts of women.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="490" height="206" class="wp-image-7726" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp11.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80.png 490w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-80-300x126.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" /></p>
<p>So where in this verse does it say that it refers to women who lures? This verse refers to women in general, it&#8217;s not confined to particular type of women, people like the author should stop giving their own interpretation. Yaska Acharya in his book Nirukta 5.13 writes that Urvashi is the name of a Nymph. Further this verse is explained in Srimad Bhagawatam/Bhagwad Purana,</p>
<p>Bhagawad Purana 9.14.36-38: &#8220;Urvasi said: My dear King, you are a man, a hero. Don&#8217;t be impatient and give up your life. Be sober and don&#8217;t allow the senses to overcome you like foxes. Don&#8217;t let the foxes eat you. In other words, you should not be controlled by your senses. Rather, you should know that the heart of a woman is like that of a fox. There is no use making friendship with women. <strong>Women as a class</strong><br />
<strong>are merciless and cunning.</strong> They cannot tolerate even a slight offense. For their own pleasure they can do anything irreligious, and therefore they do not fear killing even a faithful husband or brother. Women are very easily seduced by men. Therefore, polluted women give up the friendship of a man who is their well-wisher and establish false friendship among fools. Indeed, they seek newer and newer friends, one after another&#8221;.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON writes in the commentaries of these verses</p>
<p>&#8220;Canakya Pandita has advised, visvaso naiva kartavyah strishu raja-kuleshu ca: &#8220;Never place your faith in a woman or a politician.&#8221; Unless elevated to spiritual consciousness, everyone is conditioned and fallen, what to speak of women, who are less intelligent than men. Women have been compared to sudras and vaisyas (striyo vaisyas tatha sudrah). On the spiritual platform, however, when one is elevated to the platform of Krishna consciousness, whether one is a man, woman, sudra or whatever, everyone is equal. <strong>Otherwise, Urvasi, who was a woman herself and who knew the nature of women, said that a woman&#8217;s heart is like that of a sly fox</strong>. If a man cannot control his senses, he becomes a victim of such sly foxes. But if one can control the senses, there is no chance of his being victimized by sly, fox like women. Canakya Pandita has also advised that if one has a wife like a sly fox, he must immediately give up his life at home and go to the forest…<strong>Urvaśī frankly explained the nature of a woman</strong>. Because of her nature, a woman can respond to even a slight offense from her husband by not only leaving him but even killing him if required….Because women are easily seduced, the Manu-samhita enjoins that they should not be given freedom. A woman must always be protected, either by her father, by her husband, or by her elderly son. If women are given freedom to mingle with men like equals, which they now claim to be, they cannot keep their propriety. The nature of a woman, as personally described by Urvasi, is to establish false friendship with someone and then seek new male companions, one after another, even if this means giving up the company of a sincere well-wisher&#8221;. Source for commentaries of verses <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.36" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">36<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.37" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">37<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_9.14.38" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">38<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>So according to Srimad Bhagawatam and the commentary by such great scholar of Hinduism, this Vedic verse refers to &#8220;Women as a Class&#8221; not to women like Kareenas, Katrinas, And that all women are like sly fox, cunning, polluted.</p>
<p>The Rishi and Rishika as well as the Deities of this hymn are Urvashi and Puruava, which means their conversation and all that they are saying is a divine inspiration/commandment. So how can some Hindus claim it is Urvashi&#8217;s personal views, thus they are not divine words? The deities of this hymn are Puruava and Urvashi which is enough to prove my point.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>&#8216;Yajur Ved (Taitriya Sanhita)- &#8220;Women code says that the women are without energy. They should not get a share in property. Even to the wicked they speak in feeble manner&#8221; [Yajur Ved 6/5/8/2]
<p>Shatpath Puran, preachings of the &#8216;Yajur Veda&#8217; clubs women, &#8216;shudras&#8217; (untouchables), dogs, crows together and says falsehood, sin and gloom remain integrated in them. [14/1/1/31] In &#8216;Aiterey Puran&#8217;, preaching of the &#8216;Rig Veda&#8217; in Harsih Chandra – Narad dialogue, Narad says: &#8220;The daughter causes pain&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>1. The first reference is not clear. In any case Taitriya Samhita is not original Yajurveda. Kindly provide a reference from actual Yajurveda (Madhyandina Shukla Yajurveda Samhita to be specific, which is the actual Veda Samhita).</p>
<p>2. There is no text called Shatpath Puran and Aiterey Puran. They are Shatpath and Aitereya Brahmans. In any case, again these references are not from Vedas. Further we request the author of these allegations to provide the exact verse</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>Well, it&#8217;s not our fault if there are so many corrupted Vedas available, even the Vedas which you claim to be original is not authentic at all nor can you prove it&#8217;s authenticity. But can you show a reference from your &#8220;Original&#8221; Vedas that talks about equal inheritance? That verse is from Krishna Yajur Veda and is believed by orthodox Hindus (Mainly south Indians) to be correct/Authentic Vedas along with Shukla Yajur Veda. But the most authentic Smriti of Arya Samaj the Manu Smriti also makes no mention of equal inheritance, it rather says</p>
<p>Manu 8:416. A wife, a son, and a slave, these three are declared to have no property; the wealth which they earn is (acquired) for him to whom they belong.</p>
<p>Further Rig Veda also says that a woman will not inherit the property. Refer to my article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/no-inheritance-for-woman-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Inheritance for Women in Vedas</a>,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.31.2 &#8221;The son does not transfer paternal wealth to his sister. He makes her receptacle of the embryo of her husband. When parents procreate children of either sex, one (the male) becomes the performer of holy rites (he is the legal inheriter), the other (the female) is to be enriched with gifts.&#8221; Tr. Satyaprakash Saraswati (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>There is no polygamy in Vedas, Vedas strictly prohibit Polygamy. Vedas stands only for monogamy.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Where is the reference, We As far as Polygamy in Vedas is concerned there are numerous verses which talks about multiple wives of a man, I will quote few of them</p>
<p>7.18.2 For like a King among his wives<br />
thou dwellest: with glories, as a Sage, surround and help us…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="122" class="wp-image-7727" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp12.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-81-300x67.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p>Above Hindi translation is of Gayatri Parivar.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.116.10…who was without kindred, and made him the husband of many maidens. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="588" height="133" class="wp-image-7728" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp13.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82.png 588w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-82-300x68.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 588px) 100vw, 588px" /></p>
<p>For more information read <a href="/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hindu Dharma</a> for more details.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>The Aryans in those days used to attack the original inhabitants of this place, or other tribe within their own race, loot them and snatch away their women. Thus, these militant, wicked men had more wives. This custom of polygamy helped a great deal in bringing down the women. Rig Ved 10/59 says that Lord Indra had many queens that were either defeated or killed by his principal wife.</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Any evidence, manuscripts or any vague reference to hypothesis of either Aryan invasion theory or Aryans being a race or even any tribe claiming to be Arya killing or plundering anyone? Please cite a single reference to this most stupid hoax of Aryan Invasion.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Here is the reference</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 What do the cattle for thee among the Kikatas, they yield no milk to mix with the Soma, they need not the vessel (for the libation) Bring thou to us the wealth of Pramaganda; give up to us, O Maghavan, the low caste. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="509" height="270" class="wp-image-7729" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp14.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83.png 509w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-83-300x159.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /></p>
<p>Manu Smriti 7.96 Chariots and horses, elephants, parasols, money, grain, cattle, women, all sorts of (marketable) goods and valueless metals belong to him who takes them (singly) conquering (the possessor).</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Our challenge is open to all – Cite one single verse in all 4 Vedas that justify Sati Pratha, or support polygamy, or insult women, or justify sex-slavery and we shall quit Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>Let us add one more allegation referring to Rigveda 10.18.7 which Hindu-haters translate to mean &#8220;widow woman should go into fire&#8221;. However what the shameless haters have done is to change the word &#8220;Agre&#8221; in the mantra (which means going ahead) to &#8220;Agne&#8221; which means fire. The mantra by the way has nothing about widow. It means that: In matters of household management, wife should be the leader.</p>
<p><strong>Allegation:</strong></p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda opines that even at that time women used to have sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. The hymn says:&#8221;O woman, get up and adopt the worldly life again. It is futile to lie with this dead man. Get up and become the wife of the man who is holding your hand and who loves you. [Rig Ved 10/18/8]. Apparently this shows that woman is considered to be a property. Whenever and whosoever desired, could become her master.</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Opinion of Vivekananda or practice of &#8216;that&#8217; time is none of our concern. Many Hindus go to worship graves or even support Jihadi terrorists of Kashmir. That does not make this a practice sanctioned by Vedas or Hinduism.</p>
<p>2. The meaning of this mantra provided has been slightly distorted and misinterpreted to suit one&#8217;s mindset of hatred. Actual meaning is: &#8220;O woman, get up from here and come back to the world of living ones. Do not waste your life in grief of one who is dead. You have the children of the person who had held your hand and became your husband, to take care of.&#8221;</p>
<p>3. The next mantra (where this mantra comes in Atharva Veda 18th Chapter) refers to a childless widow. It says: &#8220;I have seen a young widow rising up from grief of dead to marry again and start her life again away from gloom and darkness.&#8221;</p>
<p>4. Thus the mantras give the noble lesson that a widow should not continue repenting on dead one but start life afresh and continue with her responsibilities. These mantras form the foundation in which widow remarriage is encouraged and Sati Pratha is discouraged. And fools quote these very mantras to showcase the entirely opposite stand!</p>
<p>I agree that condition of widows has been miserable for several centuries. This has been primarily because the first targets of all butchers who invaded from West Asia in name of Islam was to rape women – be it army of Qasim, Ghazni, Ghori, Khilji, Lodhi, Babur, Akbar or whosoever. Thus widows would have no one to even fight and lay their life for their dignity. Thus widowhood started being regarded as a curse. And soon it became a evil practice. Thanks to efforts of 19th century reformers especially Arya Samaj, this is no more the case with Hindu society that knows Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>4. But the plight of women in Pakistan is extremely horrible. With no rights for divorce and the shameful Hudood ordinance, it has been a nightmare being a woman in a Muslim dominated country.</p>
<p><strong>MY RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Those verses are mistranslated by the writer. The writer himself should quote the reference as a refutation and then explain it. The correct translation is,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.18.7 Let these unwidowed dames with noble husbands adorn themselves with fragrant balm and unguent. Decked with fair jewels, tearless, free from sorrow, first let the dames go up to where he lieth</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.18 .8 Rise, woman, (and go) to the world of living beings : come, this man near whom thou sleepest is lifeless: beget children from this appointed husband [through Niyoga], the suitor who took thee by the hand.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="506" height="222" class="wp-image-7730" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp15.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84.png 506w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-84-300x132.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /></p>
[This verse is translated into English from Hindi Bhasya]
<p>The verse Rig Veda 10.18.8 is much more worse than one can imagine, this verse is spoken by the dead husband&#8217;s brother, this is mentioned in Aswalayana Griha Sutra 4.2.</p>
<p>As per the Vedic rule, after the death of the husband, the dead husband&#8217;s bother or any other man is considered Devar i.e., he can have intercourse with the widow at anytime to fulfill his desire and to beget sons.</p>
<p>Arya Samaj commentary on the Rig Vedic verse 10.18.8, page 512 states: &#8220;When a woman capable of conceiving a child becomes widow then she may contract Niyoga with the Appointed Husband to beget childre&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="541" height="98" class="wp-image-7731" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp16.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85.png 541w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-85-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></p>
[Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/rugveda_v5/pages/p512.gif" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/rugveda_v5/pages/p512.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>The author says remarriage is strongly encouraged in Vedas but cites no reference for it. As per the Vedic law, a widow should either live a life of austerity i.e., not wearing colorful clothes, jewellery, not laughing etc., or else should enter the pyre of her Husband. She can&#8217;t desire to have sex with other men, but other men without any hesitation can have it with her. it is mentioned in</p>
<p>Parasara Smrti 4.32 If a woman follows her departed lord, by burning herself on the same funeral pile, she will dwell in heaven for as many years as there are hairs on the human frame, which reach the number of three crores and a half.</p>
<p>So a woman should either remain widow or ascend the pyre, but why should a woman have this option? Why not make this same rule applicable for men also? As per Hindu scripture a man can marry after the death of his wife but if a husband dies then the wife should either ascend her husband&#8217;s pyre or live a life of celibacy. Niyoga is clearly sanctioned by Maharishi Manu in Manu Smriti 9.81. Swami Dayanand Saraswati also discouraged widow remarriage and also said that it is prohibited. Then how can the author go against the teachings of his Guru.</p>
<p>Looks like the author has vowed to blame Islam and Muslims for all the evil practices sanctioned by the Vedas. Women are war booty in Vedic Dharm</p>
<p>As far as Divorce is concerned, a Woman can never ask for divorce</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 5. 154. Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife.</p>
<p>Hindu reformist organization like Arya Samaj did nothing for the betterment of women as the Vedas opposes it. Arya Samajis supports castiesm and Niyoga so how can the author claim such crap. The author writes</p>
<p>&#8221; Thus widows would have no one to even fight and lay their life for their dignity. Thus widowhood started being regarded as a curse.&#8221;</p>
<p>Didn&#8217;t the writer just say that remarriage is strongly encouraged in Vedas? if it is so then why these widows were not remarried so that their Husbands may protect them? Isn&#8217;t it the duty of Brother or Son as well to protect the widow? Maharishi Manu writes,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.65 In the sacred texts which refer to marriage the appointment (of widows) is nowhere mentioned, nor is the remarriage of widows prescribed in the rules concerning marriage.</p>
<p>But in case when there is a remarriage of women, the remarried woman, her husband and her son will be isolated, this is what Maharishi Manu says</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.160 …the son begotten on a re-married woman, the son self given, and the son of a Sudra female, (are) the six (who are) not heirs, (but) kinsmen.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti .166 …the husband of a remarried woman, and a carrier of dead bodies, (all these) must be carefully avoided.</p>
<p>Sati Pratha was existent in India before the advent of Muslims. Does the writer mean to say that Mudri the wife of Pandu and wives of Hindu god Krishna practiced Sati Pratha due to the fear of Muslim invaders? As there is evidence from Hindu scriptures to show that Sati Pratha was a Vedic custom practiced by some women,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.38 &#8220;The 8 queens of Krishna, who have been named, with Rukmini at their head, embraced the body of Hari, and entered the funeral fire. Revati also embracing the corpse of Rama, entered the blazing pile, which was cool to her, happy in contact with her lord. Hearing these events, Ugrasena and Anakadundubhi, with Devaki and Rohini, committed themselves to the flames.&#8221;</p>
<p>For more information read the article <a href="/index.php/2018/10/01/sati-pratha-the-burning-of-widows/" data-wpel-link="internal">Sati Pratha: The Burning of Widows</a>. The evil practice of Sati Pratha came into existence not because of Muslims, instead the Muslim rulers tried to stop this evil Vedic practice</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Though Mughals tried to impose restrictions on Sati Pratha but could not stop this evil practice. The position of a widow was miserable in the Hindu society. They were not allowed to use ornaments.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Muslim women had property right of their Husband and father but Hindu women had no property right. The Hindu female had her right only on ornaments and precious articles.&#8221;- Pratiyogita Darpan, p.133, by Upkar Prakashan.</strong></p>
<p>It has become habit of Hindu fanatics to start talking about other countries just to cover the ugly part of Hinduism. Islam gives women the right to divorce unlike Hinduism which doesn&#8217;t allow women to divorce and even says that widow should either ascend pyre of her husband or live her entire life in simplicity and chastity and chastity here includes obscene practice called Niyoga. Practices like Sati, Niyoga, Dev Daasi, female infanticide shows which religion is oppressive to women. There has been 500% increase in rape of Dalit women. The Indian court had to ban many inhumane Vedic practices and the writer in his hypocrisy crediting Arya Samaj.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Allegation</strong>:</p>
<p>In Rig Veda there are references to slave girls being given in charity as gifts. After killing the men-folk of other tribes, particularly of the native inhabitants, their women were rounded up and used as slave girls. It was custom to present slave girls to one other as gifts. The kings used to present chariots full of slave girls to their kith and kin and priests (Rig Veda 6/27/8). King Trasdasyu had given 50 slave girls. It was custom to present slave girls to Saubhri Kandav (Rig Veda 8/38, 5/47/6).</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Not again! The mantra in 6.27.8 has a &#8216;Vadhu&#8217; word which has been misquoted blatantly and foolishly. The sukta refers to national security. The actual mantra means: &#8220;May the wise king appoint a council of 20 able dynamic persons to create strategies to defend the nation from enemies.&#8221; The word &#8220;Vadhumatah&#8221; means one who is capable and dexterous in handling multiple situations smartly.</p>
<p>2. The reference to King Trasadasyu has been wrongly given again showcasing that no one even bothered to check the references. But whatever be the case, Tradasyu means one who defeats terrorists and criminals and hence ensures peace and progress. Saubhari means a noble person who takes care of students well. The actual mantra in Rigveda 8.19.36 means: &#8220;The king who is very philantrophic and protector of noble ones, who has defeated the terrorists has provided me 50 Vadhus.&#8221;</p>
<p>3. Now question is that what does Vadhu mean? Vadhu means anything that brings strength, vitality, protection or bliss. Since Vedic philosophy believes that women are source of all happiness that come in a society, Vadhu refers to a new bride who enters home of in-laws. Thus it can refer to a daughter-in-law or wife or a bride in general. It can also mean an armed force that protects the nation. Thus in no way the mantra refers to slave girls. If you take literal meaning of bride, then it means that King gave 50 already wed women to a teacher. Obviously it then means that he arranged for marriage of his graduating students. But a more sensible meaning would be that the king gave a battalion of 50 to a general to protect the country. But no way, can it refer to a slave girl.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>How can someone give &#8220;already wedded women&#8221;? A bride is not presented to anyone, only a slave girl is presented. The author has mistranslated the verses, below are the verses with correct Hindi translation of Shri Ram Acharya,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.27.8 The opulent supreme sovereign Abhy Avartin, the son of Chayamana, presents, Agni, to me two damsels riding in cars, and twenty cows</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="510" height="106" class="wp-image-7732" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp17.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86.png 510w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-86-300x62.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 510px) 100vw, 510px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.19.36 A gift of fifty female slaves<br />
hath Trasadasyu given me, Purukutsa&#8217;s son, Most liberal, kind, lord of the brave.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="558" height="91" class="wp-image-7733" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp18.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87.png 558w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-87-300x49.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 558px) 100vw, 558px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.126.3 Ten chariots drawn by bay steeds, and carrying women, stood near me, given me by Swanaya and a thousand and sixty cows… <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="541" height="98" class="wp-image-7734" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp19.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88.png 541w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-88-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></p>
<p>If these verses are referring to Bride/Wife then can Hindu tell us How can wives be presented to someone? Is it Niyoga or some other obscene Vedic practice? A slave is a commodity which can be sold, purchased or gifted and that&#8217;s what we read in Vedas here, the Woman were gifted to others. The Arya Samaj translation says,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.52.3 Eat, Indra, our (offered) cakes and butter; derive enjoyment from our praises, as a lover from women.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="509" height="281" class="wp-image-7735" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp20.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89.png 509w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-89-300x166.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /></p>
<p>The Arya Samaj translation has translated the word Vadhu as Stree (Woman) in this verse, further the commentary states,</p>
<p>&#8220;…Like the man longing for a woman is blissed by getting her…&#8221;</p>
<p>The sentence here in this verse &#8220;Vadhuyur yoshanaam&#8221; means one fond of women. The word Vadhu also means Woman, even the author writes</p>
<p>&#8221; Even the most modern Amarkosh 3.102 simply states &#8220;Vadhurjaya Snusha Stree Cha&#8221; or &#8220;Vadhu means Wife, Daughter-in-law or Woman&#8221;</p>
<p>Maharishi Manu writes about types of slaves in the most authentic Smriti of Arya Samaj the Manu Smriti,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 8.415 There are slaves of seven kinds, (viz.) he who is made a captive under a standard, he who serves for his daily food, he who is born in the house, he who is bought<br />
and he who is given, he who is inherited from ancestors, and he who is enslaved by way of punishment.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Upanishad that,</p>
<p>Brihadayanaka Upanishad 6.2.7 He said: &#8216;You know well that I have plenty of gold, plenty of cows, horses, <strong>slaves</strong>, attendants, and apparel; do not heap on me what I have already in plenty, in abundance, and superabundance.&#8217;</p>
<p>So it is evident that Slavery was prevalent in Vedic period and sanctioned by the Vedic texts.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>As for intercourse without marriage, Vedas strictly recommend against it. They recommend a relationship between man and woman that is based on commitments and for a purpose. Hidden relationships or goalless relationships are both rejected</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Mr Reference forgot to mention the reference, Can he cite a single reference that prohibits it? Vedas permits extra martial sex and adultery, read my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>As for incest (brother-sister or father-daughter relationship), Vedas recommend harshest punishment</p>
<p>that sets example for society. Further, wine drinking is considered a foolish act</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Where is the reference for this? I don&#8217;t think it is very difficult to mention the source for what you say, you just have to type it. Or at least give the reference wherein Ishwar prohibits incest? If there isn&#8217;t any then why defend it?</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Let us first provide meaning of Atharva Veda 20.96.15. It says: &#8220;We shall destroy the person who molests/rapes a woman or kills her children posing as her brother or protector&#8221;. This mantra justifies why punishment for rape is death sentence as per Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p>Now let us provide meaning to actual mantra being alleged to have intercourse between father and daughter. This is Rig Veda 1.164.33. The mantra explains the process of food/herb generation through rainfall. It says: Sunlight is like my father because he provides me nourishment and the earth is like my mother because she supports and feeds me. Sun and Earth face each other as if two armies stand against each other. Clouds impregnate the earth with rainfall so that food and herbs are produced that provide us nourishment. Thus this mantra describes a natural phenomenon through allegory and nowhere states that incest is recommended.</p>
<p>Please also note that &#8216;Duhita&#8217; means one obtained from churning. Thus the mantra also implies that earth is formed from a part of sun that separated out in a process similar to churning. Astro-physicists can corroborate if this process of creation of earth from sun is indeed correct or not.</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>The correct translation for this verse is,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.15 May we exterminate from hence, who in the form of brother, husband, or paramour, approaches thee, and seeks to destroy thy offspring.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="194" class="wp-image-7736" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp21.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-90-300x118.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>I have provided Arya Samaj Hindi translation also, so where does it say Ishwar destroys the person who &#8220;Rapes/Molests Women&#8221;, This verse is talking about Ishwar protecting the embryo in womb. This is clearly mentioned in Rig Veda 10.96 the entire hymn speaks about this. I wonder didn&#8217;t the writer read previous verses of Atharva Veda 20.96.15 or he deliberately distorted the meaning of this mantra to present it for his interests. Those verses will clear the doubt,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.12-13 …The malady of evil name that hath attacked thy babe and womb. That which destroys the sinking germ, the settled, moving embryo, That which would kill the babe at birth, even this will we drive far away.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="450" height="364" class="wp-image-7737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0700_testingresp22.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-91-300x243.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>As far as Rig Veda 1.164.33 is concerned, the writer has mistranslated that verse also, If Vedas really prohibit incest then why doesn&#8217;t he quote the verse? The fact is Vedas directly or indirectly promotes incest but doesn&#8217;t prohibit it. Read my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya gives the following meaning for the word Duhita,</p>
<p>&#8220;Daughter is called Duhita because she is Durhita (one who does bad) and Durehita (it is better if she stays far away). She is Dogdha (one who sucks parent&#8217;s wealth)&#8221; -Nirukt 3.4</p>
<p><strong>CLAIM:</strong></p>
<p>Allegation:</p>
<p>In the name of &#8216;beejdan&#8217; (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of the women was not safe. The so called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with other man&#8217;s wife. From &#8216;Niyog pratha&#8217; it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that women were looked upon as mere child producing machines. In The Position of women in Hindu Civilization, Dr. B. R. Ambedkar writes: &#8220;Though women is not married to man, she was considered to be a property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only son could be successor to the property.&#8221; Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says [Arya Niti Ka Bhadaphor, 5th ed., p. 14]: &#8220;No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic man could not keep even the relations brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery/adultery named &#8216;Niyog&#8217;. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognize neither their sister nor their daughter and also did not keep the relations with them in mind. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what a miserable plight of women was society in then.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>FANATIC&#8217;S</strong><br />
<strong>RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>1. Once more vague allegations and no reference. Once more my request: Cite authentic references from Vedas to claim anything for Hinduism and not some historical allegations.</p>
<p>2. Ambedkar is not an authority on Hinduism. He admits in his writings that he has no knowledge of</p>
<p>Sanskrit and has referred only to western authors in translations of Vedas.</p>
<p>3. And who is this Gajdhar Prasad Baudh? Yet another Prophet or reincarnation of some old prophet that his words are taken so seriously?</p>
<p>4. As for incest (brother-sister or father-daughter relationship), Vedas recommend harshest punishment that sets example for society. Further, wine drinking is considered a foolish act. In fact anything that dumbs mind – wine, lust or anger – is considered foolishness in Vedic custom. But may be this new Prophet has come with some new revelations! We request your new Prophet to cite specific references instead of vague allegations. (I know this statement is getting repetitious but we have no other option)</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE:</strong></p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati (Mulshankar) the founder of Arya Samaj wrote in his book</p>
<p>&#8220;Those, however, who cannot control their passions may beget children by having recourse to Niyoga.&#8221; By Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Satyarth Prakash, Ch 4, p.130, Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>He also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife and she is pregnant, he may contract Niyoga with a (widow) and beget offspring on her…&#8221; – Satyarth Prakash, Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 4, pg140 Tr. Chiranjiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>As we can see, it states that if a man (particularly Brahmin) is unable to control his lust then he can have sex with the widow in the name of Niyoga or Beejdan you can say. This guy is busy making his own sect, his beliefs contradict the teachings of his guru Mulshankar, and also he does not view scholars like Vivekananda as authoritative. Whenever such claims are made which the Veda sanctions Mr. Reference insists for references but Mr. Reference doesn&#8217;t provide the reference from Vedas where incest is prohibited. Can Mr. Reference furnish the evidence from Vedas wherein Ishwar recommends harsh punishments for incestuous acts? Vedas does not prohibit incest but it promotes incest in several verses. For more details on obscenity read to my article <a href="/index.php/2018/05/15/there-is-indeed-obscenity-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Obscenity in Vedas</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Read Part 2 of this article </strong><a href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-ii-2/" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part II</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/14/response-to-women-in-hinduismvedas-part-i/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to Women in Hinduism/Vedas Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The roots of Rape in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fornication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nirbhaya act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment for rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kancha Ilaiah Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal. Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Written by Kancha Ilaiah<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to behave in a cruel fashion with women. Family upbringing, societal conditioning, religious sagas and political animus, all construct our men and women into being what they are — men as aggressive and women as submissive. Which is why men here, in India, are different from men in other countries.<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-961"></span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Their cultural milieu is different. Their spiritual systems train them differently. It&#8217;s not that only Indian men rape and kill children aged three or five. This happens in other countries too, but they are the rarest of rare cases. Daily reports of infants being raped across the length and breadth of a country is a phenomenon unique to India, a society that&#8217;s otherwise highly conservative. Clearly, the institutional upbringing, including that in family, needs to undergo change.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Every time a gruesome rape gets reported, we all are ashamed and angry. That&#8217;s one thing; but working out ways and means to eradicate such evil is another thing. We cannot leave it entirely to the police or the judiciary to tackle such heinous acts. For, rape is also a cultural problem; and it is a more serious problem because of the extermination of the victim. We need to treat the malaise from its very roots.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We are a society that derives its sense of good and bad from our mythologies and spiritual ethics. Our gods and goddesses are not only worshipped but also adored. And it is our lifelong endeavour to emulate them. This is the cultural environment that shapes the lives of most people in India. So it&#8217;s natural that what gods do influences us much more than the moral lesson at the end. Now consider this: we have gods who, for instance, have cut the nose and ear lobes of a woman who approached them professing her love (Lakshman is depicted as having done this to Shurpanakha), and yet we adore him and see him as a symbol of loyalty, sacrifice and righteous indignation.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Lord Krishna stole the clothes of women while they were bathing in the Yamuna river. He did so to tease them and for the pleasure of watching the beauty of their naked bodies. We hang miniature paintings of the same act in our homes proudly. The young men who grow up seeing this, or listening to the story told in an amused tone are bound to not find such an act abhorrent.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We also have a god, Shiva, who insisted on entering the bathing arena of Goddess Parvati and did so by eliminating a child who was keeping guard at the open door. Lord Ganesha is said to have emerged out of such a union. Is this right or wrong? Our mythology tells us that what a husband does is right, that his will is greater than the woman&#8217;s. If a mythological hero is praised for his acts of killing, drinking and fornicating with multiple women (like Indra did with Rambha, Urvashi, Menaka, Tilottama and so on), it is glorification of such behaviour.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When such stories are a part of the mythological texts, they should, at least, be critically evaluated and given a more contemporary, political reading which is rooted in the concept of equality. Instead, the tendency is to not question what our gods did, but simply admire such acts.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Barring a few exceptions, there is no appreciation, per se, of a healthy man-woman relationship which is rooted in the concept of equality. Indian women are shown as lathangi (a person of delicate body), never strong enough to resist her dehumanisation. Though Durga and Kali are shown as strong, in real life such militancy is not seen as feminine.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Now let us turn to the political spectrum. We have had many great men — Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan etc — who got married at a young age with girls of much younger age, went abroad for higher studies, leaving their wives at home totally illiterate or semi-literate. We do not know how these men, or Gokhale and Tilak, treated their wives.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">But we know that they were all devotees of the deities mentioned above. The only man who treated his wife as a friend and educated her right from the first day of his marriage, Mahatma Jyotirao Phule, is not taught as an example to be emulated in our texts.  Somehow, in our patriarchal cultural milieu, unkind and inhuman treatment of women has never been a matter of concern. It&#8217;s considered sacrilegious, for example, to question Lord Ram for leaving his dutiful wife on the random outburst of a dhobi.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And Sita&#8217;s action, in turn, to not question, but to commit suicide, is considered the epitome of all that is pious. Even Gautam Buddha left his young wife, with an infant child. Questioning such acts has never been part of our public discourse.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Or, look at our cinemas. Ever since the industry came into being, silent or talkie, it has used woman&#8217;s body as a money-making object. The song and dance sequence that it has adopted as an art form falls into a common pattern — every hero is licensed to misuse the body of the heroine. The romance in our film industry is not romance; it is vulgarity bordering on the criminal.<br />
So is it a surprise that men of this country see it as their right to violate women in all spheres of life?<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The writer is director, Centre for the Study of Social Exclusion and Inclusive Policy, Maulana Azad National Urdu University, Hyderabad</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dowry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari The Manusmriti also known as Manav Dharam Shastra, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari<br />
The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manusm%E1%B9%9Bti" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Manusmriti<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> also known as <em>Manav Dharam Shastra</em>, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  It is presumed that the actual human author of this compilation used the eponym ‘Manu’, which has led the text to be associated by Hindus with the first human being and the first king in the Indian tradition.<span id="more-4827"></span><br />
<span id="more-1261"></span><br />
Although no details of this eponymous author’s life are known, it is likely that he belonged to a conservative Brahman class somewhere in Northern India. Hindu apologists consider the Manusmriti as the divine code of conduct and, accordingly, the status of women as depicted in the text has been interpreted as Hindu divine law.  While defending Manusmriti as divine code of conduct for all including women, apologists often quote the verse: <em>“yatr naryasto pojyantay, ramantay tatr devta <strong>[3/56]</strong></em> <em>(where women are provided place of honor, gods are pleased and reside there in that household)</em>, but they deliberately forget all those verses that are full of prejudice, hatred  and discrimination against women.<br />
Here are some of the ‘celebrated’ derogatory comments about women in the Manusmriti :<br />
1. “Swabhav ev narinam …..” – 2/213. It is the nature of women to seduce men in this world; for that reason the wise are never unguarded in the company of females.<br />
2. “Avidvam samlam………..” – 2/214. Women, true to their class character, are capable of leading astray men in this world, not only a fool but even a learned and wise man. Both become slaves of desire.<br />
3. “Matra swastra ………..” – 2/215. Wise people should avoid sitting alone with one’s mother, daughter or sister. Since carnal desire is always strong, it can lead to temptation.<br />
4. “Naudwahay……………..” – 3/8. One should not marry women who has have reddish hair, redundant  parts of the body [such as six fingers], one who is often sick, one without hair or having excessive hair and one who has red eyes.<br />
5. “Nraksh vraksh ………..” – 3/9. One should not marry women whose names are similar to constellations,  trees, rivers, those from a low caste, mountains, birds, snakes, slaves or those whose names inspires terror.<br />
6. “Yasto na bhavet ….. …..” – 3/10. Wise men should not marry women who do not have a brother and whose parents are not socially well known.<br />
7. “Uchayangh…………….” – 3/11. Wise men should marry only women who are free from bodily defects, with beautiful names, grace/gait like an elephant, moderate hair on the head and body, soft limbs and small teeth.<br />
8. “Shudr-aiv bharya………” – 3/12.Brahman men can marry Brahman, Kshatriya, Vaish and even Shudra women but Shudra men can marry only Shudra women.<br />
9. “Na Brahman kshatriya..” – 3/14. Although Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish men have been allowed inter-caste marriages, even in distress they should not marry Shudra women.<br />
10. “Heenjati striyam……..” – 3/15. When twice born [dwij=Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish] men in their folly marry low caste Shudra women, they are responsible for the degradation of their whole family. Accordingly, their children adopt all the demerits of the Shudra caste.<br />
11. “Shudram shaynam……” – 3/17. A Brahman who marries a Shudra woman, degrades himself and his whole family  ,becomes morally degenerated , loses Brahman status and his children too attain status  of shudra.<br />
12. “Daiv pitrya………………” – 3/18. The offerings made by such a person at the time of established rituals are neither accepted by God nor by the departed soul; guests also refuse to have meals with him and he is bound to go to hell after death.<br />
13. “Chandalash ……………” – 3/240. Food offered and served to Brahman after Shradh ritual should not be seen by a chandal, a pig, a cock,a dog, and a menstruating women.<br />
14. “Na ashniyat…………….” – 4/43. A Brahman, true defender of his class, should not have his meals in the company of his wife  and even avoid looking at her. Furthermore, he should not look towards her when she is having her meals or when she sneezes/yawns.<br />
15. “Na ajyanti……………….” – 4/44. A Brahman in order to preserve his energy and intellect, must not look at women who applies collyrium to her eyes, one who is massaging her nude body or one who is delivering a child.<br />
16. “Mrshyanti…………….” – 4/217. One should not accept meals from a woman who has extra marital relations; nor from a family exclusively dominated/managed by women or a family whose 10 days of impurity because of death have not passed.<br />
17. “Balya va………………….” – 5/150. A female child, young woman or old woman is not supposed to work independently even at her place of residence.<br />
18. “Balye pitorvashay…….” – 5/151. Girls are supposed to be in the custody of their father when they are children, women must be under the custody of their husband when married and under the custody of her son as widows. In no circumstances is she allowed to assert herself independently.<br />
19. “Asheela  kamvrto………” – 5/157. Men may be lacking virtue, be sexual perverts, immoral and devoid of any good qualities, and yet women must constantly worship and serve their husbands.<br />
20. “Na ast strinam………..” – 5/158. Women have no divine right to perform any religious ritual, nor make vows or observe a fast. Her only duty is to obey and please her husband and she will for that reason alone be exalted in heaven.<br />
21. “Kamam to………………” – 5/160. At her pleasure [after the death of her husband], let her emaciate her body by living only on pure flowers, roots of vegetables and fruits. She must not even mention the name of any other men after her husband has died.<br />
22. “Vyabhacharay…………” – 5/167. Any women violating duty and code of conduct towards her husband, is disgraced and becomes a patient of leprosy. After death, she enters womb of Jackal.<br />
23. “Kanyam bhajanti……..” – 8/364. In case women enjoy sex with a man from a higher caste, the act is not punishable. But on the contrary, if women enjoy sex with lower caste men, she is to be punished and kept in isolation.<br />
24. “Utmam sevmansto…….” – 8/365. In case a man from a lower caste enjoys sex with a woman from a higher caste, the person in question is to be awarded the death sentence. And if a person satisfies his carnal desire with women of his own caste, he should be asked to pay compensation to the women’s faith.<br />
25. “Ya to kanya…………….” – 8/369. In case a woman tears the membrane [hymen] of her Vagina, she shall instantly have her head shaved or two fingers cut off and made to ride on Donkey.<br />
26. “Bhartaram…………….” – 8/370. In case a women, proud of the greatness of her excellence or her relatives, violates her duty towards her husband, the King shall arrange to have her thrown before dogs at a public place.<br />
27. “Pita rakhshati……….” – 9/3. Since women are not capable of living independently, she is to be kept under the custody of her father as child, under her husband as a woman and under her son as widow.<br />
28. “Imam hi sarw………..” – 9/6. It is the duty of all husbands to exert total control over their wives. Even physically weak husbands must strive to control their wives.<br />
29. “Pati bharyam ……….” – 9/8. The husband, after the conception of his wife, becomes the embryo and is born again of her. This explains why women are called Jaya.<br />
30. “Panam durjan………” – 9/13. Consuming liquor, association with wicked persons, separation from her husband, rambling around, sleeping for unreasonable hours and dwelling -are six demerits of women.<br />
31. “Naita rupam……………” – 9/14. Such women are not loyal and have extra marital relations with men without consideration for their age.<br />
32. “Poonshchalya…………” – 9/15. Because of their passion for men, immutable temper and natural heartlessness, they are not loyal to their husbands.<br />
33. “Na asti strinam………” – 9/18. While performing namkarm and jatkarm, Vedic mantras are not to be recited by women, because women are lacking in strength and knowledge of Vedic texts. Women are impure and represent falsehood.<br />
34. “Devra…sapinda………” – 9/58. On failure to produce offspring with her husband, she may obtain offspring by cohabitation with her brother-in-law [devar] or with some other relative [sapinda] on her in-law’s side.<br />
35. “Vidwayam…………….” – 9/60. He who is appointed to cohabit with a widow shall approach her at night, be anointed  with clarified butter and silently beget one son, but by no means a second one.<br />
36. “Yatha vidy……………..” – 9/70. In accordance with established law, the sister-in-law [bhabhi] must be clad in white garments; with pure intent her brother-in-law [devar] will cohabitate with her until she conceives.<br />
37. “Ati kramay……………” – 9/77. Any women who disobey orders of her lethargic, alcoholic and diseased husband shall be deserted for three months and be deprived of her ornaments.<br />
38. “Vandyashtamay…….” – 9/80. A barren wife may be superseded in the 8<sup>th</sup> year; she whose children die may be superseded in the 10<sup>th</sup> year and she who bears only daughters may be superseded in the 11<sup>th</sup> year;  but she who is quarrelsome may be superseded without delay.<br />
39. “Trinsha……………….” – 9/93. In case of any problem in performing religious rites, males between the age of 24 and 30 should marry a female between the age of 8 and 12.<br />
40. “Yambrahmansto…….” – 9/177. In case a Brahman man marries Shudra woman, their son will be called ‘Parshav’ or ‘Shudra’ because his social existence is like a dead body.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upanishads: An analysis</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apara Vidya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chandogya Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganganath Jha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mundaka Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panditaa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polygyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prajapati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rahu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rishi Yajnavalkya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Maadhavananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Nikhilananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad In the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad. Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>In <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="229" height="356" class="wp-image-7250 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa1.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-193x300.jpeg 193w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /> the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad.</p>
<p>Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to be superior to the Vedas. This is the reason that the maximum number of quotations in their books are from the Upanishads while Vedic mantras are rarely quoted. Upanishads are considered as the primary source of Hindu theology.</p>
<p>More than 200 Upanishads are known, of which a dozen are variously referred to as the principal, (mukhya) main or old Upanishads. They are:</p>
<p>1. Isavasya 2. Aitareya 3. Chandogya 4. Kena 5. Taittiriya 6. Katha 7. Shvetashvatara 8. Brihadaranyak 9. Prasna 10. Mundak 11. Maandukya 12. Kaushtaki  Upanishad.</p>
<p><span id="more-5645"></span></p>
<p>Scholars disagree about the exact dates of the composition of the Upanishads. According to Dr. Radhakrishnan, they were composed between 800 B.C to 600 B.C.</p>
<p>Many Upanishads are collections of mutually unrelated and mutually contradictory statements. Every Upanishads is self refuting. Also, one Upanishad says one thing about a certain theme while another Upanishad says something entirely different. It appears that Upanishad writers were not intending to write a book. May be these were their personal notes which they expanded over time without any connection to earlier notes. This is the reason that many mutually contradictory schools like Advaita (Monism), Vishishtadvaita (qualified Monism) and Dvaita (Dualism) are derived from the Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>Opposition to the Vedas</strong></p>
<p>The Upanishads reject the Karmakaanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. For example, Mundaka Upanishad 1/1/5 calls the four Vedas as ‘lower knowledge’  (Apra) and says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="614" height="65" class="wp-image-7251" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-9.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa2.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“The lower knowledge (Apara) is the Rig-veda, Yajur-veda, Sama-veda, Atharva-veda, Siksha (phonetics), Kalpa (ceremonial), Vyakarana (grammar), Nirukta (etymology), Khandas (metre), Jyotisha (astronomy);”</p>
<p>Explaning the word ‘Apara’ Shankaracharya has written in his commentary on verse 4,</p>
<p><strong><em>Apara Vidya</em> is ignorance and that ought to be dispelled.</strong> When what is known is <em>Apara Vidya</em>, i.e., the subject of ignorance, nothing can be known as it is.</p>
<p>Condemning the Karma-kanda of the four Vedas, the same Upanishad says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="454" height="64" class="wp-image-7252" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-10.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa3.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“But frail, in truth, are those boats, the sacrifices (Yagyas), the eighteen (consisting of the sixteen <em>Ritviks</em>, the sacrificer and his wife), in which this lower ceremonial has been told. Fools who praise this as the highest good, are subject again and again to old age and death.”</p>
<p>(Mundaka Upanishad 1/2/7)</p>
<p>Believers in Karma-kaanda are being insulted as fools. This condemnation of ritualism continues in verses 8 and 9.</p>
<p><strong>Mythical Teachings</strong></p>
<p>In contrast to the above condemnation of Vedic rituals, other Upanishads themselves give strange unscientific rituals to obtain various blessings. For example consider the following recipes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="624" height="61" class="wp-image-7253" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-11.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa4.gif?w=860&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a fair complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study one Veda and that he should attain a full term of life, then they (husband and wife) should have rice cooked in milk and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>(Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad 6/4/14)</p>
<p>Here, the recipe given to produce a white son is white milk and white rice. Will this recipe work for an African kid? Let us not go far away. Will it work for the indigenous dark races of India? Will it make them white? Further how is this recipe supposed to make the born chlid a scholar of one Veda? Will the missionaries of Upanishads kindly explain this amazing scientific (?) verse to us?</p>
<p>Notice one more thing. Contrary to the condemnation of the Vedas by Mundaka Upanishad, this verse is giving a recipe to make the child a scholar of one Veda.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 15</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a tawny or brown complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study two Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in curds and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>This is also an amazing technique of producing colourful children. Additionally, just with a slight change of recipe the child will become a scholar of two Vedas.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 16</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a dark complexion and red eyes should be born to him</strong>, that he should study three Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in water and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Are all Trivedis and Tripathis in India born by this recipe?</p>
<p><strong>Verse 17</strong></p>
<p>After a long search I was finally able to find a recipe for producing a girl child in Hindu texts. This verse gives that recipe.</p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a daughter should be born to him</strong> who will be a scholar and attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked with sesamum and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a daughter.</p>
<p>I will not comment on this par excellence scientific (?) recipe mentioned in this verse. My primary concern here is about the word scholar (Panditaa in Sanskrit), for which we see the next topic ‘Upanishads and Women’ below.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 18</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that a son should be born to him who will be a famous scholar, frequenting assemblies and speaking delightful words, a student of all the Vedas and an enjoyer of the full term of life,<strong> he should have rice cooked with the meat of a young bull or of one more advanced in years</strong> and he and his wife should eat it with clarified butter. Then they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Since the time this recipe has been abandoned in India, true Vedic scholars are not taking birth. Hindus should start eating this diet to know the Vedas properly. Commenting on this recipe, Shankaracharya writes,</p>
<p>“The meat is restricted to that of a vigorous bull,  able to breed, or one more advanced in years.”</p>
<p>Let me share one last recipe with you.</p>
<p><strong>verse 12</strong> of the same chapter says,</p>
<p><strong>Now, if a man’s wife has a lover whom he detests</strong>, he should perform the following rite in order to cast an evil spell upon him: Let him put fire in an unbaked earthen vessel, spread stalks of reed and kusa grass inversely and offer in the sacrificial fire the reed tips, soaked in clarified butter, inversely, repeating the following mantra: “You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your prana and apana, you, (**HERE THE NAME OF THE LOVER SHOULD BE UTTERED**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your sons and cattle, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your Vedic rites and those done according to the Smritis, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your hopes and expectations, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! He whom a brahmin who knows this rite curses, departs from this world impotent and shorn of merit. <strong>Therefore let no one even joke with the wife of a Vedic scholar who knows this rite;</strong> for he who has this knowledge is a dangerous enemy.</p>
<p>I feel this is nothing but a fraudulent way of looting the innocent folk who are afraid of mantra-tantra. How will burning the fire in a vessel cause the death of someone else? And why is this formula not taught to a wife whose husband has a lover whom she detests? This clearly shows a sanction of polygamy in Hindu texts.</p>
<p><strong>Upanishads and Women</strong></p>
<p>I was initially glad to see that even a girl in Hinduism can become a scholar as per Briahadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/17 quoted above. However, when I read the oldest commentary of the leading scholar of Hinduism, Adi Shankaracharya, on this verse, I was disappointed. He writes,</p>
<p>दुहितुः पांडित्यं गृहतंत्रविषयमेव वेदे अनधिकारात</p>
<p>“The scholarship of the daughter is regarding domestic affairs only, for she is not entitled to read the Vedas.”</p>
<p><strong>Women as objects of lust</strong></p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/8/1 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="603" height="72" class="wp-image-7254" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-12.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa5.gif?w=816&amp;h=98" /></p>
<p>“Woman, O Gautama, is the fire, her sexual organ is the fuel, what invites is the smoke, the vagina is the flame, what is done inside is the embers, the pleasures are the sparks.”</p>
<p>A simlar verse is found in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/12/13.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 2/13/1-2 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="386" height="163" class="wp-image-7255" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-13.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa6.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>1. A man’s beckoning to a woman is the syllable <em>Him</em>; his gratifying her is the <em>Prastava</em>; his lying with her is the <em>Pratihara</em>; his spending time with her is the <em>Nidhana</em>; and the finishing of the sexual act is also the <em>Nidhana</em>. This is the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse.</p>
<p>2. He who thus knows the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse does not suffer from the pang of separation and procreates from every intercourse; he reaches the full length of life, lives brightly, becomes great in children and cattle, great in fame. For him the injunction is: <strong>“Do not reject a woman who comes to you seeking intercourse”</strong>.</p>
<p>This is the Upanishadic version of Kamasutra, so much that many scholars prefer not to comment on them. Scholar Ganganath Jha has translated Chandogya Upanishad into English but he has left these verses untranslated.</p>
<p><strong>Why and How woman was created?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/2-3 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="241" class="wp-image-7256" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-14.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa7.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Prajapati said to Himself: “Well, let Me make a firm basis for it (semen).” So He created woman. Having created her, He worshipped her bottom portion. Therefore one should worship the bottom portion of a woman. He (Prajapati) extended His organ that projects and with it impregnated her.”</p>
<p>Her lap is the sacrificial altar, her hair the sacrificial grass, her skin within the organ the lighted fire; the two labia of the vulva are the two stones of the soma—press. He who, knowing this, practises sexual intercourse wins as great a world as is won through the Vijapeya sacrifice; he acquires for himself the fruit of the good deeds of the woman. But he who, without knowing this, practises sexual intercourse turns over to the woman his own good deeds.</p>
<p>Let me bring to your notice that the English translation of Brihadaranyak Upanishad published by Swami Maadhavananda does not translate verses 3, 4 and 5 and even the Shankar bhashya is not translated. I have reproduced the translation of Swami Nikhilananda  which can be found here</p>
<p><a href="http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Now let me quote the Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/4-5</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="372" height="317" class="wp-image-7257" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-15.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa8.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>4) Having known this, Uddalaka the son of Aruna, Naka the son of Mudgala and Kumara—harita said: “Many mortals, brahmins only in name, perform the sexual act without knowledge of what has been said and <strong>depart from this world impotent</strong> and without merit.” Even if this much semen—of one asleep or of one awake—is spilled,</p>
<p>5) <strong>He should touch it</strong> and repeat the following mantra: “Whatever semen of mine has spilt on earth, whatever has flowed to plants, whatever to water, I reclaim it.” <strong>With these words he should take the semen with his ring finger and thumb and rub it between his breasts or eyebrows,</strong> repeating the following mantra: “Let the semen return to me, let Vigour come to me again, let glow and good fortune come to me again. May the deities who dwell in the sacrificial fire put the semen back in its proper place.”</p>
<p>Readers can themselves judge these words.</p>
<p><strong>Beat your wife?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadranyak Upanishad 6/4/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="376" height="106" class="wp-image-7258" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-16.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa9.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>If she (the wife) does not willingly yield her body to him (her husband), he should buy her with presents. If she is still unyielding, <strong>he should beat her with a stick or with his hand and overcome her</strong>, repeating the following mantra: “With power and glory I take away your glory.” Thus she becomes discredited.</p>
<p>What kind of teaching is this? These are only productions of imbalanced minds.</p>
<p>I would suggest that you read the remaining portion of the chapter (i.e. Brihad. Upanishad Part 6, Chapter 4) from the above link yourself because it is too obscene to be posted here.</p>
<p><strong>Polygyny</strong></p>
<p>Throughout the Upanishads there are evidences of polygyny being sanctioned. The Rishis of the Upanishads used to have several wives. For example, Yajnavalkya has two wives as is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/5/1.</p>
<p>अथ ह याज्ञवल्क्यस्य द्वे भार्ये बभूवतुर्मैत्रेयी च कात्यायनी च</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya had two wives: Maitreyi and Katyayani”</p>
<p><strong>Unscientific concepts</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the above mentioned mythical teachings, the Upanishads contain many factually unscientific errors.</p>
<p>1. Chandogya Upanishad 8/13/1 says</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="611" height="96" class="wp-image-7259" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa10.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>From the dark I come to the variegated; from the variegated I come to the Dark. Shaking off evil as a horse shakes dust from its hair, freeing myself from the body <strong>as the moon frees itself from the mouth of Rahu</strong>, I fulfil all ends and obtain the uncreated World of Brahman.</p>
<p>The lunar eclipse is thus thought to be the work of Rahu, an Asura (demon), who eats the moon.</p>
<p>2. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/3/2 mentions the dimensions of the place where those people go who have performed the Horse Sacrifice (Ashwamedh)? It says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="148" class="wp-image-7260" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa11.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Thirty—two times the space traversed by the sun’s chariot in a day makes this plane (loka); around it, covering twice the area, is the world (prithivi); around the world, covering twice the area, is the ocean. Now, as is the edge of a razor or the wing of a fly, so is there just that much space between the two halves of the cosmic shell. Through that opening they go out. “Fire, in the form of a falcon, delivered them to Vayu. Vayu, placing them in itself, took them where previous performers of the Horse Sacrifice were.”</p>
<p>Even a primary pass child today knows that there is no such meeting point of the sky and earth and no opening. They also know that there is no chariot pulling the Sun.</p>
<p>3. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/19 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="418" height="42" class="wp-image-7261" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa12.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“seventy two thousand (72,000) nerves called <strong>hita</strong>, which extend from the heart throughout the whole body.”</p>
<p>I would like to see the scientific confirmation of this statement. There are millions of nerves and blood vessels extending throught the body from the heart and not just 72,000. Another erroneous figure given in the Upanishads.</p>
<p>These are only few of the unscientific teachings of the ‘world renowned’ Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>The roots of caste based discrimination</strong></p>
<p>Upanishads clearly spell out that caste is based on birth due to the deeds of previous lives. This is the reason for this idea taking such root in the Hindu society that it continues to divide Indian society even today.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/10/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="99" class="wp-image-7262" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa13.gif?w=821&amp;h=134" /></p>
<p>“Those whose conduct here on earth has been good will quickly attain some good birth—<strong>birth as a brahmin, birth as a kshatriya, or birth as a vaisya</strong>. But those whose conduct here has been evil will quickly attain some evil birth—<strong>birth as a dog, birth as a pig, or birth as a chandala</strong>.”</p>
<p>On one hand Upanishads talk of one Soul permeating all; only Brahma being real and the world being an illusion, while on the other hand they sanction this cruel birth based caste system. It seems that even the Rishis bent of proving that the world is an illusion, used  to keep personal gains in mind. This idea becomes clear when we observe the lifestyle of Rishi Yajnavalkya, who in trying to prove the world to be an illusion, extracted huge fee (<em>Dakshina</em>) from others. When he was unable to respond to some questions he used to threaten the questioner with dire consequences, which turned the questioner silent out of fear.</p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/1/1-2 says,</p>
<p>“Janaka, Emperor of Videha, performed a sacrifice in which gifts were freely distributed among the priests. Brahmin scholars from the countries of Kuru and Panchala were assembled there. Emperor Tanaka of Videha wished to know which of these brahmins was the most erudite Vedic scholar. So he confined a <strong>thousand cows in a pen and fastened on the horns of each ten padas of gold</strong>.</p>
<p>He said to them: “Venerable brahmins, let him among you who is the best Vedic scholar drive these cows home.” None of the brahmins dared. <strong>Then Yajnavalkya said to one of his pupils: “Dear Samsrava, drive these cows home.”</strong> He drove them away. The brahmins were furious and said: “How does he dare to call himself the best Vedic scholar among us?” Now among them there was Asvala, the hotri priest of Emperor Janaka of Videha. He asked Yajnavalkya: “Are you indeed the best Vedic scholar among us, O Yajnavalkya?” He replied: “I bow to the best Vedic scholar, but I just wish to have these cows.” Thereupon the hotri Asvala determined to question him.”</p>
<p>The Yajnavalkya started answering the questions. Interestingly, Shankaracharya mentions in the preface of his commentary of Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/27,</p>
<p>“One should take away catlle of Vedic scholars who do not truly know Brahma.”</p>
<p>Similarly, when Balaki proposes to speak about God to Ajatashatru, King of Kashi, Ajatasatru offers him, for this proposal, a thousand cows as his fee. (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/1)</p>
<p>When King Janaka asked Rishi Yajnavalkya a questions about Brahma, he immediately offered the fee of thousand cows with a bull as large as an elephant (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/1/4).</p>
<p>All of these examples prove that imparting the mythical and highly philosophized knowledge of Brahma was a good profession to earn money. However, if someone used to ask difficult questions about God refuting the Rishis conjectures, they were threatened and silenced, as they feared loosing their profession. Two glaring examples can be given.</p>
<p>Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, questioned Yajnavalkya. When she cornered Yajnavalkya with her final quetion, all she got was a threat. This is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/6/1</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya ,” said she, “if all this is pervaded by water, by what, is water pervaded?” “By air, O Gargi.” “By what,is air pervaded?” “By the sky, O Gargi.” “By what is the sky pervaded?” “By the world of the gandharvas, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gandharvas pervaded?” “By the world of the sun, O Gargi. “By what is the world of the sun pervaded?” “By the world of the moon, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the moon pervaded?” “By the world of the stars, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the stars pervaded?” “By the world of the gods, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gods pervaded?” “By the world of Indra, O Gargi. “By what is the world of Indra pervaded?” “By the World of Virij, O Gargi. “By what is the World of Virij pervaded?” “By the World of Hiranyagarbha, O Gargi.” “By what is the World of Hiranyagarbha pervaded?” <strong>“Do not, O Gargi,” said he, “question too much, lest your head should fall off. You are questioning too much about a deity about whom we should not ask too much. Do not ask too much, O Gargi.” Thereupon Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, kept silent.</strong></p>
<p>The freedom of thought of Gargi was curbed by Yajnavalkya by threatening her of death. Is this not a ploy to hide the truth? Thinking people can judge for themselves.</p>
<p>Gargi was fortunate to not die but Shakalya was not so fortunate after disputing with Yajnavalkya. That is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/26-27.</p>
<p>“Now I ask you about that Person who is to be known only from the Upanishads, who definitely projects those beings and again withdraws them into Himself and who is at the same time transcendental. “If you cannot clearly explain Him to me, your head shall fall off?’ Sakalya did not know Him; his head fell off; and robbers snatched away his bones, mistaking them for something else.</p>
<p>Then Yajnavalkya said: “Venerable brahmins, whosoever among you wishes to question me may now do so, or all of you may. Or whosoever among you desires it, I shall question him, or I shall question all of you. But the brahmins did not dare.”</p>
<p><strong>The ultimate effect of Upanishads</strong></p>
<p>The above mentioned curbs on free thinking are nothing compared to that effect where all distinction of good and evil is erased from the Knower of Brahma (Brahmagyani).  Kaushitaki Upanishad 3/1/ records Lord Indra as saying the following,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="656" height="66" class="wp-image-7263" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa14.gif?w=834&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>“He who knows me thus, <strong>by no deed of his is his life harmed, not by the murder of his mother, not by the murder of his father, not by theft, not by the killing of a Brahman. If he is going to commit a sin, the bloom does not depart from his face!</strong>”</p>
<p>The theoretical commandment is exemplified by Lord Indra himself who brags about his murders in this very verse.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="123" class="wp-image-7264" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa15.gif?w=734&amp;h=149" /></p>
<p>“I slew the three-headed son of Tvashtri; I delivered the Arunmukhas, the devotees, to the wolves (salavrika); breaking many treaties, I killed the people of Prahlada in heaven, the people of Puloma in the sky, the people of Kalakanga on earth. And not one hair of me was harmed there.”</p>
<p>Thus the people who allow Upanishads to influence them are least bothered about right and wrong. That is why M. N Roy, in his book <em>Fascism; its philosophy, profession and practice</em> traced the influence of Upanishads on Fascism through people like Arthur Schopenhauer and Friedrich Nietzsche. Roy was the first to point out the fact that the roots of fascism lie in the ancient Brahminical religion, and he showed how European, particularly German, fascist philosophers borrowed concepts from Brahminical scholars and scriptures, concepts such as the Aryan race theory, the supremacy of the strong over the weak, the concept of the tyrannical superman and so on. In fact, M.N. Roy issued a’ sharp warning to Indians not to fall prey to Hindu revivalism because he saw that it was nothing but fascism in a different garb. You can see that for yourself. What was the destruction of the Babri Masjid and the mass slaughter of the Muslims but naked fascism? Goebbels, Hitler’s chief propagandist, wrote in one of his books, ‘The state must have the power to break its own laws’. That is precisely what happened on 6 December, 1992. The state was actively involved in the breaking of the mosque. Goebbels also remarked, ‘Repeat a lie- a hundred times and it becomes a truth’. You can see this Chanakyan tactic in all the false Hindutva propaganda about Muslims, Christians and Communists. We all know what horrendous and baseless things they are writing about Muslims in the school textbooks now. They have attributed all the ills of India to the Muslims, painting all of them as immoral.</p>
<p>Hindutva fascism has to be fought at the ideological level, by a superior ideology based on rationalism, and not just on the political plane. Islam is the alternative and hope for those weak humans in India who are discriminated by the cruel divisions of Caste System whose roots lie in the ancient Hindu texts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Talibanism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 18:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atrocities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destruction of temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghaznavi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains and buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persecution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: MilliGazette ] &#160; Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan? &#160; &#160; Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: <a href="http://www.milligazette.com/Archives/15042001/Art06.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MilliGazette<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="color:#0070c0;">Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan?<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5643"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and Osmania universities, and Dr MS Jayaprakash, professor of history at Kollam &#8211; throw some deep insights into the dark history of India when Buddhism was systematically eliminated by Brahminical forces who control Hinduism, then and now.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Says Jayaprakash: &#8216;The ruthless demolition of Buddha statues by Taliban has courted severe criticism from different quarters of the world. Surprisingly, the BJP-led Indian Government, supported by all Hindutva forces, also condemned the Taliban action. It is a paradox that the forerunners of the present Hindutva forces in India had wantonly destroyed not only Buddhist statues but also killed Buddhists in India. Therefore, any impartial student of history would unequivocally say that these Hindutva forces have no moral right to criticize Taliban now.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He elaborates: &#8216;Hundreds of Buddhist statues, stupas and viharas have been destroyed in India between 830 and 966 AD in the name of Hindu revivalism. Both literary and archaeological sources within and outside India speak volumes about the havoc done to Buddhism by Hindu fanatics. Spiritual leaders like Sankaracharya and many Hindu kings and rulers took pride in demolishing Buddhist images aiming at the total eradication of Buddhist culture. Today, their descendants destroyed the Babri Masjid and also published the list of mosques to be targeted in future. It is with this sin of pride that they presently condemn Taliban.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin elaborates the selfish compulsions of Brahminism to wipe-out Buddhism: &#8216;Buddhism tried to create a dynamic society in ancient India. Jainism also contributed its share. As Buddhism spread, iron ploughs and implement were used for development of agriculture. As a result, new areas were cultivated and agricultural productivity increased, apart from developing trade centres and road links. Subsistence-level economy changed to a surplus economy with grain storage facilities, exchange of goods, trade and development of bureaucratic administration. This also created social change &#8211; from elans consisting several families to tribes consisting several elans of similar socio-economic conditions. The emphasis of Brahmins, on the other hand, was for receiving and giving alms and not on production of goods. Those who give and receive alms were close to Gods and those who produce were considered as inferior. According to Manusmriti, a Sudra should not have wealth of his own. In case he has any, a Brahmin as his master can take it over without any hesitation. &#8216;Rigveda&#8217; goes a step further to kill those who do not give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the Brahmins. In other words, someone has to produce goods so that others can give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the recipient Brahmins. It was against this system of &#8216;downgrading those who produce&#8217; that Buddhism came into being.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Recalls Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;The Hindu ruler Pushyamitra Sunga had destroyed 84,000 Buddhist stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. This was followed by the demolition of Buddhist centres in Magadha. Thousands of Buddhist saints were killed mercilessly. King Jalaluka destroyed the Buddha viharas within his jurisdiction on the ground that chanting of hymns by Buddhists disturbed his sleep! In Kashmir, King Kinnara demolished thousands of viharas and captured the Buddhist villages to please Brahmins. A large number of Buddha viharas were usurped by Brahmins and converted into Hindu temples where entry of &#8216;untouchables&#8217; was prohibited. Notably, Buddhist places were regularized as Hindu temples by writing Puranas, which were invented myths or pseudo history. The important temples at Tirupathi, Aihole, Undavalli, Ellora, Bengal, Puri, Badarinath, Mathura, Ayodhya, Sringeri, Bodhigaya, Saranath, Delhi, Nalanda, Gudimallam, Nagarjunakonda, Srisailam and Sabarimala are some of the striking examples of Brahminical usurpation of Buddhist centres.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Detailing the divergence in both orientation and essence between Buddhism and Hinduism, Prof. Bahauddin says: &#8216;Equality, compassion, non-violence, utilization of human abilities for general welfare, etc. were the cardinal principles of Buddhism. According to &#8216;Sathpatha Brahmanam (22-6, 3-4-14), on the other hand, the whole universe is controlled by God, God is controlled by Mantram and Mantram is with Brahmins and, therefore, Brahmins are God (on earth). They used Mantram and Sapam to instil fear in the people to obey them, while Buddhism encouraged people to observe visible facts, to apply reason to get out of fear. Buddhism also encouraged people to do good things, besides guiding Kings to look after the people&#8217;s welfare. Buddhism considers the general welfare of the people, while Brahminism considers that the whole world was created for them all along. And, there is bound to be conflict between these two opposite ways of thinking.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr Jayaprakash, Sakaracharya had played &#8216;a demon&#8217;s role&#8217; in destruction of Buddhist statues and monuments at Nagarjunakonda (in present-day Andhra Pradesh). &#8216;A. N. Longhurst, who conducted excavations at Nagarjunakonda, had recorded this in his invaluable book, Memoirs of the Archaeological Survey of India No. 54, The Buddhist Antiquities of Nagarjunakonda (Delhi, 1938, p. 6). The ruthless manner in which all the buildings at Nagarjunakonda have been destroyed is simply appalling and cannot represent the work of treasure-seekers alone since so many pillars, statues, and sculptures have been wantonly smashed to pieces. Local tradition relates that the great Hindu philosopher and teacher, Sankaracharya, came to Nagarjunakonda with a host of followers and destroyed the Buddhist monuments. The cultivated lands on which ruined buildings stand represent a religious grant made to Sankaracharya.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Quoting Dr. B. R. Ambedkar, Prof. Bahauddin says that the conflict against Brahmin supremacy had, in fact, started before Buddhist period, between Vasishta Muni, a Brahmin, and Viswamitra, a non-Brahmin. &#8216;The dispute was about the learning of &#8216;Vedas&#8217;, the right to conduct religious ceremony, to receive gifts, and to perform coronation of King. Vasishta Muni insisted that these were the exclusive privileges of Brahmins, while Viswamitra was opposed to such exclusive rights. This dispute lasted for long period, and even Kings joined in it (Writings and Speeches of Dr. Ambedkar, vol. 7, p. 148-155. It was won by Brahmins.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin lists the different stages of Brahmin hostility against Buddhism: &#8216;1) 483-273 BC: The period after Buddha&#8217;s death upto Ashoka&#8217;s rule when attempts were made to include Brahminical ideas in Buddhist ideology. 2) 273-200 BC: When Buddhism spread all over India and became a world religion. 3) 200 BC-500 AD: The period when all possible efforts were made to disintegrate Buddhism from within by adulterating Buddhist teachings with Brahminical ideas and also through physical annihilation from outside. As a result, Buddhism divided itself into 18 sects, of which Hinayana and Mahayana were prominent ones. 4) 500-700 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in North India and efforts began to drive out Buddhism and Jainism from South India. 5) 700-1100 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in South India and, with added vigour, it moved again to North India to obtain complete supremacy over Buddhism and Jainism. 6) 1100-1400 AD: Buddhism and Jainism were destroyed from the remaining Southern States of Karnataka and Kerala and, thus, total supremacy of Brahminism all over India was achieved.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;Within Kerala, Sankaracharya and his close associate Kumarila Bhatta, an avowed foe of Buddhism, organized a religious crusade against Buddhists. A vivid description of Sankaracharya&#8217;s pleasure of seeing people of non-Brahminic faith being burnt to death is available in &#8216;Sankara Digvijaya&#8217;. Kumarila instigated King Suddhanvan of Ujjain to exterminate Buddhists. The &#8216;Mricchakatika&#8217; of Sudraka describes how the King&#8217;s brother-in-law in Ujjain inhumanly tortured the Buddhist monks, by using them as bullocks by inserting a string through their nose and yoking them to the cart! The &#8216;Keralolpathi&#8217; documents the extermination of Buddhism from Kerala by Kumarila. About the activities of Sankaracharya, even Vivekananda had observed: &#8216;And, such was the heart of Sankara that he burnt to death lots of Buddhist monks by defeating them in argument. What can you call such action on Sankara&#8217;s part except fanaticism&#8217; (Complete works of Swami Vivekananda, Vol. III, p. 118, Calcutta, 1997).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, there are hundreds of places in Kerala having names &#8216;palli&#8217; either affixed or suffixed with them. &#8216;Karunagapalli, Karthikapalli, Pallickal, Pallippuram, Edappally, etc. are some examples of these places. The term &#8216;palli&#8217; means a Buddha vihara. Notably, Kerala had 1200 years of Buddhist tradition. Earlier, the schools in Malayalam were called as &#8216;Ezhuthupalli&#8217; or &#8216;Pallikoodam&#8217;. It is also worth noticing that the Christians and Muslims in Kerala use the term &#8216;palli&#8217; to denote their church and mosque alike. These &#8216;pallies&#8217; or viharas had been ruthlessly demolished by the Hindu forces under the leadership of Sankaracharya and Kumarila. They could exterminate 1200 years of Buddhist tradition and converted Kerala into a Brahminical state based on the &#8216;Chaturvarna&#8217; system. Original inhabitants of Kerala, like the Ezhavas, Pulayas, etc., were crushed under the weight of casteism. Many a viharas was transformed into temples and majority of people were prevented from entering temples under the pretext of caste pollution. It can also be noted that the name &#8216;Kerala&#8217; is the Sanskritised Aryan version of the Dravidian and Buddhist term &#8216;Cherala&#8217;. The Parasurama legend is nothing but an invented myth for regularizing the Brahminical &#8216;Kerala&#8217; hiding its glorious Buddhist traditions.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jainism, too, met with the same fate in South India. Prof. Bahauddin elaborates: &#8216;Very little information is available about growth of Jainism in South India during 300-400 AD. The Jain book, &#8216;Digambara Darsana&#8217;, recounts the starting of a Sangham at Madurai in 470 AD and Jainism became widespread and strong during 500-600 AD (Kumaraswamy Iyengar, &#8216;Studies in South Indian Jainism&#8217;, p. 51-58)….. The Jains used to instal the images of their saints in their religious places, a practice which was followed by Brahmins. Hindu temples appeared all over Tamilnadu probably after converting the Jain religious places. The idols of 63 Brahmin Sanyasis, who led destruction of Jainism, still adorn the walls of some Hindu temples in Tamilnadu. The remains of destroyed Jain idols, their abandoned religious and living places are scattered all over Tamilnadu to narrate their story. Frescos depicting the kings of Jains could be seen on the walls near the Golden Tank at Madurai Meenakshi Temple where, of the total 12 annual festivals, five depict the killing of Jains according to Kumaraswamy Iyengar (p. 78-79).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, a number of Buddha statues have been discovered at places like Ambalapuzha, Karunagapalli, Pallickal, Bharanikkavu, Mavelikara and Neelamperur in Kerala. &#8216;They are either in the form of smashed pieces or thrown away from viharas. Lord Ayyappa of Sabarimala and Lord Padmanabha at Thiruvananthapuram are the proxy images of Buddha being worshipped as Vishnu. Hundreds of Buddhists were killed on the banks of Aluva river. The term &#8216;Aluva&#8217; was derived from &#8216;Alawai&#8217; which means &#8216;Trisul&#8217;, a weapon used by Hindu fanatics to stab Buddhists. Similarly, on the banks of the Vaigai river in Tamilnadu, thousands of Buddhists were killed by the Vaishnava Saint, Sambanthar. Thevaram, a Tamil book, documents this brutal extermination of Buddhism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls the strong reasons to believe that a large section of Jains had embraced Islam: &#8216;The spread of Islam in Tamilnadu can be considered in three or four stages. Islam spread in Kerala and Tamilnadu when Jainism was under pressure (650-750 AD). The new religion was received without resistance…. Since Islam considers every human being with equality Jainism and Buddhism had no conflict with it. When Muhammad ibn Al-Qasim attacked Sindh, the Buddhists supported him because they were facing annihilation at that time. A similar situation was prevailing in South India during 650-750 AD…. Muslims in Tamilnadu are called Anchuvanthar, Labba (teacher), Rauthar, Marakar (sailor) or Jonakan (Yavankan). The Anchuvanam is the guild of traders and groups of artisans. The Muslim mohallas of &#8216;Anchuvan Vamsagar&#8217;, &#8216;Anchuvanathar&#8217;, etc. are scattered all over Tamilnadu and seem to be the en bloc conversion of Jain guilds engaged in different activities, especially weaving. Those who ran away from Tamilnadu settled down in Sravanabalagola and Gomatheswaram in Karnataka. And, those who could not leave due to their economic interests converted to Islam. If we analyze the body structure, food, language, dress, ornaments, customs and habits of Anchuvanthar, it could be see that those are a continuation of Jain way of living and customs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Till recently, the weavers in such Muslim mohallas will not eat at noon or night, and take only one meal before dusk. This was a continuation of Jain habits. There is a separate place in such villages called &#8216;Odukkam&#8217; where Jain Munist used to sit in prayer. On the last Wednesday of the month called &#8216;Odukkathae&#8217; Wednesday, the Muslims gather together to sing religious songs, which is also a Jain tradition. When religious functions like Maulood, Rathif, etc. are organized in the house, a white cloth with lotus symbol on it called &#8216;Mekett&#8217; is tied, which resembles the &#8216;Asmanagiri&#8217; of the Jains…. The architecture of Muslim stone mosques are completely of Jain architecture. The pillars of earlier mosques have practically no difference with the Jain temple pillars. The close relationship between traders and weavers had probably cemented by conversion to Islam. During 950-1200 AD, there were large number of Sufis, Fakirs, wandering poets, singing minstrels, etc. among Muslims all over Tamilnadu. Nadirshah with 500 disciples settled down in &#8216;Trichinopoly&#8217; during 1000 AD. Aliyar Shah and his disciples made Madurai as their centre. Baba Fakhruddin travelled all over Tamilnadu. Nagur became another Sufi centre. The Muslim religious literature of Tamilnadu of that period was least different from those created by Jains and Hindus during the &#8216;Bhakti&#8217; movement.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recounts the spread of Jainism and Buddhism in Kerala, thus: &#8216;Jainism spread in North Kerala around 200 BC. The Jain architectural remains in Canara and Malabar are not available anywhere else in South of Nepal. While Jainism entered North Kerala via Mangalore, Salem, Coimbatore and Wayanad, it entered Southern Kerala from Tirunelveli, Kanyakumari, Nagercoil, Chitharal, etc. The hill near Anamala, which was an important Jain centre, is still called &#8216;Jain Durgam&#8217;. The close-by Kurumala was also a Jain centre. From Anamala through Munnar, Devikulam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor, etc. they reached Neryamangalam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor and other places. The &#8216;Kallil Kshetram&#8217; in Perumbavoor is an important Jain monument as also the &#8216;Jainmedu&#8217; in Vadakethara village of Palakkad district. Kerala&#8217;s cave temples at Chitharal, Kallil, Trikur, Erunilamkode (Thrissur district) and Thiruveghapuram (Palakkad district) were constructed during the period of Jain King Mahendra Verman-I (610-640 AD). Temple records of Rameswaram, Sucheendram, Poothadi (Wayanad), Keenalur (Kozhicode) , etc. show that they were part of &#8216;Kunavai Koottam&#8217; during 10-11th centuries. &#8216;Koottam&#8217; is the place of living for Jain Sanyasis. Temple records show that all these present-day Hindu temples were Jain religious places till 11th century. Place names with Kallu, Poothan, Aathan, Kotha, Palli, Ambalam, etc. were all Jain centres. Spread all over Kerala, names of these places show that Buddhism and Jainism were widespread. The famous Kalpathi in Palakkad district was a Buddhist-Jain centre. The &#8216;Ratholsavam&#8217; there is akin to the &#8216;Kettukazhcha&#8217; of Buddhists. The present Bhagavati temples were also Jain temples. The group, &#8216;Adikal&#8217;, had a prominent position among Jains who became &#8216;Pisharadi&#8217; after absorption of Jainism in Hinduism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&#8216;Similarly, the Buddhist stoopa at Kodungallore, located in Methala village South-East of Thrikanamathilakam, is an important Buddhist ruin in Kerala…. Mahismathi was the capital of Chera King Satyaputran, which shows the relationship of Chera country (Kerala) with Buddhism. There is a reference in &#8216;Manimekhala&#8217; about a Buddhist Chaityam in Kerala. While Vadakkumnatha Temple at Thrissur and Kurumba Temple at Kodungallore were Buddhist temples, Buddha statues were discovered from Kollam, Alappuzha, Mavelikara, Pallikkal, Karumadi and other places…. Treating mental patients in Thiruvadi temple and leprosy patients in Thakazhi temple shows that they were Buddhist temples since these kind of humanitarian services were not rendered out from Hindu temples…. By 900 AD Buddhism and Jainism were almost wiped out from Tamilnadu. The second settlement wave of Brahmins in Kerala during 900 AD was with Pandyan Kings&#8217; support. Karnataka and Kerala were the only two states where Buddhism and Jainism were still surviving and the second immigration of Brahmins might have been for driving out these two religions from the remaining places.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls: &#8216;Very few people know that Buddhism and Jainism were the prominent religions of Kerala till 1200 AD. I was also under the impression that Hinduism was in Kerala from the very beginning. When facts were pieced together, a different picture emerged. Only from the end of 1800 AD the evidence became available about Buddha, Buddhism, Ashoka, etc. That fact itself is a pathetic story….&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash in conclusion: &#8216;This is what really happened in India, the land of Buddha. But our so-called eminent historians, except a few, are bent upon eclipsing the cruelty done to Buddhists in India. These pseudo historians have succeeded in creating an impression that India is a land of righteousness and toleration. The entire world has been duped by them. The deed on the part of Taliban can be justified on the ground that Islam does not permit idols. But one has to note that Islam does not allow the demolition of other people&#8217;s religious centres and images. Whatever may be the argument for and against Taliban action, the Hindu atrocities on Buddhism in India has no parallel in the entire world history of religious struggle. Let the world know the cruel and crooked face of the &#8216;Indian vulture without culture&#8217;!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and the Vedic Dharma</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma. In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color:#333333;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p style="color:#333333;">The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. Nowhere is a prayer or charm recited to be granted a daughter. For exmaple,</span></span></p>
<p><span id="more-848"></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">1. O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. <strong style="font-style:inherit;">Vouchsafe to her ten sons</strong>, and make her husband the eleventh man. [Rigved Mandal 10, Sookt 85, Mantra 45]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_rig_10_85_45.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">2. This is thy Soma draught, O bright Âditya: take delight therein. To this mine utterance, O ye men, give credence, what good the man and wife obtain by praying: <strong style="font-style:inherit;">A manly son is born and gathers riches</strong>, and thrives for ever sinless in the dwelling. [Yajurved Adhyay 8, Mantra 5]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_yajur_8_5.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">3. Fathers, bestow on me a babe, <strong style="font-style:inherit;">a boy </strong>enwreathed with lotuses, so that there may be here a man. [Yajurved Adhyay 2, Mantra 33]</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/son_yajur_2_33.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">All prayers for being granted a boy and none for a girl.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Speaking of marriage Swami Dayanad Saraswati says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“In Sanskrit a daughter is called </span><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">duhitri</span></em><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> (from Du – distant, Hit – good), because the marriage of a girl to a man who comes from a distant country or distant part of the same country is productive of good.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">“If the bride’s people do not live very far from her husband’s home, there is a possibility of her parents becoming poor, as whenever she visits her parents, they will have to give her something or other by the way of a present.” </em>[Satyarth Prakash Chapter 4, The advantages and disadvantages of distant and near marriages, Page 85]</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Rigved Mandal 8, Sookt 33, Mantra 17 says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline,</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Her intellect hath little weight</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">.”</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_brain_rig_8_33_17.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">At another place, it is written:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">There cannot be any friendship with a woman. Her heart is</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> like</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> that of a hyena.</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Rig Veda, 10/95/15</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_hayenas_rig_10_95_15.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda says:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Women are without energy. They should not get a share in the property. Even to the wicked, they speak in a feeble manner. </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">  vi. 5. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">8</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">2</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A wife has no claim to property of her husband. The wealth that she earns is not her but her husband’s. [Manu Smriti  Chapter 8, Sholka 416]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A girl without a brother is called <em style="font-weight:inherit;">Abhratr</em> and it is prohibited to marry such a girl.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The Atharva Ved says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Those maidens there, the veins, who run their course in robes of ruddy hue, must now stand quiet, reft of power, like sisters who are brotherless. [Atharva Ved Kaand 1, Sookt 17, Mantra 1]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/brotherless_ath_1_17_1.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Explaining this word, Nirukt, which is the oldest Indian treatise on Etymology, </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Philology and Semantics, says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">They stand like women who have no brother, and whose path is  obstructed with regard to procreation and the offering of the sacrificial cake. With these words the simile implies the prohibition of marrying a brotherless maiden.[Nirukt 3:4]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Shatpath Brahman, preachings of the ‘Yajur Veda’ says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He (the Adhvaryu) then mixes it with the residue (of ghee) which is left in the prakaranî spoon. Now other libations he completes by mixing, but this one he diminishes; for ghee is a thunderbolt, and by that thunderbolt, the ghee, the gods smote the wives and unmanned them, and thus smitten and unmanned they neither owned any self nor <strong style="font-style:inherit;">did they own any heritage</strong>. And in like manner does he now, by that thunderbolt, the ghee, smite the wives and unman them; and thus smitten and unmanned, they neither own any self<strong style="font-style:inherit;"> nor do they own any heritage</strong>. [Shatpath Brahman; Kaand 4, Adhyay 4, Brahaman 2, Kaandika 13]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The same Shatpath Brahman says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“And whilst not coming into contact with Sûdras and remains of food; for this Gharma is he that shines yonder, and he is excellence, truth, and light; <strong style="font-style:inherit;">but woman, the Sûdra, the dog, and the black bird (the crow), are untruth: he should not look at these, lest he should mingle excellence and sin, light and darkness, truth and untruth</strong>. [Kaand 14, Adhyay1, Brahman1, Kaandika 31]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">A woman can never ask for divorce, even if her husband ill treats her. Manu says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife. [Manu Smriti 5:154]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Swami Dayanand Saraswati is teaching us in Satyarth Prakash how to choose a perfect wife. Listen to him.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let a man never marry one who is pale and anaemic, nor one who is altogether a bigger and stronger person than himself or has a redundant member, nor one who is an invalid, nor one either with no hair or too much hair or too much hair, nor one immoderately talkative, nor one with red eyes.” MANU 3: 8.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Nor one with the name of star,of a tree,or of a river, or of a mountain.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">So Hindu men should not marry women who are named Ashvini, Ganga, Saraswati, Himalaya, etc.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let him choose for his wife, a girl who has a graceful figure without any deformity, who has a pretty name, who walks gracefully like a swan or an elephant, who has fine hair and lovely teeth, and whose body is exquisitely soft.” MANU 3: 10</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Satyarth Prakash, Pages 89, 90]</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He forgets to teach how to choose a husband.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The ‘Vedas,’ also talk about ‘Niyog’ the custom of childless widow or woman having sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. In simple words ‘Niyog’ means sending a married woman or widow to a particular man for sexual intercourse so that she gets a son. Indication of this custom is available in Rig Veda.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> In ‘Aadiparva’ of ‘Mahabharata’ (chapters 95 and 103), it is mentioned that Satyawati had appointed her son to bestow sons to the queens of Vichitrvirya, the younger brother of Bhishma, and as a result of which Dhartrashtra and Pandu were born. Pandu himself had asked his queen, Kunti, to have sexual intercourse with a Brahmin to get a son (Aadi Parva,’ chapters 120 to 123).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">It has been said in ‘Aadi Parva’ (chapters 64 and 104), that when Parshu Ram started killing the Kshatriyas, thousands of female Kshatriyas started going to Brahmins to get sons. Similar references are found at other places in ‘Mahabharata’ also. With regard to ‘Niyog’, there are detailed discussions at a number of places in other religious books.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In Nirkut, the meaning of ‘dewar’ that is, husband’s younger brother, has been given as ‘Duvitya Var’ that is, the second husband (Nirukt 3:15).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">An ancient commentator of ‘Manu Smriti’ (Manu’s Code), Meghatithi has clearly accepted the existence of ‘Niyog‘ (quoted from ‘Dharam Shastra Ka Itihas’, by Bharatratan Mahamahopdhyay, Dr P.V. Kane, Part I, page 341).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the last century, Swami Dayanand Saraswati had claimed to have written a commentary free from defects in the interpretation, of the ancient commentators on the ‘Vedas.’ Dayanand had not only accepted the prevalence of ‘Niyog’ but also on the basic of ‘smritis’ (codes of traditional Hindu laws), discussed ‘Niyog’ in great detail in the language of the ‘Veda mantras’ (Vedic hymns). According to him there was a law that a woman or a man could have sexual intercourse with eleven persons. If no child was born from the one, then a woman could go to another. If even then she was unable to beget a child, then she could go to the third and so on till she had intercourse with eleven men (Dayanand’s commentary on Rig Veda, 10/85/45).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Woman was sometimes even forced to have sexual intercourse with men in the custom of ‘Niyog’. ‘Devtas, Rishis, Munis’ and ‘Brahmins’ used to participate in ‘Niyog’ (see ‘Mahabharata Aadi Parv; chapters 64,95,103, 104).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Chastity of woman was not safe</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the name of ‘beejdan’ (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of women was not safe. The so-called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with another man’s wife. From ‘Niyog pratha’, it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that the women were looked upon as mere child-producing machines.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In ‘The Position of Women in Hindu Civilization’, Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar writes: “<em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though woman was married to a man, she was considered to be the property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only the son could be the successor to property.”</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says: <em style="font-weight:inherit;">“No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic men could not keep even the relations between brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery / adultery named ‘Niyog’. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognise neither sister nor daughter and also they did not keep in mind their relations with them. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what the miserable plight of women was in the society then. (Refer ‘Arya Niti Ka Bhandaphor’, 5th edition page 14).</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Till such a time as these teachings have an overwhelming influence, the improvement in the position and status of the women is next to impossible.</span></span></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
