<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>vishnu &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/vishnu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The roots of Rape in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fornication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nirbhaya act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment for rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kancha Ilaiah Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal. Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Written by Kancha Ilaiah<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to behave in a cruel fashion with women. Family upbringing, societal conditioning, religious sagas and political animus, all construct our men and women into being what they are — men as aggressive and women as submissive. Which is why men here, in India, are different from men in other countries.<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-961"></span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Their cultural milieu is different. Their spiritual systems train them differently. It&#8217;s not that only Indian men rape and kill children aged three or five. This happens in other countries too, but they are the rarest of rare cases. Daily reports of infants being raped across the length and breadth of a country is a phenomenon unique to India, a society that&#8217;s otherwise highly conservative. Clearly, the institutional upbringing, including that in family, needs to undergo change.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Every time a gruesome rape gets reported, we all are ashamed and angry. That&#8217;s one thing; but working out ways and means to eradicate such evil is another thing. We cannot leave it entirely to the police or the judiciary to tackle such heinous acts. For, rape is also a cultural problem; and it is a more serious problem because of the extermination of the victim. We need to treat the malaise from its very roots.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We are a society that derives its sense of good and bad from our mythologies and spiritual ethics. Our gods and goddesses are not only worshipped but also adored. And it is our lifelong endeavour to emulate them. This is the cultural environment that shapes the lives of most people in India. So it&#8217;s natural that what gods do influences us much more than the moral lesson at the end. Now consider this: we have gods who, for instance, have cut the nose and ear lobes of a woman who approached them professing her love (Lakshman is depicted as having done this to Shurpanakha), and yet we adore him and see him as a symbol of loyalty, sacrifice and righteous indignation.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Lord Krishna stole the clothes of women while they were bathing in the Yamuna river. He did so to tease them and for the pleasure of watching the beauty of their naked bodies. We hang miniature paintings of the same act in our homes proudly. The young men who grow up seeing this, or listening to the story told in an amused tone are bound to not find such an act abhorrent.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We also have a god, Shiva, who insisted on entering the bathing arena of Goddess Parvati and did so by eliminating a child who was keeping guard at the open door. Lord Ganesha is said to have emerged out of such a union. Is this right or wrong? Our mythology tells us that what a husband does is right, that his will is greater than the woman&#8217;s. If a mythological hero is praised for his acts of killing, drinking and fornicating with multiple women (like Indra did with Rambha, Urvashi, Menaka, Tilottama and so on), it is glorification of such behaviour.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When such stories are a part of the mythological texts, they should, at least, be critically evaluated and given a more contemporary, political reading which is rooted in the concept of equality. Instead, the tendency is to not question what our gods did, but simply admire such acts.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Barring a few exceptions, there is no appreciation, per se, of a healthy man-woman relationship which is rooted in the concept of equality. Indian women are shown as lathangi (a person of delicate body), never strong enough to resist her dehumanisation. Though Durga and Kali are shown as strong, in real life such militancy is not seen as feminine.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Now let us turn to the political spectrum. We have had many great men — Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan etc — who got married at a young age with girls of much younger age, went abroad for higher studies, leaving their wives at home totally illiterate or semi-literate. We do not know how these men, or Gokhale and Tilak, treated their wives.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">But we know that they were all devotees of the deities mentioned above. The only man who treated his wife as a friend and educated her right from the first day of his marriage, Mahatma Jyotirao Phule, is not taught as an example to be emulated in our texts.  Somehow, in our patriarchal cultural milieu, unkind and inhuman treatment of women has never been a matter of concern. It&#8217;s considered sacrilegious, for example, to question Lord Ram for leaving his dutiful wife on the random outburst of a dhobi.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And Sita&#8217;s action, in turn, to not question, but to commit suicide, is considered the epitome of all that is pious. Even Gautam Buddha left his young wife, with an infant child. Questioning such acts has never been part of our public discourse.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Or, look at our cinemas. Ever since the industry came into being, silent or talkie, it has used woman&#8217;s body as a money-making object. The song and dance sequence that it has adopted as an art form falls into a common pattern — every hero is licensed to misuse the body of the heroine. The romance in our film industry is not romance; it is vulgarity bordering on the criminal.<br />
So is it a surprise that men of this country see it as their right to violate women in all spheres of life?<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The writer is director, Centre for the Study of Social Exclusion and Inclusive Policy, Maulana Azad National Urdu University, Hyderabad</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Hinduism?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[33 gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrisitanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[definition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism oldest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindusim vs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat rai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polytheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shashtra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind? At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Written by Ibn Muhammad<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is a hodge-podge or conglomeration of many mutually conflicting religions, and is not the child, so to say, of any one father. Those who practice it differ very much from one another in their faith and practice. Hinduism includes in it Vedism, Brahmanism, Sivaism, Vishnuism, Polytheism, Pantheism, Idolatory in is greatest forms, Tree-Worship, Serpent-Worship, Demon-Worship and so on.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span id="more-5644"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is not easy therefore to give a definition of Hinduism,  &#8220;Hinduism and its gods,&#8221; says Sir Alfred Lyall, &#8220;are a troubled sea, without shore or visible horizon, driven to and fro by the winds of boundless credulity and grotesque invention. A tangled jungle of disorderly superstitions, ghosts and demons, demi-gods and deified saints, household gods, tribe gods, local gods, universal gods, with their countless shrines and temples, and din of their disordent rites, deities who abhor a fly&#8217;s death, those who delight still in human victims, and those who would not either sacrifice or make offerings, such religious chaos&#8221;. <strong><sup>[1]</sup></strong><br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Authoritative Books not one but many</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A further difficulty regarding Hinduism lies in the fact that all its professors have no common sacred Book or Books to depend upon for their doctrines. Some refer to Vedas as the basis of their faith. Others rest their faith on the Shrutis, a term which includes not only the four Vedas but their Brahmanas and Upanishads as well. The Mahabharata styles itself as the fifth Veda, containing the quintessense of all the rest. Other Hindus agains follow the teachings of the Puranas. The present day educated Hindus are mainly depending upon the Bhagavad Gita, a philosophical treatise, for their guidance in matters of faith. We shall therefore briefly inquire into the contents of all these books to see what they teach about God and the way in which man should worship Him.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Religion of the Vedas</h3>
<h4>(a) Nature Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Vedism, or the Religion of the Vedas, teaches the worship of the deified forces or phenomenon of Nature, such as Fire, the Sun, Wnd and Rain. Here is the opening verse of the Rigveda, the oldest Veda, of which the others are mere repetitions and borrowing:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निमीळे पुरोहितं यज्ञस्य देवं रत्वीजम |  होतारं रत्नधातमम || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;I Laud Agni, the great high priest, god, minister of sacrifice, the herald, lavishest of wealth.&#8221; [Rigveda Mandal 1: Sookt 1: Mantra 1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The whole of the Veda goes on in this strain throughout in the hymns collected for different purposes. The contrast between the opening  verse of the Rigveda which teaches Polytheism, and that of the Jewish Bible and of the Holy Qur&#8217;an which teach Monotheism, cannot fail to be noted even by the most superficial reader. Thus the Jewish Pentateuch begins,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>בראשית ברא אלהים את השמים ואת הארץ׃</strong><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.&#8221; [Genesis 1:1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Holy Qur&#8217;an strikes the key note of its whole teaching in a still more profound manner, unparalleled in other religions:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"> &#8211; </span><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">الْحَمْدُ للَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَـلَمِينَ &#8211; الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ &#8211; مَـلِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. All Praise is due to Allah, Lord of the Worlds, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. Master of the Day of Judgement.&#8221;[Surah Al-Fatiha 1:1-4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Thus Vedism teaches the worship of the powers of Nature.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(b) Polytheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That it teaches polytheism is also evident from the expression used in the same verse and in all the succeeding verses as well:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निः पूर्वेभिर्र्षिभिरीड्यो नूतनैरुत | स देवानेह वक्षति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;He (Agni) shall bring hitherward the gods.&#8221; [Rigveda 1:1:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्ने यं यज्ञमध्वरं विश्वतः परिभूरसि | स इद्देवेषु गछति ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Verily goes to the gods.&#8221;[verse 4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निर्होता कविक्रतुः सत्यश्चित्रश्रवस्तमः | देवो देवेभिरा गमत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;May Agni, priest, the god, come hither with the gods.&#8221; [verse 5]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The number of gods in Hindu Pantheon is given as 33 in one place (Rigveda 1:34:11), which says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>आ नासत्या तरिभिर एकादशैर इह देवेभिर यातम मधुपेयम अश्विना | परायुस तारिष्टं नी रपांसि मर्क्षतं सेधतं दवेषो भवतं सचाभुवा ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Come, O Nasatyas, with the thrice-eleven Gods; come, O ye Asvins, to the drinking of the meath. Make long our days of life, and wipe out all our sins: ward off our enemies; be with us evermore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Similarly it is mentioned in Rigveda 8:30:2,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>इति सतुतासो असथा रिशादसो ये सथ तरयश्च तरिंशच्च | मनोर्देवा यज्ञियासः || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Thus be ye lauded, ye destroyers of the foe, ye Three-and-Thirty Deities, The Gods of man, the Holy Ones.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Rigeveda 10:52:6 the number is 3,339. It says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>तरीणि शता तरी सहस्राण्यग्निं तरिंशच्च देवा नवचासपर्यन | औक्षन घर्तैरस्त्र्णन बर्हिरस्मा आदिद्धोतारं नयसादयन्त || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Deities three thousand, three hundred and thirty-nine, have served and honoured Agni, Strewn sacred grass, anointed him with butter, and seated him as Priest, the Gods&#8217; Invoker.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Later Hinduism has gone still further by saying that there are no less than 33 crores of them.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(c) Pantheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Why not then say that everything is God, and God is everything? The Purusha Sukta (Rigveda 10:90) which every orthodox Brahmin is expected even now to recite daily in his prayers shows that Pantheism is also taught in the later portions of the Vedas:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>पुरुष एवेदं सर्वं यद भूतं यच्च भव्यम | उताम्र्तत्वस्येशानो यदन्नेनातिरोहति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;This Purusha(i.e. Brahma or God) is all that yet has been and all that is to be.&#8221; [verse 2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The caste system which has proved the curse of India is likewise taught in the same hymn:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>बराह्मणो.अस्य मुखमासीद बाहू राजन्यः कर्तः | ऊरूतदस्य यद वैश्यः पद्भ्यां शूद्रो अजायत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Brahmana was his (Purusha&#8217;s) mouth. Of both his arms was the Kshatriya made. His thighs became the Vaishya. From his feet the Sudra produced.&#8221;[verse 12]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Religion of the Upanishads</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Upanishads reject the Karma, Kanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. Hence they consist of speculations about the individual souls (atma) and the Supreme soul (Param-atma), and about the relationship subsisting between them, their aim being to get rid of man&#8217;s earthly existence by absorption of the individual soul into the World Soul through correct or true knowledge. They teach that the Universe or Nature (Prakriti) is unreal or <em>Maaya</em>, that is to say, it does not really exist but it only an illusion of the mind. What really exists in the Supreme Soul or Brahman, and the individual souls are all emanations from Him and identical with Him. Only they do not know it, as Brahman has invested Himself/Itself with the <em>Maaya</em>, and they also are under the influence of the same mystic power. The individual souls can be disillusioned only by means of Correct knowledge, and as soon as this consummation is reached, they know themselves to be Brahman, and get absorbed into Him. The famous formula referring to this theory is <strong><em>&#8216;Tat tvam asi&#8217;</em></strong> </span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">तत् त्वम् असि </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;That art thou&#8217;, whoever knows this &#8216;becomes the All&#8217;. Even the gods are not able to prevent him from becoming it. For he becomes their self. <em>[Brihadaranyak Upanishad 1:4:6]</em><br />
</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This theory is known as the Vedanta, the essence of the teaching of the Vedas, and has taken an immense hold on the minds of the people and lent a deeper colour to all subsequent literature. A Christian missionary asked a Brahmin, &#8220;Who and where is Brahman?&#8221; &#8220;He is talking to you,&#8221; was the prompt reply.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A Vedantist once began to dilate upon the truth of his belief in the presence of a king and vehemently maintained that the whole world was <em>Mithya</em> or unreal, imaginary: whereupon an elephant was ordered to be brought quite near to him and the man fled in terror. &#8220;Why do you run away for your life? The elephant is <em>Mithya</em>&#8221; said the king. But the Vedantist proved himself equal to the occasion and without a moment&#8217;s hesistation replied that the running away too was <em>Mithya</em>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Such is the fool&#8217;s paradise in which most of the misguided Hindus live. The expression that is often heard on their lips, and which has unfortunately recently been made famous by Dr. Zakir Naik through his televised public talks:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><em>EKAM EVA ADVITIYAM</em><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;One only without a second&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It does not mean that they believe in the &#8216;Only One True God&#8217; but it is the Vedantic or Pantheistic formula which asserts that the only real existence of the World Soul and the identity of the individual souls within it, totally denying the existence of the phenomenal world.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Puranas</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The characteristic of popular Hinduism of today is the belief in Divine incarnations, idolatory and caste. Popular Hinduism believes in the doctrine of Trimurti or Hindu Trinity as Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, in their characteristic of the Creator, Preserver and Destroyer of the Universe.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Vishnu Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The distinct feature of Vishnu worship is the incarnation of God. When wickedness in the world increases Vishnu is said to take upon himself the form of an animal or man in order to be able to protect the good and to punish the bad. The principle incarnations He is said to have so far assumed are those of (1) a fish, (2) a tortoise, (3) a Boar, (4) a man-lion (5) a Dwarf, (6) a Brahmin hero called Parasu Ram, (7) a Kshatriya Prince, the hero of Ramayana, (8) a shepherd Prince Krishna and (9) a Kshatriya heretic, Buddha.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Krishna declares:<br />
</span></h4>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;On an occasion of marriage, or of enjoying a woman, or when life is in danger, or when one&#8217;s entire property is about to be taken away, or for the sake of a Brahmin, falsehood may be uttered. These five kinds of falsehood have been declared to be sinless. On these occasions falsehood would become truth and truth would become falsehood.&#8221; [Mahabharata Book 8; Karna Parva; Section 69]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Cow Worship</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is natural for Indians to set a high value upon the cow on account of its utility, but the worship the Hindus pay to it is irrational and absurd to a degree. It is considered to be the most sacred of all animals. Every part of its body is considered to be inhabited by some deity or other. Even its excreta are considered to be most sacred. Its urine is looked upon as the best of all holy waters; a sin destroying liquid which sanctifies everything it touches, while nothing purifies like cow-dung. The ashes of its dung sprinkled over a sinner are able to convert him into a saint.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Veneration of Cow in Hindu Culture</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Present day Hindu culture is pivoted solely on the cow. Its material and spiritual concepts are both engulfed in cow worship. Such an animal worship is known as zoolatry. This is a vestide of animistic cultures among whom the worship of monkeys, sheep, elephants, cows and even snakes was prevalent. Animal worship culminated in the taking of human beings for gods so that the silhouettes were stamped on the coins and painted on the flags, and upon their honour depended the glory and honour of their realms.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Among cultivators cow worship is not a strange thing. In many countries, notably, India, Iran and Egypt, it was prevalent. Among Hindus veneration of the cow is referred to in the Vedas as Puranas and in Hindu Jurisprudence and folklore. In the Vedas several verses refer to saluting and prostrating before the cow as the following sections illustrate:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Prajapati and Parameshthin are the two horns, Indra is the head, Agni the forehead, Yama the joint of the neck. King Soma is the brain, Sky is the upper jaw, Earth is the lower jaw&#8230; All worlds and all the gods are as the cow from head to foot.&#8221; [Atharvaved Kaand 9: Sookt 7]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;You are being created and have been created for salutations and prostrations. Salutations and prostration to you, O image of God, to your hair, to your hooves.&#8221; [Atharva 10:10]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Curiously enough, the Vedic Rishis likened the chanting of their mantras (hymn) to the lowing of the cows:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अभि विप्रा अनूषत गावो वत्सं न मातरः | इन्द्रं सोमस्य पीतये || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;As the cows moo in the presence of their calves so do Brahmins recite their mantras while drinking the soma juice in the presence of Indra devta.&#8221; [Rigveda 9:12:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In old Vedic timesthe pious people picked out the grain from the cow-dung, and then ate it. They also squeezed out its water and drank it (Mahabharata). Its urine was considered a source of redemption of sins and a means of cow-dung bathed with water extracted thus. Krishna Ji revered the bull by stroking its back before mounting it. In short, in Hindu religion the cow in venerated to an extent which gods and godesses and even God Himself does not merit.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Cow-Worship and the humiliation of Man</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is to be noted that the sacredness of the cow as compared with the scant regard for human life has come to this that Swami Dayanand Saraswati in accordance with the Vedas, opines that the blood of thousands or hundreds of thousands of humans, may be shed to please these animals; (See his translation of Yajurveda 33:14 and Rigveda 1:121:10)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Vedic times, there lived an untouchable people in a village named Kikat, in todays Bihar. The used to rear cattle. Obviously to the Aryans this was a crime. So they invoked their god Indra to wage war against them and loot their cows.<br />
</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"></span></p>
<p id="VJgEpTj"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="620" height="145" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7245 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"> </span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;O Indra, what do the cows make for you among the Kikatas. They neither yield milk for your offerings, nor do they warm the vessel of libation. Bring to us these cows, bring to us also the wealth of Pramagand (their King). O Brave one, grant us the possessions of the people of low status.&#8221; [Rigveda 3:53:14]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">On the basis of this clear prnouncement, non-Aryans and untouchables have no right to keep cows. Aryans and Brahmins whenever they wish can kill them and appropriate their possessions. Hindu culture thus becomes the culture of the progress, civilization and welfare of the Aryan people alone.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Status of the Cow</h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The fact remains that Hindu culture is based on the cow. Actually it is cow-worship as may be inferred from the discussion so far. As the Noble Qur&#8217;an states,<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;And their hearts absorbed (the worship of) the calf because of their disbelief.&#8221; [Surah Baqarah 2:93]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The cow is also called mother and this is a relic of the age of ignorance. In primitive times when the mother of a young child died, the child too would die of malnutrition after two or three days. The father did not know how to save the child&#8217;s life as a substitute for the mother&#8217;s milk was not known. By chance, some wise person thought of the idea of giving goat&#8217;s milk to the child. As the goat was easier to control and milk than the cow, goat&#8217;s milk was used to save the infant&#8217;s life. Later on the cow was tamed for this purpose. From then on the polytheists began to call the cow &#8216;mata&#8217; i.e. mother. But other animals as well, such as goats, sheep, camels, supply milk as substitute for mother&#8217;s milk; yet they are never called &#8216;mother&#8217;. Strangely enough, in this age of science when so many baby-foods have been invented, none of these is called &#8216;mother&#8217;, yet wealthy and educated Hindus still apply this epithet to the cow alone.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The nation which cannot differentiate between a cow&#8217;s tail and a man&#8217;s head, lives in an extreme abyss of culture. The cow is at the utmost an animal, while even the most degraded man, being still a human being, is yet far superior to a cow.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Gita</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Since Mahabharata fails to serve as a handy and useful book of the essence of Hinduism, the present day educated Hindus are adopting the Bhagvat Gita as their guide.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Like all the other scriptures this famous poem too fails to teach True Religion to mankind. It is a highly Philosophic poem just as ill-suited to teach Religion as Berkley&#8217;s <em>Principle of Human Knowledge </em>or Milton&#8217;s <em>Paradise Lost</em> can be. The principle of its composition is Eclecticism and tries to combine Sankhya, Yoga, and Vedanta teaching into one whole to support the Vaishnava theory of Krishna&#8217;s deification.But is does promote ideas like Polytheism and Caste. Krishna claims to be the author of the caste system in India:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The four Castes were created by me according to the appointment of qualities and works.&#8221; [Gita 4:13]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Gita does not insist on the worship of the One and Only True God but promotes belief in polytheism:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Those who worship gods go to the gods&#8221; [9:25]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Worship the gods thereby; The gods shall yield thee grace.&#8221; [3:3]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That there are inconsistencies in the Bhagvad Gita is admitted today even by Hindu scholars. For example at Chapter 9, stanza 29 Krishna declares that &#8216;none is hateful to me, none dear.&#8217; And yet the remarkable verses at the close of Chapter 12 contradict it, &#8216;Linked by no ties to earth, steadfast in Me, That man I love&#8217;. At Gita Chapter 5, stanza 15 it is said, that &#8216;the Lord receives the sin and merit of none.&#8217; Yet at Chapter 5, stanza 29, and again at Chapter 9, stanza 24, Krishna calls himself &#8216;the Lord and enjoyer&#8217; of all sacrifices and penances. How, it may well be asked, can the Supreme Being &#8216;enjoy&#8217; that which he does not even &#8216;receive&#8217;?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The doctrine of transmigration is the basis from which the argument of Bhagvad Gita takes its start. Matter and spirit are without beginning (13:20). God (Krishna-Vishnu) is eternal, almighty, unborn, without beginning, the great Lord of the World (10:3). He is different not only from the fleeting world, but also from the changeless and indestructible energy of all beings. Vishnu is born from age to age (4:6-8). Krishna-Vishnu is wholly distinct from Brahma and Brahman is distinctly a lower deity than Krishna (11:15,37). In 12:1-7, the two classes, those who believe in a personal God Krishna-Vishnu, i.e. theists, and those who believe in Brahma ,i.e. pantheists are contrasted, and preference is given to former. In other words, final bliss is difficult of attainment for those who follow the Vedas and seek the heaven of Brahma. All external observances and duties prescribed by the Vedas are held to be mischievous and thrown overboard (7:20; 18:34,66). The Vedas and the works enjoined by them cannot win one the vision of the Divine (11:48,53). What a contempt is expressed for the Vedas in the following words: &#8220;Steady understanding does not belong to those, whose minds are drawn by that flowery talk (i.e. Vedas) which is full of ordinances of specific acts for the attainment of pleasures and power, and which promises birth as the fruit of acts- that flowery talk which those unwise ones utter, who are enamoure of Vedic words, who say there is nothing else, who are full of desires, an whose goal is heaven. The Vedas merely relate to the effects of the three qualities; do you, O Arjuna! rise above those effects of the three qualities.&#8221; (2:42-45). Thus the Vedas are being spoken of in very disparaging terms and the followers of Krishna were inimical to the Vedas.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This was in brief about Hinduism and in our future articles all the topics discussed here would be dealt with in detail separately.<br />
</span></p>
<p><img alt="" /></p>
<h5>REFERENCES</h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>[1] </strong><em>Asiatic Studies</em>, Vol 1, pp 2, 3<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vedic Paradise: An Overview</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-an-overview-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 08:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[72 hoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism paradise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swarga loka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virgins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-an-overview-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The concept of Paradise or a similar concept is found in almost all religious scriptures. Arya Samaj/agniveer rejects this reality, and hence we need to scrutinize it in detail. They claim that the difficulties and happiness of this worldly life are the NARK (Hell) and SWARG (Paradise) respectively. They claim that &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-an-overview-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Paradise: An Overview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>The concept of Paradise or a similar concept is found in almost all religious scriptures. Arya Samaj/agniveer rejects this reality, and hence we need to scrutinize it in detail. They claim that the difficulties and happiness of this worldly life are the NARK (Hell) and SWARG (Paradise) respectively. They claim that these are only states and not actual places. This claim is not only against the spiritual intuition of man, but also opposes the Vedas. Following exposition clearly proves this.</p>
<p><span id="more-1108"></span></p>
<p>In the Vedas, Paraside is mentioned by the names स्वर्ग (Swarga), द्यो (dyo), नाक (Naaka),सुकृतस्य (Sukratasya), etc. These words have always been used in combination with the Sanskrit word लोके(loke) which means ‘a place’, ‘a region’, ‘a world’, all Locative cases. This proves that the word Swarga in the Vedas does not refer to any condition that affects an individual, but it is a distinct place.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Vedic Paradise is not on this earth</strong></p>
<p>According to the Vedas Paradise is a place where only joy is found and misery is absent. This place is always mentioned by words which indicate that it is far from us; while as the present life is always mentioned by the words which indicate its nearness. If Swarga was only a state or feeling which one experiences in this world, it is illogical to speak of it as though it is found elsewhere. For example see the following mantras:</p>
<p><strong>7 O Pavarnana, place me in that deathless, undecaying world, wherein the light of heaven is set, and everlasting lustre shines. Flow, Indu, flow for Indra’s sake.</strong></p>
<p><strong>8 Make me immortal in that realm where dwells the King, Vivasvat’s Son, where is the secret shrine of heaven, where are those waters young and fresh. Flow, Indu, flow for Indra’s sake.</strong></p>
<p><strong>9 Make me immortal in that realm where they move even as they list, in the third sphere of inmost heaven where lucid worlds are full of light. Flow, Indu, flow for Indra’s sake.</strong></p>
<p><strong>10 Make me immortal in that realm of eager wish and strong desire, the region of the radiant Moon, where food and full delight are found. Flow, Indu, flow for Indra’s sake:</strong></p>
<p><strong>11 Make me immortal in that realm where happiness and transports, where Joys and felicities combine, and longing wishes are fulfilled. Flow, Indu, flow for Indra’s sake.</strong></p>
<p><strong>            ( Rig Veda – Mandal  9; Sookt 113, Mantras 7-11)</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="689" height="697" class="wp-image-7592" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi2.jpg?w=689&amp;h=698" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.jpeg 689w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7-297x300.jpeg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 689px) 100vw, 689px" /></p>
<p>These references amply prove that Paradise is not in this world but it is a distinct place which we can only inherit after death. The mantras quoted above show that</p>
<p>1)    There is no death in Paradise</p>
<p>2)    It is eternal</p>
<p>3)    It is resplendent with eternal light</p>
<p>4)    That world is under King Vivasvat’s Son i.e. Yama</p>
<p>5)    It has fresh water</p>
<p>6)    It is the third region</p>
<p>7)    Food is abundant there</p>
<p>8)    It is the place of the Sun</p>
<p>9)    It is a place where all desires are fulfilled</p>
<p><strong>Where is this Paradise?</strong></p>
<p>Having established that Vedic Paradise is not on this earth but is a distinct world altogether, we will now see where that Paradise is located. In several Vedic mantras, Paradise has been identified as the third region, the other 2 being the earth and space. Thus it is written in Rig Ved</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="576" height="128" class="wp-image-7593" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi3.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17.png 576w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17-300x67.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /></p>
<p>“In the <strong>third region</strong> which distils a thousand streams, may the Exhaustless Ones descend with procreant power.” [Rig Veda – Mandal 9; Sookt 74; Mantra 6]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="570" height="108" class="wp-image-7594" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi4.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18.png 570w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /></p>
<p>“Whether, O Indra and Agni, you be dwelling in highest Paradise, in central region, or on earth, come hither, from wherever you may be and drink libations of the flowing Soma.” [Rig Veda- Mandal 1; Sookt 108; Mantra 10]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="106" class="wp-image-7595" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi5.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19.png 567w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" /></p>
<p>“In the <strong>third heaven</strong> above us stands the Asvattha tree, the seat of gods. There the gods sought the Kushtha Plant, embodiment of endless life.” [Atharva Ved Kaand 5; Sookt 4; Mantra 3]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="566" height="108" class="wp-image-7596" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi6.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20.png 566w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 566px) 100vw, 566px" /></p>
<p>“May we be free in this world and that yonder, in the <strong>third world</strong> may we be unindebted. May we, debt-free, abide in all the pathways, in all the worlds which Gods and Fathers visit.” [Atharva Ved Kaand 6; Sookt 117; Mantra 3]
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="570" height="130" class="wp-image-7597" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi7.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21.png 570w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21-300x68.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /></p>
<p>“Dwelling with zeal I mount in spirit after the lofty sacrifice as it departs. Agni may we, beyond decay, invited, in the <strong>third heaven</strong>, feast and enjoy the banquet.” [Atharva Ved Kaand 6; Sookt 122; Mantra 4]
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="106" class="wp-image-7598" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi8.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>“From the back of the earth, I have ascended to the mid space. From the mid space, I have ascended to the heaven. From the top of the heaven, the sorrow less world, I have reached the world of light.”[Atharva Veda Kand 4; Sookt 14; Mantra 3]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is evident from all the above references that the Paradise promised in the Vedas is neither a condition nor or this earth. Rather, it is the third region above the earth and space, according to the sequence given in these mantras. Vedas speak of this Paradise being the third region in numerous other mantras, but I only gave few samples. These mantras also prove that real joy and happiness is found only there.</p>
<p><strong>How far is the Vedic Paradise?</strong></p>
<p>Most religions which speak of Paradise do not raise this question nor are required to answer it. It seems that Vedic Dharm is perhaps the only religion which addresses this question uniquely. Thus it is said,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="564" height="146" class="wp-image-7599" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-23.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi9.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-23.png 564w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-23-300x78.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 564px) 100vw, 564px" /></p>
<p>“This gold-hued Hansa’s wings, soaring to heaven, spread over a thousand days’ continued journey, supporting all the Gods upon his bosom; he goes his way beholding every creature.” [Atharva Ved Kaand 13; Sookt 2; Mantra 38]
<p>It is mentioned in Aitareya Brahman,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="194" height="26" class="wp-image-7600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-24.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi10.png?w=625" /></p>
<p>“For the heavenly world is at a distance of about thousand days’ travelling on a horseback (ashveen)” [Aitareya Brahman- Panicka 2: Paragraph 17; words in braces mine]
<p>The ancient Indian Sanskrit Grammarian, Panini writes</p>
<p>“One ashveen is the distance travelled over or traversed by a horse in one day” [Ashtadhyayi- Book 5; Chapter 2; Sootra 19]
<p>From these mantras we come to know that according to the Vedas the distance travelled by a horse in thousand days is the distance of Vedic Swarg from this earth. In other words, the distance of Vedic Paradise from the earth is about hundred thousand miles!!</p>
<p><strong>Who inherits Vedic Paradise and How?</strong></p>
<p>So far the previous mantras also imply that Vedic Paradise is not a Karma Jeevan (world for performing deeds) but a Bhog Jeevan(reaping the fruits of one’s deeds). To know more about this, it is good enough to take a look at more Vedic Mantras.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="577" height="181" class="wp-image-7601" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-25.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi11.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-25.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-25-300x94.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></p>
<p>“Joy have you found, and left ill-will behind you: you have attained the happy world of virtue.” [Atharva Ved Kaand 2; Sookt 10; Mantra 7]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="572" height="122" class="wp-image-7602" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-26.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi12.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-26.png 572w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-26-300x64.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 572px) 100vw, 572px" /></p>
<p>“May we, fame-seekers, reach the world of virtue by service of the Gharma and through fervour, whereby the Gods went up to heaven, the centre of life eternal, having left the body.” [Atharva Ved 4:11:6]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="576" height="128" class="wp-image-7603" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-27.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi13.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-27.png 576w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-27-300x67.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px" /></p>
<p>“With milk and butter I anoint the mighty, celestial Goat, strong-winged, and full of juices. Through him will we attain the world of virtue, ascending to the loftiest cope, to heaven.” [Atharva Ved 4:14:6]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="577" height="276" class="wp-image-7604" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-28.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi14.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-28.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-28-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></p>
<p>“Strongest is this, performed, of sacrifices: he has reached heaven who has prepared Vishtāri. [Atharva Ved 4:34:5]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="569" height="269" class="wp-image-7605" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-29.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi15.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-29.png 569w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-29-300x142.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 569px) 100vw, 569px" /></p>
<p>“High up in heaven abide the Guerdon-givers: they who give steeds dwell with the Sun forever. They who give gold are blest with life eternal. They who give robes prolong their lives, O Soma.” [Rig Veda – 10:107:2]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="107" class="wp-image-7606" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-30.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi16.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-30.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-30-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>“The Goat Panchaudana, when cooked, transports, repelling Nirriti, to the world of Svarga. By him may we win worlds which Sūrya brightens.” [Atharva Ved 9:5:18]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="131" class="wp-image-7607" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-31.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi17.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-31.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-31-300x69.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>“…This wealth I place among the Brāhmans, making a path that leads to heaven among the Fathers.” [Atharva Ved 11:1:28]
<p>To sum up, according to most mantras in Atharva Ved, feeding the Brahmins with milk and rice (Kheer), offering goats, gold, and otherDakshina earns one Paradise. Displeasing a Brahmin gives you a one way ticket to Hell. In the Rigveda, often we find ways to earn Paradise by praying to the gods and as per Yajurveda  Paradise is earned by animal sacrifice.</p>
<p>Of course, good deeds are also said to earn one Paradise as per the Vedas and other scriptures. Bad deeds earn one a place in Hell. The Judgement in the life hereafter based on the weight of good and bad deeds is mentioned in Shatpath Brahman as follows:</p>
<p>“Now, as to that balance, the right (south) edge of the Vedi. Whatever good deed man does that is inside the Vedi; and whatever evil deed he does that is outside the Vedi. Let him therefore sit down, touching the right edge of the Vedi; for, indeed, they place him on the balance in yonder world; and whichever of the two will rise, that he will follow, whether it be the good or the evil. And, verily, whosoever knows this, mounts the balance even in this world, and escapes being placed on the balance in yonder world; for his good deed rises, and not his evil deed.” [Shatpath Brahman- Kaand 11; Adhyay 2; Brahman 7; Kaandika 33]
<p>In common Hindu parlance it is called Dharm Tula and in Islamic terminology as Meezanul Amaal.</p>
<p><strong>Is Vedic Paradise physical or spiritual?</strong></p>
<p>After presenting so many references regarding the world of Swarga, it was not necessary to again bring up this topic, because all the previous mantras abundantly prove that Vedic Paradise is not spiritual but a physical dwelling. However, the following mantras throw more light on Vedic Paradise:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="130" class="wp-image-7608" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-32.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi18.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-32.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-32-300x68.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>“If Agni Jātavedas, as he bore you hence to the Fathers’ world, had left one single limb of your bodies, here do I restore it. Fathers, rejoice in heaven with all your members!” [Atharva Veda- Kaand18; Sookt 4; Mantra 64]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="216" class="wp-image-7609" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-33.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi19.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-33.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-33-300x113.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>“…The three-and-thirty Deities attend them. As such, conduct us to the world of Svarga. Unto the world of Svarga shalt thou lead us: there may we dwell beside our wife and children…” [Atharva Ved 12:3:16,17]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="570" height="128" class="wp-image-7610" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-34.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/072614_0803_vedicparadi20.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-34.png 570w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-34-300x67.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /></p>
<p>“There where our virtuous friends, who left behind them their bodily infirmities, are happy, free from distortion of the limbs and lameness, may we behold, in heaven, our sons and parents.” [Atharva Ved 6:120:3]
<p>All these mantras convincingly prove that Vedic Paradise is physical and material, where people will get material blessings. In my next article, Vedic Paradise: The Inside Story, we will take a look at the inner scene of the Vedic Paradise. All the mantras that I have produced till now, refute the strange, anti-Vedic view of Arya Samaj/agniveer.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-an-overview-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Paradise: An Overview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 18:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadiths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niyog pratha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed &#160; This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts . Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &#38; Agniveer. Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Arial;">Written by Neer Mohammed<br />
</span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts .</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5641"></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &amp; Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see whether Agniveer will quit Vedic Dharm or not?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In his present article on women, Agniveer makes so many bogus claims. In this series of articles we are going to analyze them one by one.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his recent article on women in Hinduism he makes these claims on Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1. Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">3. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span>. People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations. But neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4. On contrary, many a prophets of Christianity and Islam got children from slave-girls <span style="text-decoration:underline;">but never made them their wives!</span> Prophet Abraham is supposed to have even attempted to abandon his slave-girl to death after having child from her. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria. God only knows the veracity of these stories and support for sex-slavery in Bible and Quran. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">5. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But as far as Vedas are concerned, any relation apart from one single wife/husband is clearly considered to be cause of miseries.&#8221;</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">6. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling. However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">7. Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>Before analyzing these claims about Niyog in detail, let us see what Swami Dayanand had to say about Niyog.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>ALL THE POINTS TAKEN HERE ARE FROM SATYARTHA PRAKASH TRANSLATED  BY Shri Dr. Chrianjiva Gharadwaya.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 129</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1.Re-marriage is <span style="text-decoration:underline;">absolutely prohibited in the case of a twice born man or woman (i.e., one belonging to a Brahman, Kshatriya or Vaishya Class</span> . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. The following are the principal evils of remarriage:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">a.Diminution of love between the husband and the wife, since either of them can desert the other whenever he or she so desires, and marry another person.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">b.On the death of one party, the other will take away the property of his or her deceased consort when he or she marries again. This will give rise to family disputes. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">c.If a widow re marries, many a noble family will be blotted out of existence, and its property destroyed (by constant alienation).</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">d.Re-marriage involves loss of true conjugal love and infraction of duty towards the departed husband or wife. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 130</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> 3.Q. ~ If one of the parties dies leaving no male issue, even then the family line will become extinct. Besides, if re-marriage be not allowed, the widows and widowers will resort to adultery and fornication, procure abortion, and will commit wicked deeds of a kindred nature. For these reasons re-marriage is desirable. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ No. If the widows and widowers desire to practice Brahmacharya, no such evil consequences will accrue. Again, if the widow or widower adopts a boy of her and his Class, the family line will be continued and there will be no danger of adultery being restored to. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Those, however, who cannot control their passions may beget children by having recourse to Niyoga. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>So lets us see what the niyoga is</em> [writer]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4.Q. ~ What are the differences between re-marriage and Niyoga?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ 1.After marriage the bride leaves her paternal roof, lives with her husband, and her relations with her relations with her father&#8217;s family cease to be very close; on the contrary. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The widow (in case she contracts Niyoga) continues to live in her deceased husband&#8217;s house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2.The children begotten of marriage inherit the property of their mother&#8217;s husband, whereas, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">offspring begotten of Niyoga on a widow are not regarded as children of the begetter and consequently they don&#8217;t take his surname, nor can they be claimed by him. They are spoken fo as the children of their mother&#8217;s deceased husband, take his surname, inherit his property and live in his house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">3.Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations (after the stipulated period). </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">4.The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>5,.The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>PAGE 131</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ Do the same laws apply to Niyoga and marriage, or are they different in each case?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ They are little different. A few differences have already been enumerated, and here are some more:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>A married couple can produce children up to the limit of ten, while that connected by Niyoga cannot produce more than two or four.A married couple always lives together but not that connected by Niyoga..</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Let the widow rear the children for two or three years and hand them to her husband by Niyoga, in case it has been entered into for his behalf. In this way a widow can give birth to two children for herself and two for each of the four husbands by Niyoga. Similarly a widower can beget two children for himself and two for each of the four wives by Niyoga. Thus ten children in all can be produced by means of Niyoga. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">This is what the Veda declares:-&#8220;O thou who art fit to procreate and art strong, do thou raise upon the married wife or upon these widows, with whom thou hast <span style="text-decoration:underline;">contracted Niyoga</span>, good children, and make them happy. Do thou beget with on thy married wife ten children, and consider her the eleventh (memberof the family). O woman! Let ten children be raised on thee by the married husband or thy <span style="text-decoration:underline;">husbands by Niyoga</span> and do thou consider thy husband as the eleventh (member of thy family).&#8221; Rig Veda 10: 85, 48.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 133</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~Should the relation of Niyoga be entered into with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a different Class as well? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ A woman should contract Niyoga with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a higher Class, that is, a Vaishaya woman with a Braahman, a Kshatriya or aVaishaya; a Kshatriya woman with Kshatriya or a Braahman; a Brahman woman with a Braahman. The object of this is that the spermatic fluid should always be of a man of the same Class as the woman or of a higher Class, never </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 134</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ are there any Vedic and Shaastric authorities in favor of Niyoga, as there are in support of the marriage institution? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ <em>&#8220;O man and woman <span style="text-decoration:underline;">(connected by Niyoga</span>), just as a widow, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him</span>, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>O widow! Dothou give up thinking of they deceased husband and choose another from among living men. But thou must understand and remember that if thou should contractest Niyoga for the benefit of thy second husband with whom thou are united by performing the ceremony of joining hands, the child resulting from this union shall belong to him; but if thou interest into relation of <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> for thy benefit, the child shall be thine. Do thou bear this in mind. Let thy husband by <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> also follow this law.&#8221; RIG VEDA 18,8. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>Do thou O woman that givest no pain to thy husband or devar (husband by Niyoga), art kind to animals in this Order of householders, walk assiduously in the path of righteousness and justice, art well-versed in all the shaastraas, hast children and grandchildren, givest birth to valiant the brave boys, desirest a second husband (by Niyoga), and bestoweth happiness on all, accept a man of they choice as thy husband or devar , and always perform the Homa which is the duty of every householder.&#8221; ATHARVA VEDA 14:, 2, 18. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>The sage Manu also sanctions the marriage of <strong>virgin widows</strong>. Says he <span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8220;A virgin widow may marry the younger or the elder brother of her deceased husband</span>.&#8221; MANU. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> </em>PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>A man may also contract <strong>Niyoga with eleven women</strong> (one after the other), just as a woman may enter into the relation of <strong>Niyoga with eleven men</strong> (one after the other), as sanctioned by the Veda in the following text:- </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45. </strong></span></em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 137</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> <em>Q. ~ Can a woman contract Niyoga only after the death of her husband or even when he is alive? </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> A. ~ <strong>This relation can be entered into even in the lifetime of the husband (or of the wife</strong>). Here is Vedic text n support of this view. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> &#8220;When a man is incapable of producing children, let him address his wife as follows:- O thou that art desirous of getting children do not expect me to raise offspring upon thee. Do thou, therefore, seek another husband.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 10, 10.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Similarly when a woman on account of some chronic disease is rendered incapable of bearing children, let her address the following words to her husband. &#8220;My lord! Do not expect me to bear any children. Do thou, therefore, contract Niyoga with a widow.[THESE WORDS ARE NOT PART OF MANTRA THEY HVE BEEN ADDED BY SWAMI JI-WRITER]</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 138</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">The sage Manu declares:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;If a husband has gone abroad in furtherance of some righteous cause, </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">let his wife wait for eight years;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for he acquisition of knowledge and glory, for six years; </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for the pursuit of material ends, for three years. If after the expiry of the prescribed periods he does not turn up, she may contract Niyoga and obtain children.&#8221; MANU 9: 76. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;if the wife be sterile, let the husband wait for eight years after marriage;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if all of her children die, for ten years,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>if she bears only daughters and no sons, for eleven years</strong></span>,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <strong>if she be a termagant, let him forsake her immediately, and enter into Niyoga with another lady and beget children upon her.&#8221; MANU 9: 81</strong>. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Likewise if the husband be very cruel, let his wife forsake him, and bear children by Niyoga who will succeed to the property of her husband by marriage.[THESE ARE NOT PART OF VEDIC LAWS-i.e manu smriti] </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q.~ Monogamy being the rule (i.e., if one man be allowed to have only one wife, and one woman only one husband) what will a person do, if the wife be encienti ir afflicted with some chronic disease, or if the husband be a valetudinarian and either of them cannot control himself or herself on account of extreme youth? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 140 </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ We have answered this objection while treating of Niyoga. <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife and she is pregnant, he may contract Niyoga with a (widow) and beget offspring on her, but let him never misconduct himself with a prostitute or commit adultery.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 142</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8230; <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>Niyoga is clearly allowed by the Veda.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Above we read some laws related to niyog and remarriage which iare laid by Swami Dayanand Saraswati which he backs up through Vedas, Manusmriti and other scriptures. He even gives historical refrences from Mahabharata [<em>it is to be noted agniveer reject these refrences,now its upto reader to decide who is write and who is wrong</em>] and gives various qualities of Niyoga.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his belief the alleged reformer has claimed re-marriage as faulty and Niyog as justified and appropriate .</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand pointed back on remarriage issue as goofy, nonsense and childish . Further more as the great writer has mentioned that if a man or a woman remarries their faith/religion will be lost/destroyed but due to Niyog their basic faith will be pure and safe. Isn&#8217;t this nonsensical? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">What kind of <em>patidharam</em> is this in which if a woman remarries will loose or destroy his faith and if she maintains 11 other sexual relationships she will be safe and clean?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">If a wife is alive and due to certain reasons the husband is  incapable to reproduce, this doesn&#8217;t mean that he lacks sexual desire. If a man has sexual desire but is incapable of producing offspring and his wife approaches another men for niyog, then where and how will the husband fulfill his sexual desire?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Given a thought, everwhere he mentions about begetting a male child only after niyog, but according to the science there is 50% possibility can  be a birth of a girl child. <em>[This is another proof of wishing a male child  in Vedas which we will see later on,and it may also be noted that swami ji permits  Noyog for begetting a male child even if a daughter is present.] </em>In such circumstances where a girl child is born, the rules and conditions governing Niyog have not been mentioned </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji said that  &#8220;Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations after the stipulated period. The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.then for two or three years women have to take care of child.&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Now mark, isn&#8217;t it like lower animal activity in which after having sex only the female has to take care of the children? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As Swami has mentioned, if a woman goes on producing girl babies, still MAN can have a male child by doing niyog. Here the point to be noted is, if a woman keeps giving birth to a girl, then its not the woman but the man who is to be blamed. This is a scientific fact that the determination of gender is done by a male and not by female.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As written, if spoken bluntly, Niyog can be done if a wife is pregnant and husband seeks a sexual relationship and if a husband is ill for long time and the wife wants to have sexual relationship. In such cases they can look for proper partners and go for Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Aren&#8217;t the law, virtue and values not being locked up here? Is the not the meaning of Niyog FREE SEX? Can you imagine any society which is of more low standard than this? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">One more thing to note is what Swami Dayanand states, &#8220;that even <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife  is pregnant</em> he wants to have sexual relationship in such case he  can look for proper partners &amp; go for Niyog</strong></span>.&#8221; Now if the necessity of Niyog was only to bear children (which it is not), why go for free sex during the wife&#8217;s pregnancy?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand in order to confirm the truthfulness, authenticity and practicality gave two examples from the period of Mahabharata. It is written that Vyas had Niyog with wives of those  persons with unique semen and derived offsprings. By Niyog process, Ambika derived Dhritrashtrya, Ambalika derived Pandu and a servant derived Vidur. Another example is of the wives of King Pandu&#8217;s women Kunti and Madri. Due to the reason of incapability in production of Pandu both his wives derived offspring by Niyog. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">[<em>it is quite contrary to the view held by Agniveer that the refrence from Mahabharata is interpolation</em>]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As said in Mahabharat, what to say about Niyog, child even with a non-married woman  was considered good and venerable. The two wise &amp; great men Ved viyas and Bheeshm pitamah&#8217;s origin is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Secondly, in Mahabharat time, in a society one woman could be a wife of 5 brothers e.g. Draupadi the wife of Pandav is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Thirdly, according to what is written in Mahabharata, in this era, even without woman&#8217;s communication only men were able give birth to children. Mahabharat&#8217;s major character guru Dronacharya&#8217;s origin is a proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fourthly, in this period children were born by magical methods e.g. origin of Draupadi. Therefore, in such a society what was the need for Niyog? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">To give it a thought, under what rules Ved Vyas ji did Niyog and why did he do Niyog with three women at the same time?<span style="color:red;"><br />
</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fifthly, why did Kunti give birth to 4 children by Niyog activity on contrary to the rules? Kunti gave birth to Karan, Yudhishtir, Bheem and Arjun and all of them were called as pandu. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Sixthly, in those days when niyog was considered innocent and good then why did kunti float Karan in the river because of shame ?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Seventhly, who were those men with whom kunti had Niyog and derived offspring? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji has prohibited polygamy, where as its said that in that  in Mahabharata civilization &#8220;bahuvivah&#8221; was allowed. The society where swamiji has made niyog evident, should that only be considered as high and template?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In Sathyarth Prakash (doubt removal edition) Pandit Jwalaprasad Sharma produce few more examples in support of Niyoga. He says that in ancient period women used to derive off-springs by accepting the semen of Rishi-Munim, wise, great men by Niyog. All the evidences shown by Pandit ji are from Mahabharat period only. Was Mahabharat the only old (vaidik) period? Was Niyog the only need of Rishis?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Its ironical that with the (vaidik) incantation Swami ji demonstrated niyog tradition  with same incantation (mantra) various wise men and lecturers have demonstrated widow remarriage . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Pandit Omprakash has pointed, for widow remarriage, in his book <em>&#8220;vaidik sahitya aur sanskriti ka swaroop&#8221;</em> he has written that in vedic society there was  permission of widow remarriage.  In the mantra  ( rig ved 10-18-8)  he has given his summary as follows –</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;Hey woman! Leaving this dead husband again make arrival into the living military. accept the future husband,  who wishes to marry you&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">It&#8217;s a whacking, shameful topic where a wise man and a society reformer should support remarriage and widow remarriage, but here the supposed reformers defend niyog practice and showed it useful for the future. Isn&#8217;t it&#8217;s a sign of a wiseman&#8217;s sleazy psychology? In the movies of today that show various stars, even in them we don&#8217;t get to see subject movies on these practices and favor. Leaving swami dayanand , all other wise men and reformers belonging to navjagrun ,favored remarriage.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">LET US NOW SUMMARIZE THE VIEW OF AGNIVEER AND SWAMI JI. READERS WILL SEE THAT AGNIVEER  IS TRYING TO HIDE THE TRUTH AND IS GOING AGAINST SWAMI JI AND ALSO SATYARTHA PRAKASH [APTLY MITHYA PRAKSH OR BIBLE OF HATE].<br />
</span></p>
<div>
<table style="border-collapse:collapse;" border="0">
<colgroup>
<col style="width:199px;" />
<col style="width:351px;" /></colgroup>
<tbody valign="top">
<tr>
<td style="padding:5px;border:outset .75pt;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>AGNIVEER</strong></span></p>
</td>
<td style="border-top:outset .75pt;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>SWAMI DAYANAND JI</strong></span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Niyog is clearly allowed by the Vedas</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How can it be so as Rigved 10-85-48, 10-40-2, Atharvaved 14-2-18, etc mention Niyog.</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;">
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;O man and woman (connected by Niyoga), just as a widow, co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">LET US SEE FEW MORE CLAIMS OF AGNIVEER </span><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong><span style="color:#002060;">CLAIM 1:</span> People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">It is to be noted that only Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj  who accept Niyog had interpreted Vedic verses in support of Niyog. I had provided a reference of Pandit Omkar who saw those texts as supporting widow remarriage.  Also Mr. Agniveer in his usual hateful style tries to attack the Muslims by saying, &#8220;The meaning of this mantra (Rig 10-18-8) provided has been slightly distorted and misinterpreted to suit one&#8217;s mindset of hatred.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Thus Agniveer is calling Swami Dayanand&#8217;s view as a <strong>mindset of hatred and suting his agenda</strong>. Cheers!<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 2: Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria</strong>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Having seens the laws of Niyog it is the height of shamelessness of agniveer to look for Niyog in  Islamic and Christian scriptures.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Mother Mariah, was the WIFE of Prophet Muhammad as clearly mentioned in Hadith accounts. Agniveer as usual takes his readers for a ride by not providing any references.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 3: Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How ironical it is that pregnancy of wife becomes an emergency situation (as claimed by Swamiji)  and and Niyog is only gain a son even if a daughter is present? How pitiful?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In conclusion, I want to assert that Niyog is a curse and bad practice, it cannot be suitable for any period. The state of a women in India was extremely pitiable. It  feels like certain rishis, munis and  other men made  certain rules and regulations, where in woman was treated like a breakfast pl<span style="color:black;">ate and and thing of lust only.</span> Niyog  tradition made a woman no less than a prostitute. Like you have already read above, a widow can have niyog with 10 men. The two words widow and prostitute if taken with the same meaning, it won&#8217;t be unfair. A movie called &#8220;water&#8221; released in 2000 which was picturized on the bad condition of  widow women which was controversial and was banned. The movie was based on historical facts where widows were shown as prostitutes. Since widowed women are considered as inauspicious, they go to pilgrimage places like Kaashi, Vrindavan etc and sing religious chants and beg to earn a living. Even in these days there are nearly 16000 widows living in Kaashi.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Let us respect women, work for their empowerment and allow remarriage instead of this cursed practice of Niyog.<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and the Vedic Dharma</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma. In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color:#333333;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p style="color:#333333;">The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. Nowhere is a prayer or charm recited to be granted a daughter. For exmaple,</span></span></p>
<p><span id="more-848"></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">1. O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. <strong style="font-style:inherit;">Vouchsafe to her ten sons</strong>, and make her husband the eleventh man. [Rigved Mandal 10, Sookt 85, Mantra 45]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_rig_10_85_45.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">2. This is thy Soma draught, O bright Âditya: take delight therein. To this mine utterance, O ye men, give credence, what good the man and wife obtain by praying: <strong style="font-style:inherit;">A manly son is born and gathers riches</strong>, and thrives for ever sinless in the dwelling. [Yajurved Adhyay 8, Mantra 5]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_yajur_8_5.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">3. Fathers, bestow on me a babe, <strong style="font-style:inherit;">a boy </strong>enwreathed with lotuses, so that there may be here a man. [Yajurved Adhyay 2, Mantra 33]</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/son_yajur_2_33.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">All prayers for being granted a boy and none for a girl.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Speaking of marriage Swami Dayanad Saraswati says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“In Sanskrit a daughter is called </span><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">duhitri</span></em><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> (from Du – distant, Hit – good), because the marriage of a girl to a man who comes from a distant country or distant part of the same country is productive of good.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">“If the bride’s people do not live very far from her husband’s home, there is a possibility of her parents becoming poor, as whenever she visits her parents, they will have to give her something or other by the way of a present.” </em>[Satyarth Prakash Chapter 4, The advantages and disadvantages of distant and near marriages, Page 85]</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Rigved Mandal 8, Sookt 33, Mantra 17 says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline,</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Her intellect hath little weight</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">.”</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_brain_rig_8_33_17.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">At another place, it is written:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">There cannot be any friendship with a woman. Her heart is</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> like</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> that of a hyena.</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Rig Veda, 10/95/15</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_hayenas_rig_10_95_15.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda says:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Women are without energy. They should not get a share in the property. Even to the wicked, they speak in a feeble manner. </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">  vi. 5. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">8</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">2</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A wife has no claim to property of her husband. The wealth that she earns is not her but her husband’s. [Manu Smriti  Chapter 8, Sholka 416]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A girl without a brother is called <em style="font-weight:inherit;">Abhratr</em> and it is prohibited to marry such a girl.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The Atharva Ved says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Those maidens there, the veins, who run their course in robes of ruddy hue, must now stand quiet, reft of power, like sisters who are brotherless. [Atharva Ved Kaand 1, Sookt 17, Mantra 1]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/brotherless_ath_1_17_1.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Explaining this word, Nirukt, which is the oldest Indian treatise on Etymology, </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Philology and Semantics, says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">They stand like women who have no brother, and whose path is  obstructed with regard to procreation and the offering of the sacrificial cake. With these words the simile implies the prohibition of marrying a brotherless maiden.[Nirukt 3:4]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Shatpath Brahman, preachings of the ‘Yajur Veda’ says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He (the Adhvaryu) then mixes it with the residue (of ghee) which is left in the prakaranî spoon. Now other libations he completes by mixing, but this one he diminishes; for ghee is a thunderbolt, and by that thunderbolt, the ghee, the gods smote the wives and unmanned them, and thus smitten and unmanned they neither owned any self nor <strong style="font-style:inherit;">did they own any heritage</strong>. And in like manner does he now, by that thunderbolt, the ghee, smite the wives and unman them; and thus smitten and unmanned, they neither own any self<strong style="font-style:inherit;"> nor do they own any heritage</strong>. [Shatpath Brahman; Kaand 4, Adhyay 4, Brahaman 2, Kaandika 13]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The same Shatpath Brahman says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“And whilst not coming into contact with Sûdras and remains of food; for this Gharma is he that shines yonder, and he is excellence, truth, and light; <strong style="font-style:inherit;">but woman, the Sûdra, the dog, and the black bird (the crow), are untruth: he should not look at these, lest he should mingle excellence and sin, light and darkness, truth and untruth</strong>. [Kaand 14, Adhyay1, Brahman1, Kaandika 31]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">A woman can never ask for divorce, even if her husband ill treats her. Manu says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife. [Manu Smriti 5:154]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Swami Dayanand Saraswati is teaching us in Satyarth Prakash how to choose a perfect wife. Listen to him.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let a man never marry one who is pale and anaemic, nor one who is altogether a bigger and stronger person than himself or has a redundant member, nor one who is an invalid, nor one either with no hair or too much hair or too much hair, nor one immoderately talkative, nor one with red eyes.” MANU 3: 8.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Nor one with the name of star,of a tree,or of a river, or of a mountain.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">So Hindu men should not marry women who are named Ashvini, Ganga, Saraswati, Himalaya, etc.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let him choose for his wife, a girl who has a graceful figure without any deformity, who has a pretty name, who walks gracefully like a swan or an elephant, who has fine hair and lovely teeth, and whose body is exquisitely soft.” MANU 3: 10</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Satyarth Prakash, Pages 89, 90]</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He forgets to teach how to choose a husband.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The ‘Vedas,’ also talk about ‘Niyog’ the custom of childless widow or woman having sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. In simple words ‘Niyog’ means sending a married woman or widow to a particular man for sexual intercourse so that she gets a son. Indication of this custom is available in Rig Veda.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> In ‘Aadiparva’ of ‘Mahabharata’ (chapters 95 and 103), it is mentioned that Satyawati had appointed her son to bestow sons to the queens of Vichitrvirya, the younger brother of Bhishma, and as a result of which Dhartrashtra and Pandu were born. Pandu himself had asked his queen, Kunti, to have sexual intercourse with a Brahmin to get a son (Aadi Parva,’ chapters 120 to 123).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">It has been said in ‘Aadi Parva’ (chapters 64 and 104), that when Parshu Ram started killing the Kshatriyas, thousands of female Kshatriyas started going to Brahmins to get sons. Similar references are found at other places in ‘Mahabharata’ also. With regard to ‘Niyog’, there are detailed discussions at a number of places in other religious books.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In Nirkut, the meaning of ‘dewar’ that is, husband’s younger brother, has been given as ‘Duvitya Var’ that is, the second husband (Nirukt 3:15).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">An ancient commentator of ‘Manu Smriti’ (Manu’s Code), Meghatithi has clearly accepted the existence of ‘Niyog‘ (quoted from ‘Dharam Shastra Ka Itihas’, by Bharatratan Mahamahopdhyay, Dr P.V. Kane, Part I, page 341).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the last century, Swami Dayanand Saraswati had claimed to have written a commentary free from defects in the interpretation, of the ancient commentators on the ‘Vedas.’ Dayanand had not only accepted the prevalence of ‘Niyog’ but also on the basic of ‘smritis’ (codes of traditional Hindu laws), discussed ‘Niyog’ in great detail in the language of the ‘Veda mantras’ (Vedic hymns). According to him there was a law that a woman or a man could have sexual intercourse with eleven persons. If no child was born from the one, then a woman could go to another. If even then she was unable to beget a child, then she could go to the third and so on till she had intercourse with eleven men (Dayanand’s commentary on Rig Veda, 10/85/45).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Woman was sometimes even forced to have sexual intercourse with men in the custom of ‘Niyog’. ‘Devtas, Rishis, Munis’ and ‘Brahmins’ used to participate in ‘Niyog’ (see ‘Mahabharata Aadi Parv; chapters 64,95,103, 104).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Chastity of woman was not safe</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the name of ‘beejdan’ (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of women was not safe. The so-called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with another man’s wife. From ‘Niyog pratha’, it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that the women were looked upon as mere child-producing machines.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In ‘The Position of Women in Hindu Civilization’, Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar writes: “<em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though woman was married to a man, she was considered to be the property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only the son could be the successor to property.”</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says: <em style="font-weight:inherit;">“No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic men could not keep even the relations between brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery / adultery named ‘Niyog’. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognise neither sister nor daughter and also they did not keep in mind their relations with them. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what the miserable plight of women was in the society then. (Refer ‘Arya Niti Ka Bhandaphor’, 5th edition page 14).</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Till such a time as these teachings have an overwhelming influence, the improvement in the position and status of the women is next to impossible.</span></span></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
