<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>hindus &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/hindus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 15:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Killing Infidels in Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 05:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[answering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavarta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beheading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahmadvish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayananad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disbelievers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extremism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinduism exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innocent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ISIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jihad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kafir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kikata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murdering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non believers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plunder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puranas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaughtering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthabouthinduism.wordpress.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthofhinduism.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ved nindak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war booty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Also read new article Killing Infidels in Hinduism Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7331" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg" alt="" width="517" height="384" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1024x760.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-768x570.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1536x1141.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-2048x1521.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /></p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Also read new article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Hinduism</a></p>
<p>Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as a result of the violent passages in Vedas. As per Vedas, you must kill a person who rejects Vedas, who hates Vedas and Ishwar, who does not worship, who does not make offerings to ishwar, who insults god (Blasphemy), one who oppresses a Brahmin etc. There are several passages in Vedas which calls for death of disbelievers. I am mostly using Arya Samaji translations of Satya Prakash Saraswati, Satyakam Vidyalankar, Devi Chand, Vaidyanath Shastri, Kshemkarand Das Trivedi, Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Shripad Damodar Satvalekar, and orthodox translations of Swami Karpatri and Shri Ram Sharma Acharya (Gayatri Parivar) and I will be using Griffith’s translation as well followed by Hindi translation of Hindu scholars. In the Vedas you will find numerous words to denote non-Hindus such as Adeva, Adevayu which means Godless, anindra which means against Indra, Ayajyu, Ayajvan which means unsacrifcing, Abrahman, Anyavrata which means followers of other gods, apavrata, avrata which means riteless, devanid which means haters of gods, Brahmadvish which means haters of devotion and those who denounce Vedas.</p>
<p><span id="more-746"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.13.9 “May you (O love divine), the beholder of the path of enlightenment, purifying our mind and destroying the infidels who refuse to offer worship, come and stay in the prime position of the eternal sacrifice.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.6.3 “May the fire divine chase away those infidels, who do not perform worship and who are uncivil in speech. They are niggards, unbelievers, say no tribute to fire divine and offer no homage. The fire divine turns those godless people far away who institute no sacred ceremonies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.63.5 ”Augmenting the strength of resplendent self, urging the waters and rejuvenating all noble acts and destroying the infidels.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p><strong>One who does not offer Sacrifice is inhuman</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.70.11 “May your friend, the cloud, hurl that infidel down from heaven who differs from us in rites and rituals, is inhuman, who does not observe fire sacrificials, and who does not show reverence to Nature’s bounties.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.97.9 “O Lord of knowledge, this laudation is for you…destroy the godless and the malice of our enemy.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Killing Avrata,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.73.8 &#8220;&#8230;he, the all-wise, looks over all worlds; he censures those who are hostile in action, and who do not offer sacrifices and render no public good.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.84. 8 When will he trample, like a weed, the man [Infidel] who hath no gift for him…</p>
<p>Yaska writes,</p>
<p>Nirukta 5.17 When, with his foot, will he trample the unworshipping man like a mushroom</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.64.1-2 “May our hymns please you; O lord of resolute will power, please display your bounty. May you drive off the infidels. May you crush with your foot the niggard churls who offer no homage. You are powerful; there is none so powerful as you are.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.2.10 “May you roaring flames, O adorable Lord, be manifest in the sky as sharp weapons, to destroy infidels. In his exhilaration may his shining splendour inflict destruction. The godless hands try to bind him from all sides but do not succeed.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.79.10 “The powerful flowing elixir…It is the conferer of wealth, the king of vigour; It crushes malignities and harasses the enemies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.76.11 “Both the heaven and earth shudder when you, O the resplendent Lord, uttering your fearful roar, crush down the infidel.” Tr. Satya Prakash Sarawati</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.21.3 ‘Let this war drum made of wood, muffled with leather straps, dear to all the persons of human race and bedewed with ghee, speak terror to our foemen.”Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="464" height="205" class="wp-image-7290" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi1.png?w=464" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png 464w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x133.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.19.6 ‘May you bring near to us those who stand aloof; may you strike terror into our foes; o pure flowing elixir, please transfer their riches to us.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati and Satyakam Vidyalankar</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 17.33 “He is an ideal commander of the army, who is swift, keeps his arms sharpened, fearless like a strong bull, a zealous killer of foes, strikes terror in men…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 4.31.7 “Let the King [Varuna] and Manyu, the warm emotion give us the wealth of both kinds-earned and gathered. Let our enemies overwhelmed with terror in their mind and spirit and defeated in their design run away.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya also writes about terror,</p>
<p>Nirukta 10.21 …These are hemistichs. Like a spear hurled, it inspires terror (among enemies) or courage (among friends)…</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.36 “We learned persons accept as our ruler, thee, the introducer of new plans for our advancement, the master of loyal subjects, the embodiment of virtue, the most advanced in noble qualities and acts, the queller of the irreligious…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.44 “…This fourth warrior, full of delight, should subdue the irreligious foes.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.12 “O king, make progress in thy duty of administration, extend happiness to the virtuous. O terrible chastiser, burn down the irreligious foes. O splendid person, humiliate and consume utterly like dried up stubble, him, who encourages our foe.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.23 He who dwells fixed in the atmosphere, smiting the blasphemers of the god that do not sacrifice, to him be reverence with ten sakvarî−stanzas!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="59" class="wp-image-7291" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi2.png?w=601" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x29.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Killing Women and Children</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.21 Do not covet our cattle, our men, our goats and sheep! Bend thy course elsewhere, O strong god (ugra), slay the offspring of the blasphemers! <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="602" height="111" class="wp-image-7292" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi3.png?w=602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png 602w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.20.4-5 “Let this war-drum victorious in the battle, loudly roaring and becoming the means of seizing whatever may be seized, be seen by all. Let this war-drum utter wonderful voice and let the army-controlling man capture the possessions of the enemies. Amid the conflict of the deadly weapons let the woman of enemy waked by the roar and afflicted run forward in her terror hearing the resounding and far reaching voice of the wardrum, holding her son in her hand.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="577" height="107" class="wp-image-7293" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi4.png?w=577" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.118.8 So, Agni, with thy glowing face burn fierce against the female fiends, Shining among Uruksayas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="508" height="100" class="wp-image-7294" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi5.png?w=508" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4-300x59.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>VEDIC GOD STEALS</strong></p>
<p><strong>GOD STEALING LIKE A THIEF</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “To him, who is the performer of all deeds, the possessor and giver of strength, the truly powerful Lord, we offer devotional prayers. He a highwayman, snatches wealth from the godless exploiters and gives it to honest devotees.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Griffith’s translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “…The Hero, watching like a thief in ambush, goes parting the possessions of the godless.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.93.4 Agni and Soma, famed is that your. prowess wherewith ye stole the kine, his food, from Paṇi…<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="513" height="96" class="wp-image-7295" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi6.png?w=513" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png 513w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.61.25 “The elixir of divine love flows onward, chasing the malignant, and driving off the withholders of wealth and thus it proceeds to the holy abode of the resplendent Lord.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.19.9 ‘O bounteous Lord, pious devotees, skilled in reciting hymns, sing their songs to you for your adoration. May you select us also to join them who by their homage to you, have become entitled to appropriate the riches of infidels‘. Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.75.12 ‘Leave us not in this conflict as a bearer of load; snatch up the wealth of infidels and give it to us.’ Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.4.5 “…May you come to bless our fire ritual. May you having scattered all our adversaries, bring to us the possessions of our foeman.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Here god is prayed to eliminate the rivals and to bring their wealth. Yaska writes on this verse,</p>
<p>Nirukta 4.5 “Having destroyed all assailants, bring to us the treasures of our enemies, i.e. having destroyed the forces of our adversaries, bring to us the treasures or the food from the homes of our enemies.”- Nirukta 4.5</p>
<p><strong>ALL NON HINDUS ARE DEMONS, BARBARIANS.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="417" height="523" class="wp-image-7296" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/tolerance-hinduism-buddhism-jainism-zoroastrianism-false-religions-untitld.jpg?w=417&amp;h=523" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg 417w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole-239x300.jpeg 239w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px" /></p>
<p>The reason it is important to know who are Demons in Hinduism is because Hindu apologists find no problem with violent verses in the Veda because it says to kill ‘Demon’, they just say that these verses are referring to Demons and not to non-Hindus and try to get rid of the argument. As I said earlier Hindu apologists usually takes violent verses in lighter vein because it says to kill demons. Vedas are said to be eternal, now the question is if those verses were applicable only to Demons then it means that those verses have become useless now. So why God revealed such verses for limited period of time in the eternal book?</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote,”The Dwijaas( the twice-born) – Braahmanaas, Kshatriyas, Vaishyaas are called Aryas, while the Shudras are called Anaryas, or Non-Aryas.”ATHARVA VEDA 19:62. In the face ofthese Vedic authorities how can sensible people believe in the imaginary tales of the foreigners. In the Devaasurawars, Prince Arjuna and King Dashrathaand others of Aryavarta used to go to the assistance of the Aryas in order to crush the Asuras. This shows that the people living outside Aryavarta were called Dasyus and Malechhaas… Besides, Manu also corroborates our position. He says, “The countries other than Aryavarta are called Dasyus and Malechha countries.” MANU 10:45, 2:23. The people living in the north-east, north, north-west were called Rakshasas.” Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>Dasyu and Rakshasa mean demon. Here Swami Dayanand quoting Manu Smriti says that all people living outside Aryavrata and those who do not belong to four castes are demons (Rakshasa, Dasyu) and barbarians (Mleccha). According to Hindu Dharma all the non Hindus are demons and barbarians. Here is the full translation of Manu Smriti,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 10.45 All those tribes in this world, which are excluded from (the community of) those born from the mouth, the arms, the thighs, and the feet (of Brahman), are called Dasyus, whether they speak the language of the Mlekkhas (barbarians) or that of the Aryans.</p>
<p>Now some say that this doesn’t refer to Non-Hindus but to caste Hindus who lost their status on account of their neglecting their religious rites which lead them to loss of caste. They aren’t convinced even after providing explanation by their own scholar. Maybe they didn’t read verse 43 of this chapter 10 which says that by neglecting sacrifices the Dvijas made their successive generation fell to the status of Shudra not Dasyu. If Brahmins, Kshatriya, Vaishya and Shudra losing their caste made them Dasyu, the question is why they aren’t regarded as outcaste but as Dasyu? Because verse 43 and 45 aren’t correlated. Verse 45 is plain and clear that those tribe outside the pale of four Varnas are Dasyu and non-Hindus aren’t included in the four castes. Manu Smriti 10.45 also refutes the claim of apologists who claim that Dasyu means non-Human beings since Manu 10.45 states that Dasyu can be from four castes also who has abandoned their Vedic religion (if we go by the explanation of apologists) since they claim that Dasyu refers to demons only. Hindu scriptures from Veda to Purana mentions demon, so where are all those demons now? Dayanand Saraswati wrote,</p>
<p>“You can still see that the description of Raakshasas given therein tallies with the ugly appearance of the negroes of today.” <strong>Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</strong></p>
<p>So he is comparing Rakshasa with present day Negroes (black people) we can ascertain from this line that people living in north east and north west were not really monsters but were native people who are described in such racist manner. Swami Prabhupada also wrote,</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes: “…An atheist is called a demon, and it is a fact that even a person born of good parents can turn into a demon by bad association…” <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.3.6</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>An Indologist wrote about Dasyu,</p>
<p>“The picture of the dasyu that emerges from these passages is quite different from that of the raksas. There is nothing about taking the form of a bird and flying by night, no mention of disrupting sacrifices, and no connection with black magic. The dasyus seem to be human beings of a different race from the Aryans and of a different (adevic and abrahamanic) religion. The mention of the proper names of various dasyus who are defeated for (or by) certain Aryan princes (e.g. Dabhiti) also makes the dasyu sound more like historical figures. There are occasional mentions of taking land from the dasyus (RV 4.38.1). The mention of dasyus in connection with fortresses (pur-) is also a characteristic which is in contrast to the raksases. Raksases do not build fortresses and fight from them. It seems quite safe to agree with the general conclusion of Vedic scholars that dasyu refers to the indigenous people of the land whom the invading Aryans conquered or absorbed.” <strong>by Wash Edward Hale, p.154, Asura in Early Vedic Religion, Published by Motilal Banarsidass Publisher, 1986.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Moreover the Aryans were engaged in battle against the Dasyus and the reason given is Dasyus sings no [Vedic] hymns; Dasyus are riteless, Dasyus have alien laws; Dasyus differs from rites and rituals and doesn’t observe fire sacrifices; Dasyus are faithless, niggars, without belief, sacrifice and worship. The main reason given to fight them is that Dasyus do not offer any gifts to Vedic deities and Indra was often invoked to wage a war against the Dasyu. Refer my article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing infidels in Hinduism</a> for references. Dasa and Dasyu has been synonymously used in the Vedas. The Persian word <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dahae" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Dahae<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> maybe related to the Dasyu tribe mentioned in the Vedas. “The Dahae were a Scythian people of ancient Central Asia. A confederation of three tribes – the Parni, Xanthii and Pissuri – the Dahae lived in an area now comprising much of modern Turkmenistan. The area has consequently been known as Dahestan, Dahistan and Dihistan” [end quote]. The word Parni is also believed to be the Iranian word for Panis tribe. The Panis and Dasyu may be have been closely related to each other that’s the reason they are mentioned together in Rig Veda 7.6.3; 5.34.6. Many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dasa" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Indologists<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> have also opined that Dasa were a tribe of humans not demons. Apologist pathetic response would be that Dasyu in the Veda are described as having numerous eyes and hands which is a proof that they were demons. Even Rishis who are said to be humans are described in some texts as of having three heads, Vedic deities as of having face of horse, animal getting pregnant after drinking semen of Rishis, does that prove that Rishis and Vedic deities were also demons? Hindus have a long history of using epithets against other religions, the Aryans used to consider Dasyu as Anasa which literally translates to noseless but it actually means flat nosed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to Panis tribe. Panis too are described as Demons, but Yaska in Nirukta also calls them Merchant (Nirukta 2.17). Panis tribe were rich traders and they were consistently attacked by Aryans to plunder them since they did not patronize the priests who then invoked Vedic gods to attack Panis. Apologists gives lame excuse, when defending verses about killing and plundering Panis tribe, all that they say is Panis were demons and doesn’t explain the part where Aryans plundered them and were the first to fight the Panis tribe. If they were demons then why Aryans were so eager to get their donations? Veda reiterates that Panis brings no gifts to Vedic deities, so why crave for their wealth if they were so demonic in nature? Veda also mentions a member of Panis community named Bribu who is praised in Rig Veda 6.45.31 because he is said to have gifted many cows to Rishi Bhardwaj (Manu Smriti 10.107) in which he is referred to as a carpenter. Now all of a sudden a Panis member is praised, what’s the reason? Because the reason to kill and plunder them is clearly given in Atharva Veda 20.93.2 that the Panis brings no gifts, had they given donations like Panis Bribu then they would’ve been spared and would’ve also been praised in the Vedas. Panis were rich merchants, they also had carpenters they used to rear cattle, engaged in trade and amassed wealth. These are the characteristics of humans not demons.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kikata too were plundered like Dasyu and Panis tribes because they didn’t observe Vedic rituals and didn’t make donations to Vedic deities. Veda also mentions Zoroastrians and calls them demons (Asura). The Asuras mentioned in Vedas are non other than Zoroastrians. They are actually Ahura worshippers (Zoroastrians). Vedic religion and Zoroastrianism are roughly of the same age they have many similarities like Vedic Yagna is called Yasna in Zoroastriniasm, Soma is Homa, Deva in Veda are positive while Daeva in Zoroastrianism is neutral to negative, Zoroastrian text also mentions Aryans. From Rig Veda Mandal 1 to 7, Vedic deities are also called as Asur but the definition when applied to Vedic deities is ‘Mighty’. When the Aryans moved from Central Asia to India they brought with them the memories, thus the word Asura is used till Rig Veda Mandal 7 as a praiseworthy word. And then it was turned negative and was also used later to describe enemies residing in eastern part of India such as Bengal and Assam like Asura king Naraka of Pragiyotisapura in Assam or Mahishasura. There’s also a tribe in India named <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/meeting-the-asurs-a-marginal-tribe-in-eastern-india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Asur people<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> who claim themselves to be descendants of Mahishasura.</p>
<p>People of Lanka in Ramayana has been described as Demons. Hanuman burned hundreds of demons inhabiting Lanka for no fault of their when Ram’s enmity was towards Ravana and not towards inhabitants of Lanka. Ramayana makes no mention of humans residing in Lanka but refers to the people of Lanka as demons. Go to Sri Lanka and tell me how many demons you found there or at least try to find their bones.</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to the Puranas, which is the most important point here. Many Puranas especially Vishnu Purana book 3 chapters 17 &amp; 18 states that demons embraced Buddhism and Jainism. The reason I quote Vishnu Purana again and again is because two chapters of this scripture are dedicated in denigrating Buddhism and Jainism and gives a picture of how Hinduism perceives other religions. Hindu text says that demons embraced Buddhism. Their disciples and disciples would continue to preach this religion. Now as you may know Buddhism’s history is not unknown like Hinduism’s. We know who its founder was and when Buddhism was founded, we know that its founder really existed and was not a mythological figure. Buddhism was founded in the 6<sup>th</sup> century B.C. It was a time when humans had started recording history. So you tell me did any Greek, Roman or any traveller ever recorded that demons used to live in India and they embraced Buddhism as stated in Hindu scriptures? So what Hindus did is nothing but demonization of their enemies. Hinduism recognizes many tribes and Dasyus, Panis, Yavana… were among them and they have been demonized because as mentioned in Manu (10.45) all those who do not belong to four castes are Dasyu and Malechas. Now some also justify violent verses of Vedas saying that all violent verses about killing godless, riteless, those who do not offer gifts actually refers to demons and not to human beings and that demons were averse to humanity. An Asura named Rambha who was the father of Mahishasur was a devotee of Vedic deity Agni. Vishnu Purana bk 3 ch 17-18 states that demons were Vedic followers who couldn’t be killed unless they apostatizes from Vedic Dharma and embraces other religions like Buddhism and Jainism. So what these incidents prove is that even demons could follow Vedic religion but still that wouldn’t make them Hindus or Humans since Hinduism believes in birth based and only those belonging to four castes can be considered Vedic followers. So this refutes the claim that demons were averse to Devas or Humanity.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Sutras,</p>
<p>Apastamba Sutra, Prasna I, Patala 9, Khanda 27.11 The expression Krishna Varna, ‘the black race,’ is truly Vedic. In the Rig-veda it usually denotes the aboriginal races, and sometimes the demons.</p>
<p>Vedas also states that the one who offers no worship is inhuman, wicked, evil, miser etc.,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.20.5 “Preserve us from the reproach of every one, who makes no offerings, is vicious and wicked and who utters ill words, so that we may be free (from anxiety).” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Shouldn’t Ishwar be friendly with entire creation? Why Ishwar is friendly only with those who make offerings? Was it invented by Rishis to get wealth in the name of god? What about the poor people who don’t even have money to feed their children. Will Ishwar forgive them or punish them as he commands to kill those who doesn’t pour gifts.</p>
<p><strong>Beheading the Demons (Non Hindus)</strong></p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.2.10 “…Here do I cut off the neck of the Raksas, who hateth us, and whom we hate’, he says; there are two people, he whom he hates and he who hates him; verily straightway he cuts their necks…”</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 1.7.7 O Agni, bring thou hitherward the Yatudhanas bound and chained. And afterward let Indra tear their heads off with his thunder-bolt.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="102" class="wp-image-7297" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi7.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x49.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 5.26 By impulse of God Savitar I take thee with arms of Asvins, with the hands of Peahen.Thou art a woman. Here I cut the necks of Rakshasas away. Barley art thou. Bar off from us our haters, bar our enemies…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="554" height="210" class="wp-image-7298" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi8.jpg?w=554" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg 554w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x114.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.26.3 Thou didst impel the sage to win the daylight, didst ruin Śuṣṇa for the pious Kutsa.The invulnerable demon’s head thou clavest when thou wouldst win the praise of Atithigva.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7299" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi9.jpg?w=612" width="505" height="123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg 612w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x73.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.14.13 With waters’ foam thou torest off, Indra, the head of Namuci, Subduing all contending hosts.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7300" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi10.jpg?w=625" width="514" height="88" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x51.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>DEATH TO THOSE WHO DOESN’T POUR GIFTS TO ISHWAR</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.44.11 “Give us not, O showerer of benefits, to the wicked. Relying upon your friendship, O Lord of riches, may we remain unharmed. Many are the boons you distribute amongst men; may you demolish those who make no libation, and root out those who present no offerings.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.176.4 Slay everyone who pours no gift, who, hard to reach, delights thee not. Bestow on us what wealth he hath: this even the worshipper awaits.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="94" class="wp-image-7301" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi11.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p><strong>PLUNDERING THE PROPERTIES OF PEOPLE WHO DO NOT OFFER GIFTS</strong></p>
<p>Ishwar commands to plunder the property of people who do not offer gifts and then to kill them.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.81.9 …Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="161" class="wp-image-7302" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi12.png?w=500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.2 Crush with thy foot the niggard churls who bring no gifts. Might art thou: There is not one to equal thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="512" height="104" class="wp-image-7303" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi13.png?w=512" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png 512w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8-300x61.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 “Thou, Soma, boldest wealth in kine which thou hast seized from niggard churls: Thou calledst forth the outspun thread.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>English translation by Arya Samaji scholar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 &#8220;O elixir of bliss, you hold the wealth of kine which you win from the greedy persons; you are the force behind the extended thread (of creation).&#8221; Tr. Svami Satya Prakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>This verse refers to the Panis tribe, according to some scholars the Panis tribe were also part of the Vedic society but were plundered and killed because they made no offerings to Ishwar, this is why they are considered Niggards. But Yaska gives a different meaning, Yaska writes that Panis tribe were Demons. One is not to be deluded by the usage of the word Demon here as Demons and Barbarians are those who does not follow the Veda or who lives beyond the boundaries of Aryavarta. The Vedic followers are commanded here to crush the Panis tribe only because they make no offerings to Vedic Gods. There are more evidences to show that tribes were plundered and killed just because they made no offerings to Vedic gods.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.56.6 These people, Indra, keep for thee all that is worthy of thy choice. Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="470" height="193" class="wp-image-7304" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi14.png?w=470" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png 470w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9-300x123.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px" /></p>
<p><strong>Plundering Godless (Adeva)</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.138.4 He boldly cast down forts which none had e’er assailed: unwearied he destroycd the godless treasure-stores. Like Sun and Moon he took the stronghold&#8217;s wealth away, and, praised in song, demolished foes with flashing dart.</p>
<p>Following is the Hindi translation by Arya Samaji scholar Shripad Damodar Satwalekar</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1101" height="197" class="wp-image-7305" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg 1101w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-300x54.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-1024x183.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-768x137.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1101px) 100vw, 1101px" /></p>
<p><strong>Dark races</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;Through your fear, O universal fire, the dark evil forces, though of many minds, come under a control, having abandoned their possessions. Adorable Lord, may you shine upon all men and blaze, consuming the cities of their foes.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Another clear translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;For fear of thee forth fled the dark-hued races, scattered abroad, deserting their possessions, When, glowing, O Vaiśvānara, for Pūru, thou Agni didst light up and rend their castles.&#8221; Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p><strong> Ishwar Behaving like a Thug</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.93.5 “When two large, mutually defiant hosts, emulous in corporal vigour, contest, may you destroy the godless in favour of the god fearing and in favour of the person who pours out devotional sentiments.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.25.7 (Indra), the drinker of the effused Soma, contracts no friendship with the wealthy trader who offers not any libation ; he takes away his wealth ; destroys him when destitute; but he is a special (friend) to him who presents the libation and oblation.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="463" height="148" class="wp-image-7306" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi15.png?w=463" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png 463w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.34.8 When Indra, the possessor of opulence, discriminates between two men, both wealthy, and exerting themselves (against each other) for the sake of valuable cattle, he takes one of them [The one who performs Yajna] as his associate, causing (his adversaries) to tremble, and the agitator (of the clouds), together with the Maruts, bestows upon him herds of cattle.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="121" class="wp-image-7307" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi16.png?w=548" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11-300x66.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p>Other verses shows that Ishwar provides protection to those who make offerings to him, but Ishwar slays the person who doesn’t worship or make offerings. Why is Ishwar behaving like a thug? Shouldn’t Ishwar be equal and friendly to everyone irrespective of their offerings? All the verses I quoted above orders to kill those who make no offerings, there are several instances in Vedas wherein tribesmen were killed just because they made no offering to Ishwar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O bounteous Lord, of what avail are the cattle of infidels to you. Neither they yield milk nor do these faithless persons kindle sacred fire. May you bring wealth of these unbelievers to us and give us possession of people of low mortality and crush them.” Tr. SayaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>This verse is referring to the Kikata tribe who were plundered by Vedic heroes and killed. Maharishi Yaska explains this as,</p>
<p>Nirukta 6.32 What are the cows doing in Kikata? Kikata is the name of a country where the non-Aryans dwell. Non-Aryan tribes are (so called because it is said),’What have they done? Or their assumption is that religious rites are useless. They neither get the milk to mix with the soma, nor kindle fire.</p>
<p>Here the Vedic god is invoked to plunder the cows of of Kikata people and to plunder the wealth of the king of Kikata tribe. As I said earlier, many tribes were plundered and looted by Vedic gods just because they made no offering to Ishwar, Kikata and Panis tribes are few examples. Here is another translation by Arya Samaj,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O learned king! you possess admirable wealth, what do the cattle do among the atheists because they have no faith in the Vedic teachings and rites or in place inhabited by them. They yield no milk to mix with the Soma, and do not perform the Yajna with the ghee of the cows. Therefore, bring them to us, so that we may use them for hospitality (giving the milk mixed with Soma) to teachers and preachers. Give us wealth taken away from the wicked persons for the use of those who hailing from a good family come to us. Remove far away from us a man who uses his power for doing mean or inglorious acts or keep him under us.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p><strong>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote on this verse</strong>, “As the cows do not grow among the wicked atheists, in the same manner, Dharma and other virtues do not grow among the persons lacking faith. Among the enlightened persons atheists can never have the upper hand. Therefore, good scholars should blot out atheism.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO HATE ISHWAR AND WHOM ISHWAR  HATES</strong></p>
<p>The entire hymn of Atharva 2.19 is dedicated in burning those who hate Ishwar and to whom Ishwar hates,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.19.1 Burn thou, O Agni, with that heat of thine against the man who hates us, whom we hate.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="189" class="wp-image-7308" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi17.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12-300x110.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.15 “…By him we attack on him who hates us and whome we abhor. We overthrow and slay him through this knowledge, through this act and through this fatal weapon.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.25 …from earth we bar him who hates us and whom we hate.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="515" height="137" class="wp-image-7309" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi18.png?w=515" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png 515w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13-300x80.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="483" height="316" class="wp-image-7310" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi19.png?w=483" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png 483w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14-300x196.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Arya Samaj commentary states that a, ‘Man [Brahmin] should satisfy himself by killing his enemies with the miraculous powers given by God’.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="457" height="79" class="wp-image-7311" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi20.png?w=457" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png 457w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 457px) 100vw, 457px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.21 “O resplendent Lord, brave and opulant, protect us this day against our foes with many and excellent defences, may the vile wretch who hates us fall before us; May the breath of life depart from him whom we hate.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 15.15 This one in front, golden-tressed, with sunbeams; the leader of his host and his chieftain are Rathagritsa and Rathaujas, and Puñjikasthalâ: and Kratusthalâ his Apsarases. Biting animals are his weapon, homicide his missile weapon; to them be homage: may they protect us, may they have mercy upon us. In their jaws we place the man whom we hate and who hates us.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="539" height="204" class="wp-image-7312" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi21.png?w=539" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png 539w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16-300x114.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 539px) 100vw, 539px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.3.3 This charm shall conquer and cast down thy foemen. <strong>Be thou the first</strong> to slay the men who hate thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="248" class="wp-image-7313" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi22.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17-300x145.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Is it right to kill someone just because they hate you or Ishwar? What kind of God is Ishwar who commands to kill the person who just hates him. The above verse explicitly says to be the first one to kill those who just ‘Hate’ you. Is this justifiable? If you just oppress a Brahmin you are liable to be killed according to Vedas, but the Brahmin can kill you, deprive you of your property, there is no sin in this, but oppressing a Brahmin is a grave sin in Vedas,</p>
<p>‘Atharva Veda 13.3.1 ‘…O Rohita (King) agitate destroy and entangle in snares the man doing wrong to Brahman.” , Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="427" class="wp-image-7314" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi23.png?w=494" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18-300x259.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.52 Rend, rend to pieces, rend away, destroy, destroy him utterly. Destroy Angirasi! the wretch who robs and wrongs the Brahmans, born.</p>
<p>Poor Shudra’s fate is to be oppressed by Brahmins,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 8.417 A Brahmana may confidently seize the goods of (his) Sudra (slave); for, as that (slave) can have no property, his master may take his possessions.</p>
<p>Maharishi Manu says that a Brahmin can even kill anyone who hurts him without bringing notice to the King,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.31-33 A Brahmana who knows the law need not bring any (offence) to the notice of the king; by his own power alone be can punish those men who injure him. His own power is greater than the power of the king; the Brahmana therefore, may punish his foes by his own power alone. Let him use without hesitation the sacred texts, revealed by Atharvan and by Angiras; speech, indeed, is the weapon of the Brahmana, with that he may slay his enemies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO REJECT AND HATE VEDAS</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.62 “Rend, rend to bits, rend through and through, scorch and consume and burn to dust, the one who rejects the Vedas”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="493" height="118" class="wp-image-7315" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi24.png?w=493" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png 493w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 493px) 100vw, 493px" /></p>
[This verse is translated from the Hindi Bhasya]
<p>Arya Samaj commentary states:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="442" height="58" class="wp-image-7316" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi25.png?w=442" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png 442w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20-300x39.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px" /></p>
<p>“Godly persons shall always be ready to kill irreligious people”</p>
[Kshemkarandas Trivedi (Arya Samaj) on Atharva Veda 12.5.62, page 576]
[Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>He writes on Atharva Veda 12.5.54</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="455" height="145" class="wp-image-7317" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi26.png?w=455" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png 455w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px" /></p>
<p>‘‘Vedic followers should destroy infidels“- Kshem Karan Das Trivedi on Atharva Veda 12.5.54, page 574 [Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Hindu god Vishnu says,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.17 When the glorious Vishnu heard their prayers he emitted from his person an illusory form wliich he gave to the celestials and said. “This illusory form shall so deceive the Daityas, so that being led astray from the path of the Vedas, they may be put to death ; for all gods, demons and others, who shall transgress the authority of the Veda, shall perish by my prowess which I exercise for the preservation of the universe. Go then ; be not affraid ; this illusory form shall go before you. celestials, it shall be of great service to you, this day.</p>
<p>Veda also commands to kill the enemies of Vedas,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.12.6 …Burn down the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="469" height="248" class="wp-image-7318" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi27.png?w=469" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png 469w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22-300x159.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" /></p>
<p>Griffith has translated the word Brahmadvish as “Haters of Prayer/devotion” which is also correct but the definition “Those who hate Vedas” is precisely correct, other correct definition is ‘Enemies of Vedas’. Dayanand Saraswati founder of Arya Samaj gives the following meaning,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="185" height="26" class="wp-image-7319" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-23.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi28.png?w=185" /></p>
<p>“Brahmadivsh = The enemies of Vedas and Ishwar.</p>
[Rig Veda Dayanand Saraswati Hindi Bhasya, Mandala 2, page 323]
<p>Vidya Martanda also endorsed his Guru’s definition,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="503" height="148" class="wp-image-7320" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi29.png?w=503" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png 503w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24-300x88.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 503px) 100vw, 503px" /></p>
[Rig Veda, By Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda, Vol 3, p.469, Published by Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, April 2002 Reprint]
<p>Satya Prakash Saraswati defines Brahmadvish as,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="565" height="87" class="wp-image-7321" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi30.png?w=565" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png 565w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25-300x46.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 565px) 100vw, 565px" /></p>
[Rig Veda Samhita, by Satya Prakash Saraswati and Vidyalankar, Vol 4, page no 1294, Published by Veda Pratishthana, New Delhi, 1977]
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON gives the following meaning,</p>
<p>‘‘One who is envious of the Vedas, of a qualified Brahmana or of the Brahmana caste is called Brahma-dvis”</p>
[Krishna The Supreme Personality of Godhead: A Summary Study of Srimad-Bhagavatam’s Tenth Canto, Part 2, by A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada, page 304, Publisher Bhaktivedanta Trust, 2003 Edition]
<p>Besides Pandit Jaydev Sharma also translates it as ‘The enemies of Vedas’, Almost every commentator and translator has given the same meaning.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.4 “O God and learned person! you take the people to the target through the path of religion and justice and protect them. If you commit a sin, the soul or God is not infested with it. Those who denounce the Vedas and God, you cast your anger on them. Therefore, we should admire your greatness.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda (Arya Samaj).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="222" class="wp-image-7322" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi31.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26-300x130.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.1 …destroy the enemies of Vedas</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="502" height="185" class="wp-image-7323" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi32.png?w=502" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png 502w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27-300x111.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8 …burn down the enemies of God, Vedas and the malice…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="481" height="248" class="wp-image-7324" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi33.png?w=481" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png 481w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28-300x155.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 481px) 100vw, 481px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.52.3 …cast your destroying weapon for the destruction of the enemies of Veda, wealth and crops.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="497" height="352" class="wp-image-7325" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi34.png?w=497" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.4 …he slays, unasked, the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="505" height="243" class="wp-image-7326" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi35.png?w=505" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png 505w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8; 6.52.3, Atharva veda 20.96.4; 2.12.6 are translated into English from the Hindi Bhashya.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THE BLASPHEMERS</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.72.1 …ye killed all darkness and the Gods’ blasphemers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="479" height="93" class="wp-image-7327" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi36.png?w=479" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png 479w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 479px" /></p>
<p>It is mentioned in Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam)</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam 4.4.17 Sati continued: If one hears an irresponsible person blaspheme the master and controller of religion, one should block his ears and go away if unable to punish him. But if one is able to kill, then one should by force cut out the blasphemer’s tongue and kill the offender, and after that one should give up his own life.</p>
<p>ISKCON scholar writes on this verse,</p>
<p>“If possible she should have cut out Daksha’s tongue because he blasphemed Lord Siva. In other words, since Lord Siva is the protector of religion, a person who vilifies him should be killed at once, and after killing such a person, one should give up one’s life…The instruction set forth here in Srimad-Bhagavatam is that one should not tolerate at any cost the activities of a person who vilifies or blasphemes an authority. If one is a Brahmana he should not give up his body because by doing so he would be responsible for killing a Brahmana; therefore a Brahmana should leave the place or block his ears so that he will not hear the blasphemy. If one happens to be a Kshatriya he has the power to punish any man; therefore a Kshatriya should at once cut out the tongue of the vilifier and kill him. But as far as the Vaisyas and Sudras are concerned, they should immediately give up their bodies.” [<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"> http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17 <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.61.3 Thou castest down, Sarasvati, those who scorned the Gods…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="478" height="120" class="wp-image-7328" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi37.png?w=478" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png 478w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32-300x75.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.14 Burn up the demons with thy fiercest flaming brand, those who have scorned thee in thy manifested might…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="147" class="wp-image-7329" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi38.png?w=492" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33-300x90.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>Recommended reading <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/vedas-and-world-peace-part-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas and World Peace part 2</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Overpopulation</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overpopulation in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; by Sulaiman Razvi India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7484" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg" width="382" height="322" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-300x253.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-768x647.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 382px) 100vw, 382px" /></p>
<p>by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% population would become majority couple of years. I fail to understand why Hindus are so scared of becoming minority? Aren’t Hindus living as minority in Muslim majority countries like Malaysia, Indonesia, UAE and Bangladesh without facing any sort of discrimination which non Hindus face in India? Are they scared that once the become minority they would be treated the same way they treat minorities and Dalits presently in India? On the one hand they spread fear mongering that Muslims would soon become majority but on the other hand they are indulged in changing demographics of states which sizeable Muslim population. Muslims were once a majority community in Jammu and were reduced to minority via ethnic cleansing in Jammu massacre by Kashmiri Hindus more particularly by the Dogra Hindus. Attempts are made to change demographics of Muslim majority Kashmir and same is happening with states like Bengal and Assam which has 30% each Muslim population, these states were excluded from Inner Line Permit which means Hindus coming from Bangladesh and Pakistan would not be settled in any North-Eastern states of India but in these two states Bengal and Assam. It was decided that people with more than 2 children would not get government jobs in Assam, this was cleverly implemented as Hindus as Total Fertility Rate less than 2 in Assam while Muslims have higher than 2. But such law was not implemented in states like Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, Rajasathan… where Hindu fertility rate is higher than 2. Assam Chief Minister from BJP Hemanta Biswa specifically <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/assam-implement-two-child-policy-avail-govt-schemes-cm-himanta-biswa-sarma-1817189-2021-06-20" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">appealed<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> to the Muslim immigrants to adopt family planning. Two Child norm has been implemented in Assam and people with more than 2 children will not be able to avail some government benefits, but this law is not applicable to some Hindu classes such as SC, ST and the Tea tribe. He says he want upliftment Muslims from poverty by implementing the two child policy norm.Family planning has been a issue since independence but Hindutvadis want to implement two child policy norm in states which has Hindu TFR less than national average, two child policy would probably be implemented when Hindu TFR falls below 2.</p>
<p>Without wasting anymore time let’s see what Hindu scriptures says about population control. It is mentioned in RigVed,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.85.45 O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. Vouchsafe to her ten sons, and make her husband the eleventh man. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="105" class="wp-image-7485" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p><span id="more-927"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.24.5 Grant, Agni, to the worshipper wealth rich in heroes, plenteous store, Make thou us rich with many sons. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="82" class="wp-image-7486" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Grihya Sutra,</p>
<p>Sankhayana Grihya Sutra 1.19.6 ‘Give birth to a male child; may after him (another) male be born; their mother shalt thou be, of the born, and (to others) mayst thou give birth…</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Upanishad,</p>
<p>Khandogya Upanishad, 1 Prapathaka, Kanda 5, verse 4. &#8216;Him I sang praises to, therefore art thou my only son,&#8217; thus said Kaushitaki to his son. &#8216;Do thou therefore sing praises to the breath as manifold, if thou wishest to have many sons.&#8217;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in the Purana that Hindu god Krishna had ten sons from each wife,</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagvat Purana) 10.61.1 Sukadeva Gosvami said: Each of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa&#8217;s wives gave birth to ten sons, who were not less than their father, having all His personal opulence.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse,</p>
<p>&#8221;Lord Kṛṣṇa had 16,108 wives, and thus this verse indicates that the Lord begot 161,080 sons&#8221; He also writes on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19</p>
<p>http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_10.61.1</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>He wrote,</p>
<p>&#8221;&#8230;The birth of a human being is a great science, and therefore reformation of the act of impregnation according to the Vedic ritual called Garbhādhāna-samskāra is very important for generating good population. The problem is not to check the growth of the population, but to generate good population on the level of Vidura, Vyāsa and Maitreya. There is no need to check the growth of population if the children are born as human beings with all precautions regarding their birth. So-called birth control is not only vicious but also useless.&#8221; A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>He also wrote,</p>
<p>“&#8230;In every state all over the world, such activities are encouraged by the government in the form of birth control. Women are supplied pills, and they are allowed to go to a clinical laboratory to get assistance for abortions. This is going on as a result of sense gratification. Actually sex life is meant for begetting a good child, but because people have no control over the senses and there is no institution to train them to control the senses, the poor fellows fall victim to the criminal offenses of sense gratification, and they are punished after death as described in these pages of Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam.” A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.30.21 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" data-wpel-link="internal"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-7487" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" alt="" width="2560" height="2208" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-300x259.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1024x883.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-768x662.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1536x1325.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-2048x1767.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></a></p>
<p>Shankaracharya Vasudevananda Saraswati of Badrikashram tells Hindu women to produce 10 children. <a href="http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>https://scroll.in/latest/825148/rss-backed-seer-asks-hindus-to-have-10-children-says-god-will-take-care-of-them-toi</p>
<p>Hindu religious and political leader Sakshi Maharaj asks Hindu women to produce 4 children. <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><br />
<a href="http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>‘Hindus should beget four children till Uniform Civil Code is implemented’, says senior priest Swami Govindadev Giriji Maharaj of Bharat Mata Mandir in Haridwar<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Prachi says asked Hindus to have 4 children, not 40 puppies<br />
<a href="http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How the Gita Press opposed birth control to shore up the Hindu population<br />
<a href="https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>To save religion, Hindus should follow &#8216;we 2, our 8&#8217; policy: religious guru Swami Prabodhananda Giri<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Pragya Thakur appeals Hindus to have more children, says she will take care of them.<br />
<a href="https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Now, Saffron leaders ask Hindus to have 10 kids to ensure survival of religion</strong><br />
seer Ramanandacharya Raghvachrya said Hindus were facing threat across the world. “Lord Krishna had 16,108 wives and he had 10 children from each of them. The world will be ruled by those who have maximum population. Lord Ram too had asked his brother Bharat to have more sons for protection of the religion“</p>
<p>Slogan of ‘hum do, hamare do’ will not work. Each Hindu family should have at least eight children,” said Kanhaiyya Das, a top priest from Ayodhya.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>Couple hands over 13th girl<br />
</strong> Kamli gave her 13th daughter to the Devarakonda Shishu Vihar.<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>One son, 13 daughters and counting — all for another boy</strong><br />
Kanu confesses that her body is now unable to bear the stress of pregnancies.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Every Hindu family with five children will get Rs 2 lakh: Shiv Sena<br />
Each family that has five kids between 2010 to 2015 will get Rs 2 lakh.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Produce more children, RSS tells Hindu couples<br />
<a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Make it 5 kids: BJP leader Shyamal Goswami from West Bengal to Hindu women<br />
<a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the same time, there are also demands by leaders like Giriraj Singh and Baba Ramdev to implement two-child policy. Confusing, isn&#8217;t it? Let me explain it to you. Firstly one needs to question them why there&#8217;s a demand for 2 child policy and not 1 child policy?</p>
<p>How much a community reproduces is reflected in the fertility rate. The fertility rate of Muslims is 2.6 while that of Hindus is 2.1. Hindu religious and political leaders are exhorting Hindus to have more babies so that their population may increase, they hope that Hindus will produce more babies if they urge Hindus to have more babies, whereas there are also leaders like Giriraj and Ramdev who don&#8217;t see the possibility of Hindus having more babies, hence they want to implement 2 child policy as Hindus are already producing 2.1 children on average. So basically 2 child policy won&#8217;t affect them and only Muslims would be affected with the implementation. Event was held in Delhi on world population day attended by Hindu leaders and made inflammatory speeches against Muslims, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnGuY2eFQr8" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Giriraj Singh said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> that &#8220;to tackle declining population of Hindus and to stop the increasing population of Non-Hindus we need a law.&#8221; From his statement, one can easily understand that he wants two-child policy because he is hopeless about Hindus producing more babies.</p>
<p>The day when Hindu fertility rate falls below 1.0 then demand for 1 child policy will grow. Hindu fanatics want others to produce less babies than them, they want others to eat what Hindus wants them to eat, they want others to learn what Hindus wants to teach them, in short, they are enforcing their religion on non-Hindus.</p>
<p>Hindu population in several Arab countries are going to more than double by 2050, imagine if Muslims harass Hindus there like Hindus are unnecessarily harassing Muslims using the bogus myth of Muslim population explosion. As per <a href="https://www.pewforum.org/2015/04/02/middle-east-north-africa/154-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">PEW Research<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, Hindu population in Muslim majority Middle East and North Africa is going to double.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="403" class="wp-image-7488" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-300x189.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s come to Pakistan and Bangladesh. Hindu population is consistently increasing in Bangladesh <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindu-population-in-bangladesh-increasing-sushma-swaraj-in-rajya-sabha-5266275/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/Bangladesh%E2%80%99s-Hindus-number-1.7-crore-up-by-1-p.c.-in-a-year-report/article14397035.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and Pakistan <a href="https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/india/hinduism-fastest-growing-religion-in-pakistan-saudi-arabia-51516.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/hindu-population-in-pakistan-has-grown-at-a-faster-pace-than-in-india-119032600520_1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> whereas Hindu fanatics in India are busy peddling fake data of declining Hindu population in Pakistan and Bangladesh. As per Newslaundry Hindus in Pakistan were <a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/2015/01/09/the-vanishing-hindus-of-pakistan-a-demographic-study-2" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1.3% in 1951<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> after mass migration which increased to 1.85% in 1998 as per <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20140402081116/http:/www.census.gov.pk/Religion.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Pakistan Government Census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, as per official census Hindu population in Pakistan in the year 1951 was 1.6%. According to the <a href="https://tribune.com.pk/story/2119692/1-pakistani-hindus-reject-indias-offer-citizenship/&amp;fbclid=IwAR1qaVQxi3WJOaJ57u4CRTPsxgSqMyi6d4_9CibaH8jKcyilmdNKhjwZ6Vg/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1961 census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, the non-Muslim population was recorded at 2.83%. A decade later in 1972, the census recorded non-Muslim population at 3.25% of the total population. That means, it increased by 0.42%. In the 1981 census, the non-Muslim population was 3.30%. In the next census carried out in 1998, it was recorded as 3.70% of the total population. Population after the mass migration should be taken into consideration not post Independence survey. The second wave of mass migration happened in Bangladesh after the 1971 Liberation war. There were approx 33% Muslims in Delhi, 57% in Punjab, 67% in Jammu (before Jammu massacre). Using these figures one cannot say that Muslim population has been reduced to 14%.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2232" height="2560" class="wp-image-7489" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg 2232w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-262x300.jpeg 262w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-893x1024.jpeg 893w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-768x881.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1339x1536.jpeg 1339w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1785x2048.jpeg 1785w" sizes="(max-width: 2232px) 100vw, 2232px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Abortion is clearly prohibited in Hinduism</strong>,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.105.48 &#8220;Willful abortion and hatred of the husband are great sins in women without any expiation. Hence, she shall be shunned from a distance.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Parasara Smriti 4.20 What sin is incurred in killing a Brahman, abortion causes a sin twice as great; there is no atonement for that sin. The abandonment of such a woman has been ordained by law.</p>
<p>Gautama Dharma Shastra 21.9. A woman becomes an outcast by procuring abortion, by connection with a (man of) lower (caste) and (the like heinous crimes).</p>
<p>Vasistha Samhita 28.7. Those versed in the sacred law state that there are three acts (only) which make women outcasts, (viz.) the murder of the husband, slaying a learned Brâhmana, and the destruction of the fruit of their womb.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now a days Hindus are mocking Muslims of having ten children which isn&#8217;t true, after reading this will they still criticize Muslims with such taunt? Maharishi Manu also had ten sons,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.2 …and the ten sons of the Manu will be Sukshetra, Uttarnaujas, Harisheńa, and others.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Devi Bhagvatam</p>
<p>Devi Bhagvatam 8.4.1-4 The Risi Narayana said :&#8211; The eldest son of Svayambhuva, Priyavrata served always his father and was very truthful. He married the daughter of the Prajâpati Vis&#8217;va Karma&#8230;He begat ten sons, very spiritual and well qualified and one daughter named Ûrjasvatî….</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Mahabharata,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.115 &#8220;Vaisampayana said, &#8216;Meanwhile, O Janamejaya, Dhritarashtra begat upon Gandhari a hundred sons, and upon a Vaisya wife another besides those hundred. And Pandu had, by his two wives Kunti and Madri, five sons who were great charioteers and who were all begotten by the celestials for the perpetuation of the Kuru line.&#8217;</p>
<p>Hindu god Shiva had eight children, Ganesha, Jalandhar, Kartikey, Ashok Sundari, Ayappa, Andhaka, Manasa, and Jyoti. So its not other religion but Hinduism which encourages couple to have more children. Hinduism considers women as a child production machine,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 5.39.67 &#8220;The fruits of the Vedas are ceremonies performed before the (homa) fire; the fruits of an acquaintance with the scriptures are goodness of disposition and conduct. The fruits of women are the pleasures of intercourse and offspring.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Narada Smriti 12.19 Women have been created for the sake of propagation, the wife being the field, and the husband the giver of the seed. The field must be given to him who has seed. He who has no seed is unworthy to possess the field.</p>
<p>Skanda Purana V.iii.103.9-16 “[Atri said]…It is cited by expounders of the Vedas that a woman is one who gives sexual pleasure and a son…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The roots of Rape in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fornication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nirbhaya act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment for rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kancha Ilaiah Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal. Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Written by Kancha Ilaiah<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to behave in a cruel fashion with women. Family upbringing, societal conditioning, religious sagas and political animus, all construct our men and women into being what they are — men as aggressive and women as submissive. Which is why men here, in India, are different from men in other countries.<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-961"></span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Their cultural milieu is different. Their spiritual systems train them differently. It&#8217;s not that only Indian men rape and kill children aged three or five. This happens in other countries too, but they are the rarest of rare cases. Daily reports of infants being raped across the length and breadth of a country is a phenomenon unique to India, a society that&#8217;s otherwise highly conservative. Clearly, the institutional upbringing, including that in family, needs to undergo change.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Every time a gruesome rape gets reported, we all are ashamed and angry. That&#8217;s one thing; but working out ways and means to eradicate such evil is another thing. We cannot leave it entirely to the police or the judiciary to tackle such heinous acts. For, rape is also a cultural problem; and it is a more serious problem because of the extermination of the victim. We need to treat the malaise from its very roots.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We are a society that derives its sense of good and bad from our mythologies and spiritual ethics. Our gods and goddesses are not only worshipped but also adored. And it is our lifelong endeavour to emulate them. This is the cultural environment that shapes the lives of most people in India. So it&#8217;s natural that what gods do influences us much more than the moral lesson at the end. Now consider this: we have gods who, for instance, have cut the nose and ear lobes of a woman who approached them professing her love (Lakshman is depicted as having done this to Shurpanakha), and yet we adore him and see him as a symbol of loyalty, sacrifice and righteous indignation.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Lord Krishna stole the clothes of women while they were bathing in the Yamuna river. He did so to tease them and for the pleasure of watching the beauty of their naked bodies. We hang miniature paintings of the same act in our homes proudly. The young men who grow up seeing this, or listening to the story told in an amused tone are bound to not find such an act abhorrent.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We also have a god, Shiva, who insisted on entering the bathing arena of Goddess Parvati and did so by eliminating a child who was keeping guard at the open door. Lord Ganesha is said to have emerged out of such a union. Is this right or wrong? Our mythology tells us that what a husband does is right, that his will is greater than the woman&#8217;s. If a mythological hero is praised for his acts of killing, drinking and fornicating with multiple women (like Indra did with Rambha, Urvashi, Menaka, Tilottama and so on), it is glorification of such behaviour.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When such stories are a part of the mythological texts, they should, at least, be critically evaluated and given a more contemporary, political reading which is rooted in the concept of equality. Instead, the tendency is to not question what our gods did, but simply admire such acts.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Barring a few exceptions, there is no appreciation, per se, of a healthy man-woman relationship which is rooted in the concept of equality. Indian women are shown as lathangi (a person of delicate body), never strong enough to resist her dehumanisation. Though Durga and Kali are shown as strong, in real life such militancy is not seen as feminine.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Now let us turn to the political spectrum. We have had many great men — Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan etc — who got married at a young age with girls of much younger age, went abroad for higher studies, leaving their wives at home totally illiterate or semi-literate. We do not know how these men, or Gokhale and Tilak, treated their wives.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">But we know that they were all devotees of the deities mentioned above. The only man who treated his wife as a friend and educated her right from the first day of his marriage, Mahatma Jyotirao Phule, is not taught as an example to be emulated in our texts.  Somehow, in our patriarchal cultural milieu, unkind and inhuman treatment of women has never been a matter of concern. It&#8217;s considered sacrilegious, for example, to question Lord Ram for leaving his dutiful wife on the random outburst of a dhobi.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And Sita&#8217;s action, in turn, to not question, but to commit suicide, is considered the epitome of all that is pious. Even Gautam Buddha left his young wife, with an infant child. Questioning such acts has never been part of our public discourse.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Or, look at our cinemas. Ever since the industry came into being, silent or talkie, it has used woman&#8217;s body as a money-making object. The song and dance sequence that it has adopted as an art form falls into a common pattern — every hero is licensed to misuse the body of the heroine. The romance in our film industry is not romance; it is vulgarity bordering on the criminal.<br />
So is it a surprise that men of this country see it as their right to violate women in all spheres of life?<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The writer is director, Centre for the Study of Social Exclusion and Inclusive Policy, Maulana Azad National Urdu University, Hyderabad</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
