<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>shankaracharya &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/shankaracharya/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 13:15:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dowry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari The Manusmriti also known as Manav Dharam Shastra, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Hirday N. Patwari<br />
The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manusm%E1%B9%9Bti" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Manusmriti<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> also known as <em>Manav Dharam Shastra</em>, is the earliest metrical work on Brahminical Dharma in Hinduism. According to Hindu mythology, the Manusmriti is the word of Brahma, and it is classified as the most authoritative statement on Dharma .The scripture consists of 2690 verses, divided into 12 chapters.  It is presumed that the actual human author of this compilation used the eponym ‘Manu’, which has led the text to be associated by Hindus with the first human being and the first king in the Indian tradition.<span id="more-4827"></span><br />
<span id="more-1261"></span><br />
Although no details of this eponymous author’s life are known, it is likely that he belonged to a conservative Brahman class somewhere in Northern India. Hindu apologists consider the Manusmriti as the divine code of conduct and, accordingly, the status of women as depicted in the text has been interpreted as Hindu divine law.  While defending Manusmriti as divine code of conduct for all including women, apologists often quote the verse: <em>“yatr naryasto pojyantay, ramantay tatr devta <strong>[3/56]</strong></em> <em>(where women are provided place of honor, gods are pleased and reside there in that household)</em>, but they deliberately forget all those verses that are full of prejudice, hatred  and discrimination against women.<br />
Here are some of the ‘celebrated’ derogatory comments about women in the Manusmriti :<br />
1. “Swabhav ev narinam …..” – 2/213. It is the nature of women to seduce men in this world; for that reason the wise are never unguarded in the company of females.<br />
2. “Avidvam samlam………..” – 2/214. Women, true to their class character, are capable of leading astray men in this world, not only a fool but even a learned and wise man. Both become slaves of desire.<br />
3. “Matra swastra ………..” – 2/215. Wise people should avoid sitting alone with one’s mother, daughter or sister. Since carnal desire is always strong, it can lead to temptation.<br />
4. “Naudwahay……………..” – 3/8. One should not marry women who has have reddish hair, redundant  parts of the body [such as six fingers], one who is often sick, one without hair or having excessive hair and one who has red eyes.<br />
5. “Nraksh vraksh ………..” – 3/9. One should not marry women whose names are similar to constellations,  trees, rivers, those from a low caste, mountains, birds, snakes, slaves or those whose names inspires terror.<br />
6. “Yasto na bhavet ….. …..” – 3/10. Wise men should not marry women who do not have a brother and whose parents are not socially well known.<br />
7. “Uchayangh…………….” – 3/11. Wise men should marry only women who are free from bodily defects, with beautiful names, grace/gait like an elephant, moderate hair on the head and body, soft limbs and small teeth.<br />
8. “Shudr-aiv bharya………” – 3/12.Brahman men can marry Brahman, Kshatriya, Vaish and even Shudra women but Shudra men can marry only Shudra women.<br />
9. “Na Brahman kshatriya..” – 3/14. Although Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish men have been allowed inter-caste marriages, even in distress they should not marry Shudra women.<br />
10. “Heenjati striyam……..” – 3/15. When twice born [dwij=Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaish] men in their folly marry low caste Shudra women, they are responsible for the degradation of their whole family. Accordingly, their children adopt all the demerits of the Shudra caste.<br />
11. “Shudram shaynam……” – 3/17. A Brahman who marries a Shudra woman, degrades himself and his whole family  ,becomes morally degenerated , loses Brahman status and his children too attain status  of shudra.<br />
12. “Daiv pitrya………………” – 3/18. The offerings made by such a person at the time of established rituals are neither accepted by God nor by the departed soul; guests also refuse to have meals with him and he is bound to go to hell after death.<br />
13. “Chandalash ……………” – 3/240. Food offered and served to Brahman after Shradh ritual should not be seen by a chandal, a pig, a cock,a dog, and a menstruating women.<br />
14. “Na ashniyat…………….” – 4/43. A Brahman, true defender of his class, should not have his meals in the company of his wife  and even avoid looking at her. Furthermore, he should not look towards her when she is having her meals or when she sneezes/yawns.<br />
15. “Na ajyanti……………….” – 4/44. A Brahman in order to preserve his energy and intellect, must not look at women who applies collyrium to her eyes, one who is massaging her nude body or one who is delivering a child.<br />
16. “Mrshyanti…………….” – 4/217. One should not accept meals from a woman who has extra marital relations; nor from a family exclusively dominated/managed by women or a family whose 10 days of impurity because of death have not passed.<br />
17. “Balya va………………….” – 5/150. A female child, young woman or old woman is not supposed to work independently even at her place of residence.<br />
18. “Balye pitorvashay…….” – 5/151. Girls are supposed to be in the custody of their father when they are children, women must be under the custody of their husband when married and under the custody of her son as widows. In no circumstances is she allowed to assert herself independently.<br />
19. “Asheela  kamvrto………” – 5/157. Men may be lacking virtue, be sexual perverts, immoral and devoid of any good qualities, and yet women must constantly worship and serve their husbands.<br />
20. “Na ast strinam………..” – 5/158. Women have no divine right to perform any religious ritual, nor make vows or observe a fast. Her only duty is to obey and please her husband and she will for that reason alone be exalted in heaven.<br />
21. “Kamam to………………” – 5/160. At her pleasure [after the death of her husband], let her emaciate her body by living only on pure flowers, roots of vegetables and fruits. She must not even mention the name of any other men after her husband has died.<br />
22. “Vyabhacharay…………” – 5/167. Any women violating duty and code of conduct towards her husband, is disgraced and becomes a patient of leprosy. After death, she enters womb of Jackal.<br />
23. “Kanyam bhajanti……..” – 8/364. In case women enjoy sex with a man from a higher caste, the act is not punishable. But on the contrary, if women enjoy sex with lower caste men, she is to be punished and kept in isolation.<br />
24. “Utmam sevmansto…….” – 8/365. In case a man from a lower caste enjoys sex with a woman from a higher caste, the person in question is to be awarded the death sentence. And if a person satisfies his carnal desire with women of his own caste, he should be asked to pay compensation to the women’s faith.<br />
25. “Ya to kanya…………….” – 8/369. In case a woman tears the membrane [hymen] of her Vagina, she shall instantly have her head shaved or two fingers cut off and made to ride on Donkey.<br />
26. “Bhartaram…………….” – 8/370. In case a women, proud of the greatness of her excellence or her relatives, violates her duty towards her husband, the King shall arrange to have her thrown before dogs at a public place.<br />
27. “Pita rakhshati……….” – 9/3. Since women are not capable of living independently, she is to be kept under the custody of her father as child, under her husband as a woman and under her son as widow.<br />
28. “Imam hi sarw………..” – 9/6. It is the duty of all husbands to exert total control over their wives. Even physically weak husbands must strive to control their wives.<br />
29. “Pati bharyam ……….” – 9/8. The husband, after the conception of his wife, becomes the embryo and is born again of her. This explains why women are called Jaya.<br />
30. “Panam durjan………” – 9/13. Consuming liquor, association with wicked persons, separation from her husband, rambling around, sleeping for unreasonable hours and dwelling -are six demerits of women.<br />
31. “Naita rupam……………” – 9/14. Such women are not loyal and have extra marital relations with men without consideration for their age.<br />
32. “Poonshchalya…………” – 9/15. Because of their passion for men, immutable temper and natural heartlessness, they are not loyal to their husbands.<br />
33. “Na asti strinam………” – 9/18. While performing namkarm and jatkarm, Vedic mantras are not to be recited by women, because women are lacking in strength and knowledge of Vedic texts. Women are impure and represent falsehood.<br />
34. “Devra…sapinda………” – 9/58. On failure to produce offspring with her husband, she may obtain offspring by cohabitation with her brother-in-law [devar] or with some other relative [sapinda] on her in-law’s side.<br />
35. “Vidwayam…………….” – 9/60. He who is appointed to cohabit with a widow shall approach her at night, be anointed  with clarified butter and silently beget one son, but by no means a second one.<br />
36. “Yatha vidy……………..” – 9/70. In accordance with established law, the sister-in-law [bhabhi] must be clad in white garments; with pure intent her brother-in-law [devar] will cohabitate with her until she conceives.<br />
37. “Ati kramay……………” – 9/77. Any women who disobey orders of her lethargic, alcoholic and diseased husband shall be deserted for three months and be deprived of her ornaments.<br />
38. “Vandyashtamay…….” – 9/80. A barren wife may be superseded in the 8<sup>th</sup> year; she whose children die may be superseded in the 10<sup>th</sup> year and she who bears only daughters may be superseded in the 11<sup>th</sup> year;  but she who is quarrelsome may be superseded without delay.<br />
39. “Trinsha……………….” – 9/93. In case of any problem in performing religious rites, males between the age of 24 and 30 should marry a female between the age of 8 and 12.<br />
40. “Yambrahmansto…….” – 9/177. In case a Brahman man marries Shudra woman, their son will be called ‘Parshav’ or ‘Shudra’ because his social existence is like a dead body.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/the-status-of-women-as-depicted-by-manu-in-the-manusmriti/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Status Of Women As Depicted By Manu In The Manusmriti</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upanishads: An analysis</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apara Vidya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chandogya Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ganganath Jha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mundaka Upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panditaa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polygyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prajapati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rahu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rishi Yajnavalkya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Maadhavananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swami Nikhilananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad In the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad. Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>In <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="229" height="356" class="wp-image-7250 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa1.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.jpeg 229w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-193x300.jpeg 193w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /> the Vedic literature, Upanishads are commonly ranked after the four Vedas. As a matter of fact Upanishads are themselves contained in the Vedas. The 40th chapter of Shukla (White) Yajurveda is called Isavasya Upanishad, and it is considered to be the first Upanishad.</p>
<p>Later Hindu scholars considered the Upanishads to be superior to the Vedas. This is the reason that the maximum number of quotations in their books are from the Upanishads while Vedic mantras are rarely quoted. Upanishads are considered as the primary source of Hindu theology.</p>
<p>More than 200 Upanishads are known, of which a dozen are variously referred to as the principal, (mukhya) main or old Upanishads. They are:</p>
<p>1. Isavasya 2. Aitareya 3. Chandogya 4. Kena 5. Taittiriya 6. Katha 7. Shvetashvatara 8. Brihadaranyak 9. Prasna 10. Mundak 11. Maandukya 12. Kaushtaki  Upanishad.</p>
<p><span id="more-5645"></span></p>
<p>Scholars disagree about the exact dates of the composition of the Upanishads. According to Dr. Radhakrishnan, they were composed between 800 B.C to 600 B.C.</p>
<p>Many Upanishads are collections of mutually unrelated and mutually contradictory statements. Every Upanishads is self refuting. Also, one Upanishad says one thing about a certain theme while another Upanishad says something entirely different. It appears that Upanishad writers were not intending to write a book. May be these were their personal notes which they expanded over time without any connection to earlier notes. This is the reason that many mutually contradictory schools like Advaita (Monism), Vishishtadvaita (qualified Monism) and Dvaita (Dualism) are derived from the Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>Opposition to the Vedas</strong></p>
<p>The Upanishads reject the Karmakaanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. For example, Mundaka Upanishad 1/1/5 calls the four Vedas as ‘lower knowledge’  (Apra) and says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="614" height="65" class="wp-image-7251" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-9.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa2.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“The lower knowledge (Apara) is the Rig-veda, Yajur-veda, Sama-veda, Atharva-veda, Siksha (phonetics), Kalpa (ceremonial), Vyakarana (grammar), Nirukta (etymology), Khandas (metre), Jyotisha (astronomy);”</p>
<p>Explaning the word ‘Apara’ Shankaracharya has written in his commentary on verse 4,</p>
<p><strong><em>Apara Vidya</em> is ignorance and that ought to be dispelled.</strong> When what is known is <em>Apara Vidya</em>, i.e., the subject of ignorance, nothing can be known as it is.</p>
<p>Condemning the Karma-kanda of the four Vedas, the same Upanishad says,</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="454" height="64" class="wp-image-7252" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-10.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa3.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“But frail, in truth, are those boats, the sacrifices (Yagyas), the eighteen (consisting of the sixteen <em>Ritviks</em>, the sacrificer and his wife), in which this lower ceremonial has been told. Fools who praise this as the highest good, are subject again and again to old age and death.”</p>
<p>(Mundaka Upanishad 1/2/7)</p>
<p>Believers in Karma-kaanda are being insulted as fools. This condemnation of ritualism continues in verses 8 and 9.</p>
<p><strong>Mythical Teachings</strong></p>
<p>In contrast to the above condemnation of Vedic rituals, other Upanishads themselves give strange unscientific rituals to obtain various blessings. For example consider the following recipes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="624" height="61" class="wp-image-7253" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-11.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa4.gif?w=860&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a fair complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study one Veda and that he should attain a full term of life, then they (husband and wife) should have rice cooked in milk and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>(Brihadaranyaka-Upanishad 6/4/14)</p>
<p>Here, the recipe given to produce a white son is white milk and white rice. Will this recipe work for an African kid? Let us not go far away. Will it work for the indigenous dark races of India? Will it make them white? Further how is this recipe supposed to make the born chlid a scholar of one Veda? Will the missionaries of Upanishads kindly explain this amazing scientific (?) verse to us?</p>
<p>Notice one more thing. Contrary to the condemnation of the Vedas by Mundaka Upanishad, this verse is giving a recipe to make the child a scholar of one Veda.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 15</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a tawny or brown complexion should be born to him</strong>, that he should study two Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in curds and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>This is also an amazing technique of producing colourful children. Additionally, just with a slight change of recipe the child will become a scholar of two Vedas.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 16</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a son with a dark complexion and red eyes should be born to him</strong>, that he should study three Vedas and that he should attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked in water and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Are all Trivedis and Tripathis in India born by this recipe?</p>
<p><strong>Verse 17</strong></p>
<p>After a long search I was finally able to find a recipe for producing a girl child in Hindu texts. This verse gives that recipe.</p>
<p>If a man wishes that <strong>a daughter should be born to him</strong> who will be a scholar and attain a full term of life, then they should have rice cooked with sesamum and eat it with clarified butter. Thus they should be able to beget such a daughter.</p>
<p>I will not comment on this par excellence scientific (?) recipe mentioned in this verse. My primary concern here is about the word scholar (Panditaa in Sanskrit), for which we see the next topic ‘Upanishads and Women’ below.</p>
<p><strong>Verse 18</strong></p>
<p>If a man wishes that a son should be born to him who will be a famous scholar, frequenting assemblies and speaking delightful words, a student of all the Vedas and an enjoyer of the full term of life,<strong> he should have rice cooked with the meat of a young bull or of one more advanced in years</strong> and he and his wife should eat it with clarified butter. Then they should be able to beget such a son.</p>
<p>Since the time this recipe has been abandoned in India, true Vedic scholars are not taking birth. Hindus should start eating this diet to know the Vedas properly. Commenting on this recipe, Shankaracharya writes,</p>
<p>“The meat is restricted to that of a vigorous bull,  able to breed, or one more advanced in years.”</p>
<p>Let me share one last recipe with you.</p>
<p><strong>verse 12</strong> of the same chapter says,</p>
<p><strong>Now, if a man’s wife has a lover whom he detests</strong>, he should perform the following rite in order to cast an evil spell upon him: Let him put fire in an unbaked earthen vessel, spread stalks of reed and kusa grass inversely and offer in the sacrificial fire the reed tips, soaked in clarified butter, inversely, repeating the following mantra: “You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your prana and apana, you, (**HERE THE NAME OF THE LOVER SHOULD BE UTTERED**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your sons and cattle, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your Vedic rites and those done according to the Smritis, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! You have made a libation in my kindled fire! I take away your hopes and expectations, you, (**NAME OF THE LOVER**)! He whom a brahmin who knows this rite curses, departs from this world impotent and shorn of merit. <strong>Therefore let no one even joke with the wife of a Vedic scholar who knows this rite;</strong> for he who has this knowledge is a dangerous enemy.</p>
<p>I feel this is nothing but a fraudulent way of looting the innocent folk who are afraid of mantra-tantra. How will burning the fire in a vessel cause the death of someone else? And why is this formula not taught to a wife whose husband has a lover whom she detests? This clearly shows a sanction of polygamy in Hindu texts.</p>
<p><strong>Upanishads and Women</strong></p>
<p>I was initially glad to see that even a girl in Hinduism can become a scholar as per Briahadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/17 quoted above. However, when I read the oldest commentary of the leading scholar of Hinduism, Adi Shankaracharya, on this verse, I was disappointed. He writes,</p>
<p>दुहितुः पांडित्यं गृहतंत्रविषयमेव वेदे अनधिकारात</p>
<p>“The scholarship of the daughter is regarding domestic affairs only, for she is not entitled to read the Vedas.”</p>
<p><strong>Women as objects of lust</strong></p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/8/1 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="603" height="72" class="wp-image-7254" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-12.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa5.gif?w=816&amp;h=98" /></p>
<p>“Woman, O Gautama, is the fire, her sexual organ is the fuel, what invites is the smoke, the vagina is the flame, what is done inside is the embers, the pleasures are the sparks.”</p>
<p>A simlar verse is found in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/12/13.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 2/13/1-2 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="386" height="163" class="wp-image-7255" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-13.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa6.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>1. A man’s beckoning to a woman is the syllable <em>Him</em>; his gratifying her is the <em>Prastava</em>; his lying with her is the <em>Pratihara</em>; his spending time with her is the <em>Nidhana</em>; and the finishing of the sexual act is also the <em>Nidhana</em>. This is the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse.</p>
<p>2. He who thus knows the <em>Vamadevya Saman </em>as interwoven in sexual intercourse does not suffer from the pang of separation and procreates from every intercourse; he reaches the full length of life, lives brightly, becomes great in children and cattle, great in fame. For him the injunction is: <strong>“Do not reject a woman who comes to you seeking intercourse”</strong>.</p>
<p>This is the Upanishadic version of Kamasutra, so much that many scholars prefer not to comment on them. Scholar Ganganath Jha has translated Chandogya Upanishad into English but he has left these verses untranslated.</p>
<p><strong>Why and How woman was created?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/2-3 mentions,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="241" class="wp-image-7256" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-14.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa7.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Prajapati said to Himself: “Well, let Me make a firm basis for it (semen).” So He created woman. Having created her, He worshipped her bottom portion. Therefore one should worship the bottom portion of a woman. He (Prajapati) extended His organ that projects and with it impregnated her.”</p>
<p>Her lap is the sacrificial altar, her hair the sacrificial grass, her skin within the organ the lighted fire; the two labia of the vulva are the two stones of the soma—press. He who, knowing this, practises sexual intercourse wins as great a world as is won through the Vijapeya sacrifice; he acquires for himself the fruit of the good deeds of the woman. But he who, without knowing this, practises sexual intercourse turns over to the woman his own good deeds.</p>
<p>Let me bring to your notice that the English translation of Brihadaranyak Upanishad published by Swami Maadhavananda does not translate verses 3, 4 and 5 and even the Shankar bhashya is not translated. I have reproduced the translation of Swami Nikhilananda  which can be found here</p>
<p><a href="http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://swamij.com/upanishad-brihadaranyaka.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Now let me quote the Brihadaranyak Upanishad 6/4/4-5</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="372" height="317" class="wp-image-7257" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-15.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa8.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>4) Having known this, Uddalaka the son of Aruna, Naka the son of Mudgala and Kumara—harita said: “Many mortals, brahmins only in name, perform the sexual act without knowledge of what has been said and <strong>depart from this world impotent</strong> and without merit.” Even if this much semen—of one asleep or of one awake—is spilled,</p>
<p>5) <strong>He should touch it</strong> and repeat the following mantra: “Whatever semen of mine has spilt on earth, whatever has flowed to plants, whatever to water, I reclaim it.” <strong>With these words he should take the semen with his ring finger and thumb and rub it between his breasts or eyebrows,</strong> repeating the following mantra: “Let the semen return to me, let Vigour come to me again, let glow and good fortune come to me again. May the deities who dwell in the sacrificial fire put the semen back in its proper place.”</p>
<p>Readers can themselves judge these words.</p>
<p><strong>Beat your wife?</strong></p>
<p>Brihadranyak Upanishad 6/4/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="376" height="106" class="wp-image-7258" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-16.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa9.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>If she (the wife) does not willingly yield her body to him (her husband), he should buy her with presents. If she is still unyielding, <strong>he should beat her with a stick or with his hand and overcome her</strong>, repeating the following mantra: “With power and glory I take away your glory.” Thus she becomes discredited.</p>
<p>What kind of teaching is this? These are only productions of imbalanced minds.</p>
<p>I would suggest that you read the remaining portion of the chapter (i.e. Brihad. Upanishad Part 6, Chapter 4) from the above link yourself because it is too obscene to be posted here.</p>
<p><strong>Polygyny</strong></p>
<p>Throughout the Upanishads there are evidences of polygyny being sanctioned. The Rishis of the Upanishads used to have several wives. For example, Yajnavalkya has two wives as is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/5/1.</p>
<p>अथ ह याज्ञवल्क्यस्य द्वे भार्ये बभूवतुर्मैत्रेयी च कात्यायनी च</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya had two wives: Maitreyi and Katyayani”</p>
<p><strong>Unscientific concepts</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the above mentioned mythical teachings, the Upanishads contain many factually unscientific errors.</p>
<p>1. Chandogya Upanishad 8/13/1 says</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="611" height="96" class="wp-image-7259" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-17.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa10.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>From the dark I come to the variegated; from the variegated I come to the Dark. Shaking off evil as a horse shakes dust from its hair, freeing myself from the body <strong>as the moon frees itself from the mouth of Rahu</strong>, I fulfil all ends and obtain the uncreated World of Brahman.</p>
<p>The lunar eclipse is thus thought to be the work of Rahu, an Asura (demon), who eats the moon.</p>
<p>2. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/3/2 mentions the dimensions of the place where those people go who have performed the Horse Sacrifice (Ashwamedh)? It says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="362" height="148" class="wp-image-7260" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-18.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa11.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“Thirty—two times the space traversed by the sun’s chariot in a day makes this plane (loka); around it, covering twice the area, is the world (prithivi); around the world, covering twice the area, is the ocean. Now, as is the edge of a razor or the wing of a fly, so is there just that much space between the two halves of the cosmic shell. Through that opening they go out. “Fire, in the form of a falcon, delivered them to Vayu. Vayu, placing them in itself, took them where previous performers of the Horse Sacrifice were.”</p>
<p>Even a primary pass child today knows that there is no such meeting point of the sky and earth and no opening. They also know that there is no chariot pulling the Sun.</p>
<p>3. Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/19 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="418" height="42" class="wp-image-7261" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-19.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa12.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p>“seventy two thousand (72,000) nerves called <strong>hita</strong>, which extend from the heart throughout the whole body.”</p>
<p>I would like to see the scientific confirmation of this statement. There are millions of nerves and blood vessels extending throught the body from the heart and not just 72,000. Another erroneous figure given in the Upanishads.</p>
<p>These are only few of the unscientific teachings of the ‘world renowned’ Upanishads.</p>
<p><strong>The roots of caste based discrimination</strong></p>
<p>Upanishads clearly spell out that caste is based on birth due to the deeds of previous lives. This is the reason for this idea taking such root in the Hindu society that it continues to divide Indian society even today.</p>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/10/7 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="99" class="wp-image-7262" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-20.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa13.gif?w=821&amp;h=134" /></p>
<p>“Those whose conduct here on earth has been good will quickly attain some good birth—<strong>birth as a brahmin, birth as a kshatriya, or birth as a vaisya</strong>. But those whose conduct here has been evil will quickly attain some evil birth—<strong>birth as a dog, birth as a pig, or birth as a chandala</strong>.”</p>
<p>On one hand Upanishads talk of one Soul permeating all; only Brahma being real and the world being an illusion, while on the other hand they sanction this cruel birth based caste system. It seems that even the Rishis bent of proving that the world is an illusion, used  to keep personal gains in mind. This idea becomes clear when we observe the lifestyle of Rishi Yajnavalkya, who in trying to prove the world to be an illusion, extracted huge fee (<em>Dakshina</em>) from others. When he was unable to respond to some questions he used to threaten the questioner with dire consequences, which turned the questioner silent out of fear.</p>
<p>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/1/1-2 says,</p>
<p>“Janaka, Emperor of Videha, performed a sacrifice in which gifts were freely distributed among the priests. Brahmin scholars from the countries of Kuru and Panchala were assembled there. Emperor Tanaka of Videha wished to know which of these brahmins was the most erudite Vedic scholar. So he confined a <strong>thousand cows in a pen and fastened on the horns of each ten padas of gold</strong>.</p>
<p>He said to them: “Venerable brahmins, let him among you who is the best Vedic scholar drive these cows home.” None of the brahmins dared. <strong>Then Yajnavalkya said to one of his pupils: “Dear Samsrava, drive these cows home.”</strong> He drove them away. The brahmins were furious and said: “How does he dare to call himself the best Vedic scholar among us?” Now among them there was Asvala, the hotri priest of Emperor Janaka of Videha. He asked Yajnavalkya: “Are you indeed the best Vedic scholar among us, O Yajnavalkya?” He replied: “I bow to the best Vedic scholar, but I just wish to have these cows.” Thereupon the hotri Asvala determined to question him.”</p>
<p>The Yajnavalkya started answering the questions. Interestingly, Shankaracharya mentions in the preface of his commentary of Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/27,</p>
<p>“One should take away catlle of Vedic scholars who do not truly know Brahma.”</p>
<p>Similarly, when Balaki proposes to speak about God to Ajatashatru, King of Kashi, Ajatasatru offers him, for this proposal, a thousand cows as his fee. (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 2/1/1)</p>
<p>When King Janaka asked Rishi Yajnavalkya a questions about Brahma, he immediately offered the fee of thousand cows with a bull as large as an elephant (See Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/1/4).</p>
<p>All of these examples prove that imparting the mythical and highly philosophized knowledge of Brahma was a good profession to earn money. However, if someone used to ask difficult questions about God refuting the Rishis conjectures, they were threatened and silenced, as they feared loosing their profession. Two glaring examples can be given.</p>
<p>Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, questioned Yajnavalkya. When she cornered Yajnavalkya with her final quetion, all she got was a threat. This is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/6/1</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya ,” said she, “if all this is pervaded by water, by what, is water pervaded?” “By air, O Gargi.” “By what,is air pervaded?” “By the sky, O Gargi.” “By what is the sky pervaded?” “By the world of the gandharvas, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gandharvas pervaded?” “By the world of the sun, O Gargi. “By what is the world of the sun pervaded?” “By the world of the moon, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the moon pervaded?” “By the world of the stars, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the stars pervaded?” “By the world of the gods, O Gargi.” “By what is the world of the gods pervaded?” “By the world of Indra, O Gargi. “By what is the world of Indra pervaded?” “By the World of Virij, O Gargi. “By what is the World of Virij pervaded?” “By the World of Hiranyagarbha, O Gargi.” “By what is the World of Hiranyagarbha pervaded?” <strong>“Do not, O Gargi,” said he, “question too much, lest your head should fall off. You are questioning too much about a deity about whom we should not ask too much. Do not ask too much, O Gargi.” Thereupon Gargi, the daughter of Vachaknu, kept silent.</strong></p>
<p>The freedom of thought of Gargi was curbed by Yajnavalkya by threatening her of death. Is this not a ploy to hide the truth? Thinking people can judge for themselves.</p>
<p>Gargi was fortunate to not die but Shakalya was not so fortunate after disputing with Yajnavalkya. That is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 3/9/26-27.</p>
<p>“Now I ask you about that Person who is to be known only from the Upanishads, who definitely projects those beings and again withdraws them into Himself and who is at the same time transcendental. “If you cannot clearly explain Him to me, your head shall fall off?’ Sakalya did not know Him; his head fell off; and robbers snatched away his bones, mistaking them for something else.</p>
<p>Then Yajnavalkya said: “Venerable brahmins, whosoever among you wishes to question me may now do so, or all of you may. Or whosoever among you desires it, I shall question him, or I shall question all of you. But the brahmins did not dare.”</p>
<p><strong>The ultimate effect of Upanishads</strong></p>
<p>The above mentioned curbs on free thinking are nothing compared to that effect where all distinction of good and evil is erased from the Knower of Brahma (Brahmagyani).  Kaushitaki Upanishad 3/1/ records Lord Indra as saying the following,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="656" height="66" class="wp-image-7263" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-21.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa14.gif?w=834&amp;h=84" /></p>
<p>“He who knows me thus, <strong>by no deed of his is his life harmed, not by the murder of his mother, not by the murder of his father, not by theft, not by the killing of a Brahman. If he is going to commit a sin, the bloom does not depart from his face!</strong>”</p>
<p>The theoretical commandment is exemplified by Lord Indra himself who brags about his murders in this very verse.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="608" height="123" class="wp-image-7264" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-22.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/083114_0825_upanishadsa15.gif?w=734&amp;h=149" /></p>
<p>“I slew the three-headed son of Tvashtri; I delivered the Arunmukhas, the devotees, to the wolves (salavrika); breaking many treaties, I killed the people of Prahlada in heaven, the people of Puloma in the sky, the people of Kalakanga on earth. And not one hair of me was harmed there.”</p>
<p>Thus the people who allow Upanishads to influence them are least bothered about right and wrong. That is why M. N Roy, in his book <em>Fascism; its philosophy, profession and practice</em> traced the influence of Upanishads on Fascism through people like Arthur Schopenhauer and Friedrich Nietzsche. Roy was the first to point out the fact that the roots of fascism lie in the ancient Brahminical religion, and he showed how European, particularly German, fascist philosophers borrowed concepts from Brahminical scholars and scriptures, concepts such as the Aryan race theory, the supremacy of the strong over the weak, the concept of the tyrannical superman and so on. In fact, M.N. Roy issued a’ sharp warning to Indians not to fall prey to Hindu revivalism because he saw that it was nothing but fascism in a different garb. You can see that for yourself. What was the destruction of the Babri Masjid and the mass slaughter of the Muslims but naked fascism? Goebbels, Hitler’s chief propagandist, wrote in one of his books, ‘The state must have the power to break its own laws’. That is precisely what happened on 6 December, 1992. The state was actively involved in the breaking of the mosque. Goebbels also remarked, ‘Repeat a lie- a hundred times and it becomes a truth’. You can see this Chanakyan tactic in all the false Hindutva propaganda about Muslims, Christians and Communists. We all know what horrendous and baseless things they are writing about Muslims in the school textbooks now. They have attributed all the ills of India to the Muslims, painting all of them as immoral.</p>
<p>Hindutva fascism has to be fought at the ideological level, by a superior ideology based on rationalism, and not just on the political plane. Islam is the alternative and hope for those weak humans in India who are discriminated by the cruel divisions of Caste System whose roots lie in the ancient Hindu texts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/upanishads-an-analysis/" data-wpel-link="internal">Upanishads: An analysis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Hinduism?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[33 gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrisitanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[definition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism oldest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindusim vs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat rai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polytheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shashtra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind? At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Written by Ibn Muhammad<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is a hodge-podge or conglomeration of many mutually conflicting religions, and is not the child, so to say, of any one father. Those who practice it differ very much from one another in their faith and practice. Hinduism includes in it Vedism, Brahmanism, Sivaism, Vishnuism, Polytheism, Pantheism, Idolatory in is greatest forms, Tree-Worship, Serpent-Worship, Demon-Worship and so on.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span id="more-5644"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is not easy therefore to give a definition of Hinduism,  &#8220;Hinduism and its gods,&#8221; says Sir Alfred Lyall, &#8220;are a troubled sea, without shore or visible horizon, driven to and fro by the winds of boundless credulity and grotesque invention. A tangled jungle of disorderly superstitions, ghosts and demons, demi-gods and deified saints, household gods, tribe gods, local gods, universal gods, with their countless shrines and temples, and din of their disordent rites, deities who abhor a fly&#8217;s death, those who delight still in human victims, and those who would not either sacrifice or make offerings, such religious chaos&#8221;. <strong><sup>[1]</sup></strong><br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Authoritative Books not one but many</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A further difficulty regarding Hinduism lies in the fact that all its professors have no common sacred Book or Books to depend upon for their doctrines. Some refer to Vedas as the basis of their faith. Others rest their faith on the Shrutis, a term which includes not only the four Vedas but their Brahmanas and Upanishads as well. The Mahabharata styles itself as the fifth Veda, containing the quintessense of all the rest. Other Hindus agains follow the teachings of the Puranas. The present day educated Hindus are mainly depending upon the Bhagavad Gita, a philosophical treatise, for their guidance in matters of faith. We shall therefore briefly inquire into the contents of all these books to see what they teach about God and the way in which man should worship Him.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Religion of the Vedas</h3>
<h4>(a) Nature Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Vedism, or the Religion of the Vedas, teaches the worship of the deified forces or phenomenon of Nature, such as Fire, the Sun, Wnd and Rain. Here is the opening verse of the Rigveda, the oldest Veda, of which the others are mere repetitions and borrowing:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निमीळे पुरोहितं यज्ञस्य देवं रत्वीजम |  होतारं रत्नधातमम || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;I Laud Agni, the great high priest, god, minister of sacrifice, the herald, lavishest of wealth.&#8221; [Rigveda Mandal 1: Sookt 1: Mantra 1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The whole of the Veda goes on in this strain throughout in the hymns collected for different purposes. The contrast between the opening  verse of the Rigveda which teaches Polytheism, and that of the Jewish Bible and of the Holy Qur&#8217;an which teach Monotheism, cannot fail to be noted even by the most superficial reader. Thus the Jewish Pentateuch begins,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>בראשית ברא אלהים את השמים ואת הארץ׃</strong><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.&#8221; [Genesis 1:1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Holy Qur&#8217;an strikes the key note of its whole teaching in a still more profound manner, unparalleled in other religions:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"> &#8211; </span><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">الْحَمْدُ للَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَـلَمِينَ &#8211; الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ &#8211; مَـلِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. All Praise is due to Allah, Lord of the Worlds, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. Master of the Day of Judgement.&#8221;[Surah Al-Fatiha 1:1-4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Thus Vedism teaches the worship of the powers of Nature.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(b) Polytheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That it teaches polytheism is also evident from the expression used in the same verse and in all the succeeding verses as well:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निः पूर्वेभिर्र्षिभिरीड्यो नूतनैरुत | स देवानेह वक्षति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;He (Agni) shall bring hitherward the gods.&#8221; [Rigveda 1:1:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्ने यं यज्ञमध्वरं विश्वतः परिभूरसि | स इद्देवेषु गछति ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Verily goes to the gods.&#8221;[verse 4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निर्होता कविक्रतुः सत्यश्चित्रश्रवस्तमः | देवो देवेभिरा गमत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;May Agni, priest, the god, come hither with the gods.&#8221; [verse 5]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The number of gods in Hindu Pantheon is given as 33 in one place (Rigveda 1:34:11), which says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>आ नासत्या तरिभिर एकादशैर इह देवेभिर यातम मधुपेयम अश्विना | परायुस तारिष्टं नी रपांसि मर्क्षतं सेधतं दवेषो भवतं सचाभुवा ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Come, O Nasatyas, with the thrice-eleven Gods; come, O ye Asvins, to the drinking of the meath. Make long our days of life, and wipe out all our sins: ward off our enemies; be with us evermore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Similarly it is mentioned in Rigveda 8:30:2,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>इति सतुतासो असथा रिशादसो ये सथ तरयश्च तरिंशच्च | मनोर्देवा यज्ञियासः || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Thus be ye lauded, ye destroyers of the foe, ye Three-and-Thirty Deities, The Gods of man, the Holy Ones.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Rigeveda 10:52:6 the number is 3,339. It says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>तरीणि शता तरी सहस्राण्यग्निं तरिंशच्च देवा नवचासपर्यन | औक्षन घर्तैरस्त्र्णन बर्हिरस्मा आदिद्धोतारं नयसादयन्त || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Deities three thousand, three hundred and thirty-nine, have served and honoured Agni, Strewn sacred grass, anointed him with butter, and seated him as Priest, the Gods&#8217; Invoker.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Later Hinduism has gone still further by saying that there are no less than 33 crores of them.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(c) Pantheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Why not then say that everything is God, and God is everything? The Purusha Sukta (Rigveda 10:90) which every orthodox Brahmin is expected even now to recite daily in his prayers shows that Pantheism is also taught in the later portions of the Vedas:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>पुरुष एवेदं सर्वं यद भूतं यच्च भव्यम | उताम्र्तत्वस्येशानो यदन्नेनातिरोहति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;This Purusha(i.e. Brahma or God) is all that yet has been and all that is to be.&#8221; [verse 2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The caste system which has proved the curse of India is likewise taught in the same hymn:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>बराह्मणो.अस्य मुखमासीद बाहू राजन्यः कर्तः | ऊरूतदस्य यद वैश्यः पद्भ्यां शूद्रो अजायत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Brahmana was his (Purusha&#8217;s) mouth. Of both his arms was the Kshatriya made. His thighs became the Vaishya. From his feet the Sudra produced.&#8221;[verse 12]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Religion of the Upanishads</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Upanishads reject the Karma, Kanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. Hence they consist of speculations about the individual souls (atma) and the Supreme soul (Param-atma), and about the relationship subsisting between them, their aim being to get rid of man&#8217;s earthly existence by absorption of the individual soul into the World Soul through correct or true knowledge. They teach that the Universe or Nature (Prakriti) is unreal or <em>Maaya</em>, that is to say, it does not really exist but it only an illusion of the mind. What really exists in the Supreme Soul or Brahman, and the individual souls are all emanations from Him and identical with Him. Only they do not know it, as Brahman has invested Himself/Itself with the <em>Maaya</em>, and they also are under the influence of the same mystic power. The individual souls can be disillusioned only by means of Correct knowledge, and as soon as this consummation is reached, they know themselves to be Brahman, and get absorbed into Him. The famous formula referring to this theory is <strong><em>&#8216;Tat tvam asi&#8217;</em></strong> </span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">तत् त्वम् असि </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;That art thou&#8217;, whoever knows this &#8216;becomes the All&#8217;. Even the gods are not able to prevent him from becoming it. For he becomes their self. <em>[Brihadaranyak Upanishad 1:4:6]</em><br />
</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This theory is known as the Vedanta, the essence of the teaching of the Vedas, and has taken an immense hold on the minds of the people and lent a deeper colour to all subsequent literature. A Christian missionary asked a Brahmin, &#8220;Who and where is Brahman?&#8221; &#8220;He is talking to you,&#8221; was the prompt reply.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A Vedantist once began to dilate upon the truth of his belief in the presence of a king and vehemently maintained that the whole world was <em>Mithya</em> or unreal, imaginary: whereupon an elephant was ordered to be brought quite near to him and the man fled in terror. &#8220;Why do you run away for your life? The elephant is <em>Mithya</em>&#8221; said the king. But the Vedantist proved himself equal to the occasion and without a moment&#8217;s hesistation replied that the running away too was <em>Mithya</em>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Such is the fool&#8217;s paradise in which most of the misguided Hindus live. The expression that is often heard on their lips, and which has unfortunately recently been made famous by Dr. Zakir Naik through his televised public talks:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><em>EKAM EVA ADVITIYAM</em><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;One only without a second&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It does not mean that they believe in the &#8216;Only One True God&#8217; but it is the Vedantic or Pantheistic formula which asserts that the only real existence of the World Soul and the identity of the individual souls within it, totally denying the existence of the phenomenal world.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Puranas</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The characteristic of popular Hinduism of today is the belief in Divine incarnations, idolatory and caste. Popular Hinduism believes in the doctrine of Trimurti or Hindu Trinity as Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, in their characteristic of the Creator, Preserver and Destroyer of the Universe.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Vishnu Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The distinct feature of Vishnu worship is the incarnation of God. When wickedness in the world increases Vishnu is said to take upon himself the form of an animal or man in order to be able to protect the good and to punish the bad. The principle incarnations He is said to have so far assumed are those of (1) a fish, (2) a tortoise, (3) a Boar, (4) a man-lion (5) a Dwarf, (6) a Brahmin hero called Parasu Ram, (7) a Kshatriya Prince, the hero of Ramayana, (8) a shepherd Prince Krishna and (9) a Kshatriya heretic, Buddha.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Krishna declares:<br />
</span></h4>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;On an occasion of marriage, or of enjoying a woman, or when life is in danger, or when one&#8217;s entire property is about to be taken away, or for the sake of a Brahmin, falsehood may be uttered. These five kinds of falsehood have been declared to be sinless. On these occasions falsehood would become truth and truth would become falsehood.&#8221; [Mahabharata Book 8; Karna Parva; Section 69]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Cow Worship</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is natural for Indians to set a high value upon the cow on account of its utility, but the worship the Hindus pay to it is irrational and absurd to a degree. It is considered to be the most sacred of all animals. Every part of its body is considered to be inhabited by some deity or other. Even its excreta are considered to be most sacred. Its urine is looked upon as the best of all holy waters; a sin destroying liquid which sanctifies everything it touches, while nothing purifies like cow-dung. The ashes of its dung sprinkled over a sinner are able to convert him into a saint.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Veneration of Cow in Hindu Culture</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Present day Hindu culture is pivoted solely on the cow. Its material and spiritual concepts are both engulfed in cow worship. Such an animal worship is known as zoolatry. This is a vestide of animistic cultures among whom the worship of monkeys, sheep, elephants, cows and even snakes was prevalent. Animal worship culminated in the taking of human beings for gods so that the silhouettes were stamped on the coins and painted on the flags, and upon their honour depended the glory and honour of their realms.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Among cultivators cow worship is not a strange thing. In many countries, notably, India, Iran and Egypt, it was prevalent. Among Hindus veneration of the cow is referred to in the Vedas as Puranas and in Hindu Jurisprudence and folklore. In the Vedas several verses refer to saluting and prostrating before the cow as the following sections illustrate:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Prajapati and Parameshthin are the two horns, Indra is the head, Agni the forehead, Yama the joint of the neck. King Soma is the brain, Sky is the upper jaw, Earth is the lower jaw&#8230; All worlds and all the gods are as the cow from head to foot.&#8221; [Atharvaved Kaand 9: Sookt 7]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;You are being created and have been created for salutations and prostrations. Salutations and prostration to you, O image of God, to your hair, to your hooves.&#8221; [Atharva 10:10]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Curiously enough, the Vedic Rishis likened the chanting of their mantras (hymn) to the lowing of the cows:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अभि विप्रा अनूषत गावो वत्सं न मातरः | इन्द्रं सोमस्य पीतये || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;As the cows moo in the presence of their calves so do Brahmins recite their mantras while drinking the soma juice in the presence of Indra devta.&#8221; [Rigveda 9:12:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In old Vedic timesthe pious people picked out the grain from the cow-dung, and then ate it. They also squeezed out its water and drank it (Mahabharata). Its urine was considered a source of redemption of sins and a means of cow-dung bathed with water extracted thus. Krishna Ji revered the bull by stroking its back before mounting it. In short, in Hindu religion the cow in venerated to an extent which gods and godesses and even God Himself does not merit.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Cow-Worship and the humiliation of Man</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is to be noted that the sacredness of the cow as compared with the scant regard for human life has come to this that Swami Dayanand Saraswati in accordance with the Vedas, opines that the blood of thousands or hundreds of thousands of humans, may be shed to please these animals; (See his translation of Yajurveda 33:14 and Rigveda 1:121:10)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Vedic times, there lived an untouchable people in a village named Kikat, in todays Bihar. The used to rear cattle. Obviously to the Aryans this was a crime. So they invoked their god Indra to wage war against them and loot their cows.<br />
</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"></span></p>
<p id="VJgEpTj"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="620" height="145" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7245 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"> </span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;O Indra, what do the cows make for you among the Kikatas. They neither yield milk for your offerings, nor do they warm the vessel of libation. Bring to us these cows, bring to us also the wealth of Pramagand (their King). O Brave one, grant us the possessions of the people of low status.&#8221; [Rigveda 3:53:14]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">On the basis of this clear prnouncement, non-Aryans and untouchables have no right to keep cows. Aryans and Brahmins whenever they wish can kill them and appropriate their possessions. Hindu culture thus becomes the culture of the progress, civilization and welfare of the Aryan people alone.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Status of the Cow</h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The fact remains that Hindu culture is based on the cow. Actually it is cow-worship as may be inferred from the discussion so far. As the Noble Qur&#8217;an states,<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;And their hearts absorbed (the worship of) the calf because of their disbelief.&#8221; [Surah Baqarah 2:93]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The cow is also called mother and this is a relic of the age of ignorance. In primitive times when the mother of a young child died, the child too would die of malnutrition after two or three days. The father did not know how to save the child&#8217;s life as a substitute for the mother&#8217;s milk was not known. By chance, some wise person thought of the idea of giving goat&#8217;s milk to the child. As the goat was easier to control and milk than the cow, goat&#8217;s milk was used to save the infant&#8217;s life. Later on the cow was tamed for this purpose. From then on the polytheists began to call the cow &#8216;mata&#8217; i.e. mother. But other animals as well, such as goats, sheep, camels, supply milk as substitute for mother&#8217;s milk; yet they are never called &#8216;mother&#8217;. Strangely enough, in this age of science when so many baby-foods have been invented, none of these is called &#8216;mother&#8217;, yet wealthy and educated Hindus still apply this epithet to the cow alone.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The nation which cannot differentiate between a cow&#8217;s tail and a man&#8217;s head, lives in an extreme abyss of culture. The cow is at the utmost an animal, while even the most degraded man, being still a human being, is yet far superior to a cow.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Gita</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Since Mahabharata fails to serve as a handy and useful book of the essence of Hinduism, the present day educated Hindus are adopting the Bhagvat Gita as their guide.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Like all the other scriptures this famous poem too fails to teach True Religion to mankind. It is a highly Philosophic poem just as ill-suited to teach Religion as Berkley&#8217;s <em>Principle of Human Knowledge </em>or Milton&#8217;s <em>Paradise Lost</em> can be. The principle of its composition is Eclecticism and tries to combine Sankhya, Yoga, and Vedanta teaching into one whole to support the Vaishnava theory of Krishna&#8217;s deification.But is does promote ideas like Polytheism and Caste. Krishna claims to be the author of the caste system in India:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The four Castes were created by me according to the appointment of qualities and works.&#8221; [Gita 4:13]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Gita does not insist on the worship of the One and Only True God but promotes belief in polytheism:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Those who worship gods go to the gods&#8221; [9:25]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Worship the gods thereby; The gods shall yield thee grace.&#8221; [3:3]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That there are inconsistencies in the Bhagvad Gita is admitted today even by Hindu scholars. For example at Chapter 9, stanza 29 Krishna declares that &#8216;none is hateful to me, none dear.&#8217; And yet the remarkable verses at the close of Chapter 12 contradict it, &#8216;Linked by no ties to earth, steadfast in Me, That man I love&#8217;. At Gita Chapter 5, stanza 15 it is said, that &#8216;the Lord receives the sin and merit of none.&#8217; Yet at Chapter 5, stanza 29, and again at Chapter 9, stanza 24, Krishna calls himself &#8216;the Lord and enjoyer&#8217; of all sacrifices and penances. How, it may well be asked, can the Supreme Being &#8216;enjoy&#8217; that which he does not even &#8216;receive&#8217;?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The doctrine of transmigration is the basis from which the argument of Bhagvad Gita takes its start. Matter and spirit are without beginning (13:20). God (Krishna-Vishnu) is eternal, almighty, unborn, without beginning, the great Lord of the World (10:3). He is different not only from the fleeting world, but also from the changeless and indestructible energy of all beings. Vishnu is born from age to age (4:6-8). Krishna-Vishnu is wholly distinct from Brahma and Brahman is distinctly a lower deity than Krishna (11:15,37). In 12:1-7, the two classes, those who believe in a personal God Krishna-Vishnu, i.e. theists, and those who believe in Brahma ,i.e. pantheists are contrasted, and preference is given to former. In other words, final bliss is difficult of attainment for those who follow the Vedas and seek the heaven of Brahma. All external observances and duties prescribed by the Vedas are held to be mischievous and thrown overboard (7:20; 18:34,66). The Vedas and the works enjoined by them cannot win one the vision of the Divine (11:48,53). What a contempt is expressed for the Vedas in the following words: &#8220;Steady understanding does not belong to those, whose minds are drawn by that flowery talk (i.e. Vedas) which is full of ordinances of specific acts for the attainment of pleasures and power, and which promises birth as the fruit of acts- that flowery talk which those unwise ones utter, who are enamoure of Vedic words, who say there is nothing else, who are full of desires, an whose goal is heaven. The Vedas merely relate to the effects of the three qualities; do you, O Arjuna! rise above those effects of the three qualities.&#8221; (2:42-45). Thus the Vedas are being spoken of in very disparaging terms and the followers of Krishna were inimical to the Vedas.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This was in brief about Hinduism and in our future articles all the topics discussed here would be dealt with in detail separately.<br />
</span></p>
<p><img alt="" /></p>
<h5>REFERENCES</h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>[1] </strong><em>Asiatic Studies</em>, Vol 1, pp 2, 3<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and the Vedic Dharma</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inheritance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ravi shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivekananda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wife beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[woman in hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womanizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma. In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color:#333333;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p style="color:#333333;">The destiny of nations is governed by their beliefs and ideas. How a nation treats its men and women also reflects their culture. Let us see the position of women in the Vedic Dharma.</p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">In the Vedas wherever special prayers have been made for children, they have always been for sons. Nowhere is a prayer or charm recited to be granted a daughter. For exmaple,</span></span></p>
<p><span id="more-848"></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">1. O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. <strong style="font-style:inherit;">Vouchsafe to her ten sons</strong>, and make her husband the eleventh man. [Rigved Mandal 10, Sookt 85, Mantra 45]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_rig_10_85_45.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">2. This is thy Soma draught, O bright Âditya: take delight therein. To this mine utterance, O ye men, give credence, what good the man and wife obtain by praying: <strong style="font-style:inherit;">A manly son is born and gathers riches</strong>, and thrives for ever sinless in the dwelling. [Yajurved Adhyay 8, Mantra 5]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/sons_yajur_8_5.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">3. Fathers, bestow on me a babe, <strong style="font-style:inherit;">a boy </strong>enwreathed with lotuses, so that there may be here a man. [Yajurved Adhyay 2, Mantra 33]</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/son_yajur_2_33.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">All prayers for being granted a boy and none for a girl.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Speaking of marriage Swami Dayanad Saraswati says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“In Sanskrit a daughter is called </span><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">duhitri</span></em><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> (from Du – distant, Hit – good), because the marriage of a girl to a man who comes from a distant country or distant part of the same country is productive of good.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">“If the bride’s people do not live very far from her husband’s home, there is a possibility of her parents becoming poor, as whenever she visits her parents, they will have to give her something or other by the way of a present.” </em>[Satyarth Prakash Chapter 4, The advantages and disadvantages of distant and near marriages, Page 85]</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Rigved Mandal 8, Sookt 33, Mantra 17 says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Indra himself hath said, The mind of woman brooks not discipline,</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Her intellect hath little weight</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">.”</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_brain_rig_8_33_17.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">At another place, it is written:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">There cannot be any friendship with a woman. Her heart is</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> like</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> that of a hyena.</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[</span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Rig Veda, 10/95/15</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/women_hayenas_rig_10_95_15.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda says:</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Women are without energy. They should not get a share in the property. Even to the wicked, they speak in a feeble manner. </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Krishna </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Yajur Veda</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">  vi. 5. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">8</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">. </span><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">2</span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A wife has no claim to property of her husband. The wealth that she earns is not her but her husband’s. [Manu Smriti  Chapter 8, Sholka 416]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">A girl without a brother is called <em style="font-weight:inherit;">Abhratr</em> and it is prohibited to marry such a girl.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The Atharva Ved says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Those maidens there, the veins, who run their course in robes of ruddy hue, must now stand quiet, reft of power, like sisters who are brotherless. [Atharva Ved Kaand 1, Sookt 17, Mantra 1]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><img decoding="async" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;" src="http://www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/brotherless_ath_1_17_1.jpg" alt="" /></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Explaining this word, Nirukt, which is the oldest Indian treatise on Etymology, </span><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Philology and Semantics, says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">They stand like women who have no brother, and whose path is  obstructed with regard to procreation and the offering of the sacrificial cake. With these words the simile implies the prohibition of marrying a brotherless maiden.[Nirukt 3:4]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Shatpath Brahman, preachings of the ‘Yajur Veda’ says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He (the Adhvaryu) then mixes it with the residue (of ghee) which is left in the prakaranî spoon. Now other libations he completes by mixing, but this one he diminishes; for ghee is a thunderbolt, and by that thunderbolt, the ghee, the gods smote the wives and unmanned them, and thus smitten and unmanned they neither owned any self nor <strong style="font-style:inherit;">did they own any heritage</strong>. And in like manner does he now, by that thunderbolt, the ghee, smite the wives and unman them; and thus smitten and unmanned, they neither own any self<strong style="font-style:inherit;"> nor do they own any heritage</strong>. [Shatpath Brahman; Kaand 4, Adhyay 4, Brahaman 2, Kaandika 13]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The same Shatpath Brahman says,</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“And whilst not coming into contact with Sûdras and remains of food; for this Gharma is he that shines yonder, and he is excellence, truth, and light; <strong style="font-style:inherit;">but woman, the Sûdra, the dog, and the black bird (the crow), are untruth: he should not look at these, lest he should mingle excellence and sin, light and darkness, truth and untruth</strong>. [Kaand 14, Adhyay1, Brahman1, Kaandika 31]</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">A woman can never ask for divorce, even if her husband ill treats her. Manu says,</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though destitute of virtue, or seeking pleasure (elsewhere), or devoid of good qualities, (yet) a husband must be constantly worshipped as a god by a faithful wife. [Manu Smriti 5:154]</em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;">Swami Dayanand Saraswati is teaching us in Satyarth Prakash how to choose a perfect wife. Listen to him.</span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let a man never marry one who is pale and anaemic, nor one who is altogether a bigger and stronger person than himself or has a redundant member, nor one who is an invalid, nor one either with no hair or too much hair or too much hair, nor one immoderately talkative, nor one with red eyes.” MANU 3: 8.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Nor one with the name of star,of a tree,or of a river, or of a mountain.</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">So Hindu men should not marry women who are named Ashvini, Ganga, Saraswati, Himalaya, etc.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><em style="font-weight:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">“Let him choose for his wife, a girl who has a graceful figure without any deformity, who has a pretty name, who walks gracefully like a swan or an elephant, who has fine hair and lovely teeth, and whose body is exquisitely soft.” MANU 3: 10</span></em></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">[Satyarth Prakash, Pages 89, 90]</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">He forgets to teach how to choose a husband.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">The ‘Vedas,’ also talk about ‘Niyog’ the custom of childless widow or woman having sexual intercourse with a person other than her husband to beget a child. In simple words ‘Niyog’ means sending a married woman or widow to a particular man for sexual intercourse so that she gets a son. Indication of this custom is available in Rig Veda.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;"> In ‘Aadiparva’ of ‘Mahabharata’ (chapters 95 and 103), it is mentioned that Satyawati had appointed her son to bestow sons to the queens of Vichitrvirya, the younger brother of Bhishma, and as a result of which Dhartrashtra and Pandu were born. Pandu himself had asked his queen, Kunti, to have sexual intercourse with a Brahmin to get a son (Aadi Parva,’ chapters 120 to 123).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">It has been said in ‘Aadi Parva’ (chapters 64 and 104), that when Parshu Ram started killing the Kshatriyas, thousands of female Kshatriyas started going to Brahmins to get sons. Similar references are found at other places in ‘Mahabharata’ also. With regard to ‘Niyog’, there are detailed discussions at a number of places in other religious books.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In Nirkut, the meaning of ‘dewar’ that is, husband’s younger brother, has been given as ‘Duvitya Var’ that is, the second husband (Nirukt 3:15).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">An ancient commentator of ‘Manu Smriti’ (Manu’s Code), Meghatithi has clearly accepted the existence of ‘Niyog‘ (quoted from ‘Dharam Shastra Ka Itihas’, by Bharatratan Mahamahopdhyay, Dr P.V. Kane, Part I, page 341).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the last century, Swami Dayanand Saraswati had claimed to have written a commentary free from defects in the interpretation, of the ancient commentators on the ‘Vedas.’ Dayanand had not only accepted the prevalence of ‘Niyog’ but also on the basic of ‘smritis’ (codes of traditional Hindu laws), discussed ‘Niyog’ in great detail in the language of the ‘Veda mantras’ (Vedic hymns). According to him there was a law that a woman or a man could have sexual intercourse with eleven persons. If no child was born from the one, then a woman could go to another. If even then she was unable to beget a child, then she could go to the third and so on till she had intercourse with eleven men (Dayanand’s commentary on Rig Veda, 10/85/45).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Woman was sometimes even forced to have sexual intercourse with men in the custom of ‘Niyog’. ‘Devtas, Rishis, Munis’ and ‘Brahmins’ used to participate in ‘Niyog’ (see ‘Mahabharata Aadi Parv; chapters 64,95,103, 104).</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><strong style="font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Chastity of woman was not safe</span></strong></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In the name of ‘beejdan’ (seed donation), they used to have sexual intercourse with issueless women. This was a cruel religious custom and the chastity of women was not safe. The so-called caretakers of the religion were allowed to have sexual intercourse with another man’s wife. From ‘Niyog pratha’, it can be inferred without fear of contradiction that the women were looked upon as mere child-producing machines.</span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">In ‘The Position of Women in Hindu Civilization’, Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar writes: “<em style="font-weight:inherit;">Though woman was married to a man, she was considered to be the property of the entire family. But she was not getting share out of the property of her husband, only the son could be the successor to property.”</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Gajdhar Prasad Baudh says: <em style="font-weight:inherit;">“No woman of the Vedic age can be treated as pure. Vedic men could not keep even the relations between brother-sister and father-daughter sacred from the oven of rape and debauchery / adultery named ‘Niyog’. Under the influence of intoxication of wine, they used to recognise neither sister nor daughter and also they did not keep in mind their relations with them. It is evident from their debauchery and adultery what the miserable plight of women was in the society then. (Refer ‘Arya Niti Ka Bhandaphor’, 5th edition page 14).</em></span></span></span></p>
<p style="color:#333333;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;"><span lang="EN" style="font-weight:inherit;font-style:inherit;color:black;">Till such a time as these teachings have an overwhelming influence, the improvement in the position and status of the women is next to impossible.</span></span></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-and-the-vedic-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women and the Vedic Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
