<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>mushafiq sultan &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/mushafiq-sultan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 13:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Vedas Have Been Changed</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 10:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altered]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[path]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakhas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Textual Corruption of the Vedas (English)  Hindi Article 999 Sukta&#8217;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority Response to No Corruption in Vedas &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas Have Been Changed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><a title="Textual Corruption of the Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas (English)</a>  <a href="/index.php/2014/04/29/textual-corruption-vedas-hindi/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindi Article</a></h2>
<h2><a title="999 Sukta&#039;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/999-suktas-loststill-no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">999 Sukta&#8217;s Lost, Still no Textual Corruption</a></h2>
<h2 class="entry-title"><a title="Origin of Vedas, Their Inspirations and Authority" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration, and Authority</a></h2>
<h2 class="entry-title"><a title="Response to No Corruption in Vedas" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to No Corruption in Vedas</a></h2>
<p><span id="more-910"></span><br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/vedas-have-been-changed/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas Have Been Changed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Textual Corruption of the Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sukta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad Make sure that you read the article &#8216;Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration and Authority&#8216; to have a better comprehension of this article. After reading about the origin of Vedas, we now move on to the textual corruption of the Vedas.  A lot of claims are made by many modern Hindus about &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>Make sure that you read the article &#8216;<a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/origin-of-vedas-their-inspiration-and-authority/" data-wpel-link="internal">Origin of Vedas, Their Inspiration and Authority</a>&#8216; to have a better comprehension of this article.</p>
<p>After reading about the origin of Vedas, we now move on to the textual corruption of the Vedas.  A lot of claims are made by many modern Hindus about the perfect preservation of the Vedas. Mr. Agniveer too makes such high flying claims. I have analyzed this topic objectively and want to present the result before the readers.</p>
<p><span id="more-906"></span></p>
<p>Let me start by sharing with you an interesting yet ludicrous story that is mentioned in the Shanti Parv of Mahabharata; the story of the Vedas being stolen from the Creator of the Worlds by two demons, Madhu and Kaitabha. We read about this in Shanti Parv, Section 348. The two mighty Danavas (demons), having seized the Vedas, quickly dived into the ocean of waters which they saw and proceeded to its bottom. Seeing the Vedas forcibly taken away from him, Brahma Ji became filled with grief, and started wailing.  The Vedas were later recovered by Vishu Ji&#8217;s timely intervention but still it shows the insecurity of the Vedic texts from the very beginning. If Brahma Ji had memorized the Vedas, how could the Vedas have been stolen? Perhaps his memory was not that strong after all. I only shared this story to give the readers an idea of a book which according to Mr. Agniveer is the  &#8216;greatest wonder of human civilization&#8217;. Truly a wonder it is.</p>
<p><strong>What is the total number of the Vedas?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Three, Four or Five Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>One opinion is that there are three deiies, and from them originate the three Vedas or three types of mantras.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="372" height="196" class="wp-image-7494" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext1.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;1. Prajapati brooded over the worlds, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, Agni (fire) from the earth, Vayu (air) from the sky, Aditya (the sun) from heaven.</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. He brooded over these three deities, and from them thus brooded on he squeezed out the essences, the Rik verses from Agni, the Yagus verses from Vayu, the Saman verses from Aditya.&#8221; [Chandogya Upanishad- Adhyay 4, Khanda 17, Mantras1 and 2]</strong></p>
<p>The same view is expressed in Shatpath Brahman 11:5:8:1,2. Note only three Vedas are spoken here. Further Manu 1:23 says,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;But from fire, wind, and the sun he drew forth the threefold eternal Veda, called Rik, Yagus, and Saman, for the due performance of the sacrifice.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Also see Manu 2:118, 2:118, 2:230, 9:188, where only three Vedas have been mentioned.</p>
<p>Even Swami Dayanand writes in Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 3, on the authority of Manu Smriti 3:1,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Thus after joining the school at the age of 8 years, if a student studies the Vedas with their subsidiary subjects for 36 years, (i.e., he devotes 12 years to the study of each of the three Vedas), he completes his education at the age of 36+8=44.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, according to Swamiji and Manu Smriti, Vedas are only 3. Is Atharvaved really a genuine Veda?</p>
<p>The popular opinion is that Vedas are four in number viz. Rigved, Yajurved, Samved and Atharvaved. Another opinion is that Vedas are five in number because Atharvaved is actually two Vedas; one is Atharvaved and the other Angirasved.</p>
<p>The divergent opinions regarding the number of Vedas do not end here. Another authoritative view which holds its place is that Vedas number 1131 as we shall see.</p>
<p><strong>1131 Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>According to the Mahabhasya of Patanjali, there were 21 Shakhas of Rigveda, 9 of Atharvaveda, 101 of Yajurveda (86 of Krishna Yajurveda and 15 of Shukla Yajurveda, according to later authorities) and a 1000 shakhas of Samaveda. All these add to give the figure 1131. All these Shakhas are considered to be Vedas. The words Shakha means a &#8216;branch&#8217; or a &#8216;limb&#8217; and refers to a particular traditional text followed, as in the phrase śākhām adhite, (&#8220;he recites a particular version of the Veda&#8221;).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="585" height="501" class="wp-image-7495" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext2.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.jpeg 585w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37-300x257.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 585px) 100vw, 585px" /></p>
<p>However, out of these 1131 Shakhas, only 11 Shakhas remain alive. As far as Rigved is concerned, only one Shakha, Shaakal Shakha alone remains alive out of the 21 that existed at one time. Another shakha that may have survived is the Bāṣhkala, although this is uncertain. Out of the 101 Shakhas of Yajurveda, only 6 are alive. In fact, Yajurveda is classified broadly into Shukla Yajurveda  (White) and Krishna Yajurveda (Black). The former is popular in North India while the later is popular in South India.  Shukla Yajurveda is also known as Vajasaneyi. The Vajasaneyi Samhita has forty chapters or adhyayas and there are two extant Shakhas of Shukla Yajurveda viz. Kanvaand Madhyandina. Krishna Yajurveda has 4 extant Shakhas viz.</p>
<ul>
<li>Taittirīya</li>
<li>Maitrayani</li>
<li>Kaṭhak</li>
<li>Kapiṣṭhala</li>
</ul>
<p>There are three surviving Shakhas out of 1000 of the text of the Samaveda Samhita:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kauthuma Shakha is current in Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Orissa and since a few decades in Darbhanga, Bihar,</li>
<li>the Jaiminiya in the Carnatic, Tamilnadu and Kerala,</li>
<li>and the Rāṇāyanīya in the Maharastra.</li>
</ul>
<p>Out of the nine Shakhas of Atharvaveda, only two have survived</p>
<ul>
<li>Paippalāda, in regions south to Narmada river</li>
<li>Shaunakīya, in regions north to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>What we know today as Rigveda, Yajurveda, Samaveda and Atharvaveda are actually Shakhas from the multitude of other Shakhas. The so called Vedas are never named as Vedas in their hymns. In other words, Rigveda is never called Rigveda in the Rigveda itself. If it be said that in other scriptures they have been called as Vedas, we can respond that so many other things have been called as Vedas also. For example, Ayurveda (Medicine), Sarpaveda (snakes), Dhanurved (weapons), Itihasaveda (History), Puranaveda (Stories). These words are based on Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3.</p>
<p>Hence, 1121 versions of Vedas have been lost. If someone will say that the Shakhas are not Vedas but only the explanations/commentaries that would be erroneous. The presently known Vedas are also Shakhas. So are these commentaries or actual Vedas? To say that Shakhas are not the Vedas will be to undermine the present Vedas (read Shakhas) also. Considering the two opposing Shakhas of Yajurveda we may ask, &#8220;Is Madhyandina Shakha (Shukla Yajurveda) the original or Taittirīya Shakha (Krishna Yajurveda)?&#8221;.</p>
<p>The above analysis makes it clear that a large portion of the Vedas has been lost.</p>
<p><strong>A topical study of the corruption of the Vedic text</strong></p>
<p><strong>Missing Verses</strong></p>
<p>After the collection and codification of Vedas, many different manuscripts gained currency amongst the Brahmin groups. The number of mantras in every manuscript continued to be changed. The current version of Rigveda was collected by Shaakal Rishi and was thus called Shaakal Samhita. It is divided into 10 Mandals (Books).</p>
<p>Nirukt 7:8 mentions the following,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;There is a joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu in the ten books of the Rigveda.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>However, in the entire Rigveda, there is not a single mantra jointly praising Agni and Vishnu.  What is meant by joint oblation here? An oblation is an offering (Late Latin oblatio, from offerre, oblatum, to offer), a term, particularly in ecclesiastical usage, for a solemn offering or presentation to God. Where is an offering jointly made to Agni and Vishnu, we would like to see? This is a clear evidence that the Rigveda at the time of Yaska Muni had the joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu, but it is not found in today&#8217;s Rigveda, demonstrating corruption of the text.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption in recitation</strong></p>
<p>The oral tradition of the Vedas (Śrauta) consists of several pathas, &#8220;recitations&#8221; or ways of chanting the Vedic mantras.The padapatha consists of dividing the sentence into individual pada or words. The kramapatha consists of pairing two words at a time. There has been a lot of corruption in the former recitation. I will give some examples to demonstrate this.</p>
<p><strong>Example 1</strong></p>
<p>Yask Muni, the author of Nirukt and Nighantu, writes that Vaayah is one word [See Nirukt 6:28]. But in the Shaakal Shakha&#8217;s (Rigveda&#8217;s) padapatha, it has been divided and hence became meaningless. Rigveda 10:29:1 is the place which has made the mistake.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" width="571" height="152" class="wp-image-7496" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-1.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext3.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;As sits the young bird on the tree rejoicing, ye, swift Pair, have been roused by clear laudation,…&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Yaska himself criticizes Shakalya and says,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Sakalya has analyzed Vaayah into Vaa and yah, then the finite verb would have had the accute accent and the sense have been incomplete.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Example 2</strong></p>
<p>Rigveda 5:39:1 goes as follows,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="77" class="wp-image-7497" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-2.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext4.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;O Indra, wielder of the thunderbolt, give us whatever excellent treasure there is. With both hands bring that wealth to us, O treasure-knower&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Yaska says on this,</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Sakalya the author of Rigveda padapatha, does not analyze the word Mehanaa, while Gargya the author of Samaveda padapatha analyzes it into Me-iha-naa.&#8221; [Nirukt 4:4]</strong></p>
<p>Let us see what Samaveda, Book 4; Chapter 2; Decade 1; Mantra 4 does,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="569" height="78" class="wp-image-7498" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-3.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext5.gif" /></p>
<p>Now there is a world of difference between <strong>Mehanaasti </strong>and <strong>Me-iha-naasti</strong>. The former means &#8216;I have wealth&#8217; and the latter means &#8216;I do not have&#8217;.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Rigveda</strong></p>
<p>Shaakal Rishi is called as the collector of Rigveda. He had a number of students, who later expressed many differences and compiled their own versions of Rigveda. numbering upto 21. There are major differences between the Shaakal and Baskal samhitas of Rigveda. The Śākala recension has 1,017 regular hymns, while the Bāṣkala samhita has a total of 1025 hymns.  Thus, around  some 50 mantras are missing in Śākala samhita. There are differences even over the total number of mantras.</p>
<ul>
<li>According to Anuvakanukramani Rigveda has 10,580 mantras</li>
<li>According to Gayatri Parivar Rigveda has 10,552 mantras</li>
<li>According to Sayanacharya it has 10,000 mantras</li>
<li>According to Swami Dayanand Saraswati it has 10,589 mantras</li>
</ul>
<p>As per these figures, some 500 mantras are doubtful or interpolated. However, the story does not end here. Pandit Ram Govind Trivedi, mentions another surprising fact in the preface to his Hindi translation of the Rigveda. He says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="595" height="166" class="wp-image-7499" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-4.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext6.gif" /></p>
<p>&#8220;According to one Mantra of Rigveda (Page 1403, Mantra 8), we come to know that it has 15,000 Mantras. However, when we count the total Mantras, we get 10,469 Mantras. It is possible that  like a large portion of the books of Vedic literature and Vedas were destroyed by the anti-religious, similarly,  Mantras too suffered destruction for many reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Mantra he is talking about is Rigveda 10:114:8, which says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="565" height="106" class="wp-image-7500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-5.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext7.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>GAYATRI PARIVAR TRANSLATION</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="115" class="wp-image-7501" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-6.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext8.gif" /></p>
<p>According to this analysis, Vedas have easily lost about 4,500 Mantras.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Yajurveda</strong></p>
<p>As I said earlier, out of 101 Shaakhas of Yajurveda only 6 are extant. There are two principal texts of the Yajur-Yeda, called respectively the White and the Black, or the Vajasaneyi and Taittiriya Samhitas.</p>
<p>The Vishnu Purana gives the following explanation of their names : Vaisampayana, a pupil of the great Vyasa, was the original teacher of the Black Yajur-Veda. Yajnavalkya, one of his disciples, having displeased him, was called upon by his master to part with the knowledge which he had acquired from him. He forthwith vomited the Yajur-Yeda. The other disciples of Vaisampayana, assuming the form of partridges (tittiri), picked up from the ground its several dirtied texts. From this circumstance it received the name of Taittiriya Krishna Yajur-Veda. A more rational explanation is that Vaisampayana taught it to Yaska, who taught it to Tittiri, who also became a teacher. Yajnavalkya afterwards, by the performance of severe penances, induced the Sun to impart to him those Yajur texts which his master had not possessed. The Sun then assumed the form of a horse (Vajin), and communicated to him the desired texts. Hence the Sanhita was called Vajasaneyi, and also White (or bright) because it was revealed by the Sun.</p>
<ol>
<li>There are a lot of differences between the two versions. The first mantra of both is same despite some difference in the wording. The arrangement and wording of White Yajurveda upto Adhyay 15 is radically different from the Black Yajurveda. The mantras of the 39th Chapter of Shukla Yajurveda are not found in Krishna Yajurveda.</li>
<li>An amazing information about Shukla Yajurveda is that the last chapter (Chapter 40) is actually an Upanishad, the Ish Upanishad. As per the belief of Arya Samaj, Upanishads are not revealed scriptures. It is worth noting that while it is counted with the Upanishads, the Ish Upanishad remains non-revealed and when it is added to the Veda it become revealed.</li>
<li>The Ish Upanishad is not the only addition to this Yajurveda. A lot of Brahamanas have been inserted into the text of the Yajurveda. For example, Adhyay 24 is entirely a Brahman; Adhyay 30: verses 7 through 15 are all Brahmanas and not Mantras.</li>
</ol>
<p>Not only in the ancient period, but in recent times too there have been many changes in the Vedic texts by Swami Dayanand Saraswati and his followers.</p>
<p>Following is a list of changes that have been made.</p>
<ol>
<li>In the Yajurveda Bhasya of Dayanand Ji, Adhyay 9, Mantra 20 has been distorted by adding the word Gamyaat, which is not to be found in the text. Where did this word come from?</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="531" height="657" class="wp-image-7502" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-7.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext9.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Comparing the Yajurveda of Gayatri Parivar and Arya Samaj, there are many mantras missing in one or another of the versions. For example, the 25th Chapter of Gayatri Parivar Yajurveda has 47 mantras. Even the Yajurveda of Ralph Griffith has 47 mantras. But, the Arya Samaj version has an additional Mantra 48.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR/SANATAN DHARMI VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="581" height="509" class="wp-image-7503" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-8.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext10.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="484" height="567" class="wp-image-7504" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-9.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext11.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 26, mantra 26, the word <strong>Ayohtay </strong>was changed to <strong>Apohtay</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="44" class="wp-image-7505" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.jpeg" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext12.jpg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.jpeg 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38-300x24.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="521" height="153" class="wp-image-7506" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-10.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext13.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 39, mantra 5, the word <strong>Vishyandmaane </strong>was changed to <strong>Vishpandmaane</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="567" height="82" class="wp-image-7507" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-11.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext14.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="411" height="197" class="wp-image-7508" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-12.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext15.gif" /></p>
<ul>
<li>The longer ending in Yajurveda 13:58 has been deleted from Arya Samaj version, but exists in the Gayatri Parivar version.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SEE THE GAYATRI PARIVAR VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="568" height="102" class="wp-image-7509" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-13.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext16.gif" /></p>
<p><strong>SEE THE ARYA SAMAJ VERSION BELOW</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="513" height="166" class="wp-image-7510" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-14.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext17.gif" /></p>
<p>No one can call these interpolations and alterations to be printing errors, because the translations also have been made of the interpolations. These are examples of deliberate interpolations.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption of Samaveda</strong></p>
<p>Samaveda is heavily borrowed from the Rigveda. It consists of a collection of hymns, portions of hymns, and detached verses, all but 75 taken from the Sakala Sakha of the Rigveda, the other 75 belong to the Bashkala Sakha, to be sung, using specifically indicated melodies, called Samagana. There are differences regarding the exact number of mantras in the Samaveda. As I said earlier,  according to Patanjali&#8217;s statement, &#8220;sahasravartma samvedah&#8221; सहस्रवर्त्म<br />
समवेदः, &#8220;There are thousand branches of Samaveda&#8221;. However, only three survive:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kauthuma Shakha is current in Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Orissa and since a few decades in Darbhanga, Bihar,</li>
<li>the Jaiminiya in the Karnatak, Tamilnadu and Kerala,</li>
<li>and the Rāṇāyanīya in the Maharastra.</li>
</ul>
<p>The total mantras in the Jaimniya Shakha is 1687. Kauthama Shakha has 1869 mantras . Thus, 182 mantras are missing fromKauthama Shakha. An analysis of both these versions reveals lots of Paath-Bhed (variant readings). Besides this, there is a difference in number of songs attributed to different branches. Shri Satvalekar in his preface to Samaveda Samhita has given the following table of songs (Samagana).</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td><strong>Songs of Jaiminiya Branch</strong></td>
<td><strong>Songs of Kauthamiya Branch</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gramgeyo-gān:</td>
<td>1233</td>
<td>1197</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Aranyageya-gān:</td>
<td>291</td>
<td>294</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ooh-gān:</td>
<td>1802</td>
<td>1026</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Oohya-gān:</td>
<td>356</td>
<td>205</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total</td>
<td>3681</td>
<td>2722</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>We can easily see that the Samaganas of Jaiminiya Version are 1000 more than those of Kauthamiya Version.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption in Atharvaveda</strong></p>
<p>Atharvaveda, also known as Brahmaveda is considered the youngest amongst all other Vedas. As I mentioned earlier, out of the nine versions of Atharvaveda according to Patanjali, only two are extant</p>
<ul>
<li>Paippalāda, in regions south to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Shaunakīya, in regions north to Narmada river</li>
</ul>
<p>Both versions have lot of differences in the words and arrangement.  Paippalada Shaakha can further be divided into two parts; Atharvaveda and Angirasveda. It is mentioned in Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3:4-8 in the context of the Ashvamedha sacrifice; after theYagya (ritual) is completed, the householders should be instructed in Rigveda of the first day. old men should be instructed in Yajurveda on the second day, handsome youths should be instructed in Atharvaveda on the third day and handsome maiden should be instructed in Angirasveda on the  fourth day. Angirasveda is attributed to Rishi Angiras who is in the fourth generation after Rishi Atharva. There is no mention of Samaveda in this reference of Shatapath Brahman.</p>
<p>Patanjali Rishi, in his Mahabhasya, has given the first mantras of all the four Vedas. In the present Atharvaved (Shaunak Shaakha) it is not the first mantra, but the 26th mantra. This means 25 mantras are extra in that Shaunak shaakha.</p>
<p>Following is an exmaple of textual corruption in the Atharvaveda.</p>
<p>Atharvaveda Khand 20 and Sookt 127 is part of the Kuntap Sooktas. In the third mantra of this Sookt there has been  an alteration. The Atharvaveda of Arya Samaj and Gayatri Parivar both have it as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="365" height="67" class="wp-image-7511" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-15.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext18.gif" /></p>
<p>The word preceeding <strong>Maamahe</strong> is <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. However, in the Atharvaveda of Pandit Raja Ram Shashtri of Arya Samaj as well as the Atharvaveda printed in Germany, the text differs as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="317" height="56" class="wp-image-7512" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-16.gif" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0652_testingtext19.gif" /></p>
<p>Here the word preceeding <strong>Maamahe </strong>is <strong>Rishye </strong>and not <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. This makes a difference in the meaning of the mantra.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>The above analysis proves beyond the shadow of a doubt that Vedas have suffered heavy interpolations and changes. Talking strictly, even if one accusation of the above analysis stands, the entire Vedic literature will be unacceptable as a genuine inspired document.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Textual Corruption of the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medical Science in the Vedas?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/medical-science-in-the-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[centric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[errors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flat earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[in]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science in Vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific errors in vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vedic science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/medical-science-in-the-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad This article is for those cyber crooks who leave no stone unturned to malign Islam but fail to take note of their own heritage. Vedic medicines were based on the mistaken notion that diseases were caused by evil spirits. THE VEDA enthusiasts often assert that the &#8216;Atharvaveda&#8217; is full of information &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/medical-science-in-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Medical Science in the Vedas?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>This article is for those cyber crooks who leave no stone unturned to malign Islam but fail to take note of their own heritage.</p>
<p>Vedic medicines were based on the mistaken notion that diseases were caused by evil spirits.</p>
<p><span id="more-831"></span><br />
THE VEDA enthusiasts often assert that the &#8216;Atharvaveda&#8217; is full of information about curing fatal diseases. Influenced by such propaganda, many people blindly believe that Vedas contain all knowledge including knowledge of medicine. This notion is often tied with the idea that Indians were far ahead in medical knowledge which was the direct result of their studying the Vedas. Nothing can be more false than this, as we will analyze.</p>
<p><strong>Ayurveda has nothing to do with Atharvaveda</strong></p>
<p>In ancient India medical science was known as &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; (&#8216;Ved&#8217; or knowledge of health or longevity). Owing to the word &#8216;Ved&#8217; in &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217;, many wrongly attribute this branch of science to &#8216;Atharvaveda&#8217;. But the fact is that the word &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; has nothing to do with the &#8216;Atharv&#8217; or any other &#8216;Ved&#8217;. This word is not found in any of the &#8216;Vedas.&#8217; This word in fact is conspicuous by its absence even in the &#8216;Brahmans&#8217; and the &#8216;Upanishads&#8217; which were written after the &#8216;Vedas.&#8217;</p>
<p>The word Ved in &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; means &#8216;branch of science or a section of knowledge‘. The Sanskrit dictionaries give the meaning of the word &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; as &#8216;the science of health or longevity‘. In the &#8216;Brahman&#8217; literature there are other &#8216;Vedas&#8217; (branches of knowledge) such as &#8216;Sarp Ved&#8217;, &#8216;Pishach Ved&#8217;, &#8216;Itihas Ved&#8217; and &#8216;Puran Ved&#8217; (Gopatha Brahman 1/10; Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3). In these passages of the &#8216;Gopatha and Shatapath Brahmanas&#8217;, the word =Ved‘ means branch of knowledge.</p>
<p>While defining &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; Charak writes:</p>
<p>.That branch of knowledge which tells things which are conducive and which are harmful to life is called &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217;. (Charak Chapter 1, 1/40).</p>
<p>Sushrut defines the &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; as the branch of knowledge which enhances life. (Sushrut Samhita Chapter1).</p>
<p><strong>Early books</strong></p>
<p>The early books on &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217;, are <em>Charak Samhita</em> and the <em>Sushrut Samhita</em>. The former is a composition of Charak, who lived about 200 B.C. The latter was composed by Sushrut much later. The word &#8216;Ayurveda&#8217; was perhaps first used in Charak Samhita where it is stated:</p>
<p>Brahma was the originator of Ayurveda. He taught it to the twin-born Ashwani Kumars. They taught it to Indra.. (Charak Samhita, Sutra Sthanam, Chapter 1)</p>
<p>Besides, Charak also remarked that it was superior to the other Vedas, for this branch provided knowledge about life which was the basis of all pleasures and joys and good deeds (Charak 1-1-42)</p>
<p>Sushrut, overwhelmed by the popularity of the Vedas in his times, subordinated the Ayurveda to the Vedas. Finding no affinity whatsoever between the Atharvaveda and the Ayurveda, he declared that the latter was an upanga (minor part), of the former (See <em>Sushruta Samhita</em> 1.1/5). That is why there are imitations of the Atharvaveda in the <em>Sushrut Samhita</em> which undermine the importance of scientific data contained in the latter.</p>
<p>Later scholars refused to accept subordination of Ayurveda. Vag Bhatt said: &#8220;Ayurveda is not an upanga (sub-part) but an Upaveda (a secondary Ved) (Ashtanga Samgraha 1-1-8). The Mahabharat also says so.</p>
<p>The statement of Sushrut was not a balanced one, for he himself says that the Ayurveda was composed of one lakh verses whereas the Atharvaveda contains some six thousand verses and one thousand prose lines. To brand such a vast thing, the upang of such a tiny body is illogical.</p>
<p>Now let us analyze the medicinal prescriptions of the Vedas for various ailments and what they contain.</p>
<p><strong>Prescriptions</strong></p>
<p><strong>1. For the cure of cough</strong>, the prescription in the Atharvaveda is a prayer to cough:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="635" height="404" class="wp-image-7470" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_6_105.gif.pagespeed.ic.kV53VfDSvX.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http.png 635w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-300x191.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 635px) 100vw, 635px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Just as the fancy flies forth with conceptions of the mind. So following the fancy&#8217;s flight, O Cough, flee rapidly away. Just as the arrow, sharpened well swift to a distance flies away, So even O Cough, fly away along the broad expanse of earth. Just as the beams of light, the rays of Sūrya, fly away. So, O Cough! fly rapidly away over the current of the sea!&#8221; (Atharvaveda 6:105)</p>
<p><strong>2. The Charm for the recovery of dangerously sick man</strong> is mentioned in Athavaved 3:11. One incantation reads</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="114" class="wp-image-7471" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-1.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_3_11_2.gif.pagespeed.ic._5vZjhA2qk.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-1.png 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-1-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;If life in him declines or has departed, if on the very brink of death he totters, I snatch him from the lap of dissolution, I free him now to live a hundred autumns.&#8221; (Atharvaveda 3:11:2)</p>
<p>Reciting this incantation can ensure that you will live for a hundred years.</p>
<p><strong>3. Again, for longevity </strong>the prescription given in Atharvaveda 19:32 is that if Darbha (a kind of sacred grass, also known as Kusha grass) is tied to a person, he is expected to live long. Atharvaveda 19:32:1 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="637" height="101" class="wp-image-7472" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-2.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_19_32_1.gif.pagespeed.ic.jOZzvH7CA_.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-2.png 637w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-2-300x48.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 637px) 100vw, 637px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Hundred-jointed, hard to be stirred, thousand-leaved, uplifting; the darbha that is a formidable herb, that I bind on you for prolonged life.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>4. Prayer for the flirt:</strong></p>
<p>Interested in securing love of a woman? The Atharvaveda has a charm for that too in 6:8:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="644" height="348" class="wp-image-7473" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-3.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_6_8.gif.pagespeed.ic.zQEB_1wxkU.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-3.png 644w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-3-300x162.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 644px) 100vw, 644px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;1. Like as the creeper throws, her arms on every side around the tree, So hold you me in your embrace that you may be in love with me, my darling, never to depart. 2. As, when he mounts, the eagle strikes his pinions downward on the earth, So do I strike your spirit down that you may be in love with me, my darling, never to depart. 3. As round this heaven and earth, the sun, goes day by day, encircling them, So do I compass round your mind that you may be in love with me, my darling, never to depart.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5. Prayer for freedom from curse:</strong></p>
<p>The remedy for &#8216;curse-disease&#8217; in the Atharvaveda is:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="580" height="381" class="wp-image-7474" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-4.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_6_37.gif.pagespeed.ic.1_WEutUA7R.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-4.png 580w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-4-300x197.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;1. Hitherward, having yoked his steeds, came curse, thousand-eyed, Seeking my curser, as a wolf the home of one who owns sheep. 2. Avoid us, O Curse! as consuming fire avoids the lake. Smite you the man who curses us, as the sky&#8217;s lightning strikes the tree. 3. Who curses us, himself uncursed, or, cursed, who curses us again, Him cast I as a sop to Death, as to a dog one throws a bone.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>6. Medicine which protects one from nightmares and all diseases. </strong></p>
<p>In the 3rd Sukta of the 10th Kaand of the Atharvaveda, there is a medicine which secures long life, health, prosperity and fame.  Don&#8217;t expect too much. The medicine is nothing but an amulet (mani) called Varana. Atharvaveda 10:3:3,4 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="619" height="250" class="wp-image-7475" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-5.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_10_3_3-4.gif.pagespeed.ic.3QSSgUuetj.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-5.png 619w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-5-300x121.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 619px) 100vw, 619px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;This charm, this Varana heals all diseases, bright with a thousand eyes and golden glister. This charm shall conquer and cast down your foemen. Be you the first to slay the men who hate you. 4. This will stay witchcraft wrought for you, will guard you from the fear of man: From all distress and misery this Varana will shield you well.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>7. Chants for destroying pests:</strong></p>
<p>In the 32nd Sukta of the 2nd kaand of Atharvaveda, there is a prescription for destroying pests:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="629" height="120" class="wp-image-7476" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-6.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_2_32_3.gif.pagespeed.ic.le3yrlAyzV.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-6.png 629w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-6-300x57.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Like Atri I destroy you, Worms! in Kanva&#8217;s, Jamadagni&#8217;s way: I bray and bruise the creeping things to pieces with Agastya&#8217;s spell. (Atharvaveda 2:32:3)</p>
<p><strong>8. Remedy for impotency:</strong></p>
<p>If you are feeling impotent, Atharvaveda has a rememdy for you. It is mentioned in Atharvaveda 4:4:1</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="636" height="119" class="wp-image-7477" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-7.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_4_4_1.gif.pagespeed.ic.duDCtfNDF2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-7.png 636w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-7-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;You that the Gandharva dug for Varuna whose virility was dead, you here do we dig, a penis-erecting herb.&#8221; (Atharvaveda‘ 4:4:1)</p>
<p><strong>9. Prayer to deal with the rival mistress:</strong></p>
<p>There is yet another prayer to deal with the rival mistress. It teaches a jealous wife how to ge rid of a rival wife. Can you imagine what would happen if both were to use the same charm? The charm is mentioned in Rigveda 10:145 and repeated in Atharvaveda 3:18. I reproduce for you two mantras i.e. Rigveda 10:145:2,3.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="636" height="205" class="wp-image-7478" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-8.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xrig_10_145_2-3.gif.pagespeed.ic._JEHIv9vp8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-8.png 636w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-8-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;2. Auspicious, with expanded leaves, sent by the Gods, victorious plant, Blow you the rival wife away, and make my husband only mine. 3 Stronger am I, O Stronger One, yea, mightier than the mightier; And she who is my rival wife is lower than the lowest dames.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>10. Prescription for heart trouble and jaundice</strong></p>
<p>In the Rig Ved 1:50:11,12), there is a &#8216;prescription&#8217; for removing heart trouble and jaundice. It runs as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="624" height="230" class="wp-image-7479" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-9.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014082442im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xrig_1_50_11-12.gif.pagespeed.ic.fHi0nHePbo.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-9.png 624w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014082442im_-http-9-300x111.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;11. Rising this day, O rich in friends, ascending to the loftier heaven, Surya remove my heart&#8217;s disease, take from me this my yellow hue. (jaundice) 12. To parrots and to starlings let us give away my yellowness, Or this my yellowness let us transfer to Haritala trees.&#8221;</p>
<p>Why transfer the jaundice to poor parrots? This is totally ridiculous.</p>
<p>A long list can be drawn on this line. However, if we analyse all the prescriptions, we can divide them into three categories:</p>
<p>(1) There are some verses wherein only the word &#8216;aushadhi&#8217; (medicine), is used. What that medicine was, is not clear. So, such verses are of no use from the point of view of medical science.</p>
<p>(2) Some other verses only dictate to the diseases to go away. Apparently, it is expected that the power contained in the verses would cure a sick person or the gods would accede to his prayer and help him get well. This is nothing but superstition. Hence these verses are of no use to the modern man.</p>
<p>(3) However, there are verses which mention the name of the medicine. But most of the verses are not concerned with drug value of the medicines. Instead, they rely on supernatural powers associated with the medicine. For example, the knot of Kusha grass is supposed to destroy enemies and the knot of Udumbra bring good luck to the wearer. That is why the Atharvaveda 19:34:7) says that no old or recent medicine can equal the amulet of Janginda (name of a herb).</p>
<p>The reason for the reliance on the supposed supernatural powers of the medicines was the belief prevailing then that the diseases were caused by the evil influence of some demon or spirit. A study of Atharvaveda would give the impression that the earth was densely populated by demons and spirits and they interfered with human activity very often. It is not surprising then that the treatment of diseases, in good part, consisted in propitiating demons or spirits or trying to ward them off by various devices – amulets and charms and incantations and prayers. Drugs, perhaps, came last.</p>
<p>In short, it can .be said that the approach of the Vedas to the treatment of diseases is based on magic, demonology and witch-craft.</p>
<p><strong>Demonology</strong></p>
<p>Though Ayurveda is supposed to be medical science, it is also clouded by demonology – the doctrine that diseases are caused by demons. Demonology, in fact, constitutes one of the eight parts of Ayurveda. Demons are recognised as originators of disease, and incantations as remedies, just as we find in the Vedas. This is called Bhoot Vidya. Explaining this Vidya, the Sushrut Samhit says:</p>
<p>&#8220;The Vidya (knowledge) which deals with the offerings and sacrifices meant to avert the onslaught of the gods, demons, demigods, goblins, imps, fiends, snakes, cruel planets, manes, etc., is called the Bhoot Vidya (demonology).&#8221; (Sushrut Samhit Chapter 1)</p>
<p>In a nutshell, we can say that though the Ayurveda is an independent branch of knowledge, it remained eclipsed for a long time by the primitive crudity of the Atharvaveda. In this way, the Vedas, instead of being the originators of the medical science, proved a big hindrance to the progress of medical science. Therefore, it is wrong to claim that Vedas contain all knowledge about medical science. Had Vedas contained such knowledge, all Vedic pandits would have been doctors. To run after Vedas in the search of medicines for diseases would yield no result. And anyone who studies Vedas with this end in view is bound to be disillusioned.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/medical-science-in-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Medical Science in the Vedas?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reincarnation Reality or Myth?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2013/01/25/reincarnation-reality-or-myth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 16:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2013/01/25/reincarnation-reality-or-myth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Ibn Muhammad The theory of Re-incarnation of souls, also known as the cycle of birth and death, is very central to Hindu philosophy. To a common Muslim this is a new idea which he/she has not previously encountered. We may not accept it, but we cannot cavil at the logic of it; more especially &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2013/01/25/reincarnation-reality-or-myth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Reincarnation Reality or Myth?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">By Ibn Muhammad<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The theory of Re-incarnation of souls, also known as the cycle of birth and death, is very central to Hindu philosophy. To a common Muslim this is a new idea which he/she has not previously encountered. We may not accept it, but we cannot cavil at the logic of it; more especially as it is born from the same causes which, in Muslim theology, give rise to the concept of Hell and Paradise. If life on earth is a  life of preparation in which we have to attain certain qualifications essential for our entry into Paradise (<em>Brahma Lok</em> in the words of Shri Krishna), will it not be necessary, so would argue a Hindu divine, for us to return to earthly life again, if we have left it without acquiring the necessary perfection?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span id="more-2423"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We had to attain certain experiences not available in the next world; we left this world without doing so and consequently we do need to come back to it again. This logic is not bad and the reasoning is quite plausible; but they do not coincide with what we observe in the universe.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">For example, a fruit may leave a tree in defective condition. It need not go back into the branch of the tree it came from, to make up its deficiencies. The food we eat everyday will eventually take the form of a sperm and ovum, which will convert itself into the human shape of a child. The sperm has to pass through many stages before it reaches that stage. Things not properly cooked are sometimes taken in by us; they cause pains in the stomach, but the trouble is removed by medical treatment. The food is not sent back from stomach to the kitchen to be cooked again. We take medicine to help digestion, and enable the food to pass through the regions where it is made into blood. Sometimes, when, through the function of the stomach or through the function of a diseased liver, we produce poor blood, we seek a remedy in medicine, but no drop of that poor blood is allowed to return to the liver or the stomach for the purpose of rectification.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If therefore, this rule be universal in Nature, that the thing which has failed to attain the requisite state of perfection in one state of being is passed into the state of being next highest, where its deficiencies are corrected; and if such a system be more expedient and more conducive to the rapidity of the real progress then I fail to find any reason for subscribing to the theory of re-incarnation or transmigration of the soul.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>THEORY OF KARMA<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Closely linked to this theory is the doctrine of Karma (actions). The two, in fact, are one and the same theory, representing different aspects of the same doctrine. The doctrine of Karma takes for its genesis the diversity of circumstances in which people find themselves at their birth, from causes beyond their control. Some are born in affluence, poverty and indigence; some are born into the world with bodily defects, while others are blessed with bodily perfection; and this disparity, producing arbitrarily, comfort and discomfort, happiness and misery does seem a strange blot on the Divine Providence.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The theory of Karma, in Hindu theology, thus explains this seeming incongruity in the Divine dispensation. According to this theory, all that we receive at our birth in the form of happiness or misery, and all the differences in social status that come into our being at birth are the outcome of our deeds in the life before the present life. We take birth after birth to complete our course on this earth, and what we sow in the one; we must reap in the next. No one would question the logic of the view that human society works on the Laws of Actions. That actions must bear their fruit is the basic principle of every other religion, except Pauline Christianity. Differences in social position, in many cases, undoubtedly arise from our own actions. We are the creators of our own comfort and misery.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">According to this philosophy, inferiority of a person to a second person in the social scale is due some of his sins in his bygone life. However, differences in occupation and employment are the motive power of social machinery. We must serve each other in a wide variety of differing capacities, if adequate contribution is to be made to the common comfort.  If, however, difference of this kind is attributed to some past sin, then comfort and progress must demand the existence of evil. Men of one generation must necessarily commit sin so that, in the next, they may be reborn in the lower for the purpose of contributing to the happiness of the upper social stratum. What kind of philosophy is that considers sin and misdeeds essential to maintain and sustain the cycle of life. It is absurd on the very face of it. The process of procreation demands difference of sex. You may ascribe your present difference from another man to some cause in your previous life, but where were the actions which caused difference of sex in the first pair, whence our species has its being?<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>HAPPINESS A BENEFICENCE AND NOT A FRUIT OF ACTION<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If all our present means of happiness are given to us as a reward for past actions, how are we to explain the happiness which comes to us providentially? Much of our happiness is derived from the varied manifestations of Nature, like the Sun, the Moon, the Earth and all that it provides; and the proportion of happiness that we acquire through our actions depends too, upon the working out, by us, of sources of Nature which were in existence long before man came on the Earth. How can all this be the reward of our past actions? We cannot live without the pre-existence of millions of things in the universe; they all add to our happiness. They all come as beneficence of God, and not in reward of actions. Divine Providence, as exhibited in Nature, makes Divine Blessing, which is the main store of our happiness, a pre-existing thing; while the theory of Karma makes our actions to pre-exist the Divine Blessing, which is absurd on the face of it.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If all our happiness has to arise from out actions, our happiness would be next to nothing. What comes out of our actions in the shape of happiness sinks into insignificance when compared with what we get as Divine Blessings. If we get everything due to the actions of our past life, then we need not be grateful to God anymore. As you can see, this is a blot on the Beneficence of God.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>THE THEORY WEAKENS THE SENSE OF RESPONSIBILITY<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If our actions receive their birth and mould from our beliefs, we should not entertain any tenet or doctrine which tends to ruin our sense of responsibility, and to create in us oral or mental imbecility. Fatalism, in the received sense of the word, was condemned by Islam for this very reason. Vicarious Atonement in Christianity is another condemnable belief. If another has to bear the burden my burden, incentive for action, on my part, is lost. Similarly, we strive hard to alleviate our misery, because we believe that it is possible to alleviate it; but when we find that our trouble is absolutely without remedy, our zeal is gone, for what is the use of trying in such a case? Our misery, under the theory of Karma has come to us as the fruit of some past actions. It cannot be undone, and all our efforts to undo it will be in vain. I committed some wrong in a previous life, I must suffer for its consequences in the present life, and all my efforts to be free from it are simply to give the lie to that theory. If &#8216;A&#8217; is down will cholera which he has got on account of some past wrong, it hardly befit him to seek medical relief if he subscribes to the principle of Karma. The theory thus makes man a fatalist and thereby impedes human progress.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Pain in this life, they say, is the penalty of past actions. If persecution and want of comfort may come within the category of pain, no progress in human society has, till now, been achieved without them as the famous proverb goes, &#8220;No gains without pains&#8221;. The world has seen its best benefactors in the persons of prophets, reformers and philosophers, but, unfortunately, they are the persons who have always been subjected to every kind of persecution. Similarly all scientific discoveries, to which we owe so much of our comfort and happiness, are fruits of pain and hardship. Should we believe that all these great teachers and inventors were wicked men and sinners in the past life, because they have been for the most part persecuted people and leading the most painful lives?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">No one gets happiness without some pain and according to this theory; pain is the penalty of sin. Evil therefore becomes essential for enjoying happiness in the life to come. Such a theory cannot give birth to high character. If &#8216;A&#8217; receives some injury from &#8216;B&#8217;, it is, as a Hindu would say, to make up for some injury received by &#8216;B&#8217; from &#8216;A&#8217; in his previous birth. Thus, offence becomes a justification in the eye of a culprit, if he believes in the philosophy of Karma. I need not be thankful to my benefactors, because, I receive from them only what I gave to them in charity in the past life. The more I think upon this subject, keeping in view all the consequences to which such beliefs much logically lead, the more I am strengthened in my conviction that this philosophy is most unfavourable to our moral growth.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The explanation given by our Holy Quran of the misery around us, and of the social differences which we have been discussing, appeals to me more, as it strengthens my sense of responsibility. Parents are more interested in their children than in their own selves. the welfare of the family often keeps its members away from such misdeeds as are sometimes unscrupulously committed by those who lead single lives.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If the consequences of every action I do be shared by my own children, I shall make my actions more steady and righteous. But if I alone have to reap what I sow, despair or temptation may, sometimes, lead me to extremes.  Belief, therefore, that children born with bodily defects, owe their misfortune to paternity, which sometimes may come to them from three or four generations back, will generally prove a more efficacious check to intemperate actions, than the belief that the children are themselves responsible for their physical deficiencies. A person may not care much for the evil consequences of his actions if they are to be confined to him; but his care to see his family happy may reform him.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>PLEASURE AND PAIN<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The whole difficulty is one of misconception; or rather to conceive adequately of pain, or of pleasure, or of the real object and purpose of this our earthly pilgrimage; for what is pain to one is pleasure to another, who is to decide whether prince or peasant sleeps sounder in the nights or whether the millionaire or the bricklayer has the just perception of the end of life? The sublimation of our consciousness is the main purpose of our sojourn on earth; riches and poverty are both helpful and harmful to this end; helpful to one and harmful to another; a blessing to &#8216;A&#8217;, a curse to &#8216;B&#8217;, and vice versa. Consequently, there can be no ground whatever for any theory which ascribes the prosperity and poverty of this life to the good and evil deeds of an existence that is past.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And the same is true of all other cases wherein different persons have been variously endowed with the gifts of God. In the ordinary way of life, the organs of sense are the vehicles of knowledge and any deficiency in one tends to strengthen the perceptive power of the others. Blind persons are more imaginative that those who possess the faculties of physical sight; and if imagination be a blessing and an aid to the perfection of knowledge, then here is a blessing disguised as a curse.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When sometimes a hard problem arises, to which it is necessary that we devote our whole minds, to the exclusion of all other matters, we choose to site with closed eyes, in a room apart, so that we may be distracted by neither seeing nor hearing. In other words, we deprive ourselves of the use of these senses in order that we may use those that remain to the fuller advantage. The implication of this would be that the use of these senses of hearing and sight causes a distraction to our imagination process. So, it follows, at least at that time, the loss of the organs of sense must be a blessing, if anything, a reward for the past good deeds, rather than the punishment of old misdoings.<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2013/01/25/reincarnation-reality-or-myth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Reincarnation Reality or Myth?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No Reincarnation, No Moksha, No Mukti in the Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2013/01/25/no-reincarnation-no-moksha-no-mukti-in-the-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 16:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mushafiq sultan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2013/01/25/no-reincarnation-no-moksha-no-mukti-in-the-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Ibn Muhammad Samsaara’ (संसार cycle of births and deaths) and ‘Moksha’ (मोक्ष liberation from the cyle of births and deaths) are fundamental beliefs of orthodox Hindus and also of protestant Hindus i.e. Arya Samajists. The difference between these two groups is that while the former believe that not only the Veda Samhitas but also &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2013/01/25/no-reincarnation-no-moksha-no-mukti-in-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Reincarnation, No Moksha, No Mukti in the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>Samsaara’ (<strong>संसार</strong> cycle of births and deaths) and ‘Moksha’ (<strong>मोक्ष </strong>liberation from the cyle of births and deaths) are fundamental beliefs of orthodox Hindus and also of protestant Hindus i.e. Arya Samajists. The difference between these two groups is that while the former believe that not only the Veda Samhitas but also their related Brahmanas, Aranyaks and Upanishads are revealed, the Arya Samajists only consider the Veda Samhitas to be revealed books and infallible. Therefore, only the Vedas are the basis of their faith. Thus any fundamental belief of theirs must have its source in the Vedas. If the belief is not found explicitly in the Vedas, it cannot be claimed as true. The founder of Arya Samaj, Moolshanker aka Swami Dayanand, attempted in his own way to somehow prove that Vedas do teach about reincarnation of souls. The very fact that he could only present six verses from the thousands of Vedic verses to prove reincarnation in the Vedas, itself speaks about the dearth of clear evidence in the Vedas about reincarnation.</p>
<p><span id="more-2418"></span></p>
<p>In this article of mine I will scrutinize those six verses and show that even they do not speak of reincarnation. Modern Arya Samaj  polemicists also continue to use the same verses to prove reincarnation in the Vedas. Regarding the concept of ‘Moksha’ even the word ‘Moksha’ is not present in the entire Vedas, not to speak of the concept itself. Moreover, I have already proved in my earlier articles that Vedas teach about Paradise (Swarga) as a physical place. Combining both these views, we can conclude that the doctrine of reincarnation has no place in the Vedas. Rather the Vedas teach about Paradise (Swarga) and Hell (Narka) exactly like Islam. Therefore, people of Arya Samaj must renounce the belief in endless reincarnations as a human invention and adopt the revealed Islamic concept of life after death.</p>
<p><strong>Analysis of Swami Dayanand’s evidence</strong></p>
<p>In Part 4 of his book <em>Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika</em>, Swami Dayanand has attempted to present some evidence from the Vedas which he thinks teach reincarnation. Following is a one by one refutation of the mantras.</p>
<p>1. Swami Dayanand</p>
<p>Swami ji first quotes Rigveda Mandal 10, Sookt 59, Mantras 6-7</p>
<p>असुनीते पुनरस्मासु चक्षुः पुनः पराणमिह नो धेहिभोगम |<br />
जयोक पश्येम सूर्यमुच्चरन्तमनुमते मर्ळया नह्स्वस्ति ||<br />
पुनर्नो असुं पर्थिवी ददातु पुनर्द्यौर्देवी पुनरन्तरिक्षम |<br />
पुनर्नः सोमस्तन्वं ददातु पुनः पूषापथ्यां या सवस्तिः ||</p>
<p><strong>English rendering of Swami’s translation by Arya Samaj </strong></p>
<p>“O God! Thou conductest our pranas. We pray Thee that we may be happy whenever we may assume another body after death. Grant us, O God! The eyes and all the other senses, the pranas and the inner senses in our future birth when we may assume another body after forsaking the present. Do Thou grant us that when we are born again we may enjoy uninterruptedly all enjoyable thins. May we be able to see the luminous sun and the ingoing and outgoing pranas in all our rebirths. O God! Thou art the dispenser of honor and happiness, make us happy in all our rebirths, through Thy grace.”<br />
“Be gracious, O Lord! To grant that in our rebirths the earth may give us prana born of food and strength, the bright light of the sun may give us prana and middle region may give us life; the juices of medicines such as soma, may give us body (bodily health and vigor). O God! Thou art the giver of strength and nourishment, show us in our rebirths the path of virtue (dharma). We pray that happiness be our lit in all our births through Thy grace.”</p>
[Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika, Part 4, English Version; An Introduction to the Vedas; Translated by Ghasi Ram M.A. L.L.B.]
<p>The Response</p>
<p>The above translations are no doubt partially inaccurate and therefore give a meaning that the context would never allow. Following is the translation by Hindu scholars.</p>
<p><strong>Pandit Shri Ram Sharma Acharya</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="631" height="230" class="wp-image-7102" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna1.gif?w=938" /></p>
<p><strong>A more correct Englsh translation</strong></p>
<p>“6. Asuniti, give us back the (departed) spirit: extend our life that we may live (long): establish us that we may long behold the sun: do you cherish the body with Ghee (that we have offered).<br />
7. Restrore to us, Asuniti, sight and breath, and enjoyment in this world: long may we behold the rising sun; make us happy, gracious (goddess) with prosperity.”</p>
<p>My review</p>
<p>As you can see, Arya Samaj translations happen to be somewhat at variance with the actual translation. The word ‘<strong>rebirth</strong>‘ (Punarjanam) is not present in the text of the mantras as Arya Samaj has mistranslated. Still, I am not concerned over the translations at this moment as much as I am concerned with the wrong deduction being made by Swami ji from these mantras. Following are the points which refute the claim that these mantras are speaking of reincarnation.</p>
<ol>
<li>These mantras are no doubt a prayer. A prayer is always made for something that cannot be achieved ordinarily. According to Hindu theology of Karma, as per a persons deeds he/she is born again with a birth that is appropriate for the deeds done in previous life. A prayer for the same is useless and NOT required.</li>
<li>Moreover, why will one ask for rebirth, even though one knows the sufferings of this world? Why not pray for Moksha i.e. liberation from the cycle of births and deaths, which will at least make some sense?</li>
<li>When is this prayer being made? After death or at the time of death?</li>
<li>The words of the prayer become very weird if we assume that it is speaking about reincarnation. What is that ‘thing’ asking for the spirit and body? It appears to have neither spirit nor body.</li>
<li>What is the guarantee that this prayer is accepted?</li>
<li>Can this not be a prayer at the time of sleep, because sleep is the sister of death? Why assume that it is hinting at reincarnation? This prayer can very well be made at the time of sleep to wake up again with vigour and all the senses intact. That appears far more logical.</li>
<li>The prayer is of very cheap nature in the sense that it is asking for wordly food and enjoyment.</li>
<li>The mantras make mention of <strong>ASUNITI, </strong>the goddess that takes the souls. In no sanskrit lexicon does Asuniti stand for God as has been mistranslated by Arya Samaj.</li>
</ol>
<p>These points prove that there is nothing about reincarnation in these mantras.</p>
<p>2. Swami Dayanand</p>
<p>The next verse provided by Swami ji to prove that Vedas teach about reincarnation is Yajurveda chapter 4, Mantra 15.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="531" height="52" class="wp-image-7103" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna2.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>English rendering of Swami’s translation by Arya Samaj </strong></p>
<p>“O God! May the mind with knowledge and other good qualities an may the full term of life come to us in our rebirth, through Thy favor. May pure thoughts come to us in our rebirth and may sight and hearing also come to us. O God! Thou art the guide and director of the universe; in Thee there is no fault such as arrogance, deceit; thou are the protector of our bodies, and art all wisdom and bliss; keep us aloof from evil deeds and protect us in all our birth-cycles, so that being free from sin we may remain happy in all our births.”</p>
[Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika, Part 4, English Version; An Introduction to the Vedas; Translated by Ghasi Ram M.A. L.L.B.]
<p>The Response</p>
<p>Just like the first two mantras, this mantra has been wrongly translated by inserting the word <strong>rebirth</strong> which is not present in the text. You can even see the english rendering of Swami ji’s translation interpolates many words which are not used by Swamiji. Thus these translations become dubious. I will present more authentic translations of Hindu scholars.</p>
<p><strong>Translation of Swami Karpaatra Maharaj</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="591" height="87" class="wp-image-7104" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna3.gif?w=625" /><strong><br />
A more correct English translation</strong></p>
<p>“Thought has returned to me and life, my breath and soul have come again, sight and hearing have come again. Our bodies’ guard, unscathed, Vaisvânara Agni keep us away from bad deeds and dishonour.”</p>
<p>My review</p>
<p>Similar to the first two mantras, the word <strong>Rebith</strong> is not present in this mantras as well. Following points disprove this mantra in favour of reincarnation:</p>
<ol>
<li>The way Arya Samaj has translated this mantra makes it a prayer. Therefore it cannot be taken as evidence for reincarnation. Refer to point 1 of the above review.</li>
<li>Same as point 2 of the above review.</li>
<li>The words of the prayer become very weird if we assume that it is speaking about reincarnation. What is that ‘thing’ asking for the soul and body? It appears to have neither soul nor body.</li>
<li>Shatapath Brahman 3:2:2:23 CLEARLY says that this passage is read after one wakes up from sleep. Those who bring this mantra as evidence of reincarnation have not even read the Shatapath Brahman of Shukla Yajurveda or they are deceiving the people. They only seek to deceive people. [<em>átha yátra suptvaa | púnarnaavadraasyanbhávati tádvaacayati púnarmánah- púnaraáyurma aáganpúnah- praaNah- púnaraatmaá ma aáganpúnashcákSuh- púnah</em>] “And when he has slept and does not wish to fall asleep again, (the Adhvaryu) makes him mutter the text (Yajurveda 4:15), “Thought has returned to me and life, my breath and soul have come again, sight and hearing have come again.””</li>
</ol>
<p>All these evidences prove that even this mantra has NOTHING to say about reincarnation.</p>
<p>3. Swami Dayanand</p>
<p>Next, the Swami quotes Atharvaveda 7/67/1.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="318" height="57" class="wp-image-7105" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna4.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>English rendering of Swami’s translation by Arya Samaj </strong></p>
<p>“O Lord! May we get, through Thy favor in our rebirths all the senses and that force which sustains the pranas. may we be endowed with the noble riches of knowledge and have firm devotion to Thee. May we get human bodies so that we may be able to tend the fires, Ahavaniya, etc. O Lord of the Universe! May we have the same form, intellect and good bodies as we were endowed with in our previous birth so that we may be able with the help of intellect to discharge our duties properly in the world of our rebirth and may we never suffer pain on any account.”</p>
[Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika, Part 4, English Version; An Introduction to the Vedas; Translated by Ghasi Ram M.A. L.L.B.]
<p>The Response</p>
<p>Another case of deliberate mistranslation by Arya Samaj. Both the Hindi and English translations of this otherwise short verse have been unnecessarily elongated. Again the word ‘<strong>rebirth</strong>‘ is NOT present in the text. It is only an assumption that leads to this mistranslation. Following is the translation by Hindu scholars.</p>
<p><strong>Translation of Shripad Damodar Satvalekar</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="871" height="83" class="wp-image-7106" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna5.gif?w=938" /></p>
<p><strong>A more correct English Translation</strong></p>
<p>“May sense (indriyaa) come to me, again soul, property, and brahmana (sacred knowledge) ; let the fires of the sacred hearth again officiate just here in their respective stations.”</p>
<p>My review</p>
<p>My review of this mantra is similar to the review of first two mantras from Rigveda, because it is on similar lines. Following points refute the claim that this mantra is speaking about reincarnation:</p>
<ol>
<li>This mantra is no doubt a prayer. A prayer is always made for something that cannot be achieved ordinarily. According to Hindu theology of Karma, as per a persons deeds he/she is born again with a birth that is appropriate for the deeds done in previous life. A prayer for the same is useless and NOT required.</li>
<li>Moreover, why will one ask for rebirth, even though one knows the sufferings of this world? Why not pray for Moksha i.e. liberation from the cycle of births and deaths, which will at least make some sense?</li>
<li>When is this prayer being made? After death or at the time of death?</li>
<li>The words of the prayer become very weird if we assume that it is speaking about reincarnation. What is that ‘thing’ asking for the soul? It does not appear to have a soul.</li>
<li>What is the guarantee that this prayer is accepted?</li>
<li>Can this not be a prayer at the time of sleep, because sleep is the sister of death? Why assume that it is hinting at reincarnation? This prayer can very well be made at the time of sleep to wake up again with vigour and all the senses intact. That appears far more logical.</li>
</ol>
<p>Unless all these points are answered satisfactorily, there is no question of accepting reincarnation in this mantra.</p>
<p>4. Swami Dayanand</p>
<p>Swami ji then turns to Atharvaveda 5/1/2 in the hope of establishing reincarnation.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="426" height="66" class="wp-image-7107" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna6.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>English rendering of Swami’s translation by Arya Samaj </strong></p>
<p>“A man who, has done good actions in his previous birth, gets many good bodies in virtue of those good actions, but if he has done evil deeds he does not get human body and is born into the body of an animal, etc., and suffers pain.”</p>
[Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika, Part 4, English Version; An Introduction to the Vedas; Translated by Ghasi Ram M.A. L.L.B.]
<p>The Response</p>
<p>Again if you check this mantra, there is no word ‘<strong>rebirth</strong>‘ (Punarjanam) in it. Following is the translation by Hindu scholars.</p>
<p><strong>Translation of Shripad Damodar Satvalekar</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="700" height="94" class="wp-image-7108" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna7.gif?w=938" /></p>
<p><strong>A more correct English Translation</strong></p>
<p>“He who first attained to the ordinances makes thence many wondrous forms; eager, he first entered the womb {yoni), he who understood speech unspoken.”</p>
<p>My review</p>
<p>Following points do not allow this mantra to be considered as evidence for reincarnation:</p>
<ol>
<li>This hymn is in praise of the deity Varuna.</li>
<li>Mantra 1 of this hymn is speaking about Varuna and how he enters into human form</li>
<li>This mantra also is in praise of Varuna and cannot be used as evidence for reincarnation.</li>
</ol>
<p>5. Swami Dayanand</p>
<p>Lastly Swami ji turns to Yajurveda Adhyaai 19, Mantra 47.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="399" height="74" class="wp-image-7109" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna8.gif?w=625" /></p>
<p><strong>English rendering of Swami’s translation by Arya Samaj </strong></p>
<p>“We have heard that there are two paths in this world for enjoying the good and suffering the bad consequences of virtue and vice. The first is the path trodden by the <em>pitris</em> (the wise) and the <em>devas</em> (the learned) and such men as are devoid of knowledge and wisdom. The first is divided two fold i.e., the <em>pirtriyana</em> and the <em>Devayana</em>. That in which a <em>jiva</em> obtaining a body from the father and mother enjoys happiness as the fruit of its good actions and suffers pain as the consequences of its evil and deeds and again and again, i.e., in which it is subject to past and future birth is called the <em>pitriyana</em>. That in which it obtains emancipation, is liberated from the world i.e., the migrations of birth and death is called <em>devayana</em>. In the former, after having enjoyed the fruits of its stock of virtue it is born again and dies also. In the latter, it is not born again, nor does it die. By these two paths the whole world passes and repasses.”</p>
[Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhumika, Part 4, English Version; An Introduction to the Vedas; Translated by Ghasi Ram M.A. L.L.B.]
<p>The Response</p>
<p>The above rendering of Yajurveda 19/47 by Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj is less of a translation and more of a twisted interpretation. This is the height of dishonesty that short mantra is made to extend like a commentary and is labelled a translation. Again there is no word ‘<strong>rebirth</strong>‘ mentioned in this mantra. Following is the translation by Hindu scholars.</p>
<p><strong>Translation by Swami Karpaatra Maharaj</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="657" height="57" class="wp-image-7110" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.gif" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/012516_1620_noreincarna9.gif?w=938" /></p>
<p><strong>A more correct English Translation</strong></p>
<p>“I have heard mention of two several pathways, way of the Fathers, way of Gods and mortals. On these two roads each moving creature travels, each thing between the Father and the Mother.”</p>
<p>My review</p>
<p>There is no mention of reincarnation in this mantra.</p>
<p>Following points do not allow this mantra to be considered as evidence for reincarnation:</p>
<ol>
<li>When Shatapath Brahman has already interpreted this mantra, there remains no room for any modern wishful interpretation. Shatpatha Brahmana 12/8/1/21 clearly interprets the two paths leasing to Pitrilok (world of the fathers) and Devalok (world of the gods). There is no mention of any rebirth.</li>
<li>Shatapath Brahman 6/6/2/4 says that the gate of the heavenly world or devalok is in the NORTH-EAST. Shatapath Brahman 13/3/1/5 says that the gate of the world of Fathers or Pitrilok is in the SOUTH-EAST. If, according to Arya Samaj, Pitriyaana and Devayaana mean rebirth and emanicipation respectively, then assigning directions to Pitrilok and Devalok is MEANINGLESS.</li>
<li>Brihadaranyak Upanishad 1/5/16 categorizes the worlds into three viz. the world of men (Manushyalok), the world of the Fathers (Pitrilok), the world of the Devas (Devalok). If by Pitrilok is meant rebirth, then Manushyalok becomes meaningless. The full mantra says, <em>“Next there are verily three worlds, the world of men, the world of the Fathers, the world of the Devas. The world of men can be gained by a son only, not by any other work. By sacrifice the world of the Fathers, by knowledge the world of the Devas is gained. The world of the Devas is the best of worlds, therefore they praise knowledge.”</em>  Explaining how the world of Men is gained by a son, Adi Shankaracharya says that a son continues the lineage of the father and in case the father has not performed certain sacrifice he was required to perform, the son performs them for him. The idea is this: A father who has a son instructed in this way remains in this very world as that son; that is, he should not be considered dead.</li>
</ol>
<p>Thus we find that even Yajurveda 19:47 is speaking nothing about the doctrine of reincarnation as is being claimed by Hindu polemicists.</p>
<p>The claim of reincarnation in the Vedas based on half a dozen mantras has been disproved. The only alternative is to go for the concept of Swarga and Narka, of which the Vedas are the upholders.</p>
<p>Agniveer, the modern polemical website tries to add one more mantra of the Rigveda to somehow prove <strong>Rebirth </strong>and <strong>Moksha</strong>. They quote Rigveda 1/24/1-2 as follows</p>
<p>“Question: Whom do we consider the most pure? Who is the most enlightened one in entire world. Who provides us mother and father again in the world after gifting us ultimate bliss or Mukti?</p>
<p>Answer: The self-enlightening, eternal, ever-free Ishwar alone is most pure. He alone provides us mother and father again in the world after gifting us ultimate bliss or Mukti.”</p>
<p>The translation is again dubious ignoring the context of the entire hymn. This hymn narrates the story of Shuna Shep, the son of Rishi Ajigart. He was sold for a hundred cows by his father to Raja Harishchandra as a victim for human sacrifice (Purushmedha). The details are provided in the Aitareya Brahman. It is at the time when Shuna Shep is tied to the stake for sacrifice, that he utters the prayers to Agni to save him so that he may be able to see his father and mother again. There is absolutely no mention of any rebirth or moksha in this mantra as agniveer has tried to present.</p>
<p>The bottom line is that in any scripture in order to prove the validity of a doctrine, it MUST be put forward clearly and unambiguously. To clutch at straws and twist the meanings of other unclear passages to make them speak of the doctrine is purely fraudulent. It is only an act of deception to make others see in the scripture something that is not there. Instead of moulding their thinking according to their scriptures, they mould the scriptures according to their thinking. That is the tragedy of the ancient Vedas, which actually do not belong to this era and have to be left in the ancient era.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2013/01/25/no-reincarnation-no-moksha-no-mukti-in-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">No Reincarnation, No Moksha, No Mukti in the Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
