<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>india &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/india/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The roots of Rape in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fornication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nirbhaya act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment for rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kancha Ilaiah Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal. Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Written by Kancha Ilaiah<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to behave in a cruel fashion with women. Family upbringing, societal conditioning, religious sagas and political animus, all construct our men and women into being what they are — men as aggressive and women as submissive. Which is why men here, in India, are different from men in other countries.<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-961"></span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Their cultural milieu is different. Their spiritual systems train them differently. It&#8217;s not that only Indian men rape and kill children aged three or five. This happens in other countries too, but they are the rarest of rare cases. Daily reports of infants being raped across the length and breadth of a country is a phenomenon unique to India, a society that&#8217;s otherwise highly conservative. Clearly, the institutional upbringing, including that in family, needs to undergo change.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Every time a gruesome rape gets reported, we all are ashamed and angry. That&#8217;s one thing; but working out ways and means to eradicate such evil is another thing. We cannot leave it entirely to the police or the judiciary to tackle such heinous acts. For, rape is also a cultural problem; and it is a more serious problem because of the extermination of the victim. We need to treat the malaise from its very roots.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We are a society that derives its sense of good and bad from our mythologies and spiritual ethics. Our gods and goddesses are not only worshipped but also adored. And it is our lifelong endeavour to emulate them. This is the cultural environment that shapes the lives of most people in India. So it&#8217;s natural that what gods do influences us much more than the moral lesson at the end. Now consider this: we have gods who, for instance, have cut the nose and ear lobes of a woman who approached them professing her love (Lakshman is depicted as having done this to Shurpanakha), and yet we adore him and see him as a symbol of loyalty, sacrifice and righteous indignation.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Lord Krishna stole the clothes of women while they were bathing in the Yamuna river. He did so to tease them and for the pleasure of watching the beauty of their naked bodies. We hang miniature paintings of the same act in our homes proudly. The young men who grow up seeing this, or listening to the story told in an amused tone are bound to not find such an act abhorrent.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We also have a god, Shiva, who insisted on entering the bathing arena of Goddess Parvati and did so by eliminating a child who was keeping guard at the open door. Lord Ganesha is said to have emerged out of such a union. Is this right or wrong? Our mythology tells us that what a husband does is right, that his will is greater than the woman&#8217;s. If a mythological hero is praised for his acts of killing, drinking and fornicating with multiple women (like Indra did with Rambha, Urvashi, Menaka, Tilottama and so on), it is glorification of such behaviour.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When such stories are a part of the mythological texts, they should, at least, be critically evaluated and given a more contemporary, political reading which is rooted in the concept of equality. Instead, the tendency is to not question what our gods did, but simply admire such acts.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Barring a few exceptions, there is no appreciation, per se, of a healthy man-woman relationship which is rooted in the concept of equality. Indian women are shown as lathangi (a person of delicate body), never strong enough to resist her dehumanisation. Though Durga and Kali are shown as strong, in real life such militancy is not seen as feminine.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Now let us turn to the political spectrum. We have had many great men — Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan etc — who got married at a young age with girls of much younger age, went abroad for higher studies, leaving their wives at home totally illiterate or semi-literate. We do not know how these men, or Gokhale and Tilak, treated their wives.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">But we know that they were all devotees of the deities mentioned above. The only man who treated his wife as a friend and educated her right from the first day of his marriage, Mahatma Jyotirao Phule, is not taught as an example to be emulated in our texts.  Somehow, in our patriarchal cultural milieu, unkind and inhuman treatment of women has never been a matter of concern. It&#8217;s considered sacrilegious, for example, to question Lord Ram for leaving his dutiful wife on the random outburst of a dhobi.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And Sita&#8217;s action, in turn, to not question, but to commit suicide, is considered the epitome of all that is pious. Even Gautam Buddha left his young wife, with an infant child. Questioning such acts has never been part of our public discourse.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Or, look at our cinemas. Ever since the industry came into being, silent or talkie, it has used woman&#8217;s body as a money-making object. The song and dance sequence that it has adopted as an art form falls into a common pattern — every hero is licensed to misuse the body of the heroine. The romance in our film industry is not romance; it is vulgarity bordering on the criminal.<br />
So is it a surprise that men of this country see it as their right to violate women in all spheres of life?<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The writer is director, Centre for the Study of Social Exclusion and Inclusive Policy, Maulana Azad National Urdu University, Hyderabad</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paedophilia in Hinduism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 17:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immorality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[age of marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child marriage in Hindu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homosexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[torture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yon shushan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pedophilia in Hinduism (Updated) Written by Sulaiman Razvi Hinduism considers it a sin if the girl is not married before her puberty, it even says that forefathers of the girl shall drink blood of her monthly courses if she isn’t married before puberty. Hinduism also says that marriage of a girl before puberty sanctifies 21 &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Paedophilia in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7649" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/women-child-marriage-paedphilia-facebook_1493731334107.jpg" width="361" height="481" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.jpeg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8-225x300.jpeg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 361px) 100vw, 361px" /></p>
<p>Pedophilia in Hinduism (<strong>Updated</strong>)</p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Hinduism considers it a sin if the girl is not married before her puberty, it even says that forefathers of the girl shall drink blood of her monthly courses if she isn’t married before puberty. Hinduism also says that marriage of a girl before puberty sanctifies 21 generations. Marriage of a Brahmin man with a Shudra girl is censured and Brahmin man marrying a Shudra is considered Vrisalapati and it is considered on par with marrying a girl whose menses has started, a man marrying a girl whose menstruation has started is also considered Vrisalapati. A girl who lives in her father’s house even after her menses begins to appear is considered a degraded girl. Smritis and Puranas says that a 30 years old man shall marry a girl of 12. Swami Prabhupada <a href="https://prabhupadabooks.com/conversations/1977/feb/mayapura/february/27/1977-1?d=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, “Even an eighty-years-old man can marry a sixteen-years-old girl.” This is how Hinduism encourages paedophilia. There is also evidence from Puranas to show that it was practised at the time it was composed. Child marriage and paedophilia was more prevalent in India before the Hindu law were codified. Despite making it illegal, child marriage is still practised,</p>
<p><span id="more-5646"></span></p>
<p>84% Of 12 mn married children under 10 are Hindus (Special to IANS)<br />
<a href="http://www.business-standard.com/article/news-ians/84-of-12-mn-married-children-under-10-are-hindus-special-to-ians-116060101132_1.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.business-standard.com/article/news-ians/84-of-12-mn-married-children-under-10-are-hindus-special-to-ians-116060101132_1.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>33 per cent of the world’s child brides are in India: Report based on last Census<br />
<a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/33-per-cent-of-the-world-s-child-brides-are-in-india-report-based-on-last-census/story-3qOjffxTckWSpyRNmtyD1J.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/33-per-cent-of-the-world-s-child-brides-are-in-india-report-based-on-last-census/story-3qOjffxTckWSpyRNmtyD1J.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>India has second highest number of child marriages as per UNICEF’s 2014 report.<br />
<a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-asia/46-of-south-asian-girls-marry-by-18-unicef/article6403721.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-asia/46-of-south-asian-girls-marry-by-18-unicef/article6403721.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>As per 2016 report, 30% of women were married under the age of 18 years due to cultural impact.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/explained/child-marriage-women-india-census-data-2011-2826398/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indianexpress.com/article/explained/child-marriage-women-india-census-data-2011-2826398/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>71% of those married in Uttar Pradesh are minor girls<br />
<a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/71-of-those-married-in-up-are-minor-girls/articleshow/56695717.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/71-of-those-married-in-up-are-minor-girls/articleshow/56695717.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sexual assault on children is on the rise in India, According to the National Crime Records Bureau a total of 12,363 cases of child rape were reported in the country during 2013 as compared to 8,541 in 2012 accounting for an increase of 44.7%. The maximum child rape cases were reported in Madhya Pradesh (2,112 cases) followed by Maharashtra (1,546 cases) and Uttar Pradesh (1,381 cases). These three states together accounted for 40.8% of the total child rape cases reported in the country.<br />
<a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Online-database-to-name-and-shame-pedophiles/articleshow/46869620.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Online-database-to-name-and-shame-pedophiles/articleshow/46869620.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>But as usual Hindus won’t admit evils which exists in their society or religion and rather puts the blame on Muslims. Hindus says that child marriage were introduced in India by the Muslim invaders. But this claim is refuted by their own scholar Swami Vivekananda who acknowledged that Hinduism permits paedophilia,</p>
<p>“…A girl of eight is married to a man of thirty, and the parents are jubilant over it…. And if anyone protests against it, the plea is put forward, “Our religion is being overturned.” What sort of religion have they who want to see their girls becoming mothers before they attain puberty even and offer scientific explanations for it? Many, again, lay the blame at the door of the Mohammedans. They are to blame, indeed! Just read the Grihya-Sutras through and see what is given as the marriageable age of a girl. … There it is expressly stated that a girl must be married before attaining puberty. The entire Grihya-Sutras enjoin this…” The Complete Works of Swami Vivekananda, Volume 6/Epistles – Second Series/LXXI Rakhal [ <a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_6/Epistles_-_Second_Series/LXXI_Rakhal" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_6/Epistles_-_Second_Series/LXXI_Rakhal<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>So now Hindus can’t deny that paedophilia is sanctioned by Hinduism and started because of Hinduism. Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON wrote,</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes,</p>
<p>”…As soon as a woman attains the age of puberty, she immediately becomes very much agitated by sexual desire. It is therefore the duty of the father to get his daughter married before she attains puberty…” A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 4.25.42 [ <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.25.42" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.25.42<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Another Hindu scholar Sadhguru hints at child marriage,</p>
<p>“It’s a tragic situation. We should realise that we are a society in transition. There was a time when girls would be married at 15. Now they are not married till 25 and 30. So this is the peak of their hormones. In our mindset we are in the past, but in our physical situation, we are in the present. What is causing these rapes? Humans have their needs. If you keep them suppressed, they will do something violent. We need to address this on a much larger scale – hanging rapists or putting them behind bars, that is not the solution. Yes, it needs to be done when it happens. But more importantly as a society, we need to understand why.” <a href="http://www.newindianexpress.com/education/edex/Seven-minutes-with-the-Sadhguru/2016/06/13/article3475994.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.newindianexpress.com/education/edex/Seven-minutes-with-the-Sadhguru/2016/06/13/article3475994.ece <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Brahma Purana states that a girl should be given in marriage when she is only four years old,</p>
<p>Brahma Purana: Gautami Mahatmya 95.7 ”After the fourth year and before the completion of the tenth year the marriage of his daughter must be performed scrupulously by the father.” Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7650" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4.jpeg" width="294" height="444" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4.jpeg 1095w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-198x300.jpeg 198w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-678x1024.jpeg 678w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-768x1161.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-1016x1536.jpeg 1016w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Rama married six years old Sita</strong></h2>
<p>As per Valmiki Ramayana, Rama is said to have married Sita when she was 6 years old,</p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Aranya Kanda 3, Sarga 47, Verses 3-5 “I am the daughter of noble-souled Janaka, the king of Mithila, by name I am Seetha, and the dear wife and queen of Rama, let safety betide you. On residing in the residence of Ikshvaku-s in Ayodhya for twelve years, I was in sumptuosity of all cherishes while relishing all humanly prosperities. In the thirteenth year the lordly king Dasharatha deliberated together with his imperial ministers to anoint Rama as Crown Prince of Ayodhya. When Raghava’s anointment was being organised my venerable mother-in-law known as Kaikeyi begged her husband Dasharatha for a boon. Restraining my veracious father-in-law by a good deed once done by her in his respect, Kaikeyi besought two boons from him, namely expatriation of my husband, and anointment of her son Bharata. ‘If Rama is anointed now, come what may I will not eat, sleep, or drink, and my life ends this way,’ thus Kaikeyi was adamantine, and the king and my father-in-law entreated her who is nagging with meaningful riches, but she did not make good on that entreaty. My great-resplendent husband was of twenty-five years of age at that time, and to me eighteen years are reckoned up from my birth.” Tr. Sri Desiraju Hanumantha Rao</p>
<p>If we do little maths here we understand that Sita was 18 years old when she went into exile with her husband and before the exile she had spent 12 years with her husband in the house of King Dashratha, so if we deduct the age of Sita at the time of exile (18 years of age) and number years she spent in the house of King Dasharath (i.e., 12 years) we get,<br />
18-12= 6 years old<br />
Sita after marrying at 6, lived in the palace of King Dashrath for 12 years. When she was sent to exile with her husband, she was 18 years old. The age difference between Rama and Sita was 7 years. Skanda Purana clearly states that Sita was married when she was only six years old,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana Book, III, Section 2, Chapter 30, Verses 8-9 “The bow of Isvara that was kept in the abode of Janaka, was broken. In his fifteenth year, O king, Rama married the six year old beautiful daughter of the king of Mithila, Sita who was not born of a womb. On getting Sita, Raghava became contented and happy.” Tr. Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare</p>
<p>Hindu scholars Ramswaroop Acharya Maharaj and Pandit Mahendra Pal Arya says Sita was married to Ram when she was 6 years old.</p>
<div style="width: 1220px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-5646-1" width="1220" height="686" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4?_=1" /><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" data-wpel-link="internal">/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4</a></video></div>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" data-wpel-link="internal">Download</a> this video.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Krishna married eight years old Rukmini and many prepubescent girls</strong></h2>
<p>As per Puranas, Krishna is said to have married prepubescent Rukmini when she was only eight years old. Although Hindu text doesn’t mention the age of Krishna at the time of his marriage with Rukmini but the way Hindu text describes him shows that he was an adult at the time of his marriage with prepubescent Rukmini. And other Puranas also shows his sexual intercourse after marriage which is enough to prove that he was a fully grown man.</p>
<p>As per Skanda Purana when Rukmini was born an ethereal voice told her father Bhishmaka that she should be given in marriage to four-armed one born on earth. When Rukmini reached the age of eight her father became worried about her marriage and about the ethereal voice that commanded him to give his daughter in marriage to four-armed one. Then in the meantime Damaghosa visited him and told him that his son Shishupala is considered four-armed one, then the marriage was fixed but Krishna carried away Rukmini and Rukmini had also fell in love with Krishna on first sight, But while Krishna was carrying Rukmini in chariot, Rukmini’s brother Rukmi stopped Krishna and they both fought each other resulting in Rukmi’s defeat. Krishna was about to kill Rukmi but Rukmini begged to forgive her brother and Krishna forgave him, Krishna tonsured Rukmi as per Bhagvad Purana. Then Krishna called all Brahmins born to sages and marriage ceremony took place. This is the summary of the Skanda Purana story, it’s little bit different than the story mentioned in Srimad Bhagavatam where Swayamvar was arranged and it was attended by many kings, But Srimad Bhagavatm doesn’t mention the age of either Rukmini or Krishna but it does say that Rukmini had not attained puberty at the time of her marriage with Krishna. It’s mentioned in Skanda Purana,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana Book V, Section iii, Chapter 142, Verses 8-79 “…The second child born was a daughter named Rukmini. At that time an unembodied ethereal voice told him, ‘O Bhismaka, this girl should be given to a Four-armed One (born) on this earth.’… As time passed on she became a girl of eight years. The king recollected the words of the embodied being and became worried. ‘To whom shall I give this daughter? Who will be the four-armed one?’… In the meantime Damaghosa, the chieftain of Cedi came there from the excellent mountain Raivata. He entered the royal palace where King Bhismaka was present. On seeing him arrived in the abode, the king duly adored him. He was taken to the Royal Court and given a proper seat. ‘This day has dawned meritoriously. I was eager to see you. O great king, my daughter has come to the age of eight years. The ethereal voice of an unembodied being has told that she should be given to a Four-armed one.’ On hearing the words of Bhismaka, Damaghosa said thus: ‘My son is well known in all the three worlds as Four-armed One (Caturbhuja). O Bhismaka, let this girl be given to Sisupala.’ On hearing the words of Damaghosa, O king, Rumini was betrothed to Sisupala by Bhismaka. The auspicious ceremonial beginning was made by Bhismaka, O Yudhisthira. All the kinsmen and members of the family who were staying far-off countries in every direction, were invited and they duly arrived…At the time of dusk, Rukmini, the bride of seductive charms, went out of the city accomplished by her female companions for the worship of Ambika. There she saw Hari, the Lord of Devas, in the guise of a cowherd. On seeing him, she was excited by the god of Love and became completely fascinated. On seeing her, Kesava said to Sankarsana, ‘On dear brother in my view the excellent jewel of a girl should be taken away.’ On hearing the words of Kesava, Sankarsana said: ‘Go ahead, O Krsna, O mighty one. Let the jewel of a girl be seized quickly. I shall follow you closely behind causing much havoc unto all these demons. On getting the consent of Sankarsana, Kesava, the slayer of Kesin, seized the girl, immediately put her on the chariot and went off…Rukma said: O Lord Kesava, unlucky and sinful that I am, I had hit your chest with arrows. It behoves you to forgive me. Formerly Janaki was given over to you by Janaka himself. Now, O lord of Devas, Rukmini is offered unto you by me. Marry her duly in accordance with the injunctions…When Rukma went back Krsna invited excellent Brahmanas. They were the seven mental sons of Brahma…In this manner the Slayer of Madhu honoured them duly and perfectly and then grasped the hand of Rukmini in marriage.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>So this proves that Krishna married Rukmini when she was only eight years old. Srimad Bhagavatam the most authentic Purana of Krishna devotees explicitly states that she had not attained puberty,<br />
Srimad Bhagavatam Canto 10, Chapter 53, Verse 51 “Beholding that charming princess Rukmini gifted with a beautiful waist, a countenance adorned with Kundalas, not attaining the age of puberty, with a golden mekhala beautifying her waist, with rising signs of womanhood, with moving eyes as if in fear…” Tr. J.M. Sanyal</p>
<p>Another translation,</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 10.53.51 “Smitten with love kindled (in their breast) by her, the illustrious warriors assembled (there) felt bewildered to behold the princess, who was possessed of a shapely (slender) waist and had not yet attained puberty, and who had a girdle of jewels thrown about her hips and in whom signs of womanhood were (just) manifesting themselves…” Tr. Gita press Publications</p>
<p>A Hindu scholar named Swami Venkatesananda wrote,</p>
<p>“After the wordhip Rukmini took part of the offerings she had made to the goddess, as a token of the goddess’s blessings. She then left the temple and was talking towards the waiting chariot. Rukmini, who was of exquisite beauty though she had not yet attained puberty, looked for Krsna among the assembled princes. These princes, who had been robbed of their senses by her great charm, had for the moment been paralysed, and stood gaping. As she was about to mount her chariot, Krsna sprang forward, grasped her hand and helped her to his own vehicle, while the princes still stood looking on helplessly. However, as Krsna’s vehicle moved towards Dvaraka, the princes, headed by Jarasandha, began to say to one another: ‘What a disgrace: while we great warriors were watching, the cowherds snatched away a princess!” <strong>The Concise Srimad Bhagavatam, By Swami Venkatesananda, page 292, Publisher SUNY Press, 1989</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other Puranic verses shows that she was engaged in child like sports,</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 105.1-10 “…The monarch Bhismaka observed his beautiful daughter engaged in child-like sports and increasing in splendour day by day like a digit of the moon in the midst of clouds. Considering it advisable to marry his youthful and lovely daughter…” Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So all these references proves that Rukmini was a prepubescent girl of eight years old. If anyone wants to refute this claim of mine then they should furnish reference clearly showing the age of Rukmini, other tricks of twisting facts will not be accepted.</p>
<p>Another thing is that, Krishna is said to have married 16100 princesses after liberating them from a demon named Narakasur. Hindu scriptures says that Krishna died in old age.</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.37.15-20 states that Krishna lived over a hundred years, some Hindu scholars says that he lived up to 120 or 125. Now please read it carefully, Devi Bhagavatam 2.28.1-23; Padma Purana 1.23.91-121 and Padma Purana 1.23.74b-87a states that Krishna’s 16100 wives were abducted by bandits or fishermen and they were made prostitutes after the death of Krishna, refer my article <a href="/index.php/2018/06/20/how-krishna-died-and-what-happened-to-his-wives/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">How Krishna Died &amp; What Happened To His Wives?</a></p>
<p>Now the question is, why would anyone abduct old women for carnal purpose? There must have been many really young and beautiful girls in the city Dvaraka so why they were not abducted and instead Krishna’s wives were abducted? Obviously only young women would be abducted by perverts so Krishna’s 16100 must have been quite young when they were abducted or let’s assume that they were 30 years old when 100+ years old Krishna died. So let’s assume that Krishna had married them some 10 or 20 years before his death then that means those girls were 10 or 20 years old or perhaps less than 10 when 90+ year old Krishna married them, now such coincidence is impossible that all of 16100 princesses were of the same age there must have been a huge age gap between those princesses, some may have been under 10 when Krishna in his old age married them. So does that mean Krishna in old age married extremely youthful girls?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Shiva’s marriage with Parvati</strong></h2>
<p>Unlike the case of Ram and Krishna where age of brides is clearly mentioned, the case of Shiva’s is little complicated. Hindu texts does say that gods and sages fixed the marriage of Parvati with Shiva when Parvati was only eight years old. But doesn’t state her age at the time of her marriage. As per Puranas, When Sati the first wife of Shiva immolated herself, Shiva promised that he would not wed any other lady. But Sati reincarnated on earth as Parvati the daughter of king Himavat. The story has different versions in Skanda Purana, Shiva Purana and Vamana Purana. I shall mention them all. Stories in Shiva and Skanda Puranas are quite same. First I shall discuss the story mentioned in Shiva and Skanda Purana, I will try to make it as short as possible. Himavat along with Parvati went to Shiva and paid obeisance, while Shiva was meditating. Himavat asked Shiva that his daughter along with maids would serve him but Shiva refused. Sages had told Himavat that Parvati’s husband would be Shiva so Parvati started performing penance to gain Shiva as her husband. The duration of her penance is not mentioned, it could last for few months, a year or say for four years. But that doesn’t make any difference to a eight years old girl. Following verses are about when Parvati had not yet started her penance,</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudra Samhita, ParvatiKhanda, section III.8.51- “On hearing the story from Narada, Parvati bent down her head in bashfulness but her smile heightened the beauty of her face. On hearing the story, the lord of mountains stroked her fondly, kissed her on the head and placed her on his seat.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Placing a girl on seat is possible only if she is a child although previous verses clearly says that she was eight years old, it’s not possible to place on seat a full grown girl. Verses of Skanda and Shiva Purana shows that Parvati was only eight before she went to Shiva abode and later started performing her penance,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana I.i.20.1 “Lomasa said: The chaste girl grew up day by day and shone very much. Living in the house of Himalaya, she reached the age of eight years.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudrasamhita, Parvatikhanda, section III.11.1-2 “Brahma said:- O Narada, the daughter of the mountain, honoured in the three worlds, was brought up in the palace of Himacala. When she was eight years old, Siva distressed by Sati’s separation came to know of her birth. Keeping her wonderful memory within his heart He rejoiced much.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudrasamhita, Parvatikhanda, section III.8.4-13 “Himavat said:- O sage Narada…Please read the horoscope of my daughter and tell me about her good and bad fortune. Whose beloved wife will my fortunate daughter be? Narada said: ‘O Mena, O king of mountains, this daughter of yours has all auspicious signs…There is an abnormal line also. Listen to the indication thereof. Her husband will be a naked Yogin, without any qualities. He will be free from lust. He will have neither mother nor father. He will be indifferent to honours. His dress and manners will be inauspicious…O sage, on hearing your words, and inferring that indications reffered to Siva, Parvati’s joy knew no bounds.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>When Shiva was pleased with Parvati’s penance he sent seven sages to Himavat to ask Parvati’s hand in marriage,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana I.i.23.3-9 “Why have all of you come? Tell me the reason for your visit. Then the Seven Sages said: ‘We have been sent by Mahesa. We have come to you in order to see the girl. O Mountain, understand us. Show us your daughter immediately.’ Saying ‘So be it’ to the group of Sages, Parvati was brought there. Himavan, the lord of Mountains, who loved his children, placed Parvati in his lap and said laughingly. ‘This is my daughter indeed. But listen to my words again. Siva is the most excellent one among ascetics. The destroyer of Madana is devoid of attachment. How does he by whom Smara (Madana) has been made Ananga (bodiless), seek a marriage alliance? Offering the daughter in marriage to the following persons is not recommended: one who is very near (i.e. closely related), one who is very far off, one who is extremely rich one, one who is devoid of wealth, one who is unemployed and a foolish fellow. One shall not offer one’s daughter in marriage to a stupid person, to a person who is devoid of attachment, to a self-esteeming person, to a sick man and to a madcap. Hence, O excellent…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p><strong>Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare writes on verse 5:</strong> “Evidence of child-marriage at the time of our text. Parvati who performed penance for a long time, must have been too old to sit in the lap of her father.”</p>
<p>This is a very important point. Parvati along with her father went to Shiva’s abode when she was eight years old, the duration of her penance is not mentioned so let’s assume that she performed penance for a year or let’s say for four years. Considering that her father placed her in his lap even after the penance so she must be very young girl at the time. Another point is that, When Narada and gods approached him and told him that his daughter would marry Shiva he was somehow convinced to give his eight years old daughter to Shiva without thinking about the age difference.</p>
<p>Now let’s have a look at Vamana Purana version about the marriage of Shiva and Parvati.</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 25.1 “Pulastya said Three daughters endowed with beauty and merit were born to Mena and a son named Sunabha was born as the fourth. [5-7] O sage, six years after their birth, the three daughters born to her, went out to perform penance, Gods saw those handsome girls. The austere Kutila who was as beautiful as the rays of the Moon was then taken to the heaven of Brahman by the Adityas and the Vasus. Then the gods said, ‘O Brahman, please tell us whether she will give birth to a son who will slay Mahisa.” Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 25.8-27 “The great god Brahman said, ‘This austere girl is not capable of holding the semen of Sankara. Leave this poor girl.’ But then O Narada, the enraged Kutila said to Brahmana, ‘O Lord, I shall so endeavour that I hold the semen of Sankara which is very difficult to be born…She too who was called Ragavati, was brought to heaven by the gods. Offering her to Brahman, Prajapati spoke to her in the same manner. Losing her temper, she too said, ‘Truly I shall undergo penance in such a manner that the slayer of Mahisa will become associated with my name. ‘Then the austere Mena knowing, as she did, that the two daughters had already left her, prevented her third daughter from taking to penance. And she exclaimed ‘Uma (O do not practice penance).’ Her mother the brillaint daughter of the Pitrs gave her daughter the name Uma. She then went to the forest…Then Brahman said, ‘She is undoubtedly the consort of Sankara, by whose lustre indeed you have been distracted and have become lustreless…” Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>So the gods tried to marry 6 years old girl to Shiva. Swami Parmeshwaranand explains it as,</p>
<p>“Three daughters named Kutila, Ragini and Parvati and a son named Sunabha were born to Himavan by his wife Mena. The three daughters went to the Himalayas for penance, to get Siva as husband. They were not even six years old then. The Devas saw them. The Adityas and the Vasus took Kutila who was doing penance, to the world of the gods. All the gods gathered together and asked Brahma. “Oh Lord, be pleased to tell us if this girl will be able to hear a son who could kill Mahisasura”. Brahma replied. “This poor girl will not be capable of bearing the radiance of Siva. So let her go away.” Kutila got angry at Brahma and said “Lord, I will try to become fit to bear the unbearable radiance of Siva. Harken, I will do penance properly and please Visnu and make Siva bow his head. I take a vow to that effect.” Brahma became angry and told Kutila, “You, wicked Kutila, you did not succumb to my words. So by my curse you will be turned to water.” Kutila having been cursed by Brahma became water and began to flood the world of Brahma. Seeing the flow of water, Brahma made cause-ways on four sides with the Vedas of Rg, Yajus, Sama and Atharva. Thus being tied up she stays in the world of Brahma. The Devas took Ragini also before Brahma and put the same question. The reply of Brahma was the same as before. She also got angry and said to Brahma. “I will do great penance so as to enable to give birth to one in my family to be the killer of Mahisasura.” Brahma cursed her also. “You are deliberately disobeying my words which even Devas won’t gainsay. So you will become the colours of the twilight.” Thus, she became the fast colours of the twilight, and her body was divided among the Pleiades. (Vamana Purana, Chapter 51).” <strong>Encyclopaedic Dictionary of Puranas, Volume 1, p.237, by Swami Parmeshwaranand, Published by Sarup &amp; Sons, 01-Jan-2001</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><strong>Hindu scriptures promoting paedophilia</strong></h1>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.94 A man, aged thirty years, shall marry a maiden of twelve who pleases him, or a man of twenty-four a girl eight years of age; if (the performance of) his duties would (otherwise) be impeded, (he must marry) sooner.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.88 To a distinguished, handsome suitor (of) equal (caste) should (a father) give his daughter in accordance with the prescribed rule, though she have not attained (the proper age).</p>
<p>Parasara Smriti 7.5-6 When the twelfth year is reached by the female child, if the guardian does not give her away in marriage, her fore-fathers drink, without interruption, during each succeeding month, whatever blood is passed in her courses. The mother, and the father, and likewise the eldest brother, all these three relatives will go to hell, if before menstruation they neglect to marry the girl.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada <a href="http://www.prabhupada.org.uk/articles1/48_53/48.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, “All my sisters were married within twelve years. My second sister, she became twelve years, and I heard my mother become so disturbed: &#8220;Oh, this girl is not being married. I shall commit suicide…And she was given to a boy, my brother-in-law, for the second marriage. Means that my brother-in-law lost his first wife, and still, he was twenty-one years old. My sister was twelve years old and brother-in-law was twenty-one. In the sastra&#8230; I do not know exactly what is that sastra, but they say that if the girl before marriage has menstruation, then the father has to eat that menstrual liquid. Means it is, mean, very strict. And if the father is not living, then the elder brother has to eat. (break) &#8230;ty of getting the girl married rests on the father. In the absence of the father, the eldest brother. The girl must be married. That is it. It is called daya, kanya-daya.”</p>
<p>Yama Samhita verse 22 “The father, who does give away [in marriage] his maiden-daughter after she has attained the twelfth year, drinks her menstrual blood, month after month.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Padma Prana VI.118.2-15 &#8220;&#8230;A man should marry his daughter as long as she has not attained puberty. Wise men recommend a girl&#8217;s marriage when she is eight years old&#8230;&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 76.43-52 &#8220;&#8230;Whoever having decorated his virgin daughter aged eight years with apparel reverentially makes a gift of her to a good Brahmin, reaps the benefits of the gift of Durga.&#8221; Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>Samvarta Samhita verses 66-68 “[A maiden] eight years [old] becomes Gouri; one of nine years a Rohini; and of ten years, a Kanya (maiden); and after that, a Rajasvala (a woman in menses). By seeing a maiden in menses, her mother, father and eldest brother these three go to hell. Therefore one should espouse a maiden before she has menstruated; the marriage of an eight years old maiden is most preferrable.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 24.41. A damsel whose menses begin to appear (while she is living) at her father’s house, before she has been betrothed to a man, has to be considered as a degraded woman: by taking her (without the consent of her kinsmen) a man commits no wrong.</p>
<p>Gautama Dharmashastra 18.21 A girl should be given in marriage before (she attains the age of) puberty.</p>
<p>Baudhayana Dharmashastra, Prasna 4, Adhyaya 1.11 Let him give his daughter, while she still goes naked, to a man who has not broken the vow of chastity and who possesses good qualities, or even to one destitute of good qualities; let him not keep (the maiden) in (his house) after she has reached the age of puberty”</p>
<p>Vasishtha Dharmashastra 17.70 ‘Out of fear of the appearance of the menses let the father marry his daughter while she still runs about naked. For if she stays (in the house) after the age of puberty, sin falls on the father”</p>
<p>Mahabharata13.44.13 “A person of thirty years of age should wed a girl of ten years of age called a Nagnika. Or, a person of one and twenty years of age should wed a girl of seven years of age.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.10.16 “If he marry, he must select a maiden who is of a third of his age.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Padma Purana II.85.62-66a ”…Wise men get married their unmarried daughter(s). As long as she does not menstruate (i.e. does not attain puberty)…” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Padma Purana II.47.47-65 “…The father should keep his daughter in his house till she becomes eight years old. He should not keep a strong (i.e. grown up) one. Both the parents get the (fruit of the) sin which a daughter, living in her father’s house, commits…” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Garuda Purana chapter 95 “…”The relations of a girl incur the sin of wilfully creating a miscarriage, or of killing a foetus in the even of their failing to give her away in marriage before she has commenced to menstruate. A girl is liberty to make her own choice, and to be united with a husband, in the absence of any such relation to give her away in marriage…” Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.19.11 “Many sons should be sought so that at least one would go to Gaya, one shall marry a girl of the Gauri type (i.e. of eight years or one who is a virgin) or one shall discharge a Nala (? lean like a red) bull.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Vayu Purana 21.12 “…It is better to wish for many sons. At least one of them will go to Gaya or marry a girl eight years old or discharge a blue ox (free to wander).’ [15] Brhaspati said: A son begot after marrying after marrying a girl of eight years sanctifies twentyone generations. Moreover, he sanctifies six generations in the family of his maternal uncle. This is remembered as the benefit (of such marriage).” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Kisari Mohan Ganguli writes,</p>
<p>“Vrishalipati literally means the husband of a Sudra woman. By actually marrying a woman of the lowest order, by marrying before the elder brother, by marrying a girl that has attained to puberty, and by certain other acts, a Brahmana comes to be regarded as a Vrishalipati.” On Mahabharata 13.126 <a href="http://www.sacred-texts.com/hin/m13/m13b091.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">www.sacred-texts.com/hin/m13/m13b091.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Vyasa Samhita 2.2-4 “…of auspicious signs, clad in silken garments, and not above eight years of age, and whose paternal ancestors to the tenth degree in the ascending line were all men of renown, should be solemnly wedded by a (twice-born) according to religious rites, if preferred in marriage. [7] The sin incidental to (an act of) procuring abortion (lie: destruction of the foetus) is committed, if through the negligence of her giver a girl menstruates before her marriage. He, who does not give away a daughter in marriage before she attains puberty, becomes degraded.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Skanda Purana VII.I.205.80-86 “If a girl, before being consecrated by marriage rites, has her menses in the house of her father, her Pitrs become fallen and that girl is called Vrsali. If a Brahmana knowingly marries that girl, they say, he is not fit for a Sraddha. He cannot be in the same row as others. He is a Vrsalipati. Gauri virgin is the best and most important. Rohini is considered as Madhyama (middling). Rajasvala should be known as the bases though equal to her (Rohini) image. When there is no menstrual flow, she is Gauri. When there is the flow she is Rohini. If the girlhood has not fully developed she is Kanya. One without breasts is Nagnika. A seven year old girl is Gauri; nine year old is Nagnika. Ten year old shall be Kanya; above that she is Rajasvala. Through breasts she spoils the family of her father and through menstrual flow, she spoils the desirable goal (salvation) and pleasures of the other worlds of her father. He who marries one with menstrual flow should be known as Vrsalipati.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 9.41.26-47 “The World-Mother never stays even for a moment in his house who eats at the house of one who marries an unmarried girl twelve years old in whom menstruation has commenced…” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Above two verses considers the man sinful who marries a girl who started her menstruation in her father’s house which means a person should marry a girl who has not yet started her menstrual period.</p>
<p><strong>Proof that girls as young as 10 were married off</strong></p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 3.27.40 “My daughter has come to a marriageable age; I have no money. Her age has exceeded ten years; the marriageable age limit has been exceeded. Alas! What am I to do?” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Radha the concubine and aunt of Krishna was married to Rayana at the age of 12,</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Prakriti Khanda, Chapter 49, Verses 36-40 &#8220;In the Varaha-kalpa, Radhika was born in the village of Gokula in the family of a Vaisya cowherd. She was born without any human contact&#8230;After the <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">expiry of twelve years</span>, finding her becoming youthful, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">she was married to a trader named Rayana</span>&#8230;&#8221; Tr. Shanti Lal Nagar, edited by Acharya Ramesh Chaturvedi</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 5.17.3-26 “The King Chandrasena, the father, was very pleased to have this beautiful daughter and gladly called her by the name of Mandodarî. This daughter began to grow daily like the phases of the Moon. When she grew ten years old, she became very handsome. The King now became anxious to have a suitable bridegroom and used to think of it everyday. The Brâhmins then told the king that there was a prince named Kambugrîva, the intelligent son of the powerful king Sudhanvâ of Madra” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Skanda Purana III.iii.18.4-6 “When she was aged twelve years, the girl had beauty of form and all good features. A Brahmana named Padmanabha whose wife had passed away, requested for the haand of the girl. The Brahmana had plenty of wealth. He was calm and qui. He was a permanent companion of the king. So the father of the girl did not dare to refuse. He gave the daughter to him. The marriage was celebrated at midday…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana VII.I.166.17-20 “…You are to behave in a manner that will give no cause to the Devas to despise me. My dear daughter, I have heard this cited in sacred scriptures. ‘If without being consecrated (in marriage) a girl discharges her menses in her father’s house the father earns the sin of Brahmana-slaying and the girl is known as a Vrsali (Sudra). Therefore, I am sending you off in the company of aged ministers. Hurry up. Choose your own husband and decide.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>Some Hindus have attempted to refute the above points with futile arguments, so here’s a response to those apologists. I have quoted dozens of verses, several apologists have attempted to refute only 20-30% of the article which means a large part of the article is irrefutable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: According to Rig Veda 10.85.40-41 and Padma Purana V.118.2-15 a girl should be given in marriage only after she attains puberty.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The verse actually states the stages of development of a girl, it doesn’t talk about marrying off daughter only after she attains puberty, in the Atharved it’s a prayer made by a man thanking gods for bestowing riches and sons. A girl can conceive a child only after she attains puberty and that’s what it’s stating here. The apologist has quoted Padma Purana verse out of context (to buttress his RigVed claim) otherwise the verse itself would have refuted the explanation of the apologist, here are the next lines of the verse,</p>
<p>Padma Purana V.118.2-15 &#8220;When small hair appears (on the private parts), Soma enjoys a daughter. When she attains puberty, gandharvas (enjoy her); and when breasts appear (prominent), Fire (enjoys her). <u>A man should marry his daughter as long as she has not attained puberty</u>. <u>Wise men recommend a girl&#8217;s marriage when she is eight years old</u>. She should be duly given to a brahmana who is well-versed in sacred learning, possesses moral virtue, has actually studied Vedas, and has observed celibacy. This is said to be the rule regarding a daughter to be given (in marriage).” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>What is alluded here is that a girl should be given in marriage before she is enjoyed by gods i.e. before she attains puberty, these are Hindu god Shiva’s words. Rigved verses 36-38 indicates that the bride was already married and then she started becoming mature.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: The translation of Valmiki Ramayana about the age of Sita is wrong, here’s the correct translation, “<em>She had been in Ikshwaku dynasty of King Dashratha for <strong><u>two years</u></strong> and got all the materialistic pleasure available for human kind.</em><em> Thereafter, in the <strong>third year</strong>, the king and lord Dasaratha consulted other kings and ministers to consecrate Rama.” </em>The word Dash here doesn’t mean 10 but mentions Dasharath, so Sita’s age at the time of her marriage was 18-2=16 not 6.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The Sanskrit words mentioned in these verses are so simple that even those fluent in Hindi language can define those words. I am quoting the Sanskrit verses,</p>
<p>उषित्वा <u>द्वा दश</u> समाः इक्ष्वाकूणाम् निवेशने |<br />
भुंजाना मानुषान् भोगान् सर्व काम समृद्धिनी ||</p>
<p>तत्र <u>त्रयो दशे वर्षे</u> राज अमंत्र्यत प्रभुः |<br />
अभिषेचयितुम् रामम् समेतो राज मन्त्रिभिः || ३.४७.४-५</p>
<p>The apologist instead of explaining the verses has mischievously mistranslated his scripture. If the word Dasha here doesn’t mean Ten but rather mentions the name of Dasharath then I am eager to know how would the apologist write twelve and thirteen in Sanskrit language? The word Dva means two, Dasha means ten, Varsha means years, which is quite same for the next verse wherein the word Trayo means three. These words are so simple that I don’t find the necessity to quote any lexicon here. In Shiva Purana, Section 1 Vidyesvara Samhita, Chapter 15, verses 42-45 the same word Dva-Dash is mentioned which is translated by all scholars as Twelve. Apologists are conveniently ignoring Skanda Purana Book III, Section 2, Chapter 30, Verses 8-9 which leaves no doubt regarding the age of Sita at the time of her marriage, it explicitly mentions that Sita was 6 years old at the time of her marriage. To convince the apologist, let me quote another verse from Valmiki Ramayana about the age of Sita at the time she was wedded to Rama,</p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Sundara Kanda 5, Chapter 33, Verses 13-14 “I stayed in Rama&#8217;s house there for twelve years, enjoying the worldly pleasures belonging to human kind and fulfilling all my desires. Thereafter, in the thirteenth year, King Dasaratha along with his preceptors started to perform anointment of the kingdom to Rama, a celebrity of Ikshvaku dynasty.” Tr. Desiraju Hanumantha Rao</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After calculating the years mentioned here we get the same number that Sita was 6 years old.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ Claim</strong>: Srimad Bhagavatam 10.53.51 is a mistranslation, the verse nowhere states that Rukmini had not attained puberty at the time of her marriage with Krishna. There’s no word for puberty here.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The Sanskrit words mentioned in this verse are Stanim (breasts) and Vyanjat (budding) which means her breasts had started budding, these words are used as idioms to state that Rukmini had not yet attained puberty, because the breasts of a girl doesn’t start budding when she is a sixteen years old girl (as apologists claim), by the time a girl reaches the age of 16 she becomes an adult. Almost all translators have translated the same.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ Claim</strong>: Skanda Purana Book V, Section iii, Chapter 142, Verses 8-79 cannot be used to show that Rukmini was 8 years old because the Sanskrit words mentioned here are Adashta Varsha in which the word Ada is ambiguous so it may mean anything like she has become twice the age.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: Even the apologist himself is confused, or maybe he is deliberately twisting words in order to cause confusion in the minds of readers. The apologist instead of buttressing his claim with lexicons or texts is rather making assumptions. The Sanskrit words mentioned here are quite clear, words Ashta Varsha means 8 years. This claim of mine about 8 years old Rukmini been wedded to Krishna as per Skanda Purana remains uncontested. Here too I don’t find the necessity to quote lexicons to refute the pathetic claim of the apologist.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: As per Harivamsa Purana Visnuparva 2.59.37 Rukmini was sixteen years old when she was married to Krishna.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: To my knowledge, there are no Sanskrit words in this verse that can be translated as ‘sixteen years old’, though the text describes Rukmini as an adult. Apologist can quote the Sanskrit words which translates as 16 years old.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Apologists also quotes a verse from Brahmavaivarta Purana where Rukmini is described as of having attained puberty. But does that negate Skanda Purana and Bhagavad Purana verses? Does that nullify or refute verses from Skanda and Bhagavad Purana? No, rather they are to be taken as different versions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: The gods and sages didn’t attempt to marry off 6 years old Parvati to Shiva, the reference of Vamana Purana given is wrong.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: This story is mentioned in Vamana Purana, Saromahatmya chapter 25, verses 1-27, following is the screenshot from the scripture,</p>
<p>My emphasis was not on when Parvati was married to Shiva as Hindu scriptures don’t mention the age of Parvati at the time of her marriage. The Hindu gods had already made up that 6 year old Parvati would be able to hold Shiva’s semen i.e., she would be able to conceive the child of Shiva.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-8696" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-300x148.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="296" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-300x148.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-768x379.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1.jpg 808w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: Manu Smriti 9.94; Mahabharata 13.44.13 A man, aged thirty years, shall marry a maiden of ten or twelve. These verses merely tells the man to simply marry a girl younger than him, these shouldn&#8217;t be taken literally.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: Apologists are playing with words to distort their Hindu texts. It’s not a commandment that a man should marry only when he is 30 years old or that a girl should be given in marriage only when she is 10 or 12 years old, and this is what Acharya Medhatithi is also alluding to. A man can marry at the age of 25 given that the girl is very much younger than him, this is already mentioned in Vishnu Purana,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.10.16 “If he marry, he must select a maiden who is of a third of his age.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>So a 40 year old man should wed a girl who is around 13 years old, if a man is 20 years old then he must marry a girl who is one third of his age that is he must marry a 6 or 7 years old girl and this is exactly what Mahabharata and Manu Smriti states. The apologists are deliberately ignoring the age gap mentioned in Mahabharata and Manu Smriti that a 30 years old adult man should wed a prepubescent girl of 10-12 years who is one third of his age.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: Vishnu Smriti 24.41 makes it clear that only those girls are considered degraded who haven’t given in marriage before they started menstruating, it doesn’t say keeping a married daughter who started menstruating in father’s home is degraded. It is because a girl has to stay in father’s home after her marriage till she completes her third year after she started menstruating, as we seen earlier.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The author himself seems to be confused, he has acknowledged that “only those girls are considered degraded who haven’t given in marriage before they started menstruating”. As the apologist has admitted it, I don’t find the reason to explain it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Paedophilia in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="https://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" length="47713340" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 11:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal status]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honor killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed &#160; Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show Satyamev Jayate has once again brought the issue to public attention. In the discussions that followed the verse &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Neer Mohammed</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7866 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png" alt="" width="359" height="239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf-300x200.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f404e3cf.png 450w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" />Female foeticide is undoubtedly one of the most inhuman practices that plagues our society today. A lot has been said and written on this sensitive topic. The recent discussion on Aamir Khan’s show <em>Satyamev Jayate</em> has once again brought the issue to public attention.</p>
<p>In the discussions that followed the verse <strong>यत्र</strong> <strong>नार्यस्तु</strong> <strong>पूज्यन्ते</strong> <strong>रमन्ते</strong> <strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>देवता</strong>  (Devatas reside where women are worshipped) was used repeatedly. This painted a misleading picture of the ancient indian society suggesting that misogyny sprung up from nowhere. A closer examination reveals, however, that this verse from Manu Smriti has been divorced from its context and the word <strong>“</strong><strong>पूजन</strong><strong>” or “</strong><strong>पुजा”</strong> has been interpreted rather arbitrarily to suit a particular view. We reserve the discussion of this verse for future articles.</p>
<p><span id="more-856"></span></p>
<p>Earlier there were 40 accepted Vedic sanskar (sacraments), now however only 16 of these are conducted. The first of these 16 sanskar is that of “<strong>Garbahabhan</strong>” (conception), the second being “<strong>Punsavan</strong>”. Before coming to the main subject of the article, I would like to place before the reader a few facts about these sanskar (sacraments).</p>
<p><strong>Varna System or Death System?</strong></p>
<p>What follows is a brief analysis of these sanskar (sacraments) and the caste system. In Hinduism the evil of caste gets associated with the person from his birth itself. On the face of it Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj seem to reject the birth based caste system and accept a social system based on merit but do they practice what they preach? To investigate this let us consider the following three verses from Manu Smriti. The first two of these occur as they are in Swami Dayanand’s <em>Sanskar Vidhi</em> published by Arya Sahitya Prachar Trust (Arya Samaj)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7867" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png" alt="" width="549" height="267" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a-300x146.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f6e4ed8a.png 652w" sizes="(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px" /></p>
<p>(A)&#8221;Garbhan and other Sanskar (sacrament) of dwija should be performed with holy rites prescribed by the Veda. Because these sanctify the body and purify in this life and after death&#8221; ( Manu Smriti 2-26)</p>
<p>(B)&#8221;By womb related sacraments (Garbhadan, Punswan, Simantyan), Jatkarma, Chudakarma and Upanyan sanskar (sacraments) the defects related to the womb and the semen of the Dwijas is removed&#8221; (Manu Smriti 2-27).</p>
<p>(C)“Let (the first part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s name (denote something) auspicious, a Kshatriya&#8217;s be connected with power, and a Vaisya&#8217;s with wealth, but a Sudra&#8217;s (express something) contemptible.</p>
<p>(The second part of) a Brahmana&#8217;s (name) shall be (a word) implying happiness, of a Kshatriya&#8217;s (a word) implying protection, of a Vaisya&#8217;s (a term) expressive of thriving, and of a Sudra&#8217;s (an expression) denoting service.” [Manu Smriti 2/31-32]
<p>The third verse is not from the above mentioned book however the idea is mentioned in the book in following manner</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7869" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png" alt="" width="550" height="66" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a-300x36.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f268f82f249a.png 611w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>“The male child born should be named thus &#8211; if the child is Brāhman &#8211; name him ‘Devsharmā’, if he is Kshatriya- name him ‘Devvarmā’, if he is Vaishya &#8211; name him ‘Devgūpta’,if he is a Shūdra name him ‘Devdās’.</p>
<p>Here it has been advised to name a child in the naming ceremony (10 days after birth) according to the above mentioned rules.</p>
<p>Whether such practices can remedy deficiencies of semen or womb is irrelevant but a number of questions arise after reading the above, why is this practice limited only to the Dwijas (Brahman, Kshatriya and Vaishya)? What is the basis of this distinction drawn between the Dwijas (referred to as ‘twice-born’ henceforth) on one hand and the Shudras on another? Certainly there is no difference in merit of 10 days old twice-born and Shudra, then why is a child born in Shudra family believed to be a ‘Shudra’ and has ‘das’ appended to his name? These people who keep insisting that Varna system is not based on birth but on merit have no answers to these questions.</p>
<p><strong>Punsavan Sanskar (Sacrament)</strong></p>
<p>What exactly is this Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament)? Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelkar while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ sukta from Atharvaved, in his commentary of Atharvaved writes,</p>
<p>“The birth of son is called ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ and birth of girl is called ‘<strong>Straishuya</strong>’”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar has named the section where he explains this sukta as “Certain birth of son” this in itself explains the term ‘Punsavan’. Swami Dayanand’s associate who later became the leader of Sanatan Dharma, Pandit Bhimsen Sharma while explaining the ‘Punsavan’ writes,</p>
<p><strong>उत्पत्स्यमानगर्भस्य</strong> <strong>बेजिकगार्भिकदोषपरिहारार्न्थ</strong> <strong>पुंरूपत्वसंपत्तये</strong> <strong>च</strong> <strong>पुंसवनम्</strong></p>
<p>(षोडशसंस्कारविधी, तृतीय संस्करण,1926, पृ. 72-73)</p>
<p>“Punsavan Sanskar (sacrament) is conducted to remove the semen and womb related deficiencies of the unborn child and to make it male”</p>
<p>In other words the sanskar (sacrament) is conducted so that a male child is born and if the unborn child is female then it should be transformed to a male child. This is the ancient Vedic way of getting rid of female foetuses. Even if we leave aside the question of effectiveness of such a procedure, the mentality operating behind such practices can be easily seen. If the female foetus itself is converted to male foetus then there is no question of birth of girls. This indicates that why even today people do not wish a girl child to be born to them.</p>
<p>While today, scientific methods are used to detect the sex of the foetus and to kill it if it is a girl, in Vedic times the foetus itself was transformed (at least people wished to do so) to a male foetus. The underlying mentality is same, only the methods have changed.</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand presents five proofs related to Punsavan Sanskar, without mentioning their meaning. However, the meanings given by other Arya Samaji Scholars make the picture clearer. Below is the meaning given by Ramgopal Vidyalankar in his book titled <em>Sanskar-Prakash Arthart Mahrshi Dayanand Sarsvati Parnit Sanskarvidhi</em> on pages 43-44</p>
<p><strong>पुमानग्निः</strong> <strong>पुमानिन्द्र</strong><strong>: </strong><strong>पुमान्देवो</strong> <strong>ब्रहस्पति</strong><strong>:  </strong><strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>पुत्रं</strong> <strong>विन्दस्व</strong> <strong>तं</strong> <strong>पुमाननु</strong> <strong>जायतां</strong> <strong>स्वाहा</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>मंत्रब्राह्मण</strong><strong> 1/4/9]</strong></p>
<p>“Agni, Indra, and learned scholar of diverse disciplines &#8211; give you strength. May you get a strong son and let even his descendent be strong.” [Mantra Brahman 1/4/9]
<p><strong>शमीमश्वत्थ</strong> <strong>आरूढ़स्तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवानं</strong> <strong>कृतम्</strong> <strong>तद्वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेद्नं</strong> <strong>तत्स्त्रीष्वाभरामसि</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/1]</strong></p>
<p>“’Punsavan is done after a man as virile as a horse conceives a woman calm by nature as it is the best solution to get a son. The sanskar (sacrament) is conducted on women.” [Atharvaved 6/11/1]
<p>Let me also mention the interpretation of Pandit Shripad Damodar Satvelekar</p>
<p>“(<strong>अश्व</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>त्थ</strong><strong>: </strong>) Peepal tree (<strong>शमी</strong> <strong>आरूढ़</strong><strong>:</strong>) where it grows on Shami tree (<strong>तत्र</strong> <strong>पुंसवनं</strong> <strong>कृतं</strong> ) Punsavan is done there. (<strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>) This ensures birth of a son (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रीषु</strong> <strong>आ</strong> <strong>भरामसि</strong>) we give this to women ”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains the procedure of this sanskar (sacrament) in his exegesis of this verse</p>
<p>“1. The Peepal tree that grows on the Shami tree makes the foetus in the womb take male form. That is if a woman takes the medicine prepared out of this then she will definitely give birth to a son. 2. Such a Peepal tree ensures the birth of a son. 3. The consumption of it ensures the birth of a son. 4. Women should be given the medicine prepared from such a Peepal tree to ensure the birth of a son.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar continues</p>
<p>“The peepal tree growing on a Shami tree should be powdered and should be consumed with honey or milk etc. This makes the woman’s womb capable of producing a son. This medicine should be given to a woman who gives birth only to girls. This changes their womb and may generate strength to produce a male child.”</p>
<p>Now let us take a look at the second verse of ‘Punsavan’</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar writes</p>
<p><strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>रेतो</strong> <strong>भवति</strong> <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियामनुषिच्यते</strong> <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong> <strong>तत्प्रजापतिरब्रवित्</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/2]</strong></p>
<p>“God Prajapati has said that semen definitely is in man, this is nurtured in the woman and thus a son produced.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar explains this as</p>
<p>(<strong>पुंसी</strong> <strong>वे</strong> <strong>रेतः</strong> <strong>भवति</strong>)Semen definitely is in the man (<strong>तत्</strong> <strong>स्त्रियो</strong> <strong>अनु</strong> <strong>षिच्यते</strong>) it is nurtured in the women ( <strong>तद्</strong> <strong>वै</strong> <strong>पुत्रस्य</strong> <strong>वेदनं</strong>)it is a means to get a son,( <strong>तत्</strong> <strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अब्रवित्</strong> ) this is said by Prajapati .</p>
<p>Let us turn to the 3rd verse.</p>
<p>Ramgopal Vidyalankar &#8211;</p>
<p><strong>प्रजापतिरनुमतिः</strong> <strong>सिनीवाल्यचीक्लृपत्</strong><strong>  </strong><strong>स्त्रैषूमन्यत्र</strong> <strong>दधत्पुमांसमु</strong> <strong>दधदिह</strong><strong> [</strong><strong>अथर्ववेद</strong><strong> 6/11/3]</strong></p>
<p>“Prajapati, Anumati and Siniwali (Sanvatsar, Pournima and Amavasya) complete the foetus. The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere, the rules related to male are described here.”</p>
<p>Shri Damodar writes &#8211;</p>
<p>“(<strong>प्रजापतिः</strong> <strong>अनुमतिः</strong>) Father should be determined to get a son (<strong>सिनी</strong><strong>&#8211;</strong><strong>वाली</strong> <strong>अचीक्लृपत्</strong>) and the mother should be capable (of bearing a son) only if this happens (<strong>पुमांसं</strong> <strong>उ</strong> <strong>इह</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) a male foetus is formed (<strong>अन्यत्र</strong> <strong>स्त्रैषूयं</strong> <strong>दधत्</strong>) otherwise a female foetus is formed..”</p>
<p>Whatever has been said about this third verse of ‘Punsavan’ sukta of Atharvaved is quite clear except the second part which can have three meanings</p>
<p>The first and second are given these scholars</p>
<ol>
<li>The rules concerning the birth of female are mentioned elsewhere the rules related to men are described here.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation could have been accepted if the rules concerning the birth of females had been mentioned in the Vedas elsewhere but we have to say with great disappointment that perhaps this is not true. For this reason this interpretation is unacceptable. However, even with this interpretation the importance given to the birth of a son can be clearly seen.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Male foetus is formed (in the conditions mentioned above) otherwise a female foetus is formed.</li>
</ol>
<p>This interpretation given by Shri Damodar is accepted but the implications of such an interpretation are noteworthy. If this interpretation is true then definitely birth of a son would be wished for since ‘Punsavan’ is performed by everyone.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Third interpretation would be – Let girl/female foetus be placed in some other womb and male fetus be placed in this womb. Even this meaning exposes the underlying mentality which wishes for a male child and rejects a female child.</li>
</ol>
<p>So, these are the verses used to prevent a female child from taking birth and ensuring the birth a male child. It would not be wrong to call this the ancient and Vedic version of female foeticide. The Hindu scriptures enjoining ‘<strong>Punsavan</strong>’ fail to even mention the sanskar (sacrament) named “<strong>Straisuy</strong>”</p>
<p>As far as Vedas are concerned women are not allowed to give birth to a female child, there however, is the command to give birth to 10 sons. A verse from Rigveda reads</p>
<p><strong>इमां</strong> <strong>तवमिन्द्र</strong> <strong>मीढ्वः</strong> <strong>सुपुत्रां</strong> <strong>सुभगां</strong> <strong>कर्णु</strong> <strong>।</strong> <strong>दशास्यां</strong> <strong>पुत्राना</strong> <strong>धेहि</strong> <strong>पतिमेकादशं</strong> <strong>कर्धि</strong><strong> ||</strong> -ऋग्वेद 10/85/45</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand writes the meaning of this verse as follows</p>
<p>O majestic man capable of nurturing semen! Give a married woman or widow the best son and grant her good fortune. Produce 10 sons for a married woman and consider the 11th to be a woman.</p>
<p>This makes it clear that the birth of a girl is neither desired nor considered good since ancient times. However such verses can neither change the way sex is determined nor can they prevent the birth of a girl child. As such a girl once born has to be accepted. But nothing changes after this</p>
<p>In the ‘<strong>Harish-Narad dialogue</strong>’ in <em>Aitreya Brahman</em> which is an explanation of the Rigved, Narad says:</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>कृपणं</strong> <strong>ह</strong> <strong>दुहिता</strong></p>
<p>“Daughter leads to suffering and is a cause of misery”</p>
<p>While explaining this, scholar Sayancharya quotes an ancient verse</p>
<p><strong>संभवे</strong> <strong>स्वजनदुः</strong> <strong>खकारिका</strong> <strong>संप्रदानसमयेर्थदारिका</strong> <strong>योवनेपि</strong> <strong>बहुदोषकारिका</strong> <strong>दारिका</strong> <strong>ह्रदयदारिका</strong> <strong>पितुः</strong></p>
<p>“When a girl is born, she makes relatives unhappy; when she gets married she takes away wealth. She commits a lot of mistakes in her youth that is why it is said that she cleaves her father’s heart”</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya writes with respect to ‘daughter’ in his Nirukt</p>
<p>“Daughter is called Duhita because she is <em><u>Durhita</u></em> (one who does bad) and <em>Durehita</em> (it is better if she stays far away). She is <em>Dogdha</em> (one who sucks parent’s wealth)” – (Nirukt Adhayay 3, Khand 4)</p>
<p>In the next Adhyay of the same book, while explaining the word  ‘Kanya’ Acharya Yaska writes,</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>क्वेयं</strong> <strong>नेत्व्य</strong></p>
<p>(Nirukt Adhyay 4 Khand 15)</p>
<p>“Kanya is so called because as soon as she takes birth parents start worrying about her marriage”</p>
<p>These examples show the negative view associated with the birth of girl in Hindu culture and Hindu religious scriptures. It is this mentality which is criticized in the Qur’an in the following words &#8211;</p>
<p>And when one of them is informed of [the birth of] a female, his face becomes dark, and he suppresses grief. He hides himself from the people because of the ill of which he has been informed. Should he keep it in humiliation or bury it in the ground? Unquestionably, evil is what they decide. (Qur’an 16/58-59)</p>
<p>Allah, the Exalted puts an end to the discrimination between a boy and a girl in the Qur’an</p>
<p>To Allah belongs the dominion of the heavens and the earth; He creates what he wills. He gives to whom He wills female [children], and He gives to whom He wills males. (Qur’an 42/49)</p>
<p>A point worth noting is that in this verse daughters are mentioned before sons. Commenting on this verse Sayyidina Wathilah ibn Aska said, fortunate is the woman who has a daughter as her first child.</p>
<p>Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) said,</p>
<p>If anyone has a female child, and does not bury her alive, or slight her, or prefer his sons to her, Allah will bring him into Paradise. [Narrated by Abdullah ibn Abbas; Abu Dawud, Kitaab al-Adab, Hadith 5127)</p>
<p>To conclude, I would like to say that to put an end to the evil practice of female foeticide and the negative view associated with a girl child, the mentality operating behind these needs to be destroyed. How do we do that? Well,</p>
<p><strong>किं</strong> <strong>ग्राहृयमग्राहृयमिति</strong> <strong>कवयो</strong> <strong>नात्र</strong> <strong>मोहिताः</strong><strong>, </strong><strong>अज्ञस्तु</strong> <strong>मूढ़मतित्वात्सतृणमभ्यवहारी</strong> <strong>।।</strong></p>
<p>Deciding between the acceptable and unacceptable is not difficult. A wise person embraces the acceptable and rejects the unacceptable but a foolish person due to his foolishness believes a cow and donkey to be the same.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/female-foeticide-the-bitter-truth/" data-wpel-link="internal">Female Foeticide- The Bitter Truth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Caste and Racial Discrimination</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/caste-and-racial-discrimination/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 09:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caste System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambedkar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahmin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low caste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sudra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[untouchables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/caste-and-racial-discrimination/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad A study of various religions of the world makes it clear that only the Hindu religion sanctions the worst form of discrimination based on one&#8217;s birth. May be some followers of other religions also practice some sort of caste discrimination. However, their religious texts do not approve of the caste discrimination. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/caste-and-racial-discrimination/" data-wpel-link="internal">Caste and Racial Discrimination</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="color: #56595e;">Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p id="MycBZsh"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="206" height="285" class="size-full wp-image-7660  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/img_5f257a0344907.png" alt="" />A study of various religions of the world makes it clear that only the Hindu religion sanctions the worst form of discrimination based on one&#8217;s birth. May be some followers of other religions also practice some sort of caste discrimination. However, their religious texts do not approve of the caste discrimination. This is not the case with Hinduism though. Hindus derive the caste system directly from their scriptures and their scriptures sanction Caste discrimination.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">The Hindu religion, from the very beginning, has sowed division between one human and the other.  Let us take a look at the sanction provided to this discriminatory institution in the Hindu scriptures and also, simultaneously respond to modern Hindu polemics which try to deny Caste System in Hindu Scriptures.</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">Following is a list of verbatim quotations from Hindu scriptures, which speak of and approve the caste system:</p>
<p><span id="more-821"></span></p>
<ol style="color: #56595e;">
<li><strong>बराह्मणो.अस्य मुखमासीद बाहू राजन्यः कर्तः |<br />
ऊरूतदस्य यद वैश्यः पद्भ्यां शूद्रो अजायत || </strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;The <em style="color: #999999;">Brahmana </em>was his [God&#8217;s] mouth, of both his arms was the <em style="color: #999999;">Rājanya </em>made. His thighs became the <em style="color: #999999;">Vaishya</em>, from his feet the <em style="color: #999999;">Shudra </em>was produced.&#8221; </span> [Purusha Sukta; Rigveda 10/90/12 and Yajurveda 31/11 and Atharvaveda 19/6/6]</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;For Brahman (Priesthood) he binds a Brahmana to the stake; for Kshatriya (Royalty) a Râjanya; for rearing cattle a Vaishya; for Penance a Shudra;&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 30/5]</li>
<li><strong>नृत्ताय सूतं </strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;For Dance, God creates a <em style="color: #999999;">Soot</em>.&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 30/6] A &#8216;Soot&#8217; is the son of a Kshatriya and a Brahmin woman who generally does the business of dancing. Here caste and profession is determined by birth. Refer to Manu Smriti 10/11.</li>
<li><strong>गीताय शैलूषं</strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;For song, God creates a bard.&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 30/6]</li>
<li><strong>तपसे कौलालं </strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;For penance, God creates a potter&#8217;s son.&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 30/7]</li>
<li><strong>वैशन्ताभ्यो वैन्दं </strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;For maintaining small tanks, God creates the son of a <em style="color: #999999;">Nishada</em>.&#8221; </span>[Yajurveda 30/16] A &#8216;Nishada&#8217; is the son of a Brahmin man and a Shudra woman. Refer to Manu Smriti Chapter 10, verse 8.</li>
<li><strong>ये गर्भा अवपद्यन्ते जगद् यच्चपलुप्यते |<br />
वीरा ये तृह्यन्ते मिथो ब्रह्मजाया हिनस्ति तान् ||<br />
</strong><span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Whatever infants die, untimely born, </span><span style="color: #ff0000;">Whatever </span><span style="color: #ff0000;">herds of cattle waste away, </span><span style="color: #ff0000;">Whatever </span><span style="color: #ff0000;">heroes strike each other dead, the Brāhmin&#8217;s wife destroys them.&#8221;</span> [Atharvaveda 5/17/7]</li>
<li><strong>उत यत् पतयो दश स्त्रियाः पूर्वे अब्राह्मणाः <strong>|</strong><br />
ब्रह्मा चेद्धस्तमग्रहीत् स एव पतिरेकधा <strong>||<br />
</strong>ब्राह्मण एव पतिर्न राजन्यो न वैश्यः <strong>|</strong></strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Even if ten former husbands—none a Brāhmin—had espoused a dame, And then a Brāhmin took her hand, he is her husband, only he<span style="font-weight: bold;">, </span>not Vaisya, not Rājanya, no, the Brāhmin is indeed her lord:<span style="font-weight: bold;">&#8220;</span><strong> </strong></span>[Atharvaveda 5/17/8-9]</li>
<li><strong>शूद्रार्यावसृज्येताम</strong><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Shudra and Arya were created.&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 14/30]  Here Shudras and Aryas are clearly differentiated. Thus only Brahmins, Kshatriyas and Vaishyas are considered Arya (translated as &#8216;Noble&#8217; by Arya Samaj). Therefore, Shudras are &#8216;Anaryas&#8217;.</li>
<li><strong>आर्य ईश्वर्पुत्रः<br />
</strong>&#8216;<span style="color: #ff0000;">Arya&#8217; means &#8216;Son of God&#8217;</span>, according to Nirukt 6/26<strong>. </strong>Combining points 9 and 10, Shudras and other low castes are not sons of God or the beloved of God.</li>
<li> So, what should be the behaviour of Aryans towards the non-Aryans? Various mantras of the Vedas make it clear that Aryans have the God-given right to oppress the non-Aryans, take their wealth and if they resist, kill them.</li>
<li>In Vedic times, there lived an untouchable people in a village named <strong>Kikat</strong>, in todays Bihar. The used to rear cattle. Obviously to the Aryans this was a crime. So they invoked their warrior god Indra to wage war against them and loot their cows.<span style="color: #000000;"><strong>किं ते कर्ण्वन्ति कीकटेषु गावो नाशिरं दुह्रे न तपन्तिघर्मम |<br />
आ नो भर परमगन्दस्य वेदो नैचाशाखं मघवन्रन्धया नः ||</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;O Indra, what do the cows make for you among the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Kikatas</strong></span>? They neither yield milk for your offerings, nor do they warm the vessel of libation. Bring to us these cows, bring to us also the wealth of Pramagand (their King). O Brave one, grant us the possessions of the people of low status.&#8221; [Rigveda 3:53:14]</span><br />
On the basis of this clear pronouncement, non-Aryans and untouchables have no right to keep cows. Aryans, whenever they wish can kill them and appropriate their possessions. Hindu culture thus becomes the culture of the progress, civilization and welfare of the Aryan people alone. The pathetic plight of the untouchables of India was due to instructions like these given by Hindu scriptures.</li>
<li>These non-Aryans have been described at several places in the Vedas as <strong>अन्यव्रतम </strong>(followers of another religion),<strong>अमानुषम </strong>(not human), <strong>अयज्वानम </strong>(not performing Yajna) [Rigveda 8/70/11]</li>
<li><strong>इन्द्रः समत्सु यजमानमार्यं परावद विश्वेषु शतमूतिराजिषु सवर्मीळ्हेष्वाजिषु | मनवे शासदव्रतान तवचं कर्ष्णामरन्धयत | </strong><br />
Indra is said to help the Aryan worshippers in battles and punishes the neglector of religious rites, who are said to be having &#8216;black skin&#8217; (<strong>तवचं कर्ष्णाम</strong>). [Rigveda 1/130/8]</li>
<li>The maidens of the &#8216;dark race&#8217; are the free sexual dishes of Aryans. Nirukt 12/13 mentions that &#8216;<strong>Raamaa</strong>&#8216;, the lovely maidens belonging to the dark race are only for enjoyment and not for any sacred purpose.</li>
<li>Shudras have no right to read the Vedas according to Hindu scriptures. However, in recent times some modern Hindus who felt ashamed to carry the burden of this clear discrimination and suppression, tried to reinterpret Hindus texts in such a way which allowed Shudras to also read the Vedas. Some Hindu polemicists, present mantra 2 of Yajurveda chapter 26 as proof that all Brahmins, Kshatriyas, Vaishas, Shudras, the kinsfolk allowed to study the Vedas. The Arya samaj translation of Swami Dayanand more or less goes like this,<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;I do hereby address this salutary speech for the benefit of humanity, for Brahmins, the Kshatriyas, the Shudras, the Vaishas, my women and servants, and the men of lowest position in society. Dear may I be to the learned and the guerdon-giver in this world. Fulfilled be this desire of mine. May I achieve my aim.&#8221;</span> [Yajurveda 26/2]
This new, unique, twisted translation of Swami ji is opposed to common sense. If these are the words of God, according to the Swami, who are the women of God? and who are His servants? When did God get married to have kinsfolk? When God has already named Brahmins, Kshatriyas, Vaishas and Shudras, for what purpose are women and servants  listed separately? Are women and servants outside the castes mentioned? Besides this, the desperation of God that he may be dear to all and his DESIRE be fulfilled , shows him as one craving for fame. This does not behoove God at all.<br />
All these questions are solved if we take these as not being the words of God. The words are in reality spoken by a Yajmaan (one who is performing the Yajna) asking for his desires to be fulfilled and the food presented in the Yajna be partaken by all. This mantra cannot be used to allow Shudras to read the Vedas.</li>
<li>On the other hand the Hindu scriptures clearly prohibit a Shudra from studying the Vedas. Let us see the commentary on Brahmasutra 1/3/38<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/b-skr_136.gif" alt="" width="320" height="32" /><br />
And on account of the prohibition, in Smriti, of (the Sûdras&#8217;) hearing and studying (the Veda) and (knowing and performing) (Vedic) matters.<br />
Adi, Shankaracharya commenting on it writes,<br />
<strong>&#8220;The Sûdras are not qualified for that reason also that Smriti prohibits their hearing the Veda, their studying the Veda, and their understanding and performing Vedic matters.</strong> The prohibition of hearing the Veda is conveyed by the following passages: <span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#8216;The ears of him who hears the Veda are to be filled with (molten) lead and lac,&#8217; and &#8216;For a Sûdra is (like) a cemetery, therefore (the Veda) is not to be read in the vicinity of a Sûdra.&#8217;</span> From this latter passage the prohibition of studying the Veda results at once; for how should he study Scripture in whose vicinity it is not even to be read? There is, moreover, an express prohibition (of the Sûdras studying the Veda). <span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#8216;His tongue is to be slit if he pronounces it; his body is to be cut through if he preserves it.&#8217;</span> The prohibitions of hearing and studying the Veda already imply the prohibition of the knowledge and performance of Vedic matters; there are, however, express prohibitions also, such as<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> &#8216;he is not to impart knowledge to the Sûdra,&#8217;</span> and &#8216;to the twice-born belong study, sacrifice, and the bestowal of gifts.&#8217;&#8211;From those Sûdras, however, who, like Vidura and &#8216;the religious hunter,&#8217; acquire knowledge in consequence of the after effects of former deeds, the fruit of their knowledge cannot be withheld, since knowledge in all cases brings about its fruit. Smriti, moreover, declares that all the four castes are qualified for acquiring the knowledge of the itihâsas and purânas; compare the passage, &#8216;He is to teach the four castes&#8217; (Mahâbh.).&#8211;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>It remains, however, a settled point that they do not possess any such qualification with regard to the Veda.&#8221;</strong></span><br />
Acharya Ramanuja commenting on the same Brahmasutra writes,<br />
&#8220;The Sûdra is specially forbidden to hear and study the Veda and to perform the things enjoined in it. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#8216;For a Sûdra is like a cemetery, therefore the Veda must not be read in the vicinity of a Sûdra;&#8217;</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#8216;Therefore the Sûdra is like a beast, unfit for sacrifices.&#8217;</span> And he who does not hear the Veda recited cannot learn it so as to understand and perform what the Veda enjoins. The prohibition of hearing thus implies the prohibition of understanding and whatever depends on it.&#8221;<br />
So, here we have two of the most influential Hindu schholars and intellectual giants totally prohibiting the Shudras from studying the Vedas.</li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>स्तुता मया कीर्ति वेदमात प्र चोदयन्तां पावमानी द्विजानाम् </strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Let my libations, giving boons, adoring, further the Twice-born&#8217;s (Brahmins, Kshatriyas and Vaishas) song that honours Soma.&#8221;</span> [Atharvaveda 19/71/1]</li>
<li>Shatapath Brahman 2/1/4/12 says,<br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;With &#8216;bhû<i>h</i>!&#8217; Pra<span style="font-style: italic;">j</span>âpati generated the Brahmin; with &#8216;bhuva<i>h</i>!&#8217; the Kshatriya; with &#8216;<i>s</i>va<i>h</i>!&#8217; the V<span style="font-style: italic;">aisya</span>. As much as are the Brahmin, the Kshatriya, and the Vaisya, so much is this universe: with the universe it (the fire) is accordingly established.&#8221;</span></li>
<li>The Upanishads are also supportive of the evil caste system.<br />
Upanishads clearly spell out that caste is based on birth due to the deeds of previous lives. This is the reason for this idea taking such root in the Hindu society that it continues to divide Indian society even today.</li>
</ol>
<p>Chandogya Upanishad 5/10/7 says,</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Those whose conduct here on earth has been good will quickly attain some good birth—<strong>birth as a brahmin, birth as a kshatriya, or birth as a vaisya</strong>. But those whose conduct here has been evil will quickly attain some evil birth—<strong>birth as a dog, birth as a pig, or birth as a chandala</strong>.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>On one hand Upanishads talk of one Soul permeating all; only Brahma being real and the world being an illusion, while on the other hand they sanction this cruel birth based caste system.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some Hindus give the example of Satyakaam Jabali, who was the son of a prostitute and became a Brahmin. This is an outright lie. If we read carefully the interview of Satyakaam by his would be Guru, Gautama Haridrumata, we find that birth based caste system is again affirmed. When the Guru asked Satyakaam of what family he was, he replied he did not know except what his mother told him. Hearing this straightforward answer, the Guru declared that he was a Brahmin, because NO ONE BUT A BRAHMIN SPEAKS IN SUCH A LANGUAGE. [Chandogya Upanishad 4/4/4-5] Note that the boy had not yet acquired knowledge and thus could not be a Brahmin. The Guru just by listening to his words decalred that he was from a Brahmin FAMILY. This proves that the caste was determined by birth. So this example of the modern Hindu revisionist backfires.</li>
<li>Even the ancient books on Sanskrit grammar are not free from the caste mindset. Panini states in his book <em style="color: #999999;">Ashtadhyaayi</em>Book 8, Chapter 2, Sootra 83 that <span style="color: #ff0000;">in response to the salution of greeting of a Shudra, one should reply to the salutation without any cheerfulness or being too friendly.</span> However, in the case of the Dwijas/Twice borns, greeting must be returned with a better greeting.</li>
<li>Further, the same Panini writes in <em style="color: #999999;">Ashtadhyaayi </em>2/4/10 <strong>शूद्राणां निरवसितानाम</strong> and <strong>शूद्राणां अनिरवसितानाम </strong><span style="color: #ff0000;">The latter means a Shudra who can take food from the dish of a higher class without permanently defiling the vessel. The former is that Shudra whose touch permanently defiles the vessel in which he takes food.</span></li>
<li>Manu Smriti is the clearest Hindu document which spells out that Shudras are just filthy and have to be enslaved. Many Hindus want to just do away with Manu Smriti but the excerciseis futile. Manu Smriti is authenticated by the Vedas and also the Upanishads.</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">But for the sake of the prosperity of the worlds he caused the Brahmana, the Kshatriya, the Vaisya, and the Sudra to proceed from his mouth, his arms, his thighs, and his feet.</span> [Manu Smriti 1/31]</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">A low-caste man who tries to place himself on the same seat with a man of a high caste, shall be branded on his hip and be banished, or (the king) shall cause his buttock to be gashed.</span> [Manu 8/281] Caste is by birth.</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">A Brahmana may confidently seize the goods of (his) Sudra (slave); for, as that (slave) can have no property, his master may take his possessions</span>. [Manu 8/417]</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">But a Sudra, whether bought or unbought, he may compel to do servile work; for he was created by the Self-existent (Svayambhu) to be the slave of a Brahmin</span>. [Manu 8/413]</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">A Sudra, though emancipated by his master, is not released from servitude; since that is innate in him, who can set him free from it?</span> [Manu 8/414]</li>
<li><span class="st"><span class="st">Dr. <em style="color: #999999;">Surendra Kumar</em> has written a detailed translation of <em style="color: #999999;">Manu Smriti</em> in Hindi that analyzes each shloka on various parameters and weeds out the verses which he assumed to have been interpolated. He concluded that a certain verse of Manu Smriti was interpolated if it contradicted with the Vedas. Now let us see the how these modern Hindus cremated their own ideology by this misadventure. Manu Smriti 1/96-97 says,</span></span><span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Of created beings the most excellent are said to be those which are animated; of the animated, those which subsist by intelligence; of the intelligent, mankind; and <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">of men, the Brahmins; Of Brahmins, those learned (in the Veda)</span></strong>; of the learned, those who recognise (the necessity and the manner of performing the prescribed duties); of those who possess this knowledge, those who perform them; of the performers, those who know the Brahman.&#8221;</span><br />
Note the bold and underlined text. It clearly implies that a Brahmin is one by birth. That is why is uses the words <strong>&#8216;of Brahmins, the most excellent are those learned (in the Veda)&#8217;</strong>. For the modern Hindus who assume that caste ACCORDING TO THE VEDAS is not by birth but by qualities, this text of Manu Smriti was an interpolation. Thus they removed it from the Revised Manu Smriti.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, in their ignorance of the Vedas, they did a blunder. The same text is present in Atharvaveda 12/4/22 which says,<br />
<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;If hundred other Brāhmins beg the Cow of him who owns her, The Gods have said, She, verily, belongs to him who is learned.&#8221;</span><br />
This mantra also implies that Brahmins are Brahmins by birth and there may be more learned people among them. Now, if the text of Manu Smriti was ousted as an interpolation then by the same standard this mantra of Atharvaveda also is an interpolation.</p>
<ul>
<li>Manusmriti declares that a Shudra cannot marry a girl from outside his caste. But a Brahmin can marry in the other three castes also in addition to his own. Similarly Kshatriyas and Vaishyas are allowed to marry girls from castes lower than their own besides from their own castes. [Manusmriti 3/13]</li>
<li><span style="color: #ff0000;">Know that a Brahmana of ten years and Kshatriya of a hundred years stand to each other in the relation of father and son; but between those two the Brahmana is the father.</span>  [Manusmriti 2/135]</li>
<li>Manusmriti forbids a Shudra from giving evidence in a law-suit involving Brahmins. Similarly, a Brahmin cannot give evidence in a Shudra&#8217;s case. Shudras alone can appear as witnesses in a case involving Shudras and the same rule applies to scavangers also. [Manusmriti 8/ 68]</li>
<li>In short, the scriptures provide maximum punishment for Shudras, while the other castes get lesser punishment for the same kind of offence. The tongue of a Shudra who utters harsh words against the twice-born must be cut, says the &#8216;Manusmriti.&#8217; If a Shudra pronounces the name and surname of a twice-born or utters impertinent words like &#8220;Hey Yagnadatt, you are a low Brahmin&#8221;, etc., a ten-inch-long, red-hot iron nail is to be thrust into his mouth.<br />
[Manusmriti 8 / 267 &#8211; 268]</li>
<li>Ironically, a Shudra is punished even for doing good deeds. Religious preaching was considered to be righteous act. But &#8216;Manusmriti&#8217; says that hot oil must be poured into the mouth and ear of a Shudra who dares to preach to a Brahmin [Manusmriti 8 / 270 &#8211; 271]</li>
<li>A Shudra is not to be given good advice. Manu Smriti 4/80 says,<span style="color: #ff0000;">&#8220;Let him not give to a Sudra advice, nor the remnants (of his meal), nor food offered to the gods; nor let him explain the sacred law (to such a man), nor impose (upon him) a penance.&#8221;</span></li>
<li>Let him not allow a dead Brahmin to be carried out by a Sudra, while men of the same caste are at hand; for that burnt-offering which is <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">defiled by a Sudra&#8217;s touch</span> is detrimental to (the deceased&#8217;s passage to) heaven.</strong> [Manusmriti 5/104]</li>
<li>Even social reformers like Swami Dayanand could not escape the strong influence of the Shastric injunctions. He too gives some do&#8217;s and don&#8217;ts in dealing with Shudras. Some of them are as follows:<br />
1. Eat food offered by Brahmins but don&#8217;t eat food offered by the Shudras like Chandals, scavengers, cobblers etc.<br />
2. Only on the occasion of grave emergency is one allowed to take food cooked in a Shudra&#8217;s house.<br />
3. A shudra who fulfils the conditions needed to pursue the studies of scriptures can be taught all the Shastras except the Vedas. Many religious teachers agree to the fact that a Shudra can pursue studies of scriptures but there can be no sacred thread ceremony for him. Since Swami Dayanand does not refute this attitude of the teachers, it can be inferred that he also subscribes to their views.<br />
4. The tag &#8216;Das‘ must be attached to the name of a Shudra (Sanskaar Vidhi  Pg 66)</li>
<li>Death is the reward for a Shudra who performs religious rites. An episode in the &#8216;Valmiki Ramayan&#8217; says that a Brahmin put the blame for the death of his young son on Lord Ram. Then Narad came and explained to Ram that the death was owing to the illegitimate asceticism of a Shudra named Shambhuka.<br />
In another context, it is said that Ram saw a boy in the direction of South doing penance. When Ram asked the boy the reason for his penance, he replied that he wanted to conquer the &#8216;Devalok&#8217; and then attain Godhood. He introduced himself as a Shudra named Shambhuka. When Ram came to know the Shudra identity of Shambhuka, he immediately killed him with his sword. And the Gods expressed their gratitude by showering praises on Ram.</li>
<li><strong>Did Ram eat the fruit tasted by Shabri ?</strong><br />
One is prompted to ask the question why Shudras are treated with contempt if, as claimed earlier, Ram ate the fruit offered by Shabri (a Shudra woman)?<br />
We want to know in which of the &#8216;Ramayans&#8217; the above episode occurs? Surely, there is no mention about Ram&#8217;s eating the defiled fruit in &#8216;Anand Ramayan&#8217;, &#8216;Manjul Ramayan&#8217; or &#8216;Tulsi Ramayan&#8217;. The mention of Shabri&#8217;s low origin does occur in &#8216;Adhyatm Ramayan&#8217;. But it does not say anything about Ram&#8217;s eating the plum she offered, after tasting it herself first.<br />
In &#8216;Ramacharit Manas,&#8217; the following reference to Shabri occurs in &#8216;Aranya Kand&#8217;. When Ram steps into Shabri&#8217;s hut, she is reminded of Sage Matanga&#8217;s prediction that Ram would one day visit her hut. Seeing the two brothers (one is dark and the other is fair) with lotus-like eyes, long arms, matted hair and adorned with garlands, Shabri fell at their feet Overwhelmed with love and devotion, she could not utter a word. Instead she prostrated at their feet again and again. Then after washing their feet and offering them honourable seats, she brought lot of fruits and roots for the distinguished guests.<br />
It becomes clear from this that the question of Ram&#8217;s taking fruit tasted by a Shudra woman does not arise. Moreover, the Shastras do not put any restrictions on accepting fruits and roots etc. from low caste people. Therefore, by accepting the fruit offered by Shabri, Ram neither antagonised the Shastras nor did he do anything radical.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #56595e;">This being the fact, there are people who claim that in Hindu scriptures, Shudras are treated with equality and love. But apparently those who claim thus have either not read the scriptures properly, or want to keep the Shudras in eternal subjugation, or dare not raise a voice against the inhuman attitude of the Shastras, or want to interpret this discriminating attitude as friendly.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/caste-and-racial-discrimination/" data-wpel-link="internal">Caste and Racial Discrimination</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
