<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>adultery &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/adultery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:29:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Polygamy in Hindu Dharma</title>
		<link>/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[16800]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apsara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four wives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monogomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiple wives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paradise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyandry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polygamy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polygyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swarga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wives]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2016/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Having more than one spouse (especially wife) is known as Polygamy. The Hindu Marriage Act 1955 prohibits Polygamy for Hindus but Hindu scriptures allows polygamy and it’s still in practice among some Hindus. Not a single verse of any Hindu text says that ‘You should marry only one’ and yet Hindus &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hindu Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="476" height="317" class="wp-image-7069" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-poly.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/polygamy.jpg?w=476&amp;h=317" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-poly.jpeg 476w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-poly-300x200.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 476px) 100vw, 476px" /></h1>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Having more than one spouse (especially wife) is known as Polygamy. The Hindu Marriage Act 1955 prohibits Polygamy for Hindus but Hindu scriptures allows polygamy and it’s still in practice among some Hindus. Not a single verse of any Hindu text says that ‘You should marry only one’ and yet Hindus claim that Hinduism permits only monogamy. Many Hindus think that Polygamy is prohibited in Hinduism, Hence Hindus are not allowed to have more than one wife. This is not true. Hinduism permits a man to have more than one wife at a time. When you tell a Hindu that Hinduism permits polygamy he won’t talk about scriptures rather he will tell you that Indian law prohibits polygamy for Hindus and Hindus have accepted the law unlike Muslims. They claim that Hindus are very adaptive. Hindus didn’t stop practices like Sati, Polygamy etc., but it was enforced by the Indian court. Recently some women and children were beaten up for entering a temple and the court had to intervene and it allowed entrance of women into some temples. So Hindus had to adapt because they had no choice but to accept court’s decisions. As far as my knowledge on polygamy is concerned I haven’t read a single verse from any Hindu scripture prohibiting polygamy.</p>
<p><span id="more-2522"></span></p>
<p>This article deals with the following subjects</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a id="post-7068-practice"></a>Practice of Polygamy in modern India</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" width="453" height="336" class="wp-image-7070" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-prac.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/practise-of-polygamy.jpg?w=453&amp;h=337" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-prac.jpeg 453w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-prac-300x223.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /></p>
<p>While Hindus makes mockery of Muslims for having four wives each (which isn’t true) they are unaware of the fact that Hindu men are more polygamous than Muslims in India. Let’s have a look at the survey,<br />
<img decoding="async" width="477" height="366" class="wp-image-7071" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-wome.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/women-polygamy-010517_0630_conditionof2.png?w=481&amp;h=368" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-wome.png 477w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-wome-300x230.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 477px) 100vw, 477px" /></p>
<p>As per Government’s 1961 census, 5.8% of Hindus were polygamous compared to Muslim’s 5.7%. Polygamy among Buddhist men was 7.9%, Jains 6.7% and incidence of polygamy was highest among Adivasis with 15.25% of Adivasi practicing polygamy.</p>
<p>It is illegal for non-Muslims in India to have more than one wife. In spite of this, many Hindus have multiple wives. Official reports brought out in 1974, almost two decades after the prohibition of Hindu bigamy, highlighted the shocking fact that polygamy among Hindus was higher than among Muslims (Adivasis: 15 per cent, Hindus: 5.8 per cent, Jains: 6.7 per cent, Buddhists: 7.9 per cent, Muslims: 5.6 per cent). Figures for subsequent decades are not available. The difference may appear insignificant but in real terms, it is huge — as many as one crore Hindu men had more than one wife, as opposed to just 12 lakh Muslims. In fact, according to the 2011 Census, 66 lakh women are still in bigamous marriages.</p>
<p>The National Family Health Survey carried out in 2006 showed that 2.5% of Muslim men were polygamous compared to 1.7% of Hindu men and 2.1% of Christian men. The number of polygamous marriages has dropped significantly in both Hindus and Muslims. But this time the percentage of polygamy is higher among Muslims with a 0.8% gap between Hindus and Muslims. But this 0.8% gap is not a huge number. There is something worth noticing that Indian law permits Polygamy for Muslims while Hindu Marriage Act 1955 prohibits Hindu men to have more than one wife at a time, despite this prohibition 1.7% Hindus still practices polygamy. Imagine the rate of polygamy in Hindus if Indian law permits them to have more than one wife. Indian law permits polygamy for Muslims based on Sharia law and yet only 2.5% of men practices polygamy. 1961 and 1974 census are more important because they are the only two official census to look marriages on religious lines. Apart from this, in Goa a Hindu man can practice polygamy if his wife did not bore him a child.</p>
<p>Sources:-</p>
<p><a href="http://scroll.in/article/669083/muslim-women-and-the-surprising-facts-about-polygamy-in-india" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://scroll.in/article/669083/muslim-women-and-the-surprising-facts-about-polygamy-in-india<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/articleshow/5004493.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/articleshow/5004493.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.cpsindia.org/index.php/pub/87-religious-demography-of-india/reviews/84-indian-currents-lies-half-truths-and-statistics-by-john-dayal" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.cpsindia.org/index.php/pub/87-religious-demography-of-india/reviews/84-indian-currents-lies-half-truths-and-statistics-by-john-dayal<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/opinion/columns/three-is-a-crowd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/opinion/columns/three-is-a-crowd/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="431" height="323" class="wp-image-7072" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-6399.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/63998019-319b-4521-8ad8-ec715a2769e8-1.jpg?w=431&amp;h=323" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-6399.jpeg 431w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-6399-300x225.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px" /></p>
<p>There are some tactics used by Hindus to practice polygamy in India as Hindu Marriage Act prohibits them to have more than one wife at a time. Some converts to Islam to have more than one wife but at the same time practices polygamy, some Hindus after marrying the second says that their first marriage was not solemnized as some ceremonies pertaining to Hindu law were not duly performed.</p>
<p>When a Hindu marries a second wife, the first wife lodges a criminal case against her husband pointing out his polygamy. In many cases the court rejects the case based on meager legal points and eludes the culprit out of punishment.</p>
<p>In Maharastra Mr. Balrao Sankar Lokande married a second wife. His first wife lodged a criminal case against him. Session court and High court convicted him. Mr. Balrao appealed to the Supreme court, the Supreme court released him. As he left some ceremonies pertaining to the Laws of Hindus Marriage, it can’t be considered as marriage. Since it is not a marriage, he did not commit any mistake to punish is the judgment.<br />
<a href="https://indiankanoon.org/doc/80924/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">https://indiankanoon.org/doc/80924/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><br />
Mr. Balrao Sankar Lokande against Government of Maharastra AIR 1965 SC 1566)</p>
<p>Mr. Suresh Chandra Gosh married a second wife. His first wife Priya Bala Gosh lodged a criminal case against him. High court refused to convict him on legal ground. Since he left some ceremonies pertaining to the Laws of Hindus Marriage, it can’t be considered as marriage.<br />
Mrs. Priya Bala Gosh against Mr. Suresh Chandra Gosh AIR 1971 SC 1153)</p>
<p>In Andra Mr.L.Venkata Reddy married a second wife. His first wife Mrs.Lingari Oppallamma lodged a criminal case against him. In this case also High court did not convict him. As he left some ceremonies pertaining to the Laws of Hindus Marriage, it can’t be considered as marriage.</p>
<p>Mrs.Lingari Oppallamma against Mr.L.Venkata Reddy and others AIR 1979 SC 848)<br />
<a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Findiankanoon.org%2Fdoc%2F766841%2F&amp;h=ATPhVpvkmb-w7e5CcQ-KLzCaIR3xmp4ha2UQ8brbtfRFMW2nswia3IwSkBedv5aPdcyMRabtD48hYYfqSGo_f9YLPlxrZAfDf99IeNBZCQMLHSKd87WBY25geXDNlmCbiPBmuR2WiSWNSe4qbw2MxWrHE9jJVpsiqyKkBr1MSsOaj3ykHI7uNrStbp3DyfdEXhFVXOZraS91_FPYEJR3nJm-jgZCQsJX5fTBY8fOYhM8ItAlYHdiNqj7Q9pK2a9W2Dutm2nWC0FZk8ykSUihMSkEZxfhGgFPDUXtRKVDIpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://indiankanoon.org/doc/766841/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>In Kashmir Mr. Bangari married a second wife. His first wife lodged a criminal case against him. The court released him. As he left some ceremonies pertaining to the Laws of Hindus Marriage, it can’t be considered as marriage. His second wife is a concubine only. Since There is no law to punish for keeping a concubine.</p>
<p>Mr. Banari against the State Government of Jammu &amp; Kashmir AIR 1965 SC 105)</p>
<p>Thus our High Courts and Supreme Court passed judgments in many cases.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Another tactic</strong> used by Hindus is the practice of Live-in relationship. A married man can have another partner through live-in relationship. And this practice has got legal backing in Gujarat where it is known as Maitri Karar. Though both men and women can practice Maitri Karar but its mostly upper caste rich Hindu men who are opting for Maitri Karar. In this practice they can have a wife and a live in partner at a time. In Madhya Pradesh too such case was reported where court ordered a man to spend equal time with wife and live-in partner. Here are the links,<br />
<a href="http://archive.indianexpress.com/news/college-girl-gets-court-nod-for--livein--with-married-man/967694/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">http://archive.indianexpress.com/news/college-girl-gets-court-nod-for–livein–with-married-man/967694/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/lok-adalat-orders-man-to-spend-equal-time-with-wife-and-livein-partner/article5411359.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/lok-adalat-orders-man-to-spend-equal-time-with-wife-and-livein-partner/article5411359.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>According to Navbharat Times the man’s name is Basant Mahulal<br />
<a href="https://navbharattimes.indiatimes.com/state/madhya-pradesh/other-cities/lok-adalat-tells-man-to-spend-equal-time-with-wife-and-live-in-partner/articleshow/26701964.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://navbharattimes.indiatimes.com/state/madhya-pradesh/other-cities/lok-adalat-tells-man-to-spend-equal-time-with-wife-and-live-in-partner/articleshow/26701964.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>For more information on this, you can read my article Condition of <a href="/index.php/2012/01/05/condition-of-hindu-women-in-india/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hindu Women in India</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a id="post-7068-examples"></a>Examples of Polygamy in Hindu scriptures</h2>
<p><strong>Ram’s father Dasharath had three wives</strong></p>
<p>As per Padma Purana V.57.27-40 and Tulsi Ramayana Chaupai 194, Doha 186 King Dasharath the father of Ram had three wives. Other texts names them as Kaushalya, Sumitra and Kaikeyi</p>
<p>But as per Padma Purana V.116.42-45a King Dasharat had four wives, Rama was born from Kausalya, Laksmana from Sumitra, Bharata from Surupa and Satrughna from Suvesa</p>
<p><strong>Krishna had 16,100 junior wives along with 8 major wives</strong></p>
<p>Vishnu Purana book 5.28.1-5 “RUKMINÍ bare to Krishńa these other sons, Chárudeshńa, Sudeshńa, Chárudeha, Sushena, Chárugupta, Bhadracháru, Cháruvinda, Sucháru, and the very mighty Cháru; also one daughter, Chárumatí. Krishńa had seven other beautiful wives, Kálindí, Mitravrindá, the virtuous Nágnajití, the queen Jámbavatí; Rohińí, of beautiful form; the amiable and excellent daughter of the king of Madra, Mádrí; Satyabhámá, the daughter of Śatrujit; and Lakshmańá, of lovely smiles 1. Besides these, he had sixteen thousand other wives.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Brahma Purana 95.12-18 &#8220;&#8230;Krsna took possession of elephants, horses, and other wealth brought by the servants from the collection of Naraka. Krsna, on an auspicious day married damsels brought from Naraka&#8217;s residence. O excellent brahmins, with a separate body for each of these, Krsna married them in accordance with piety. There were sixteen thousand and one hundred women or even more. Lord Krsna took up as many forms. But those virgins considered him as their sole lord individually, thinking, &#8216;Krsna married me alone.&#8217; During the nights, O brahmins, Krsna the creator of the universe, Krsna of universal forms, stayed in the abodes of all of them.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><strong>Vasudeva the father of Krishna had 14 wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Purana 112.35 “Vasudeva had fourteen excellent women as his wives. The first five were: a descendant of Puri named Rohini, Madira, Vaisakhi, Bhadra and Sunamni. The second set of seven ladies comprised Sahadeva, Santideva, Sridevi, Devaraksita, Vrkadevi, Upadevi, and Devaki. The thirteenth and the fourteenth were Sutanu and Yadavi. These two had at first been maid servants. [42] The renowned Sauri (Krsna) was born of Devaki and Vasudeva…” Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Vasudeva having 14 wives is also mentioned in Harivamsa Purana 1.35.3</p>
<p><strong>Soma the moon god had 27 wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Purana 1.173 “Brilliant children of unmeasured splendour were born of those ladies of holy rites who had been mentioned as the twenty seven wives of Soma.” Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri Soma having 27 wives is also mentioned in Skanda Purana V.ii.26.1-6; Varaha Purana 35.1-2</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Brahma Khanda 9.42 “…Now I am going to narrate to you the names of the wives of the Moon-god and the wonderful features of their character which constitute the essence of the Puranas. They are 27 in number and their names are as follows: Aswini, Bhrani, Krittika, Rehini, Mriga-siri, Ardra, Punarvasu, Pusya, Aslesa, Magha, Purva-Phalguni, Uttar-Phalguni, Hasta, Chitra, Swati, Visakha, Anuradha, Jestha, Mafa, Purvabhadra-padi, Purva-asada, Uttar-asada, Dhanistha, Sravana, Sata-bhisa, uttar-bhidra-padi and Revati…” Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 6.6.2 — He gave ten daughters in charity to Dharmarāja [Yamarāja], thirteen to Kaśyapa [first twelve and then one more], twenty-seven to the moon-god, and two each to Aṅgirā, Kṛśāśva and Bhūta. The other four daughters were given to Kaśyapa. [Thus Kaśyapa received seventeen daughters in all.]
<p><strong>Hanuman’s father Kesari had two wives Anjana and Adrika. Hanuman was born from Anjana and wind god Vayu</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Purana: Gautami Mahatmya 14.1-4 “…O Narada, there is a mountain Anjana. On that mountain, O excellent sage, there was an excellent celestial damsel Anjana. She had a downfall due to a curse. Her face resembled that of a monkey. Her husband’s name was Kesari. Adrika was another wife of Kesari. She too was a celestial damsel who had a downfall due to a curse. Her face and head resembled those of a cat. She too stayed on the Anjana mountain.” Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><strong>Rudra had eleven wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Brahma Khanda 9.13-22 “Now I am going to recite, O great saint, the names of the wives of Rudra. They are celebrated by the names of (1) Kala, (2) Kalavati, (3) Kashta, (4) Kalika, (5) Kalahapriya, (6) Kandali, (7) Bhisana, (8) Basna, (9) Pramocha, (10) Bhusana, (11) Suki. They produced several children and were all followers of Siva…” Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>Rudra having eleven wives is also mentioned in Srimad Bhagavatam 3.12.13</p>
<p><strong>Agni had two wives</strong></p>
<p>As per Devi Bhagavatam 12.10.81-100 Agni had two wives namely Svaha and Svadha</p>
<p><strong>Ganesh had two wives Siddhi and Buddhi who were both daughters of Prajapati Vishwarupa</strong></p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudra Samhita 2.20.1-10 Ganesha had two wives namely Siddhi and Buddhi who were the daughters of Prajapati Visvarupa and begat two sons.</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudra Samhita 2.20.13 “By this that was celebrated, Ganesa has obtained two wives joyously. They are the excellent daughters of Prajapati Visvarupa. He has begot of his two wives of auspicious body two sons, Ksema of Siddhi and Labha of Buddhi. They bestow happiness on every one.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><strong>Vishnu had three wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Prakriti Khanda 6.13-21 “…Laksmi, Saraswati and Ganga are the three wives of Hari…” Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>As per another version he had four wives which later included Tulsi after he raped her. She quitted her body and became wife of Vishnu as per Brahma Vaivarta Purana</p>
<p><strong>Brahma had two wives</strong></p>
<p>As per Skanda Purana III.i.41.98-99 Brahma had two wives Gayatri and Saraswati</p>
<p><strong>Yamaraja had ten wives</strong></p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 6.6.4 The ten daughters given to Yamarāja were named Bhānu, Lambā, Kakud, Yāmi, Viśvā, Sādhyā, Marutvatī, Vasu, Muhūrtā and Saṅkalpā. Now hear the names of their sons.</p>
<p><strong>Garuda had many wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.7.448-454; Vayu Purana 8.319 “…The wives of Garuda were the other five viz.-Bhasi, Kraunci, Suki, Dhrtarastri and Syeni…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p><strong>Svayambhuva Manu, son of Brahma, had two sons; Priyavrata and Uttanapada. Uttanapada had two wives; Suruci and Suniti</strong></p>
<p>Linga Purana 62.1-5 Uttanapada had two wives, Suniti and Suruci and Dhruva was born of his elder wife Suniti</p>
<p>Also mentioned in Srimad Bhagavatam 4.8.8</p>
<p><strong>Manu had ten wives</strong></p>
<p>As per Maitrayani Samhita 1.5.8 Manu had ten wives.</p>
<p><strong>Sage Yagnavalkya had two wives</strong></p>
<p>Brihadaranyaka Upanishad 4.5.1 Yagnavalkya had two wives, Maitreyi and Katyayan</p>
<p><strong>Sage Mandarkini had five wives</strong></p>
<p>As per Valmiki Ramayana, Aranya Kanda 3, Chapter 11 Sage Mandakarni had five Apsaras (Nymphs) as his wives.</p>
<p><strong>Prajapati Angira had two wives</strong></p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 6.6.19 The prajāpati Aṅgirā had two wives, named Svadhā and Satī. The wife named Svadhā accepted all the Pitās as her sons, and Satī accepted the Atharvāṅgirasa Veda as her son.</p>
<p><strong>Sage Saubhari had fifty wives</strong></p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 9.6.52 says that Saubhari Muni had fifty wives.</p>
<p><strong>Sage Visravas had four wives</strong></p>
<p>Vayu Purana 9.32-34 “The sage Visravas was born of Idavida. He had four wives who made the family of Pulastya flourish. Brhaspati, the preceptor of the Devas, had a famous daughter named Devarinini. He (Visravas) married that girl. He (Visravas) married Puspotkata and Vaka, the daughters of Malyavan as well as Kaikasi, the daughter of Malin. Listen to their progeny.” Tr. G.V. Tagare, edited by G.P. Bhatt</p>
<p><strong>Atri had ten wives</strong></p>
<p>Vayu Purana 9.64 “I shall now recount the lineage of Atri, the third Prajapati. He had ten chaste and beautiful wives.” Tr. G.V. Tagare, edited by G.P. Bhatt</p>
<p><strong>Sage Bhrigu had two wives</strong></p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.1.74-76 “The two wives of Bhrgu were excellent nobility of birth. They were unrivalled and splendid. (One of them) was the daughter of Hiranyakasipu, well-renowned by the name of Divya. The second was Paulomi, the daughter of excellent complexion, of Puloman…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>also mentioned in Vayu Purana 4.73;</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Vayaviyasamhita 7.17.54 Ayati and Niyati became the wives of the sons of Bhrgu…” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><strong>Sage Marici had four wives upon who bore him 60,000 children</strong></p>
<p>Brahma Purana 1.195-8 “Upadanava was the daughter of Hayasiras, Sarmistha was the daughter of Vrasaparvan, Puloman and Kalaka were the two daughters of Vaisvanara. They were the wives of Marici. They had great strength and they bore many children. They had sixty thousand sons who delighted Danavas…” Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>also mentioned in Brahmanda Purana 2.3.6.26</p>
<p><strong>Brahma’s son was Marici, Marici’s son was Kashyapa. Kashyapa Rishi had thirteen wives who were all sisters, Kashyap had two major wives namely Diti and Aditi</strong></p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 6.6.24-26 …O King Parīkṣit, now please hear from me the names of Kaśyapa’s wives, from whose wombs the population of the entire universe has come. They are the mothers of almost all the population of the entire universe, and their names are very auspicious to hear. They are Aditi, Diti, Danu, Kāṣṭhā, Ariṣṭā, Surasā, Ilā, Muni, Krodhavaśā, Tāmrā, Surabhi, Saramā and Timi…</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 4.3.21-22 Vyâsa said :– Daksa Prajâpati had two daughters, Diti and Aditi; these two, of high rank, were married to Kas’yapa; and they were his favourites. Aditi gave birth to the very powerful Indra, the king of the Devas. Diti, too, asked for a son of the same strength, prowess, and splendour as those of Indra.</p>
<p>Brahma Purana 1.164-5 “O leading brahmins, now listen to the names of the wives of Prajapati Kasyapa. They are Aditi, Diti, Danu, Arista, Surasa, Khasa, Surabhi, Vinata, Tamra, Krodhavasa, Ira, Kadru and Muni. O brahmins, know the children born of them.” Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri also mentioned in Brahmanda Purana 2.3.3.56</p>
<p>Matsya Purana 4.53-54 “Out of the girls he created, he gave ten to Dharma, thirteen to Kasyapa…” Tr. Taluqdar of Oudh, edited by B.D. Basu</p>
<p><strong>Aditi’s son Aditya had four wives</strong></p>
<p>Kurma Purana I.20.1-2 “Aditi gave birth to her son Lord Aditya (the sun-god) from Kasyapa. This Aditya had four wives. They were Samjna, Rajni, Prabha, and Chaya…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Aditya had three wives, the fourth Chaya was the shadow of Samjna</p>
<p><strong>Seventh son of Aditi also had four wives</strong></p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 6.18.3-4 Dhātā, the seventh son of Aditi, had four wives, named Kuhū, Sinīvālī, Rākā and Anumati. These wives begot four sons, named Sāyam, Darśa, Prātaḥ and Pūrṇamāsa respectively. The wife of Vidhātā, the eighth son of Aditi, was named Kriyā. In her Vidhātā begot the five fire-gods named the Purīṣyas. The wife of Varuṇa, the ninth son of Aditi, was named Carṣaṇī. Bhṛgu, the son of Brahmā, took birth again in her womb.</p>
<p>Polygamy among Kshatriyas was more prevalent which is accepted by Hindu apologists also. Rig Veda shows the same,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.18.2 For like a King among his wives thou dwellest: with glories, as a Sage, surround and help us…</p>
<p><strong>As per Devi Bhagavatam book 2, chapter 7 Other than common wife Draupadi, Arjuna had one more wife by name Subhadra who was the sister of Krishna. On Krishna’s consent Arjuna stole her away by force.</strong></p>
<p><strong>King Harishchandra the son of Vedhas had one hundred wives</strong></p>
<p>Aitareya Brahmana, chapter 3, para 13 Harischandra, the son of Vedhas, of the Ikshavaku race, was a king who had no son. Though he had a hundred wives, they did not give birth to a son.</p>
<p>King Pandu had two wives Kunti and Madri.</p>
<p>As per Padma Purana II.79.1-2 King Yayati is said to have three wives</p>
<p>There are dozens of examples of Kings having several wives but I have limited it to few.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a id="post-7068-scriptures"></a>Hindu scriptures permitting Polygamy</h2>
<p>Renowned Hindu scholar Vijnanesvara writes,</p>
<p>“According to the order of the classes, for the Brahmana three, for the Ksatriya two wives, and for the Vaisya one wife are ordained. A Sudra can have only one wife born in the same class.” <strong>Vijnanesvara in his commentary Mitakshara on Yajnavalkya Smriti 3.57</strong></p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda finds no problem with Polygamy,</p>
<p>“For women, they hold chastity as the most important virtue, no doubt. One man marrying more than one wife is not so injurious to society as a woman having more than one husband at the same time, for the latter leads to the gradual decay of the race.” <strong>The Complete Works of Swami Vivekananda/Volume 5/Writings: Prose and Poems/The East and The West/France-Paris</strong><br />
<a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_5/Writings:_Prose_and_Poems/The_East_and_The_West/France-Paris" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_5/Writings:_Prose_and_Poems/The_East_and_The_West/France-Paris<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON on Polygamy,</p>
<p>“…According to our Vedic process, polygamy is allowed. For example, Krsna married 16,000 wives, Arjuna married 3 or 4 wives, Krsna’s father Vasudeva, married 16 or 18 wives, like that. So according to the Vedic system polygamy is not prohibited…” <strong>By Swami Prabhupada, Letter to Karandhara written from Bombay</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/730109_-_Letter_to_Karandhara_written_from_Bombay" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://vanisource.org/wiki/730109_-_Letter_to_Karandhara_written_from_Bombay<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>“People have become so degraded in this age that on the one hand they restrict polygamy and on the other hand they hunt for women in so many ways. Many business concerns publicly advertise that topless girls are available in this club or in that shop. Thus women have become instruments of sense enjoyment in modern society. The Vedas enjoin, however, that if a man has the propensity to enjoy more than one wife—as is sometimes the propensity for men in the higher social order, such as the brāhmaṇas, kṣatriyas and vaiśyas, and even sometimes the śūdras—he is allowed to marry more than one wife. Marriage means taking complete charge of a woman and living peacefully without debauchery. At the present moment, however, debauchery is unrestricted. Nonetheless, society makes a law that one should not marry more than one wife. This is typical of a demoniac society.” <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 4.26.6</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.26.6" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.26.6<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>He also writes,</p>
<p>“A man is allowed to keep more than one wife because he cannot enjoy sex when the wife is pregnant. If he wants to enjoy sex at such a time, he may go to another wife who is not pregnant. These are laws mentioned in the Manu-samhita and other scriptures.” <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 4.27.5</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.27.5" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.27.5<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Vedas the oldest scriptures of Hinduism neither permits nor prohibits Polygamy. But traces of polygamy can be found in Vedas which implies that it was practiced in the Vedic period, I am using Shri Ram Sharma’s Hindi translation.</p>
<p>Indra is said to have three wives as per the following verse,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.42.12 May the House-friends, the cunning-handed Artists, may the Steer&#8217;s Wives, the streams carved out by Vibhvan, And may the fair Ones honour and befriend us, Sarasvatī, Brhaddiva, and Rākā.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1142" height="249" class="wp-image-7073" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-59.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-59.jpeg 1142w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-59-300x65.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-59-1024x223.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-59-768x167.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1142px) 100vw, 1142px" /></p>
<p>Maitrayani Samhita 3.11.1 [140, 10-11] &#8220;The three goddesses growing by means of oblation, enjoying Indra like wives, Sarasvati, heavenly Ida, and all-conquering Bharati with their swelling milk [enjoying] the unbroken thread&#8230;&#8221; Tr. Catherine Ludvik</p>
<p>Vishnu is said to have had two wives, Sarasvati and Aditi. This is truly a case of polygamy unless it is a contradiction,</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 29.60 “…a mess of boiled rice is to be made for Prajâpati; the same for Vishnu&#8217;s Consort Aditi…” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 7.46.3 “O Consort of Vishnu Goddess, urge thy Lord to bounty…” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>Veda seems to sanction Polyandry as well, Rig Veda 6.49.7 considers Sarasvati as wife of Indra which is contrary to what above verses say unless it is contradiction. Sarasvati is also called wife of Ashwin brothers in Yajur Veda 19.94 which is clearly a case of polyandry.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.43.1. IN perfect unison all yearning hymns of mine that find the light of heaven have sung forth Indra’s praise. As wives embrace their lord, the comely bridegroom, so they compass Maghavan about that he may help.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="517" height="93" class="wp-image-7074" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/rig-veda-10-43-1.png?w=517&amp;h=93" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-.png 517w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig--300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.58.8 “As youthful ladies of love and virtue, inspired with passion and smiling in bliss, proceed to meet agni, enlightened husband, so do streams of ghrta move and flow into the vedi to meet the lighted fire, and the rising fire, loving and gracious, cherishes to receive the flow of the holy yajaka’s offer.” Tr. Tulsi Ram<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="517" height="112" class="wp-image-7075" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-1.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/rig-veda-4-58-8.png?w=517&amp;h=112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-1.png 517w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-1-300x65.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /></p>
<p>Another clear English translation</p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.58.8 “The streams of Ghi incline to Agni as devoted wives, auspicious and smiling, to a husband: they feed (the flame) like fuel, and Jatavedas, propitiated, accepts them.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.5.1.4 …therefore as one goes many follow; therefore one becomes superior among many; therefore one wins many wives…</p>
<p>A verse in Rig Veda clearly shows that an old Rishi Chyavana was married to many girls after he was rejuvenated,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.116.10 Ye from the old Cyavana, O Nasatyas, stripped, as ’twere mail, the skin upon his body, Lengthened his life when all had left him helpless, Dasras! and made him lord of youthful maidens.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="526" height="114" class="wp-image-7076" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-2.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/rig-veda-1-116-10.png?w=554&amp;h=120" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-2.png 526w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-2-300x65.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 526px) 100vw, 526px" /></p>
<p>Above is Shri Ram Sharma’s Hindi translation and following translation is by Pandit Ram Govind Trivedi<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="501" height="122" class="wp-image-7077" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-3.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2016/05/rig-veda-1-116-10-govind-trivedi.png?w=501&amp;h=122" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-3.png 501w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2016-05-rig-1-3-300x73.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 501px) 100vw, 501px" /></p>
<p>Chyavana being rejuvenated is also mentioned in Nirukta 4.19, Mahabharata Adi Parva 1.177 and Pancavimsa Brahmana 14.6.10 but it doesn’t state anything about his marriages. Maidens here may refer to several maidens or just two maidens. As Hindu texts only mentions his two wives. Scriptures doesn’t give much detail about Chyavana’s wives and stresses more on Sukanya the daughter of King Saryati. Sukanya became the wife of Chyavana as mentioned in Srimad Bhagavatam 9.3, other texts talks about another wife named Arushi the daughter of Manu who bore him a son named Aurva and this is mentioned in Mahabharata Adi Parva 1.66.47.</p>
<p>Other Hindu scriptures are clear on Polygamy. They permit polygamy without a doubt.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 3.12-13 For the first marriage of twice-born men (wives) of equal caste are recommended; but for those who through desire proceed (to marry again) the following females, (chosen) according to the (direct) order (of the castes), are most approved. It is declared that a Sudra woman alone (can be) the wife of a Sudra, she and one of his own caste (the wives) of a Vaisya, those two and one of his own caste (the wives) of a Kshatriya, those three and one of his own caste (the wives) of a Brahmana.</p>
<p>Agni Purana 285.63-67 “…A husband of many wives, should lick with his tongue, every day, a syrup composed of Triphala, Pippali, honey, clarified butter, and pulverised Amalaki treated with the expressed juice of the same fruit, and then drink water…” Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.85. If twice-born men wed women of their own and of other (lower castes), the seniority, honour, and habitation of those (wives) must be (settled) according to the order of the castes (varna).</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.160.36 “There is no sin in this. For a man polygamy is an act of merit, but for a woman it is very sinful to betake herself to a second husband after the first.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 14.80.12-18 “Oh, let Vijaya, let him that is called Gudakesa, let this hero with reddish eyes, come back O life. O blessed lady, polygamy is not fault with men. Women only incur fault by taking more than one husband.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.197.27-28 “Drupada answered, ‘O scion of Kuru’s race, it hath been directed that one man may have many wives. But it hath never been heard that one woman may have many husbands!” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Hindu scriptures also gives instructions on which wife should do religious duties with the husband if he has several wives.</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 26.1-4 If a man has several wives of his own caste, he shall perform his religious duties together with the eldest (or first married) wife. (If he has several) wives of diverse castes (he shall perform them) even with the youngest wife if she is of the same caste as himself. On failure of a wife of his own caste (he shall perform them) with one belonging to the caste next below to his own; so also in cases of distress (i.e, when the wife who is equal in caste to him happens to be absent, or when she has met with a calamity); But no twice born man ever with a S’udra wife.</p>
<p>Katyayana Samhita 8.6 “Many wives of the same caste and of other castes existing, the rite of churning, for producing the Fire, should be done by the chaste wives of the same caste, on account of the superiority of birth.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>FOUR WIVES</strong>:</p>
<p>The only confusion regarding Polygamy in Hindu scriptures is that some Hindu scriptures permits a Brahmin to marry four women and some permit only three. Following verses permits four wives for a Brahmin, three (as well as numerous) to a Kshatriya, two to a Vaishya and only one to a Shudra,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 13.47.4 “It has been laid down, O grandsire, that a Brahmana can take four wives, viz., one that belongs to his own order, one that is a Kshatriya, one that is a Vaisya, and one that is a Sudra, if the Brahmana wishes to indulge in the desire of sexual intercourse.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Mahabharata 13.48.4 “The Brahmana may take four wives, one from each of the four orders. In two of them (viz.,the wife taken from his own order and that taken from the one next below), he takes birth himself (the children begotten upon them being regarded as invested with the same status as his own)…A Kshatriya may take three wives…The Vaisya may take two spouses…The Sudra can take only one wife, viz., she that is taken from his own order. The son begotten by him upon her becomes a Sudra….” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Agni Purana 153.1 ”Pushkara said:- A Brahman may take four wives, a Kshatriya three, a Vaishya two, while a member of the Shudra caste is not allowed to have more than a single wife.” Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.149. If there be four wives of a Brahmana in the direct order of the castes, the rule for the division (of the estate) among the sons born of them is as follows:</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 24.1-5 Now a Brahmana may take four wives in the direct order of the (four) castes; A Kshatriya, three; A Vaisya, two; A Sudra, only one.</p>
<p>Baudhyana Dharma Shastra, Prasna I, Adhyaya 8, Kandika 16, verses 1-5 There are four castes (varna, viz.) Brâhmanas, Kshatriyas, Vaisyas, and Sûdras. (Males) belonging to them (may take) wives according to the order of the castes, (viz.) a Brâhmana four, A Kshatriya three, A Vaisya two, A Sudra one.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>THREE WIVES:</strong></p>
<p>Paraskara Grihya Sutra I Kanda, 4 Kandika, 8-11 Three (wives are allowed) to a Brahmana, in accordance with the order of the castes, Two to a Raganya, One to a Vaisya, One Sudra wife besides to all, according to some (teachers), without using Mantras (at the ceremonies of wedding, &amp;c.).</p>
<p>Yajnavalkya Smriti 3.57 “Three, according to the order of the caste, so also two, and one for a Brahmana, a Ksatriya and a Vaisya respectively (may be the wives). To a person born as a Sudra, a girl of her own caste is his wife.” Srisa Chandra Vasu</p>
<p>See commentary by Vijnanesvara on this verse for explanation which I have mentioned in this article.</p>
<p>Sankha Samhita 4.7 “Brahmana can marry three wives, a Kshatriya can take a couple of wives, while a Vais’ya or S’udra can marry a single wife. A Brahmana can marry a Brahmana, Kshartriya, or a Vais’ya girl.” Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Vasistha Samhita 1.24. Three wives (are permitted) to a Brâhmana according to the order of the castes, two to a Kshatriya, one to a Vaisya and to a Sûdra.</p>
<p>Mahabharata 13.44.11-12 “A Brahmana can take three wives. A Kshatriya can take two wives. As regards the Vaisya, he should take a wife from only his own order. The children born of these wives should all be regarded as equal. Of the three wives of a Brahmana, she taken from his own order should be regarded as the foremost. Similarly, of the two wives permitted to the Kshatriya, she taken from his own order should be regarded as superior. Some say that persons belonging to the three higher orders may take, only for purposes of enjoyment (and not for those of virtue), wives from the lowest or the Sudra order. Others, however, forbid the practice.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Some allows a Brahmin to have four wives while others allow three. As I said in my article <a href="/index.php/2016/06/05/caste-system-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Caste System in Hinduism</a>, There is unanimity among scholars that a Brahmin should first marry a woman from his own caste and then of succeeding castes. This applies for Kshatriya and Vaisya also. They can marry several women from their own castes also but laws concerning marriage with other castes is mentioned in those verses. As for those who allow a Brahmin to marry only three, they say it on the following basis,</p>
<p>Yajnavalkya Smriti 3.56 “Though it has been said that a twice born may take a wife from a Sudra family, yet that is not my opinion, because out of her, he is born himself.” Tr. Srisa Chandra Vasu</p>
<p>Similar thing is also said in Manu Smriti 3.14. A man belonging to low caste cannot marry girl belonging to preceding caste. But a Brahmin can marry a girl of any caste. Following two verses will clear the confusion,</p>
<p>Narada Smriti 12.4-6 When a Brahman, Kshatriya, Vaisya, or Sudra takes a wife, it is best for him to take her out of his own caste; and so is a member of her own caste (the most eligible) husband for a woman (of any caste). A Brahman may marry three wives of different caste, in the direct order of the castes; and so may a Sudra woman take a husband of any of the three castes above her own. For a Kshatriya, two wives differing (from him) in caste are permitted; for a Vaisya, a single wife differing (from him) in caste…</p>
<p>Munis to King</p>
<p>Markandeya Purana 113.31-34 “O king, A brahman who marries wives among all the castes, provided that he marries first a brahman woman, incurs no injury in his brahman-hood. Likewise a kshatriya who marries first a kshatriya’s daughter, incurs no harm if he marries wives from lower castes; and therefore, O king, these other wives fall not from their own righteousness. Thus a vaisya, who marries first a vaisya woman and afterwards a girl born from a sudra family, is not excluded from the vaisya family. The law is thus declared in order…”</p>
<p>Do mention this link when you copy any verse <a href="http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2018/05/05/polygamy-in-hindu-dharma/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hindu Dharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The roots of Rape in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fornication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hindu god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nirbhaya act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishment for rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Kancha Ilaiah Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal. Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Written by Kancha Ilaiah<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Rape has, of late, become an acute disease in the Indian society. Prima facie, this is a problem arising out of a mental disorder, but there is also a larger cultural context that, to an extent, explains how the Indian male became so brutal.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Our cultural upbringing conditions male minds to behave in a cruel fashion with women. Family upbringing, societal conditioning, religious sagas and political animus, all construct our men and women into being what they are — men as aggressive and women as submissive. Which is why men here, in India, are different from men in other countries.<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-961"></span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Their cultural milieu is different. Their spiritual systems train them differently. It&#8217;s not that only Indian men rape and kill children aged three or five. This happens in other countries too, but they are the rarest of rare cases. Daily reports of infants being raped across the length and breadth of a country is a phenomenon unique to India, a society that&#8217;s otherwise highly conservative. Clearly, the institutional upbringing, including that in family, needs to undergo change.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Every time a gruesome rape gets reported, we all are ashamed and angry. That&#8217;s one thing; but working out ways and means to eradicate such evil is another thing. We cannot leave it entirely to the police or the judiciary to tackle such heinous acts. For, rape is also a cultural problem; and it is a more serious problem because of the extermination of the victim. We need to treat the malaise from its very roots.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We are a society that derives its sense of good and bad from our mythologies and spiritual ethics. Our gods and goddesses are not only worshipped but also adored. And it is our lifelong endeavour to emulate them. This is the cultural environment that shapes the lives of most people in India. So it&#8217;s natural that what gods do influences us much more than the moral lesson at the end. Now consider this: we have gods who, for instance, have cut the nose and ear lobes of a woman who approached them professing her love (Lakshman is depicted as having done this to Shurpanakha), and yet we adore him and see him as a symbol of loyalty, sacrifice and righteous indignation.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Lord Krishna stole the clothes of women while they were bathing in the Yamuna river. He did so to tease them and for the pleasure of watching the beauty of their naked bodies. We hang miniature paintings of the same act in our homes proudly. The young men who grow up seeing this, or listening to the story told in an amused tone are bound to not find such an act abhorrent.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We also have a god, Shiva, who insisted on entering the bathing arena of Goddess Parvati and did so by eliminating a child who was keeping guard at the open door. Lord Ganesha is said to have emerged out of such a union. Is this right or wrong? Our mythology tells us that what a husband does is right, that his will is greater than the woman&#8217;s. If a mythological hero is praised for his acts of killing, drinking and fornicating with multiple women (like Indra did with Rambha, Urvashi, Menaka, Tilottama and so on), it is glorification of such behaviour.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">When such stories are a part of the mythological texts, they should, at least, be critically evaluated and given a more contemporary, political reading which is rooted in the concept of equality. Instead, the tendency is to not question what our gods did, but simply admire such acts.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Barring a few exceptions, there is no appreciation, per se, of a healthy man-woman relationship which is rooted in the concept of equality. Indian women are shown as lathangi (a person of delicate body), never strong enough to resist her dehumanisation. Though Durga and Kali are shown as strong, in real life such militancy is not seen as feminine.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Now let us turn to the political spectrum. We have had many great men — Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan etc — who got married at a young age with girls of much younger age, went abroad for higher studies, leaving their wives at home totally illiterate or semi-literate. We do not know how these men, or Gokhale and Tilak, treated their wives.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">But we know that they were all devotees of the deities mentioned above. The only man who treated his wife as a friend and educated her right from the first day of his marriage, Mahatma Jyotirao Phule, is not taught as an example to be emulated in our texts.  Somehow, in our patriarchal cultural milieu, unkind and inhuman treatment of women has never been a matter of concern. It&#8217;s considered sacrilegious, for example, to question Lord Ram for leaving his dutiful wife on the random outburst of a dhobi.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">And Sita&#8217;s action, in turn, to not question, but to commit suicide, is considered the epitome of all that is pious. Even Gautam Buddha left his young wife, with an infant child. Questioning such acts has never been part of our public discourse.<br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Or, look at our cinemas. Ever since the industry came into being, silent or talkie, it has used woman&#8217;s body as a money-making object. The song and dance sequence that it has adopted as an art form falls into a common pattern — every hero is licensed to misuse the body of the heroine. The romance in our film industry is not romance; it is vulgarity bordering on the criminal.<br />
So is it a surprise that men of this country see it as their right to violate women in all spheres of life?<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The writer is director, Centre for the Study of Social Exclusion and Inclusive Policy, Maulana Azad National Urdu University, Hyderabad</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/01/the-roots-of-rape-in-india-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">The roots of Rape in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polygamy in Hinduism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/polygamy-in-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[16800]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apsara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four wives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monogomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiple wives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paradise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyandry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polygamy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polygyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex slaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swarga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wives]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/polygamy-in-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad &#160; Swami Dayanand Saraswati writes in his books Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 4 and Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhoomika, Chapter ‘on Marriage’, “One man should have only one wife and one woman only one husband. That is to say, the marriage of one man with many women and of one woman with many men is prohibited.” &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/polygamy-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati writes in his books Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 4 and Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhoomika, Chapter ‘on Marriage’,</p>
<p>“One man should have only one wife and one woman only one husband. That is to say, the marriage of one man with many women and of one woman with many men is prohibited.”</p>
<p><span id="more-823"></span></p>
<p>He based his claim on the premise that “in the Vedic verses only the singular number is used for the husband or the wife”. This very argument is used by modern Arya Samaj ‘pracharaks’ (preachers). Strangely this argument is coming from that camp who make grand claims of being the true scholars of Sanskrit. They have tried to establish the prohibition of polygamy only on this argument that in the mantras which mention the words husband and wife, they have been used in the singular number. However, the appropriate method of establishing a prohibition is to provide explicit statements containing the prohibition rather than implicit evidence.</p>
<p>If Swami Dayanand and his followers would have followed their own established rules of interpreting Vedas, they would have known that the verbs in the Vedic mantras do not always follow the grammar conventions. An example of this is provided by Swami Dayanand himself in his book Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhoomika as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="371" height="30" class="wp-image-7082" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download.png" alt="download" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download.png 371w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-300x24.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px" /></p>
<p>“In this (Rigveda 1/162/6) is used the word (He hews) as singular- Although it should have been plural (they hew) because the performer (the hewers) are in the plural.” [Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhoomika, published by agniveer, page 287]
<p>Not only this; Swami ji is even an advocate of interchanging the masculine and feminine words as well as altering the pronouns in a Vedic mantra [Refer to the same Page as above]. Further, on page 292, Swami gives the following example,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="318" height="26" class="wp-image-7083" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xbhumika_hindiagniveer_pg292.gif.pagespeed.ic.m1gh-UxDvk.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http.png 318w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-300x25.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /></p>
<p>“In this example, (Rigveda 10/85/23) instead of the plural <strong>अस </strong>, the singular <strong>स </strong>has been used. Consequently, <strong>पन्था </strong>has been used which actually should have been <strong>पन्थानः</strong>“</p>
<p>If the Vedic rules are unreliable to this extent, then why make a fuss if in certain mantras, the words for husband and wife have been used in the singular number while the word husband may stand for all husbands instead of just one person and the word wife stands of all wives instead of just one person? Thus the argument of the Swami turns out to be flimsy. It would have been better if the Swami and Arya Samaj had followed the meanings of the mantras as given by their great scholars and ancestors. But alas, they did not.</p>
<p>Now, let me present before you the scriptural evidences in favour of polygamy and I invite the followers of Swami Dayanand to refute these evidences if they can.</p>
<p>A study of Swami Dayanand’s books reveals that the permission of polygamy is primarily based on the Vedas. For example, Purush Sookta i.e. Yajurveda 31/22 as translated by Swami Dayanand in Rigvedadi Bhashya Bhoomika Page 106 says</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="680" height="128" class="wp-image-7084" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-1.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xyajur_31_22_bhumika_pg106.gif.pagespeed.ic.1qALehNKd8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-1.png 680w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-1-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>“O God! Shri (beauty) and Lakshmi (splendid wealth) serve you like two loving wives.”</p>
<p>Can the followers of Vedic religion as interpreted  by Swami Dayanand care to explain the presence of such analogies in the Vedas which undermine their own claims about polygamy? This reference itself proves that had polygamy been prohibited in the Vedic text such analogies would not have been used.</p>
<p>Many mantras in the Rigveda also prove that polygamy is permitted in Vedic religion. Here I will present only a few examples.</p>
<p>Rigveda 1/62/11 says</p>
<p>पतिं न पत्नीरुशतीरुशन्तं सप्र्शन्ति तवा शवसावन्मनीषाः ||</p>
<p>As yearning wives cleave to their yearning husband, so cleave our hymns to you, O Lord most potent.</p>
<p>Rigveda 7/18/2 says</p>
<p>राजेव हि जनिभिः कषेष्येवाव दयुभिरभि विदुष कविः सन |</p>
<p>For like a King among his wives you dwell with your glories, as a Sage, surround and help us.</p>
<p>Rigveda 7/26/3 says</p>
<p>जनीरिव पतिरेकः समानो नि माम्र्जे पुर इन्द्रःसु सर्वाः ||</p>
<p>Indra has taken and possessed all castles, like as one common husband does his spouses.</p>
<p>Shatapath Brahmana, which is the authentic commentary of Shukla (White) Yajurveda and is also considered authentic by Swami Dayanand, also gives permission for polygamy.  It is mentioned in Shatapath Brahmana 9/4/1/6</p>
<p>“To the male (deity) he makes offering first, then to the females: he thereby endows the male pre-eminently with power. To a single male he makes offering, and to many females, whence even a single man has many wives. To the male (deity) he makes offering both with the Vashat-call and the Svâhâ-call, to the female (deities) only with the Svâhâ: he thereby endows the male pre-eminently with power.”</p>
<p>Further, Vedas are filled with the detailed mention of the concept of Swarga (Paradise) and the blessings which the dwellers of Paradise would enjoy. According to this Vedic concept, humans who inherit Paradise will enter it with all their organs, inclusing the sexual organs. One particular verse is produced here</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="394" height="59" class="wp-image-7085" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-2.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharva_16_4_64.gif.pagespeed.ic.8VtdViFKG-.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-2.png 394w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-2-300x45.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 394px) 100vw, 394px" /></p>
<p>“If Agni Jātavedas, as he bore you hence to the Fathers’ world, had left one single limb of your bodies, here do I restore it. Fathers, rejoice in heaven with all your organs!” [Atharvaveda 16:4:64]
<p>So the private organs will be there in Vedic Paradise. Supporing this view Shatpath Brahman Kaand 10, Adhyay 4, Brahaman 4, Kaandika 4 says,</p>
<p>“Wherefore let him who knows this by all means practise austerities; for, indeed, when he who knows this practises austerities, <strong>even to (abstention from) sexual intercourse, every (part) of him will share in the world of heaven</strong>“</p>
<p>It is clear from these mantras that sexual powers will be present in Vedic Paradise. Now the question is how and for what will these powers be used in Vedic Paradise. Atharvaved 4:34:2 answers this question as,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="393" height="54" class="wp-image-7086" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-3.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xatharvaved_4_34_2.gif.pagespeed.ic.a13xjmeMCh.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-3.png 393w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-3-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 393px) 100vw, 393px" /></p>
<p>“Boneless, pure, cleansed with the wind, brilliant, they go to a brilliant world. The fire does not burn their male organ. <strong>In Swarga they get plenty of women</strong>.” [Atharvaved 4:34:2]
<p>This mantra strikes a death blow to all those so-called Brahmacharis who sweat at the mere mention of women in Paradise, fearing that this will violate their Dharma. Vedas reject such apprehensions. There will not be just one, but numerous women to fulfill the desire of sex. In this mantra, the word Strenam (<strong>सत्रैणम</strong>) is used which means ‘<strong>a collection of women</strong>‘. This is the meaning given by the ancient Indian Grammarian Panini in his book Ashtadhyayi – Adhyay 4; Paad 1; Sootr 87. Lest any Arya Samji tries to do some word gymnastics as they are so renowned for, we have given this source. Also the word Shishan (<strong>शिशन</strong>) used in this mantra only means ‘phallus’ according to Nirukt 4:19.</p>
<p>These mantras reveal that one man will get plenty of women in Vedic Paradise and it has been described  as a great pleasure. This undoubtedly proves that polygamy is not a bad practice according to Vedas.</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand also in his Yajurveda Bhashya of 28/32 gives the following advice to Vedic followers:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="574" height="87" class="wp-image-7087" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-4.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xyajur_28_32_dayanand.gif.pagespeed.ic.CNaJnzkLMz.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-4.png 574w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-4-300x45.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 574px) 100vw, 574px" /></p>
<p>“Like a bull impregnates the cows thus increasing the cattle, men also should imprenate women to increase the population.”</p>
<p>This means like one bull impregnates many cows to produce more cattle, similarly, a Vedic man should impregnate many women regardless of their number to increase the population of Vedic followers. This analogy also proves that polygamy is permitted in the Vedic religion.</p>
<p>Further, Manu Smriti Chapter 7, shloka 221 says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="677" height="38" class="wp-image-7088" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-5.png" alt="https://web.archive.org/web/20131014101245im_/http:/www.islamhinduism.com/images/stories/xmanu_7_221.gif.pagespeed.ic.kvsEjtFmeM.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-5.png 677w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-web-archive-org-web-20131014101245im_-http-5-300x17.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 677px) 100vw, 677px" /></p>
<p>When he (the King) has dined, he may divert himself with his wives; but when he has diverted himself, he must, in due time, again think of the affairs of state.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti chapter 9, shloka 149 gives directions about the distribution of property among the sons of a Brahmin from his four wives. In fact the Maharishi Manu himself has 10 wives as is mentioned in another Shamhita (version) of Yajurveda, Maitrayani Samhita 1/5/8.</p>
<p>Following is the practical manifestation of the above mentioned scriptural permission regarding polygamy, by the great ancestor of the Vedic people:</p>
<p>The great Rishi of Shatapath Brahman, Yajnavalkya, practiced polygamy and had two wives namely ‘<strong>Maiteryi</strong>‘ and ‘<strong>Katyayani</strong>‘. This is mentioned in Brihadaranyak Upanishad 4/5/1.</p>
<p>अथ ह याज्ञवल्क्यस्य द्वे भार्ये बभूवतुर्मैत्रेयी च कात्यायनी च</p>
<p>“Yajnavalkya had two wives: Maitreyi and Katyayani”</p>
<p>As per the belief of Aryas. Rishi Yajnavalkya was a true devotee of Ishwara. On top of it he was a Rishi, which means an expert in all the sciences and thereby a teacher. Had polygamy been prohibited by the Vedic religion, then Rishi Yajnavalkya would not have practiced it and if polygamy be a sin and an evil deed then he is disqualified from the position of a Rishi. Rishi Yajnavalkya was present in the times when Vedic civilization was at its zenith. So his action directly gives proof of polygamy being Vedic.</p>
<p>Another great icon of Hindus, Sri Krishna, had eight principle wives, which is accepted by all Hindu scholars. They were Rukmini, Satyabhama, Jambavati, Satya, Lakshmana, Kalindi, Bhadra, Mitravinda. He further married 16,100 women whom he rescued from Narakasur as is clearly mentioned in the Anushana Prav of Mahabharata. The Pandavas also had many wives besides Draupadi who was their common wife (polyandry).</p>
<p>Modern Arya ‘pracharaks’ and Veda thumpers, try to claim that thse references are not accurate but interpolations. However, they present no credible evidences to back up this claim. I have already proved in my articles <a href="http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">[1]<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> <a href="http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">[2]<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> that Vedas too have been corrupted. Therefore, if they want to call Mahabharata as adulterated text, then they would have to give up Vedas as well, which leaves them with nothing. Further, their own Guru, Swami Dayanand derived the support for the Vedic concept of Niyog from the same Mahabharata [Refer to <a href="http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">this<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> article].</p>
<p>All the above evidences prove that Vedic religion does not prohibit Polygamy and the great icons of Vedic religion practiced polygamy perfectly according to the teachings of Vedic religion. Those who claim that Vedic religion/Hinduism prohibits polygamy have no proper evidence.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/polygamy-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Polygamy in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
