<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Rebuttal: History &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/rebuttals/history/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 14:15:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>No, Mughals didn&#8217;t loot India. They made us rich</title>
		<link>/index.php/2017/05/17/no-mughals-didnt-loot-india-they-made-us-rich/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 11:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2017/09/17/no-mughals-didnt-loot-india-they-made-us-rich/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>They remained as Indians, not colonists. by Rana Safvi (DailyO.in) India gained independence in 1947 after a long freedom struggle with British imperialism. Perhaps because of that, lack of historical knowledge and sense we see all conquests as colonisation. Colonisation is described by professor Harbans Mukhia as &#8220;governance of a land and its people, now &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2017/05/17/no-mughals-didnt-loot-india-they-made-us-rich/" data-wpel-link="internal">No, Mughals didn&#8217;t loot India. They made us rich</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>They remained as Indians, not colonists.</h4>
<p>by Rana Safvi (DailyO.in)</p>
<p>India gained independence in 1947 after a long freedom struggle with British imperialism. Perhaps because of that, lack of historical knowledge and sense we see all conquests as colonisation.</p>
<p>Colonisation is described by professor Harbans Mukhia as &#8220;governance of a land and its people, now on behalf of and primarily for the economic benefits of a community of people inhabiting a far-off land&#8221;.</p>
<p>The Mughals came to India as conquerors but remained as Indians not colonists. They subsumed their identity as well as the group&#8217;s identity with India and became inseparable from it, says professor Mukhia, giving rise to an enduring culture and history.</p>
<p>In fact, Mukhia goes on to say that this issue of Mughals being foreign was never a discussion point till quite recently, so well had they integrated and assimilated into the country they had made their own.<br />
<span id="more-1084"></span></p>
<p>There was no reason for it either since Akbar onwards all were born in India with many having Rajput mothers and their &#8220;Indianness&#8221; was complete.</p>
<p>Babur had invaded India at the behest of Daulat Khan Lodi and won the kingdom of Delhi by defeating the forces of Ibrahim khan Lodi at Panipat in 1526 AD. Thus, was laid the foundation of the Mughal Empire.</p>
<p>Most of the Mughals contracted marriage alliances with Indian rulers, especially Rajput. They appointed them to high posts and the Kachhwaha Rajput of Amber normally held the highest military posts in the Mughal army.</p>
<p>It was this sense of identification with the Mughal rulers that led the Indian sepoys who stood up in 1857 AD against the British East India Company in the first war of Indian Independence, to turn towards the aged, frail and powerless Mughal Emperor, Bahadur Shah Zafar, coronating him as emperor of Hindustan and fighting under his banner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" title="taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" alt="taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" /><strong>The Taj Mahal, which was built by Shah Jahan, has an average annual ticket sale of over Rs 21 crore.</strong></p>
<p>From 16<sup>th</sup> century to 18<sup>th</sup> century, the Mughal kingdom was the richest and most powerful kingdom in the world and as French traveller Francois Bernier, who came to India in the 17<sup>th</sup> century, wrote, “Gold and silver come from every quarter of the globe to Hinduostan.”</p>
<p>This is hardly surprising considering that Sher Shah, and the Mughals had encouraged trade by developing roads, river transport, sea routes, ports and abolishing many inland tolls and taxes. Indian handicrafts were developed. There was a thriving export trade in manufactured goods such as cotton cloth, spices, indigo, woollen and silk cloth, salt etc.</p>
<p>The Indian merchants trading on their own terms and taking only bullion as payment, leading Sir Thomas Roe to say that &#8220;Europe bleedeth to enrich Asia&#8221;.</p>
<p>This trade was traditionally in the hands of the Hindu merchant class who controlled the trade. In fact, Bernier wrote that the Hindus possessed &#8220;almost exclusively the trade and wealth of the country&#8221;. The Muslims mainly held high administrative and army posts.</p>
<p>A very efficient system of administration set up by Akbar facilitated an environment of trade and commerce.</p>
<p>It was this which led the East India Company to seek trade concessions from the Mughal empire and eventually control then destroy it.</p>
<p>A very interesting painting in possession of the British Library painted by Spiridione Roma, named <em>The East Offering Her Riches to Britannia,</em> dated 1778, shows Britannia looking down on a kneeling India who is offering her crown surrounded by rubies and pearls. The advent of the famous drain of wealth from India started with the East India Company not the Delhi Sultanate or the Mughals.</p>
<p>Edmund Burke was the first to use the phrase in the 1780s when he said, India had been &#8220;radically and irretrievably ruined&#8221; through the company’s &#8220;continual Drain&#8221; of wealth.</p>
<p>Let us examine India’s economic status prior to its becoming a British colony.</p>
<p>The Cambridge historian Angus Maddison writes in his book, <em>Contours of the World Economy 1–2030 AD: Essays in Macro-economic History,</em> that while India had the largest economy till 1000 AD (with a GDP share of 28.9 per cent in 1000AD) there was no economic growth. It was during the 1000 AD-1500 AD that India began to see a economic growth with its highest (20.9 per cent GDP growth rate) being under the Mughals. In the 18<sup>th</sup> century, India had overtaken China as the largest economy in the world.</p>
<p><strong>The changing share of world GDP 1600–1870 (in million 1990 international $)</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" title="table-copy_091617061055.jpg" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/table-copy_091617061055.jpg" alt="table-copy_091617061055.jpg" /><strong> Source: Angus Maddison, The World Economy, Paris: OECD, 2001, p. 261, Table B-18</strong></p>
<p>In 2016, on a PPP adjusted basis, India’s was 7.2 per cent of the world GDP.In 1952, India’s GDP was 3.8 per cent. “Indeed, at the beginning of the 20th century, &#8220;the brightest jewel in the British Crown&#8221; was the poorest country in the world in terms of per capita income,&#8221; former prime minister Dr Manmohan Singh once said.</p>
<p>Since it&#8217;s established now that the Mughals did not take away money, let’s talk of what they invested in. They invested in infrastructure, in building great monuments which are a local and tourist draw generating crores of rupees annually.</p>
<p>As per figures presented by the Ministry of Culture in Lok Sabha, just the Taj Mahal built by Shah Jahan has an average annual ticket sale of over Rs 21 crore. (Last year saw a drop in visitors to the Taj Mahal and figures stood at Rs 17.8 crore.) The Qutub Complex generates over Rs 10 crore in ticket sales, Red Fort and Humayun’s Tomb generate around Rs 6 crore each.</p>
<p>A beautiful new style known as Indo-Islamic architecture which imbibed the best of both was born.</p>
<p>They invested in local arts and crafts, and encouraged old and created new skill sets in India. As Swapna Liddle, covenor of INTACH, Delhi Chapter, says, “To my mind, the greatest Mughal contribution to India was in the form of patronage to the arts. Whether it was building, artisanal crafts like weaving and metal-working, or fine arts like painting, they set standards of taste and perfection that became an example for others to follow, and brought India the global recognition for high quality handmade goods that it still enjoys.”</p>
<p>Mughal paintings, jewels, arts and crafts are the key possessions of many a western museum and gallery as they were looted in and after 1857. Some can be seen in Indian museums too.</p>
<p>Art and literature flourished. While original work was being produced in the local and court languages, translation work from Sanskrit to Persian was also taking place. Akbar encouraged the <a href="http://ranasafvi.com/3265-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">translation <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>of the Ramayana and the Mahabharata to dispel ignorance, which led to communal hatred.</p>
<p>Dara Shukoh’s Persian translation of the Upanishads named <em>Sirr-e-Akbar</em> taken by Bernier to France where it reached Anquetil Deperron, who translated it into French and Latin. The Latin version reached the German philosopher, Schopenhauer, who was greatly influenced by it and called the Persian Upanishad, &#8220;the solace of his life&#8221;. This awakened an interest in post-Vedic Sanskrit literature amongst the European Orientalists.</p>
<p>It wasn’t only the Mughal emperors who were building, but Hindu mansabdars and traders too were building temples and dharmshalas in many cities, especially Banaras. Madhuri Desai in her extremely well-researched book, <em>Banaras Reconstructed</em>, writes: “The riverfront ghats bear an uncanny resemblance to the Mughal fortress-palaces that line the Jamuna river in Agra and Delhi.”</p>
<p>It’s dangerous to generalise history, especially on communal lines. While economic deprivations for the common man existed, as they did and do in any society, as Frances W Pritchett, professor emerita, Columbia University, says, “The impression one gains from looking at social conditions during the Mughal period is of a society moving towards integration of its manifold political regions, social systems and cultural inheritances.</p>
<p>The greatness of the Mughals consisted in part at least in the fact that the influence of their court and government permeated society, giving it a new measure of harmony.”</p>
<p>Thus, to say that the Mughals <a href="https://amp.scroll.in/article/850526/mughals-only-looted-india-history-syllabus-will-be-rewritten-says-up-deputy-cm" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">looted <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>India is a falsification of facts.</p>
<p>It’s always best to read history in history books where one can get facts not on WhatsApp forwards where people often share false data and information as per their own bias.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>India gained independence in 1947 after a long freedom struggle with British imperialism. Perhaps because of that, lack of historical knowledge and sense we see all conquests as colonisation.</p>
<p>Colonisation is described by professor Harbans Mukhia as &#8220;governance of a land and its people, now on behalf of and primarily for the economic benefits of a community of people inhabiting a far-off land&#8221;.</p>
<p>The Mughals came to India as conquerors but remained as Indians not colonists. They subsumed their identity as well as the group&#8217;s identity with India and became inseparable from it, says professor Mukhia, giving rise to an enduring culture and history.</p>
<p>In fact, Mukhia goes on to say that this issue of Mughals being foreign was never a discussion point till quite recently, so well had they integrated and assimilated into the country they had made their own.</p>
<p>There was no reason for it either since Akbar onwards all were born in India with many having Rajput mothers and their &#8220;Indianness&#8221; was complete.</p>
<p>Babur had invaded India at the behest of Daulat Khan Lodi and won the kingdom of Delhi by defeating the forces of Ibrahim khan Lodi at Panipat in 1526 AD. Thus, was laid the foundation of the Mughal Empire.</p>
<p>Most of the Mughals contracted marriage alliances with Indian rulers, especially Rajput. They appointed them to high posts and the Kachhwaha Rajput of Amber normally held the highest military posts in the Mughal army.</p>
<p>It was this sense of identification with the Mughal rulers that led the Indian sepoys who stood up in 1857 AD against the British East India Company in the first war of Indian Independence, to turn towards the aged, frail and powerless Mughal Emperor, Bahadur Shah Zafar, coronating him as emperor of Hindustan and fighting under his banner.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" title="taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" alt="taj-copy_091617061832.jpg" /><strong>The Taj Mahal, which was built by Shah Jahan, has an average annual ticket sale of over Rs 21 crore.</strong></p>
<p>From 16<sup>th</sup> century to 18<sup>th</sup> century, the Mughal kingdom was the richest and most powerful kingdom in the world and as French traveller Francois Bernier, who came to India in the 17<sup>th</sup> century, wrote, “Gold and silver come from every quarter of the globe to Hinduostan.”</p>
<p>This is hardly surprising considering that Sher Shah, and the Mughals had encouraged trade by developing roads, river transport, sea routes, ports and abolishing many inland tolls and taxes. Indian handicrafts were developed. There was a thriving export trade in manufactured goods such as cotton cloth, spices, indigo, woollen and silk cloth, salt etc.</p>
<p>The Indian merchants trading on their own terms and taking only bullion as payment, leading Sir Thomas Roe to say that &#8220;Europe bleedeth to enrich Asia&#8221;.</p>
<p>This trade was traditionally in the hands of the Hindu merchant class who controlled the trade. In fact, Bernier wrote that the Hindus possessed &#8220;almost exclusively the trade and wealth of the country&#8221;. The Muslims mainly held high administrative and army posts.</p>
<p>A very efficient system of administration set up by Akbar facilitated an environment of trade and commerce.</p>
<p>It was this which led the East India Company to seek trade concessions from the Mughal empire and eventually control then destroy it.</p>
<p>A very interesting painting in possession of the British Library painted by Spiridione Roma, named <em>The East Offering Her Riches to Britannia,</em> dated 1778, shows Britannia looking down on a kneeling India who is offering her crown surrounded by rubies and pearls. The advent of the famous drain of wealth from India started with the East India Company not the Delhi Sultanate or the Mughals.</p>
<p>Edmund Burke was the first to use the phrase in the 1780s when he said, India had been &#8220;radically and irretrievably ruined&#8221; through the company’s &#8220;continual Drain&#8221; of wealth.</p>
<p>Let us examine India’s economic status prior to its becoming a British colony.</p>
<p>The Cambridge historian Angus Maddison writes in his book, <em>Contours of the World Economy 1–2030 AD: Essays in Macro-economic History,</em> that while India had the largest economy till 1000 AD (with a GDP share of 28.9 per cent in 1000AD) there was no economic growth. It was during the 1000 AD-1500 AD that India began to see a economic growth with its highest (20.9 per cent GDP growth rate) being under the Mughals. In the 18<sup>th</sup> century, India had overtaken China as the largest economy in the world.</p>
<p><strong>The changing share of world GDP 1600–1870 (in million 1990 international $)</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" title="table-copy_091617061055.jpg" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/table-copy_091617061055.jpg" alt="table-copy_091617061055.jpg" /><strong> Source: Angus Maddison, The World Economy, Paris: OECD, 2001, p. 261, Table B-18</strong></p>
<p>In 2016, on a PPP adjusted basis, India’s was 7.2 per cent of the world GDP.In 1952, India’s GDP was 3.8 per cent. “Indeed, at the beginning of the 20th century, &#8220;the brightest jewel in the British Crown&#8221; was the poorest country in the world in terms of per capita income,&#8221; former prime minister Dr Manmohan Singh once said.</p>
<p>Since it&#8217;s established now that the Mughals did not take away money, let’s talk of what they invested in. They invested in infrastructure, in building great monuments which are a local and tourist draw generating crores of rupees annually.</p>
<p>As per figures presented by the Ministry of Culture in Lok Sabha, just the Taj Mahal built by Shah Jahan has an average annual ticket sale of over Rs 21 crore. (Last year saw a drop in visitors to the Taj Mahal and figures stood at Rs 17.8 crore.) The Qutub Complex generates over Rs 10 crore in ticket sales, Red Fort and Humayun’s Tomb generate around Rs 6 crore each.</p>
<p>A beautiful new style known as Indo-Islamic architecture which imbibed the best of both was born.</p>
<p>They invested in local arts and crafts, and encouraged old and created new skill sets in India. As Swapna Liddle, covenor of INTACH, Delhi Chapter, says, “To my mind, the greatest Mughal contribution to India was in the form of patronage to the arts. Whether it was building, artisanal crafts like weaving and metal-working, or fine arts like painting, they set standards of taste and perfection that became an example for others to follow, and brought India the global recognition for high quality handmade goods that it still enjoys.”</p>
<p>Mughal paintings, jewels, arts and crafts are the key possessions of many a western museum and gallery as they were looted in and after 1857. Some can be seen in Indian museums too.</p>
<p>Art and literature flourished. While original work was being produced in the local and court languages, translation work from Sanskrit to Persian was also taking place. Akbar encouraged the <a href="http://ranasafvi.com/3265-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external">translation <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>of the Ramayana and the Mahabharata to dispel ignorance, which led to communal hatred.</p>
<p>Dara Shukoh’s Persian translation of the Upanishads named <em>Sirr-e-Akbar</em> taken by Bernier to France where it reached Anquetil Deperron, who translated it into French and Latin. The Latin version reached the German philosopher, Schopenhauer, who was greatly influenced by it and called the Persian Upanishad, &#8220;the solace of his life&#8221;. This awakened an interest in post-Vedic Sanskrit literature amongst the European Orientalists.</p>
<p>It wasn’t only the Mughal emperors who were building, but Hindu mansabdars and traders too were building temples and dharmshalas in many cities, especially Banaras. Madhuri Desai in her extremely well-researched book, <em>Banaras Reconstructed</em>, writes: “The riverfront ghats bear an uncanny resemblance to the Mughal fortress-palaces that line the Jamuna river in Agra and Delhi.”</p>
<p>It’s dangerous to generalise history, especially on communal lines. While economic deprivations for the common man existed, as they did and do in any society, as Frances W Pritchett, professor emerita, Columbia University, says, “The impression one gains from looking at social conditions during the Mughal period is of a society moving towards integration of its manifold political regions, social systems and cultural inheritances.</p>
<p>The greatness of the Mughals consisted in part at least in the fact that the influence of their court and government permeated society, giving it a new measure of harmony.”</p>
<p>Thus, to say that the Mughals <a href="https://amp.scroll.in/article/850526/mughals-only-looted-india-history-syllabus-will-be-rewritten-says-up-deputy-cm" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">looted <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>India is a falsification of facts.</p>
<p>It’s always best to read history in history books where one can get facts not on WhatsApp forwards where people often share false data and information as per their own bias.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>SOURCE:</strong> <a href="http://www.dailyo.in/politics/mughals-contribution-indian-economy-rich-culture-tourism-british/story/1/19549.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dailyo.in/politics/mughals-contribution-indian-economy-rich-culture-tourism-british/story/1/19549.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2017/05/17/no-mughals-didnt-loot-india-they-made-us-rich/" data-wpel-link="internal">No, Mughals didn&#8217;t loot India. They made us rich</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A ‘miser&#8217; who donated generously</title>
		<link>/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 12:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Correspondent Mir Osman Ali Khan donated liberally to places of worship Along with Muslim employees, Christians and Hindus given special leave for visiting holy places The seventh Nizam also granted Rs. 1 lakh each to the Andhra and the Benaras Hindu Universities &#160; Hyderabad: The Yadgarpally temple at Bhongir received a grant of Rs. &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/" data-wpel-link="internal">A ‘miser&#8217; who donated generously</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="content-body-14269002-15988076" class="_hoverrDone">
<p>Special Correspondent</p>
<p><i>Mir Osman Ali Khan donated liberally to places of worship</i></p>
<p><i>Along with Muslim employees, Christians and Hindus given special leave for visiting holy places</i></p>
<p><i>The seventh Nizam also granted Rs. 1 lakh each to the Andhra and the Benaras Hindu Universities</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-1092"></span></p>
<p>Hyderabad: The Yadgarpally temple at Bhongir received a grant of Rs. 82,825. Sitarambagh temple got Rs. 50,000, Bhadrachalam temple Rs. 29,999 and Balaji temple in Tirupati Rs. 8,000</p>
<p>No, these are not grants made by the present dispensation but by the erstwhile Nizam&#8217;s regime. The Seventh Nizam, Mir Osman Ali Khan, was generous in donations to churches, mosques and Gurudwaras too. Though a strict follower of Islam, he displayed exemplary tolerance towards other faiths.</p>
<p>These little known details were an eye opener to many who turned up for the talk on “The cultural contributions of Mir Osman Ali Khan” organised at the Princess Esin Women&#8217;s Educational Centre here on Thursday. The programme was held as part of the formation day of the H.E.H. The Nizam&#8217;s Museum. A.K.V.S. Reddy, Director-General, National Institute of Tourism and Hospitality Management, presided.</p>
<p>Among the audience was the last Nizam&#8217;s grandson, Muffakham Jah Bahadur. It was his keen interest that led to the establishment of the Nizam&#8217;s Museum in 2000. Zareena Parveen, Director, A.P. State Archives and Research Institute, raised eyebrows of many when she explained how the last Nizam was secular to the core. Often dubbed a ‘miser&#8217;, he was benevolent when it came to helping out others.</p>
<p>Preserved culture</p>
<p>He took pains for preservation of the ancient and medieval culture of the Deccan and did his best for cultural synthesis. He took steps for protection of the world famous frescoes of Ajanta and Ellora. His government honoured religious leaders like Guruswamy Danamamal. Along with Muslim government servants, the Hindus and Christians were given six months special leave and advance salary for visiting their holy places. “He always proclaimed that Hindus and Muslims were his two eyes,” Dr. Parveen said.</p>
<p>Education</p>
<p>A progressive ruler, the Nizam&#8217;s reign ushered in an era of construction of public buildings. He also patronised learning institutions and granted Rs. 1 lakh each to the Andhra and the Benaras Hindu Universities, besides financing several socio charitable institutions.</p>
<p>Dr. Parveen lauded the pragmatic approach of the Nizam for emancipation of women.</p>
<p>Despite opposition, he introduced progressive reforms and encouraged education of the downtrodden and vulnerable sections of society.</p>
</div>
<p><strong>SOURCE: </strong><a href="http://www.thehindu.com/todays-paper/tp-national/tp-andhrapradesh/A-lsquomiser-who-donated-generously/article15988076.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thehindu.com/todays-paper/tp-national/tp-andhrapradesh/A-lsquomiser-who-donated-generously/article15988076.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/" data-wpel-link="internal">A ‘miser&#8217; who donated generously</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2016/10/30/a-miser-who-donated-generously/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 09:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivaji]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Probably not. And here are five reasons why. by Shoaib Danyal [Source: Scroll.in] As has been happening ever so often since Narendra Modi took power, history has burst out into modern-day politics. The New Delhi Municipal Corporation has proposed renaming &#8220;Aurangzeb Road&#8221; in Lutyen&#8217;s Delhi to &#8220;APJ Abdul Kalam Road&#8221;. The move had wide support &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:#333333;font-size:13pt;background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>Probably not. And here are five reasons why.<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><span style="color:#222222;font-size:13pt;"><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">by Shoaib Danyal [Source: Scroll.in] </span></span></span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/article-uzednshbdr-1441184122.jpg" alt="Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?" /></p>
<p><span id="more-815"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><span style="color:#222222;font-size:13pt;"><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">As has been happening ever so often since Narendra Modi took power, history has burst out into modern-day politics. The New Delhi Municipal Corporation has proposed renaming &#8220;Aurangzeb Road&#8221; in Lutyen&#8217;s Delhi to &#8220;APJ Abdul Kalam Road&#8221;. The move had wide support and both the Bharatiya Janata Party and the Aam Admi Party seem to have pitched for it, even as the Congress has maintained a studied silence. This also revived the long-standing Shiv Sena demand to rechristen Aurangabad in Maharashtra. Once the Mughal capital in the Deccan and founded by the Prime Minister (Peshwa) of the Ahmadnagar Sultanate, Malik Ambar, the city is set to be renamed Sambhaji Nagar, after Shivaji&#8217;s son.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Many people assume that history is an impersonal record of past events; a dull roll call of facts, events and figures. While raw data is certainly a component in the writing of history, there&#8217;s more to it in the way of how the historian interprets that data. In the words of EH Carr:</span><br />
<span style="font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="background:#fcfcfc;"><span style="color:#6f6f6f;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;">&#8220;History consists of a corpus of ascertained facts. The facts are available to the historian in documents, inscriptions and so on, like fish on the fishmonger&#8217;s slab. The historian collects them, takes them home, and cooks and serves them in whatever style appeals to him.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The final meal, then, depends not only on the fish available with the fishmonger, but also what the chef selects to cook and how he wants to cook it.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Most Indian state-written histories, for example, choose to elide the devastating <a href="http://tarikhpartarikh.blogspot.in/2014/03/the-maratha-invasion-of-bengal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">invasion</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of the Marathas into western Bengal in the 1740s. A majority of Indian narratives look at the Marathas as a &#8220;national&#8221; force and ignore the fact that (like any medieval army) they had no concept of nationalism and were mostly interested in loot. In a mirror image, Pakistan has named its missiles after Afghan king Mahmud of Ghazni, deliberately choosing to forget that the man made his fortune by mostly plundering what is current-day Pakistan.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">This is not to say that a history of Bengal that does not include the Maratha invasion is per se false. After all, any history of Bengal has to leave out something or the other in order to tell a cogent story. This example is just to introduce the concept of a narrative and its power in shaping our concept of history.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">With Aurangzeb, therefore, at least in the popular realm, a narrative has taken root which paints him as a Mughal Voldemort, so dreadful and tyrannical that even his name on a single road in the entire country could endanger the republic.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, it is impossible to disprove (or prove) such a narrative in an article. Nevertheless, here are five facts that at least don&#8217;t fit into it.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>1. Aurangzeb built more temples than he destroyed</strong></span><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The issue of temple destruction has taken on a particular hysteria after the violent mass movement in the 1980s and 1990s led by the Bharatiya Janata Party to destroy the Babri Masjid, based on the belief that the spot once housed a temple to the god Ram.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Ironically, there are almost no complaints of temple destruction by Mughal Hindu citizens in the medieval period itself, when these acts were actually supposed to have been carried out. Or even after Mughal power had waned in the 18th century (in case one would want to argue some sort of Mughal censorship). As the historian Richard Eaton has <a href="http://www.tehelka.com/2013/11/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">shown</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, destruction of temples by Muslim rulers in India was exceedingly rare and even when it did happen, it was a political act meant to chasten recalcitrant rulers and not a theological move.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In spite of his terrible reputation, Aurangzeb sticks to this template. Temples are rarely destroyed (Eaton puts the number of instances at 15 for Aurangzeb) and, if they are, the reason is political. For example, Aurangzeb almost never targetted temples in the Deccan, although that is where his massive army was camped for most of his reign. In the north, he did attack temples, for example the Keshava Rai Temple in Mathura. But the reason was political: the Jats of the Mathura region had revolted against the empire.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">For these same reasons of statecraft, Aurangzeb also patronised temples, since Hindus who remained loyal to the state were rewarded. In fact, as Katherine Butler Schofield from King&#8217;s College London <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayFulltext?type=1&amp;fid=573344&amp;jid=ASS&amp;volumeId=41&amp;issueId=01&amp;aid=573340" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">points</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> out, &#8220;Aurangzeb built far more temples than he destroyed.&#8221; Scholars such as <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/history/south-asian-history/architecture-mughal-india?format=HB" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">Catherine Asher</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, M Ather Ali and <a href="http://alkindi4.ideo-cairo.org/manifestation/168289" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">Jalaluddin</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>have pointed to numerous tax-free grants bestowed on Hindu temples, notably those of the Jangam Bari Math at Benares, Balaji&#8217;s temple at Chitrakoot, the Someshwar Nath Mahadev temple at Allahabad, the Umanand temple at Gauhati, and numerous others.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Also, temple destruction was a common part of Indian politics at the time and was not restricted to Muslims. In 1791, for example, the Maratha army raided and damaged the Shankaracharya&#8217;s temple in Sringeri because it was being patronised by Tipu Sultan, their enemy. Later on, Tipu renovated the temple and had the idol reinstalled.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>2. Music flourished in India during Aurangzeb&#8217;s reign</strong></span><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">A crucial part of the entire narrative of Aurangzeb as a tyrant is the parable that he banned music. It is a powerful tale and one that could really clinch the case. The only problem? It&#8217;s not true.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Far from being banned throughout India, as Katherine Butler Schofield comprehensively<a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayFulltext?type=1&amp;fid=573344&amp;jid=ASS&amp;volumeId=41&amp;issueId=01&amp;aid=573340" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">establishes</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, music wasn&#8217;t proscribed even in Aurangzeb&#8217;s court. The Emperor&#8217;s own coronation anniversaries were marked by both musicians and dancers. Not only that, his patronsiation of music meant that a number of dhrupads were composed in his name. Even further, he also seemed to be quite knowledgeable about it himself. In the <em>Mirat-e-Alam</em>, Bahktawar Khan wrote of the Emperor having a &#8220;perfect expert&#8217;s knowledge&#8221; of music. The<em>Rag Darpan</em>, a musical treatise by Mughal noble Faqirullah lists out Aurangzeb&#8217;s favourite singers and instrumentalists by name. Aurangzeb&#8217;s dearest son, Azam Shah went one step further and, during the lifetime of his father, became an accomplished musician.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In fact, it could even be said that music flourished under Aurangzeb&#8217;s. Schofield writes: &#8220;More musical treatises in Persian were written during Aurangzeb&#8217;s reign than in the previous 500 years of Muslim rule in India, and all of them make significant references to current music making.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">In spite of his own love for it, later on in life, as Aurangzeb got more religious, he did stop listening to music himself. However, given the evidence, the assumption that this personal preference of Aurangzeb&#8217;s fashioned Mughal state policy seems incorrect.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>3. Aurangzeb employed more Hindus (including Shivaji) than any other Mughal<br />
</strong>It is a well-established fact that the number of Hindus employed by the Emperor&#8217;s administration was the highest ever in Mughal history up till then. In fact, the number of Hindu bureaucrats rose significantly during Aurangzeb&#8217;s rule, a statistic that, in the <a href="http://www.oup.co.in/product/oxford-india-paperback/history/medieval-india/232/the-mughal-nobility-under-aurangzeb-revised-edition/9780195655995" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">words</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of M Ather Ali, provides a &#8220;fine lawyer&#8217;s answer to any charge that Aurangzeb discriminated against Hindu mansabdars&#8221;.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The proportion of commanders, senior court officials and provincial administrators who were Hindu rose from 24% under Aurangzeb&#8217;s father, Shahjahan to 33% in the fourth decade of the Aurangzeb&#8217;s own rule.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">This trend actually becomes sharper as you move up the administration. A remarkably large number of Aurangzeb&#8217;s top generals were Hindu Rajputs. In fact, when Aurangzeb&#8217;s campaign against the Marathas or Sikhs is presented in a communal light, it is often forgotten that the actual Mughal army in the field was almost always led by a Rajput general.  Shivaji, himself, in fact, <a href="http://www.cambridge.org/co/academic/subjects/history/south-asian-history/marathas-16001818" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:#f16529;">served</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> in Aurangzeb&#8217;s army as a mid-level commander (mansabdar) at one time and, <a href="http://www.amazon.in/Shivaji-His-Times-Jadunath-Sarkar/dp/8125040269" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">writes</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> Jadunath Sarkar, even expected to be made the Mughal Viceroy of the Deccan, but was refused by Aurangzeb, who could not gauge his military genius.</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://theindianmuslim.files.wordpress.com/2015/09/090315_0904_wasaurangze1.jpg" alt="" /><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#222222;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><br />
<span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>4. Aurangzeb&#8217;s mother tongue was Hindi<br />
</strong>Being unIndian is a charge levied not only at Aurangzeb but at almost any ruler who happens to be Muslim in medieval India. At one level, it is a puerile and, in fact, absurd test, given that there simply was no concept of &#8220;<a href="https://books.google.co.in/books?id=4mmoZFtCpuoC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">nationalism</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>&#8221; in 17th century India (or almost anywhere else).</span></span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Nevertheless, almost by any standards, Aurangzeb was a pukka upper-class Hindustani (a somewhat obvious point, since he <em>was</em> born and raised upper-class Hindustani). Patronising Braj Bhasha, a North Indian literary language for poetry and song, had been a long-standing Mughal tradition which continued into Aurangzeb&#8217;s rule. The patronage climate for Braj in Aurangzeb&#8217;s court was a &#8220;lively and encouraging one&#8221;, <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?aid=7179784&amp;fileId=S0026749X09990205" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">says</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> historian Allison Busch. Azam Shah, his son, was keenly interested in Braj poetry and patronised some of the biggest names in the language such as Mahakavi Dev. Vrind was another giant of Braj who was employed by Aurangzeb&#8217;s administration.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Moreover – again, this is obvious – the mother tongue of Aurangzeb and the other Mughals by then had become an early form of modern Hindi-Urdu. In a fascinating <a href="https://archive.org/stream/rukaatialamgirio00aurarich/rukaatialamgirio00aurarich_djvu.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">letter</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, written by Aurangzeb to his 47-year old son, Azam Shah, the Emperor gifts him a fort and orders that drums be beaten in his name. He then reminisces about Azam&#8217;s childhood, reminding him that he loved drums as a toddler and would often exclaim, &#8220;Babaji, dhun dhun!&#8221; to Aurangzeb in Hindi when he heard them.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, the Mughals still mostly wrote in Persian, which was the official language of the day. However, since you&#8217;re reading this in English, that shouldn&#8217;t be too much of an issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;"><strong>5. The jizya tax wasn&#8217;t unusually discriminatory <em>for its time<br />
</em></strong>Controversial point, this, but let&#8217;s see it through.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Abolished by Akbar and reintroduced by Aurangzeb, the jizya was a tax levied on non-Muslims in the realm over and above all other duties. It functioned in three slabs depending on income and its rate ranged from 0.5% to 6%. It also had a number of exceptions built in and the poor, unemployed and disabled were not expected to pay. Moreover, Brahmans &#8220;as the <a href="https://books.google.co.in/books?id=Zpa8gyGW_twC&amp;redir_esc=y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">spiritual leaders</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of the Hindu community&#8221; were also exempt, as were bureaucrats.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The Muslim counterpart to the religious tax of jizya was the zakat, or alms tax, also to be paid over and above normal taxes. Aurangzeb, however, abolished the zakat.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">From the modern point of view, this is clearly discriminatory and modern nations do not (with minor exceptions such as the Hindu Undivided Family provision in India) impose taxes on groups based on identity.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Judging people in the 17th century with today&#8217;s morals, though, would result in an absurd situation: <em>everyone</em> would come out looking terrible. Taxation based on identity is an anachronism today but was not that much in Aurangzeb&#8217;s time. The Marathas, who went on to replace the Mughals in large parts of the Deccan, had a discriminatory taxation policy as well; a mirror image of Aurangzeb&#8217;s, in fact. They <a href="https://books.google.co.in/books/about/Beyond_Turk_and_Hindu.html?id=9ZhT5Ilq5kAC" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">collected</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> zakat from Muslims with no corresponding tax from Hindus.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">However, in many ways, both the Maratha zakat and Mughal jizya were, for their time, only mildly discriminatory, involving minor sums and a tiny percentage of the population (modern India&#8217;s income tax base is less than 3% of the population, so you can imagine how small it was for Mughal India). Unlike today, the main axis of India&#8217;s society at the time did not revolve around &#8220;Hindu&#8221; and &#8220;Muslim&#8221;. To see real 17th century discrimination, one needs to go to caste.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">The Maharashtrian Mahar Dalit caste under the Peshwa rule, for example, had to hang a broom from their backs, which swept away their footsteps as they walked so as to not &#8220;pollute&#8221; the path, in case an upper caste person should happen to use it later. A pot had to be hung below their neck, to collect any saliva that should inadvertently fall out from their mouths, also to prevent &#8220;pollution&#8221;. Arms and education were, of course, banned and any Mahar breaking these caste laws was summarily put to death.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">So degrading was the condition of the Mahars under Peshwa rule that BR Ambedkar, also a Mahar, <a href="http://drambedkarbooks.com/2011/12/30/the-battle-of-bhima-koregaon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:#f16529;">celebrated</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> the victory of the British in the Anglo-Maratha wars – a practice that continues till today with the Mahars.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color:#fcfcfc;">Of course, our evaluation of tyranny in the past is not based on any objective reading of history (if such a thing were possible at all) but rests mostly on our modern prejudices and politics. This is why Aurangzeb&#8217;s jizya is discussed threadbare but the Maratha zakat or policy on caste is mostly swept under the carpet. And this is why Delhi&#8217;s Aurangzeb Road may soon be renamed.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Was Aurangzeb the most evil ruler India has ever had?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/09/03/was-aurangzeb-the-most-evil-ruler-india-has-ever-had-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Were Muslim Rulers Iconoclasts?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 06:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Maqbool Ahmed Siraj Much of the evidence of what Hindu nationalists claim about demolishing and desecration of temples by Muslim rulers is found in Persian sources. Now this is projected as a proof of Muslim intolerance, tyranny and despotism against Hindu subjects or the vanquished people. But it does not tell all. We had &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/" data-wpel-link="internal">Were Muslim Rulers Iconoclasts?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Maqbool Ahmed Siraj</p>
<p>Much of the evidence of what Hindu nationalists claim about demolishing and desecration of temples by Muslim rulers is found in Persian sources. Now this is projected as a proof of Muslim intolerance, tyranny and despotism against Hindu subjects or the vanquished people. But it does not tell all.</p>
<p><span id="more-776"></span></p>
<p>We had this Babri Masjid /Ramjanambhoomi movement built around this point which caused great upheavals in Indian politics and led to bloodshed. Conceptual framework for the same was provided by History books such as Sita Ram Goel’s two-volume Hindu Temples: What Happened to them? and Prafull Goradia’s Hindu Masjids.</p>
<p>Between 986 and 1192 AD several invaders plundered North India and took away a lot of movable wealth. These kings included Sabuktagin and Mahmood Ghaznavi (who ruled Kabul between 998 and 1130 AD). These raids were mainly targeted at material gain. They never sought permanent rule in India.</p>
<p>But as Muslims established their rule they took upon two tasks:<br />
i &#8211; State patronage of India based sufi order. Chishtia order was thus patronized by all sultanates and Muslim kings.</p>
<p>ii &#8211; A policy of selective temple desecration in order not to loot and finance their military machine but to delink the Hindu state patronage to temples and divinity of the kings.</p>
<p>We will go into the second aspect in detail. The saffron historians hide this aspect. Those temples that housed the ruling dynasty’s state deity or rashtra-devata were normally desecrated, defiled or destroyed. This was to strip the rajah of the divine legitimacy. Temples that were not so identified were left untouched.</p>
<p><strong>Hindu Kings also demolished Temples<br />
</strong><br />
But this was not alone with Muslim conquerors. This was a custom even before Muslim armies arrived. From 6th century onwards, all deities, sanctum sanctorum, images associated with dynastic authority were considered politically vulnerable. All Hindu kings, armies, kingdoms treated their Hindu rivals the same way. Even Historian R. M. Eaton has described this as a rule of the war. He writes, ‘Hindu rulers to effectively legitimize their rule over the conquered territory resorted to temple destruction of the vanquished raja. The temples were normally looted, the presiding deity of the dynasty as every Hindu rulers had his own presiding deity’. (Ref. R. M. Eaton, Essays in Indian History, page 104)</p>
<p><strong>Here are a few facts:<br />
</strong><br />
1089-1101 AD: King Harsha of Kashmir of the first Lohara dynasty indulged in ruthlessly looting the treasures of the temples of Bhimasai and also systematically confiscated and defiled the metallic statues of Gods by outcasts throughout the Kashmir valley in order to obtain the valuable material. He even imposed tax on the night soil.<br />
(Ref. Kalhana, Rajataran-gini, Vol. 1, sec. 5, Motilal Banarsidas, page 113)</p>
<p>Between 986 and 1192 AD several invaders plundered North India and took away a lot of movable wealth. These kings included Sabuktagin and Mahmood Ghaznavi (who ruled Kabul  between 998 and 1130 AD).</p>
<p>• 642 AD: Pallava king Narasimhavarman I looted the image of Ganesha from the Chalukyan capital of Vatapi (present day Badami in Belgaum dist.)</p>
<p>• 692 AD: Chalukyas invaded North India and brought back to the Deccan what would appear to be images of Ganga and Yamuna looted from defeated powers.</p>
<p>• 8th century AD: Bengali troops sought revenge on King Lalithaditya’s kingdom in Kashmir by destroying what they thought was an image of Vaikunta the state deity of Kashmir kingdom.</p>
<p>• 9th century AD: Rashtrakuta king Govinda III invaded and occupied Kanchipuram which so intimidated the King of Sri Lanka that he sent Govinda (probably Buddhist) images representing the Sinhala state.</p>
<p>• Rashtrakuta king Indira III not only destroyed the temple of Kalapriya at Kalpa near the Jamuna river, patronized by their deadly enemies, the Pratiharas, but they took special delight in recording the fact.</p>
<p>• 9th century AD: Pandyan King Srimara Srivallabha also invaded Sri Lanka and took back to his capital golden Buddha image.</p>
<p>• Early 10th century, Pratihara King, Hermabapala, seized solid gold image of Vishnu Vaikunta when he defeated the Sahi kings of Kangra (Himachal Pradesh)</p>
<p>• Early 11th century: Chola King, Rajendra I furnished his capital with images he seized from several prominent neighboring kings: Durga and Ganesha images from the Chalukyas, Bhairava, Bhairavi and Kali images from the Kalingas or Orissa as Nandi image from the Eastern Chalukyans. (Ref: David Gilmartin and Bruce B. Lawrence (ed.), Beyond Hindu and Turk, University Press of Florida, 2000.</p>
<p>In short, the temples were the sites where royal authority was challenged before the arrival of Muslim Turks in India. This generally happened with early Muslim rulers. But this practice declined after Muslims began to wrest territories and rule from the territories held by their preceding Muslim rulers.</p>
<p><strong>Some more facts can be noted</p>
<p></strong>• In many cases the temple desecration was never recorded.</p>
<p>• Between 1192 AD and 1729 AD, 89 instances of temple desecration are found recorded in the Indian history. Their historicity appears reasonably certain.</p>
<p>• Most such acts were undertaken by military officers.</p>
<p>• They happened mostly along the moving frontiers of conquests.</p>
<p>• These acts were never directed at people but at the enemy king and the image that incarnated and displayed his state deity.</p>
<p>But this attitude changed once these conquered land were integrated into the Muslim kingdoms. Then the religious properties were left unmolested. Some instances of patronage of temples:</p>
<p>1. Mohammad Ibne Kasim is quoted to have said: Temples shall be unto us like the churches of Christian, Synagogues of Jews and fire temples of Magians.<br />
(Ref. William Jackson A.V., (ed) History of India, Vol. 5, The Grolier Society, London, Baroda edition 1907, page 12).</p>
<p>2. Muhammad bin Tughlaq appointed Muslim officials to repair Siva temple in Kalyana in Bidar district in 1326 thereby facilitating resumption of normal worship.</p>
<p>3. Sultan Shahabuddin Tughlaq (1355-73) rebuked his Brahaman minister for having suggested melting down Hindu and Buddhist images in his kingdom as a means of obtaining quick cash.</p>
<p>4. Sikandar Lodhi (1489-1517), was advised in these words by Muslim jurists : It is not lawful to lay waste ancient idol temples and it does not rest with you to prohibit ablution in a reservoir which has been customary from ancient times.</p>
<p>5. In Mughal rule, Akbar allowed high ranking Rajput officers in his service to build their own monumental temples in the provinces to which they were posted.</p>
<p>6. Between 1590 and 1735, Mughal officials repeatedly oversaw and on occasion even initiated the renewal of Orissa’s cult, that of Jagannath in Puri. By sitting under a canopied chariot which accompanying the cult’s annual car festival, Shah Jehan’s officials ritually demonstrated that it was the Mughal emperor operating through the appointed officers (mansabdar), who was the temple’s and hence God’s representative.</p>
<p>7. Aurangzeb (1656-1707) ordered the local officials in Benares to protect the temples and Brahman temple functionaries. (Ref. Firman ordering mansabdar Abulhasan in Benares dt. Feb. 28, 1659, quoted by the Journal of the Asiatic Society of Bengal, Page 689-90, 1911)</p>
<p>8. Sikandar Lodhi (1489-1517) received information that a lot of Hindus had gathered at Kurukshetra and were raising a lot of ruckus there. He wanted to demolish the temple and kill all the Hindus there. He sought advice from the ulema. Malikul Ulama Abdullah issued an edict: It is anti-sharia to demolish a traditional place of worship of Hindus (dhimmis) and discontinue the convention of bathing at the ghat or a pond. Sikandar flew into rage and warned him of dire consequences. Abdullah said: He did not fear anyone and the life and death are in the hands of the Almighty Allah. At this Sikandar gave up the idea.(Ref. Sheikh Mohammad Ikram quotes Syed Ameer Ali from Islamic culture)</p>
<p>Muhammad bin Tughlaq appointed Muslim officials to repair Siva temple in Kalyana in Bidar district in 1326 thereby facilitating resumption of normal worship.</p>
<p><strong>Mahmood Ghaznavi and Bamiyan Buddhas<br />
</strong><br />
Mahmood Ghaznavi ruled Afghanistan from Ghazni. He led 11 army expeditions between 1001 and 1055 AH on Hindustan and is accused of desecrating and demolishing temples. If indeed Mahmood’s objective was iconoclasm, he could have turned his ire against Bamiyan Buddhas which stood for nearly 2000 years in Bamiyan. He did not touch them. It could be asked as to why a confirmed ‘iconoclast’ merely passed by the Buddhas.</p>
<p><strong>Mosques were also not spared</p>
<p></strong>It was not merely temples but even mosques were not spared if the Muslim emperors suspected their edifices being used for purposes other than worship. Aurangzeb ordered the demolition of Jama Masjid of Golconda after sacking the Qutb Shahi kingdom in 1687 to get access to treasure that lay beneath the mosque floor.</p>
<p>It will be less than fair to attribute desecration or defiling of religious places to bigotry and hatred. It owed much to the customs of the age whereby vanquished kings had to be divested of the religious halo and authority. Rulers, Hindu or Muslims, followed the practice regardless of their own religious beliefs.</p>
<p>(For feedback: debumkmyths @yahoo.co.in)</p>
<p>Courtesy: Islamic Voice, May 2006</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/" data-wpel-link="internal">Were Muslim Rulers Iconoclasts?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/were-muslim-rulers-iconoclasts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Truth behind tales of Temple destruction</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 06:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Name of the Book: Temple Destruction and Muslim States in Medieval India Author: Richard M. Eaton, Publisher: Hope India, Gurgaon (hope_india@indiatimes.com) Year: 2004 Pages: 101 Price: Rs.225 ISBN: 81-7871-027-7 Reviewed by: Yoginder Sikand Central to the diverse memories of Hindus and Muslims in India about the history of Hindu-Muslim relations are incidents or claims of &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/" data-wpel-link="internal">Truth behind tales of Temple destruction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Name of the Book: Temple Destruction and Muslim States in Medieval India<br />
Author: Richard M. Eaton,<br />
Publisher: Hope India, Gurgaon (hope_india@indiatimes.com)<br />
Year: 2004 Pages: 101 Price: Rs.225 ISBN: 81-7871-027-7</p>
<p><b>Reviewed by: Yoginder Sikand </b></p>
<p><span id="more-773"></span></p>
<p>Central to the diverse memories of Hindus and Muslims in India about the history of Hindu-Muslim relations are incidents or claims of the destruction of Hindu temples by Muslim rulers. These memories are a defining element in the construction of contemporary communal identities. Some Muslims see medieval Muslims Sultans who are said to have destroyed temples as valiant heroes who struggled against Brahminism, idolatry and polytheism. For many Hindus, these very kings are the epitome of evil and godlessness.</p>
<p>The theme of the iconoclast Muslim Sultan is routinely put to use for political mobilization by communal forces, as so tragically illustrated in the case of the Babri Masjid controversy, resulting in the deaths of thousands of people. Not content with that, Hindutva forces are on record as declaring that they aim at destroying or capturing some 30,000 mosques and Muslim shrines, which, they claim, were built on the sites of Hindu temples allegedly destroyed by Muslim rulers. Hindutva literature is replete with exhortations to Hindus to avenge the misdeeds, both real and imaginary, of medieval Muslim kings, including destruction of temples. This propaganda and the communal mobilization that it has provoked have resulted in a sharp deterioration of inter-communal relations in recent years.</p>
<p>That some Muslim kings did indeed destroy certain Hindu temples is an undeniable fact, which even most Muslims familiar with medieval history would readily concede. However, as this remarkable book by the noted historian Richard Eaton points out, extreme caution needs to be exercised in accepting the claims of medieval historians as well as in interpreting past events in terms of today’s categories. Failure to do this, he says, has resulted in the construction of the image of all Muslims as allegedly fired by an irrepressible hatred of Hindus, a gross distortion of actual history.</p>
<p>The notion of the Muslim Sultan as temple-breaker, Eaton says, derives essentially from history texts written by British colonial administrators, who, in turn, drew upon Persian chronicles by Muslim historians attached to the courts of various Indian Muslim rulers. Eaton argues that British colonial historians were at pains to project the image of Muslim rulers as wholly oppressive and anti-Hindu, in order to present British rule as enlightened and civilized and thereby enlist Hindu support. For this they carefully selected from the earlier Persian chronicles those reports that glorified various Muslim Sultans as destroyers of temples and presented these as proof that Hindus and Muslims could not possibly live peacefully with each other without the presence of the British to rule over them to prevent them from massacring each other. Although some of these reports quoted in British texts were true, many others were simply the figment of the imagination of court chroniclers anxious to present their royal patrons as great champions of Islamic orthodoxy even if in actual fact these rulers were lax Muslims.</p>
<p>Dealing with actual instances of temple-breaking by Muslim rulers, Eaton appeals for a more nuanced approach, arguing that in most cases these occurred not simply or mainly because of religious zeal. Thus, the raids on temples by the eleventh century Mahmud Ghaznavi must be seen as motivated, at least in part, by the desire for loot, since the temples he destroyed were richly endowed with gold and jewels, which he used to finance his plundering activities against other Muslim rulers in Afghanistan, Iran and elsewhere. Beginning in the early thirteenth century, the Delhi Sultans’ policy of selective temple desecration aimed, not as in the earlier Ghaznavid period, to finance distant military operations on the Iranian plateau but to de-legitimize and extirpate defeated Indian ruling houses. The process of Indo-Muslim state building, Eaton says, entailed the sweeping away of all prior political authority in newly conquered territories. When such authority was vested in a ruler whose own legitimacy was associated with a royal temple, typically one that housed idol of ruling dynasty’s state-deity, that temple was normally looted or destroyed or converted into a mosque, which succeeded in ‘detaching the defeated raja from the most prominent manifestation of his former legitimacy’. Temples that were not so identified were normally left untouched. Hence, Eaton writes, it is wrong to explain this phenomenon by appealing to what he calls as an ‘essentialized theology of iconoclasm felt to be intrinsic to Islam’.</p>
<p>Royal temple complexes were pre-eminently political institutions, Eaton says. The central icon, housed in a royal temple’s garba griha or ‘womb-chamber’ and inhabited by the state-deity of the temple’s royal patron, expressed the ‘shared sovereignty of king and deity’. Therefore, Eaton stresses, temple-breaking, especially of temples associated with ruling houses, was essentially a political, rather than simply religious, act. As proof of this thesis he cites instances of the sacking of royal temples of Hindu rulers by rival Hindu kings as early as the sixth century C.E.. In AD 642 CE the Pallava king Narashimhavarman I looted the image of Ganesha from the Chalukyan capital of Vatapi.. In the eighth century, Bengali troops sought revenge on king Lalitaditya by destroying what they thought was the image of Vishnu Vaikuntha, the state deity of Lalitaditya&#8217;s kingdom in Kashmir. In the early ninth century the Pandyan king Srimara Srivallabha also invaded Sri Lanka and took back to his capital a golden Buddha image that had been installed in the kingdom&#8217;s Jewel Palace. In the early eleventh century the Chola king Rajendra I furnished his capital with images he had seized from several neighboring Chalukya, Kalinga and Pala rulers. In the mid-eleventh century the Chola king Rajadhiraja defeated the Chalukyas and plundered Kalyani, taking a large black stone door guardian to his capital in Thanjavur, where it was displayed to his subjects as a trophy of war. In addition to looting royal temples and carrying off images of state deities, some Hindu kings, like some of their later Muslim counterparts, engaged in the destruction of the royal temples of their political adversaries. In the early tenth century, the Rashtrakuta monarch Indra III not only destroyed the temple of Kalapriya (at Kalpa near the Jamuna River), patronized by the Pratiharas, but, Eaton writes, ‘took special delight in recording the fact’.</p>
<p>This and other such evidence clearly suggests, Eaton argues, that ‘temples had been the natural sites for the contestation of kingly authority well before the coming of Muslim Turks to India’. Hence, the Turkish invaders, in seeking to establish themselves as rulers, followed a pattern that had already been established before their arrival in India. Yet, the iconoclastic zeal of the Muslim rulers of India must not be exaggerated, Eaton says. He claims that based on evidence from epigraphic and literary evidence spanning a period of more than five centuries (1192-1729), ‘one may identify eighty instances of temple desecration whose historicity appears reasonably certain’, a figure much less than what Hindutva ideologues today claim.</p>
<p>In judging these incidents, extreme caution is necessary, Eaton suggests. These temples were destroyed not by ‘ordinary’ Muslims, but, rather, by officials of the state. Further, the timing and location of these incidents is also significant. Most of them occurred, Eaton says, on ‘the cutting edge of a moving military frontier’, in the course of military raids or invasions of neighboring territories ruled by Hindu kings. Once Muslim rulers had conquered a particular territory and incorporated it into their kingdom typically such incidents were few, if at all. When Muslim rulers grew mainly at the expense of other Muslim ruling houses, temple desecration was rare, which explains, for instance, why there is no firm evidence of the early Mughal rulers Babar and Humayun, whose principal adversaries were Afghans, in engaging in temple desecration, including, strikingly, in Ayodhya. Certain later Mughal and other rulers are said to have engaged in the destruction of royal temples and building mosques on their sites in territories ruled by rebel chieftains. These acts were intended to be punishments for rebellion, and once rebellions were quelled few such incidents took place.</p>
<p>Whatever form they took, Eaton says, ‘acts of temple desecration were never directed at the people, but at the enemy king and the image that incarnated and displayed his state-deity’. Eaton cites in this regard a contemporary description of a 1661 Mughal campaign in Kuch Bihar, northern Bengal, which resulted in the annexation of the region, makes it clear that Mughal authorities were guided by two principal concerns: to destroy the image of the state-deity of the defeated Raja, Bhim Narayana and to prevent Mughal troops from looting or in any way harming the general population of Kuch Bihar. Accordingly, the chief judge of Mughal Bengal, Saiyid Muhammad Sadiq, was directed to issue prohibitory orders that nobody was to touch the property of the people. Sayyid Sadiq, Eaton tells us, ‘issued strict prohibitory orders so that nobody had the courage to break the laws or to plunder the property of the inhabitants. The punishment for disobeying the order was that the hands, ears or noses of the plunderers were cut’. In newly annexed areas formerly ruled by non-Muslims, as in the case of Kuch Bihar, Eaton goes on, ‘Mughal officers took appropriate measures to secure the support of the common people, who after all created the material wealth upon which the entire imperial edifice rested’.</p>
<p>The theory that politics, rather than simple religious zeal, lay behind most instances of temple-breaking by Muslim rulers is strengthened by the fact that, as Eaton points out, once Hindu Rajas were defeated by Muslim kings and their territories annexed, pragmatism dictated that temples within the Emperor’s realm remained unharmed. This was the case even with the Mughal Emperor Aurangzeb, generally projected as the epitome of Muslim iconoclasm. Eaton quotes an order issued by Aurangzeb to local officials in Benares in 1659 to provide protection to the Brahman temple functionaries there, together with the temples at which they officiated. The order reads:</p>
<p><b>In these days information has reached our court that several people have, out of spite and rancor, harassed the Hindu residents of Benares and nearby places, including a group of Brahmans who are in charge of ancient temples there. These people want to remove those Brahmans from their charge of temple-keeping, which has caused them considerable distress. Therefore, upon receiving this order, you must see that nobody unlawfully disturbs the Brahmans or other Hindus of that region, so that they might remain in their traditional place and pray for the continuance of the Empire. </b></p>
<p>Justifying this order, Aurangzeb asserted, ‘According to the Holy Law (shari&#8217;at) and the exalted creed, it has been established that ancient temples should not be torn down’. At the same time, he added that no new temples should be built, a marked departure from the policy of Akbar. However, Eaton says that this order appears to have applied only to Benares because many new temples were built elsewhere in India during Aurangzeb&#8217;s reign.</p>
<p>Eaton thus seeks to dismiss the notion that various Muslim rulers in India wantonly engaged in destroying Hindu temples, allegedly driven by a ‘theology of iconoclasm’. Such a picture, he insists, cannot, sustained by evidence from original sources from the early thirteenth century onwards. Had instances of temple desecration been driven by a ‘theology of iconoclasm’, he argues, this would have ‘committed Muslims in India to destroying all temples everywhere, including ordinary village temples, as opposed to the highly selective operation that seems actually to have taken place’. In contrast, Eaton’s meticulous research leads him to believe that ‘the original data associate instances of temple desecration with the annexation of newly conquered territories held by enemy kings whose domains lay on the path of moving military frontiers. Temple desecration also occurred when Hindu patrons of prominent temples committed acts of treason or disloyalty to the Indo-Muslim states they served’. Otherwise, he notes, ‘temples lying within Indo-Muslim sovereign domains, viewed normally as protected state property, were left unmolested’.</p>
<p>This slim volume is a path-breaking book, a passionate protest against the horrendous uses to which the notion of the ‘theology of iconoclasm’ has been put by contemporary Hindutva ideologues to justify murder in the name of avenging ‘historical wrongs’. It urgently deserves to be translated into various Indian languages and made readily available at a more affordable price.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/" data-wpel-link="internal">Truth behind tales of Temple destruction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/truth-behind-tales-of-temple-destruction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Was Somanatha Raided by Mahmud of Ghazni?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 06:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Linguistic analysis of Somnatha &#160; The word Somanatha is a composite of two independent words: Soma and Natha. Some historians mentioned that the word Soma in Somanatha was originally Shobha, that means beauty in Sanskrit, but the word has been changed into Soma due to frequent use and over time, while the word Natha means &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/" data-wpel-link="internal">Why Was Somanatha Raided by Mahmud of Ghazni?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:24pt;"><strong>Linguistic analysis of Somnatha<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p><a href="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/images1.jpg" class="broken_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-993" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/images1.jpg" alt="Somnath" width="287" height="175" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span id="more-765"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The word Somanatha is a composite of two independent words: Soma and Natha. Some historians mentioned that the word Soma in Somanatha was originally Shobha, that means beauty in Sanskrit, but the word has been changed into Soma due to frequent use and over time, while the word Natha means owner, lord or possessor, thus, &#8216;Shobha Natha&#8217; became Somanatha that is the owner of the beauty. Perhaps, the name was given because the temple or the city was a symbol of beauty<sup>(1)</sup> due to the abundant offerings and money that flooded to it from all parts of Indian subcontinent by its devotees of Indian people including the kings and princes.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However, Al-Beruni mentions another explanation for the word Somanatha, concluding that it was attributed to the moon, he says: &#8220;Soma is the moon and Natha means the lord, thus Somanatha means the lord of the moon.&#8221;<sup>(2)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:24pt;"><strong>Was Somnatha of a Miraculous Nature ?<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">It is said that Somanatha remained a center of myths and false beliefs across its history, people believed that Somanatha had a miraculous nature. Dayananda Saraswati (1824 –1883 A.D.) was asked about the miracles ascribed to Somanatha as was mentioned in his book Satyarth Prakash: &#8220;Question: See, Somanatha rested above the ground, which was a great miracle. Is it false also? Answer: Yes, it is false. Listen to me. There were magnets above and below of the idol, as a result of their attraction, the idol was hanging in the air without any visible support. When Mahmud of Ghazni raided it, the false miracle became unmasked when the roof was broken it fell sown on the earth and the priests and devotees faced humiliation. Also the Hindu army was hundreds of thousands of strong men who were defeated by only ten thousands of Muslim fighters.&#8221;<sup>(3)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In fact, we do not care here if the miracle of Somanatha temple was a false or true, myths or fact. That was not the cause of its raid by Mahmud. The real motive behind it was that the remnants of the defeated coalition army which entered the temple and used it as a shield and fort to attack the armies of Mahmud of Ghazni.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In addition to that, the temple was a hub for the enemies of Sultan Mahmud of Ghazni, including Brahmins of Mathura and Thanesar as well as it was a refuge of Qaramitians and Isma`ilis of Sindh, Iran and Gujarat, who conspired day and night against Mahmud of Ghazni. This was the basic motive that led him to attack the temple, as there was no other way to fight those plotters.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Suppose if there are fighters in a temple who use it as shield and inflict losses upon your army, what will you do? Will you wait or will you raid it?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Furthermore, the Brahmins had propagated and spread amongst the people by all ways and means that the idol of Somanatha was angry with the idol of Thanesar and Muthra that is why Smonath consented to the acts of Mahmud of Ghazni and did not prevent him from destroying it. But now, when Mahmud and his soldiers intended to raid Somanatha itself, the idol of Somanatha is going to eliminate them within a moment since it is the king of all idols, the sea itself comes to worship it during some fixed days. Somanatha was located on the coast of the sea, and the water was extended to Somanatha because of the lunar tide that is a common and natural phenomena. But the priests and spiritual leaders made people to believe that the sea comes to worship the idol of Somanatha.<sup>(4)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Five hundred volunteer girls were dedicated to serve this idol on the permanent basis that belonged to wealthy families of princes and kings. The temple included two thousand priests of Brahmins to organize the activities of worship, offerings and religious services.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">We have already mentioned that the remnants of the Indian coalition army fled the fighting and entered the temple. Furthermore, the devotees of Somanatha believed in the superiority of Somanatha over other deities and idols that were worshiped in northern India. Also the worshippers of Somanatha always degraded and demeaned the devotees of other idols, attributing the calamities and defeat of the people of northern India to the weakness of their gods and inabilities of their deities. So the people of northern India incited the king Mahmud to demolish the idol which was a source pride for its devotees in Gujarat and a cause of humiliation for its opponents to expose their false belief and blind-following to Somanatha taking the revenge of their continuous degrading and disgracing.<sup>(5)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The king Mahmud heard of the false propaganda and rumors by priests that the defeat of northern India at his hands was due to the anger of Somanatha with the idols and deities of northern India. They believed that if Sultan Mahmud only neared to the Somanatha with his army he will face a humiliating defeat. When he heard such myths and fairy tales, he intended to abolish such assertions.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The Sultan Mahmud began his journey from Ghazni, Afghanistan on the 10th of Sh`aban in 415 A.H., 17th October, 1024 A.D. and arrived Multan on the 15th of Ramadan, 415 A.H., 20th November 1024 A.H., then he traveled from Multan to Gujarat. In fact, this operation was necessary in order to protect his state from the plots and political intrigue of the king of Gujarat which was a center of evil activities against Sultan Mahmud. The king of Gujarat and his supporters themselves violated the sanctity of the temple because they made ​​it a place of intrigues and political plans instead of a place of worship and adoration. The Indian king fled the city when he feared of his defeat on the hand of Mahmud of Ghazni. When they managed to enter the city, some Indian people stood on the wall and shouted: &#8220;Your death brought you here, no one of you will escape safe, and the Somanatha will eliminate you all within a second.&#8221; They were fully convinced that the deity has supernatural powers and the king Mahmud would be defeated miraculously. The king Mahmud ordered his army to throw arrows on the fighters inside the temple who were more than ten thousands, fearless and courageous fighters. The fighting lasted for two days, they stood bravely in front of Mahmud, who was attacked from behind by two Indian Kings Dabashalim and Paramdev of neighboring cities with forty thousand fighters. It was a very critical condition for the king Mahmud. However, he prayed Allah (Glory be to Him) asking for help. He divided his fighters into two groups, one of them continued fighting with the warriors of Somanatha and other fought Dabashalim and Paramdev and their 40000 brave men, and thus he defeated both fronts of the fighters successfully. Most of the historical accounts agree that Sultan Mahmud broke the idol of Somanatha but did he did not harm any ordinary citizen, rather, he treated them with mercy, kindness and tolerance.<sup>(6)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Some historians mentioned that the temple was not destroyed but was raided as deduced from the memoirs of the King Kadamba the ruler of Goa, who visited the temple in 1038 A.D. Romila Thapar mentions on the authority of some historians that the temple of Somanatha was not destroyed, only the idol was broken and the temple was desecrated and was restored and renovated immediately after his mission had finished and it returned to become a place of <a title="Worship between Islam and Hinduism" href="http://www.islam-hinduism.com/en/worship-between-islam-and-hinduism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">worship</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>.<sup>(7)</sup><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Perhaps, the king Mahmud himself ordered to repair and reform the temple after the campaign was completed because it became in his rule. This also confirms that Mahmud of Ghazni did not raid the Somanatha temple for any religious zeal; he raided it only to eliminate the terrorist elements that used it as shield and fort.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">There was no animosity between Hindus and Muslims in India during the Islamic rule, the Somanatha temple was not destroyed completely; it was merely raided for the above-mentioned reasons. The whole story of demolition and destruction of the temple by the king Mahmud is fabricated and imaginary. It was fabricated by English colonists to create an atmosphere of enmity and hatred between Muslims and Hindus in order to make them believe that Muslim rulers terrorized Hindus for centuries, forcing them to convert to Islam and destroyed their temples, to instill feelings of hatred and anger towards Muslims to make them believe that the British just came to India to save them from the clutches of the Muslim rulers to consolidate their occupation. Thus, Hindus would render their thanks and appreciation for colonial rule.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Unfortunately, we find some contemporary historians rely on the literature prepared by the occupiers, without questioning its authenticity.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Anyway, we can summarize the motives that led the king Mahmud to raid the temple of Somanatha in following points:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The First:</strong> The remnants of the Indian army who entered the temple seeking refuge in the temple and used it as a fort and shield to attack the king Mahmud. It was a key reason for raiding the temple.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Second:</strong> The temple was a centre of political conspiracy of Qarmatians who were bitter enemies of Sultan Mahmud. The priests were the first who desecrated the temple when they allowed them to abuse the place of worship. This is also among the reasons that justified the attack on the temple.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Third:</strong> The Hindus of north India who did not believe in Somanatha and worshipped their own gods and idols and were belittled and disgraced by the devotees of Somanatha asked the Sultan to demolish the idol to expose their true faces.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Fourth:</strong> The king wanted to reveal to the people in a practical way that the idol can not protect himself then how can it protect others? If he could not defend himself, how would it defend others?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Fifth</strong>: The idol was hanging in the air without any visible support due to the magnetic attraction, while people believed it as sort of divine miracle. So, the King wanted to show the people the secret of this idol.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Sixth</strong>: As I have mentioned in the light of historical sources that he did not destroyed the whole temple he only removed the idol as it was enough to abolish the false belief of the people.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>The Seventh</strong>:It is also said that the peasants residing in the outskirts of Somnath complained to the King Mahmud that the priests of the temple wrong and loot their prosperity on the name of Somnath, they force them to give their daughters to serve the temple, throwing them into prostitution. They requested the King seeking his help. This led the King to chase the priests of the temple. Thus, the King was required to raid the temple. He entered and captured all its money and wealth and distributed them amongst the oppressed farmers of Somnath.(8)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">[article taken from islam-hinduism.com]
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">___________________<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(1)  Durgaprashad, <em>Tarikh Gulistan – e- Hind</em>, Queen Press, Sandhela, Hardui, India 1897, p.24.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(2)  Al-Beruni, <em>India</em>, publication of Hyderabad, Deccan 1957, p.178.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(3)  Dyanand Sarswati, <em>Sithyarth Prkash</em>, an authentic Urdu translation by Pundit Rimaldas, Arya Patr 1899, p.428-429.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(4)  Qasim Farishtah, <em>Tarikh –e- Farishtah</em>, Urdu translation by Muhammad Fida `Ali, Othmaniyah University, Hyderabad, Deccan 1926, vol.1, p.101.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(5)  Moulana Akbar Shah, <em>A&#8217;inah Haqiqat Numa</em>, Hamdard Press, India, p.192.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(6)  Ibid.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(7)  Romila Thapar, <em>Somanatha: The Many Voices of a History</em>, first published in Viking by Penguin Books, India 2004. P.78, 79.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">(8) See:http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UEjWI-RcAis. (Last accessed on 10-2-2014)<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/" data-wpel-link="internal">Why Was Somanatha Raided by Mahmud of Ghazni?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/why-was-somanatha-raided-by-mahmud-of-ghazni/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aurangzeb, Mohammed Ghaznavi, Shivaji and Tipu Sultan</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 06:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A famous Hindu writer writes some historical events without fear or favour. Temple Destructions: Among all these beliefs, we will first try to understand the truth about temple destructions. Were temples demolished to humiliate Hindu religion? Here the first case we will analyze is that of Mohammed Ghaznavi destruction of the Somnath temple. Most likely, &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/" data-wpel-link="internal">Aurangzeb, Mohammed Ghaznavi, Shivaji and Tipu Sultan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A famous Hindu writer writes some historical events without fear or favour.</p>
<p><strong>Temple Destructions</strong>:</p>
<p><span id="more-761"></span></p>
<p>Among all these beliefs, we will first try to understand the truth about temple destructions. Were temples demolished to humiliate Hindu religion? Here the first case we will analyze is that of Mohammed Ghaznavi destruction of the Somnath temple. Most likely, the name Ghaznavi came from a city called Ghazna in Afghanistan where Mohammed Ghaznavi ruled. He must have traveled a long distance to come to Somnath from Ghazna and it is quite certain that he must have passed by numerous temples on his way. The question is why did he not destroy all those temples? He must have seen the famous Buddha idols in Bamiyan but he did not touch them. So the question is- Why did he choose to demolish the Somnath temple only? When he was proceeding towards the Somnath temple, he crossed a city called Multan. Ghaznavi sent a message to the Nawab of Multan whose name was Abdul Fath Daud that he wanted his permission to pass through his city on his way to Somnath. Abdul Fath Daud however declined the permission. This led to a battle between Ghaznavi and Daud during which Multan&#8217;s &#8220;Jama Masjid&#8221; was demolished. So for those people who see Ghaznavi as the protector of Islam, they need to wonder how Ghaznavi, on his way to demolishing the Somnath temple, had no hesitation in even destroying a Masjid to achieve his goal. After Multan, there was another city named Thaneswar, whose king&#8217;s name was Anandpal. Again, Ghaznavi requested the king for permission to allow his army to cross his kingdom, which the king provided.</p>
<p>Most people are strangers to the fact that before Ghaznavi actually demolished the Somnath temple, he took into his possession the wealth worth crores of rupees. It should be clearly established here that in mediaeval times, some temples-places of worship- had enormous wealth as the devotees gave these offerings to the deity. It is said that the Somnath temple had jewels, diamonds, gold and silver worth Rs. 200 crores. Ghaznavi looted the entire wealth and proudly asserted that because Islam did not accept idol worship, he was demolishing the Hindu temple at Somnath. The question that must be raised is that if Ghaznavi was a soldier of Islam, then why did he not break other temples along the way? Another question that must be raised is that if he was really a soldier of Islam, then why was he instrumental in demolition of Masjid on the way. Mohammed Ghaznavi army had one-third Hindus as soldiers and out of twelve &#8216; siphasalars&#8217; – (generals), five were Hindus. Their names were: Tilak, Sondhi, Harjan, Rann and Hind. After winning Somnath, a Hindu king was nominated as his representative and a currency was issued on which the letters were inscribed in Sanskrit.</p>
<p>This event reminds me of the story, the elephant and six blind men. When the six blind men tried to comprehend the nature of the elephant they were made to grasp its different parts: one person touched its trunk, another its legs, a third its tail and so on. Later, all of them began to quarrel with each other regarding the actual shape of the elephant. they insisted that it resembled a big rock, a snake, a trunk of a tree etcetera. They did this because they had perceived only one part of the larger truth and hence could not grasp the entire truth. We are also like them because we do not know the full facts of history and we create an opinion on the basis of few facts, which do not represent the totality. There is another thing to remember that many kings used the name of religion to accomplish many of their deeds. Expansion of kingdoms or increasing the wealth of their kingdoms was also undertaken in the name of religion. Earlier, court poets used to write the history of kings. As they were directly dependent on kings, they had no option, but to appreciate all the actions of those kings, hence, mostly they presented their kings as noble religious souls.</p>
<p>Now we will discuss about king Harshdev of eleventh century Kashmir. There was a poet in his court whose name was Kalhan. Kalhan wrote a book entitled- Rajtarangini. In this book, he wrote that during his reign, king Harshdev created a new post, whose title was &#8220;Devotpannayak&#8221;. It means the official who uprooted the images and idols of gods and goddesses. Try to imagine that this is a Hindu king who has appointed an official who would go into temples and uproot and retrieve the idols of gods and goddesses. The fascinating part, however, is that such kings had no use of stone idols, rather they were interested in idols made of gold, silver or the ones&#8217; studded with precious stones. Similarly, once the Maratha army attacked Tipu Sultan. This attack did not produce any definitive results, nobody won or lost. The retreating Maratha army demolished the Hindu temple of Srirangapatnam, located in Tipu Sultan&#8217;s territory. Tipu Sultan however got the temple repaired. Was Maratha army not Hindu, then why did they destroy the temple? It is clear that they wanted to humiliate Tipu Sultan by showing that they could enter his kingdom and destroy its property. Why did Tipu Sultan get this temple repaired? Because he wanted to send a message to his subjects that he respected their sentiments. No king can rule without respecting the wishes of his subject and Tipu did the same.</p>
<p>If I ask you- &#8220;Who was the most terrible king in the Indian subcontinent? &#8221; you will certainly take the name of Aurangzeb. It is as true as the claim of Pakistan&#8217;s communal historians that Aurangzeb was the greatest ruler ever of the subcontinent! But what is the truth? Aurangzeb ruled this country for a long time. During his reign, whereas he demolished mandirs and masjids, he also built few mandirs and masjids. He even gave &#8221; jagirs&#8221; for their maintenance and upkeep. Once, the Nawabs of Golkunda did not give Aurangzeb his tribute for a considerable period of time. Before we go ahead, we must know something about the tribute system of that period in India. During this time, poor farmers and shudras carried out most of the production. A big share of that production used to go to the zamindar , who, in turn, used to give one portion of it to the local king and another portion to the emperor.</p>
<p>Coming back to Aurangzeb, when the Nawab of Golkunda did not give the tribute for three years, Aurangzeb sent a team of spies who found out that the Nawab had hidden his treasure beneath a mosque. Aurangzeb ordered that the mosque be dug up and the property confiscated and brought back to Delhi. So this was the &#8216;ideal&#8217; Muslim king! The same Aurangzeb gave considerable land in the area of Kashi and Vrindavan for temples. One great historian Dr. Vishwambhar Nath Pandey has mentioned many such firmans court orders in his book &#8220;The Farmans of King Aurangzeb&#8221;. Within this region, there is a Krishna mandir, which was gifted with a lot of gold jewelry by Aurangzeb. Even to the present day during Navratri celebrations, the idol of god Krishna is decked with the same gold jewelry. Dr. Pattabhi Sitaramayya in his book &#8220;Feathers and Stone&#8221; describes a very painful story. Once Aurangazeb was traveling from Delhi to Calcutta. There were many Hindu Rajas and Queens in his retinue. When the caravan reached Kashi, the queens requested that if there is an overnight stay in Kashi, they can have a holy dip in the Ganges and also pay their respects to Lord Vishwanath in the morning. Aurangzeb readily agreed to the request. The next day morning, the queens went and had a holy dip in the Ganges and then went to have Darshan of Lord Vishwanath. When the group returned, one queen,  Queen of Kutch was missing. After a long search, she was found dishonored in the temple basement, precisely under the idol of Lord Vishwanath. The Mahant of the temple had raped her. There was intense anger in the whole camp, the Mahant was punished with death sentence and since the temple had been polluted, the idol of Lord was shifted to the new temple and Aurangzeb gave all the money from his treasury to build the new temple. The well-known curator of Patna museum Dr. P.L. Gupta has corroborated this version.</p>
<p>This story also tells us that Mughal kings did not bring in too many changes in the social structure of the society. Even Hindus had a large presence in Mughal administration. We all know that out of the nine jewels of Akbar&#8217;s crown Navratna, two of them Todarmal and Birbal were Hindus. In Shahjahan&#8217;s administration, the number of Hindu kings was 24% and this number went up to 34% in the reign of King Aurangzeb. There are accounts in History where Parmar kings especially Shubhatvarman got many a Jain temples destroyed. Similarly King Shashank of Gauda got the Bodhi tree cut off. We have to understand that religion was not the major motive of king&#8217;s action. On the contrary, kings used the name of religion for their actions. Hindu kings also destroyed temples, Muslim kings destroyed temples and mosques both.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/" data-wpel-link="internal">Aurangzeb, Mohammed Ghaznavi, Shivaji and Tipu Sultan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/aurangzeb-mohammed-ghaznavi-shivaji-and-tipu-sultan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BJP’s attempt to poison the past</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 06:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; By Pawan Khera http://www.abplive.in/author/pawan_khera/2014/11/30/article447526.ece/BJP%E2%80%99s-attempt-to-poison-the-past The BJP attempted to do in Aligarh Muslim University what it is best at doing &#8211; fanning communal trouble by culling out from History selective instances to further its polarizing cause. Aligarh Muslim University Campus &#160; Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh is the latest victim of right wing opportunism. In a &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/" data-wpel-link="internal">BJP’s attempt to poison the past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By Pawan Khera</p>
<p><a href="http://www.abplive.in/author/pawan_khera/2014/11/30/article447526.ece/BJP%E2%80%99s-attempt-to-poison-the-past" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.abplive.in/author/pawan_khera/2014/11/30/article447526.ece/BJP%E2%80%99s-attempt-to-poison-the-past<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The BJP attempted to do in Aligarh Muslim University what it is best at doing &#8211; fanning communal trouble by culling out from History selective instances to further its polarizing cause.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span id="more-757"></span><br />
<img decoding="async" src="http://theindianmuslim.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/062515_0601_bjpsattempt1.jpg" alt="" /><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Aligarh Muslim University Campus<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh is the latest victim of right wing opportunism. In a clever political move, the ABVP (students&#8217; wing of the BJP) demanded to celebrate the birthday of the Jat ruler in AMU. The stated reason being that Raja Mahendra Pratap had donated land to the Aligarh Muslim University and was therefore one of the founders of the institution.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh was the maverick Jat ruler of Mursan, Aligarh. He traveled to Germany to meet Kaiser Wilhelm II. He lobbied with Germany, Turkey, Egypt and Japan to end the British rule. He then established the first provisional Government of India in Kabul. His Marxist revolutionary zeal brought him close to Lenin. He was nominated for the Nobel Peace Prize in 1932. In 1957, as an independent candidate Raja Mahendra Pratap defeated Atal Bihari Vajpayee of the Jan Sangh from the Mathura Lok Sabha seat. Vajpayee lost his deposit in this election.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">BJP&#8217;s claim that the Raja donated the land to set up the University is a white lie. The Mohammedan Anglo Oriental College (became Aligarh Muslim University in 1920) was established in 1876 – 10 years before the birth of Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh. An alumnus of the Mohammedan Anglo Oriental College, the Raja leased a 3 acre piece of land (Tikonia Park) to the AMU in 1929 – 53 years after the institution was established.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Attempts by the Sangh Pariwar to appropriate heroes are beginning to look ridiculous. Raja Mahendra Pratap is as far from the Sangh ideology as is Narendra Modi from bringing back black money allegedly stashed in foreign banks.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">If it were an innocent political move to appropriate a hero, it could still have been dismissed as the Sangh Pariwar desperately needs to borrow heroes, considering the only martyr the right wing can boast of is Nathuram Godse. In the backdrop of post-Muzaffarnagar polarization of Jats and Muslims in Western Uttar Pradesh, the demand to celebrate the birthday of Raja Mahendra Pratap in AMU is far more sinister and can deal a fatal blow to peaceful coexistence of the two communities in the region. The outcry on social media and the firm stand taken by the Vice Chancellor resulted in a climb down by BJP, which has agreed to a seminar on the contribution of Raja Mahendra Pratap Singh to mark his birthday on December 1. The issue leaves us with uncomfortable questions about the agenda of the right wing in India. It also hurls some questions for the right wing to answer.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Muslim rulers donated land for Janki Ghat temple in the disputed premises of the Babri Masjid. Hanuman Garhi was built by Muslim rulers. Will the Sangh Pariwar consider celebrating their birthdays too?<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The Nizam of Hyderabad, Mir Osman Ali Khan donated 10 Lakhs for the Banaras Hindu University and 5 Lakhs for the Aligarh Muslim University. He also donated 54 acre land to Baba Saheb Ambedkar to set up the Milind Education Society. Would the BJP consider celebrating his birthday in Banaras Hindu University?<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/" data-wpel-link="internal">BJP’s attempt to poison the past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/bjps-attempt-to-poison-the-past/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Muslim rule in India</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 05:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by M H Faruqi Courtesy: Impact International, Vol 28, July 1998, Copyright © 1998, All Rights Reserved. The noted Indian scholar and historian, Dr Bishambhar Nath Pande, ranked among the very few Indians and fewer still Hindu historians who tried to be little careful when dealing with the Muslim rule in India that lasted for &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Muslim rule in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:13pt;"><strong>by M H Faruqi<br />
</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Courtesy: <em>Impact International</em>, Vol 28, July 1998, Copyright © 1998, All Rights Reserved. </strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span id="more-751"></span></p>
<div>
<table style="border-collapse:collapse;" border="0">
<colgroup>
<col style="width:780px;" /></colgroup>
<tbody valign="top">
<tr>
<td style="padding:1px;" valign="middle"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="padding:1px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The noted Indian scholar and historian, Dr Bishambhar Nath Pande, ranked among the very few Indians and fewer still Hindu historians who tried to be little careful when dealing with the Muslim rule in India that lasted for almost 1000 years. Dr Pande passed away on 1 June 1998 and Impact International of London (July 1998) wrote the following obituary [at the end of the article], which we think sheds some light into some of the myths on Indian history, such as on <strong>Mughal Emperor Aurangzeb</strong>, created by the British with the clear objective of divide and rule:<br />
</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The Muslim rule in India lasted for almost 1000 years. How come then, asked the British historian <em>Sir Henry Elliot</em>, that Hindus &#8216;had not left any account which could enable us to gauge the traumatic impact the Muslim conquest and rule had on them&#8217;? Since there was none, Elliot went on to produce his own eight-volume History of India from its own historians (1867). His history claimed Hindus were slain for disputing with &#8216;Muhammedans&#8217;, generally prohibited from worshipping and taking out religious processions, their idols were mutilated, their temples destroyed, they were forced into conversions and marriages, and were killed and massacred by drunk Muslim tyrants. Thus Sir Henry, and scores of other Empire scholars, went on to produce a synthetic Hindu versus Muslim history of India, and their lies became history.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However, the noted Indian scholar and historian, Dr Bishambhar Nath Pande, who passed away in New Delhi on 1 June, ranked among the very few Indians and fewer still Hindu historians who tried to be a little careful when dealing with such history. He knew that this history was &#8216;originally compiled by European writers&#8217; whose main objective was to produce a history that would serve their policy of divide and rule.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>Lord Curzon</em> (Governor General of India 1895-99 and Viceroy 1899-1904, d.1925) was told by the Secretary of State for India, <em>George Francis Hamilton</em>, that they &#8216;should so plan the educational text books that the differences between community and community are further strengthened&#8217;.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Another Viceroy, <em>Lord Dufferin</em> (1884-88), was advised by the Secretary of State in London that the &#8216;division of religious feelings is greatly to our advantage&#8217;, and that he expected &#8216;some good as a result of your committee of inquiry on Indian education and on teaching material&#8217;.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8216;We have maintained our power in India by playing-off one part against the other,&#8217; the Secretary of State for India reminded yet another Viceroy, <em>Lord Elgin</em> (1862-63), &#8216;and we must continue to do so. Do all you can, therefore, to prevent all having a common feeling.&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In his famous <em>Khuda Bakhsh Annual Lecture</em> (1985) Dr Pande said: &#8216;Thus under a definite policy the Indian history books text-books were so falsified and distorted as to give an impression that the medieval [i.e. Muslim] period of Indian history was full of atrocities committed by Muslim rulers on their Hindu subjects and the Hindus had to suffer terrible indignities under Muslim rule. And there were no common factors [between Hindus and Muslims] in social, political and economic life.&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Therefore, Dr Pande was extra careful. Whenever he came across a &#8216;fact&#8217; that looked odd to him, he would try to check and verify rather than adopt it uncritically.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">He came across a history text-book taught in the Anglo-Bengali College, Allahabad which claimed that &#8216;three thousand Brahmins had committed suicide as <strong>Tipu</strong> wanted to convert them forcibly into the fold of Islam&#8217;. The author was a very famous scholar, <em>Dr Har Prashad Shastri</em>, head of the department of Sanskrit at Calcutta University. (<strong>Tipu Sultan</strong> (1750-99), who ruled over the South Indian state of Mysore (1782-99), is one of the most heroic figures in Indian history. He died on the battlefield, fighting the British.)<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Was it true? Dr Pande wrote immediately to the author and asked him for the source on which he had based this episode in his text-book. After several reminders, Dr Shastri replied that he had taken this information from the <em>Mysore Gazetteer</em>. So Dr Pande requested the Mysore University vice chancellor, Sir Brijendra Nath Seal, to verify for him Dr Shastri&#8217;s statement from the Gazetteer. Sir Brijendra referred his letter to <em>Prof Srikantia</em> who was then working on a new edition of the Gazetteer. Srikantia wrote to say that the Gazetteer mentioned no such incident and, as a historian himself, he was certain that nothing like this had taken place. <em>Prof Srikantia added that both the prime minister and the commander-in-chief of Tipu Sultan were themselves Brahmins. He also enclosed a list of 136 Hindu temples which used to receive annual grants from the Sultan&#8217;s treasury.</em><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">It transpired that Shastri had lifted this story from <em>Colonel Miles&#8217; History of Mysore</em> which Miles claimed he had taken from a Persian manuscript in the personal library of Queen Victoria. When Dr Pande checked further, he found that no such manuscript existed in Queen Victoria&#8217;s library. Yet Dr Shastri&#8217;s book was being used as a high school history text-book in seven Indian states, Assam, Bengal, Bihar, Orissa, Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan and Madhya Pradesh. So he sent his entire correspondence about the book to the vice chancellor of Calcutta University, <em>Sir Ashutosh Chaudhary</em>. Sir Ashutosh promptly ordered Shashtri&#8217;s book out of the course. Yet years later, in 1972, Dr Pande was surprised to discover the same suicide story was still being taught as &#8216;history&#8217; in junior high schools in Uttar Pradesh. The lie had found currency as a fact of history.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The <strong>Mughal Emperor Aurangzeb</strong> (born 1618, reigned 1658-1707) is the most reviled of all Muslim rulers in India. He was supposed to be a great destroyer of temples and oppressor of Hindus, and a &#8216;fundamentalist&#8217; too! As chairman of the Allahabad Municipality (1948-53), Dr Pande had to deal with <em>a land dispute between two temple priests</em>. One of them had filed in evidence some <em>farmans</em> (royal orders) to prove that Aurangzeb had, besides cash, gifted the land in question for the maintenance of his temple. Might they not be fake, Dr Pande thought, in view of Aurangzeb&#8217;s fanatically anti-Hindu image? He showed them to his friend, Sir Tej Bahadur Sapru, a distinguished lawyer as well a great scholar of Arabic and Persian. He was also a Brahmin. Sapru examined the documents and declared they were genuine farmans issued by Aurangzeb.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>For Dr Pande this was a &#8216;new image of Aurangzeb&#8217;; so he wrote to the chief priests of the various important temples, all over the country, requesting photocopies of any farman issued by Aurangzeb that they may have in their possession. The response was overwhelming; he got farmans from several principal Hindu and jain temples, even from Sikh Gurudwaras in northern India. These farmans, issued between 1659 and 1685, related to grant of jagir (large parcel of agricultural lands) to support regular maintenance of these places of worship.</em><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Dr Pande&#8217;s research showed that Aurangzeb was as solicitous of the rights and welfare of his non-Muslim subjects as he was of his Muslim subjects. Hindu plaintiffs received full justice against their Muslims respondents and, if guilty, Muslims were given punishment as necessary.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">One of the greatest charges against Aurangzeb is of the demolition of <strong>Vishwanath temple</strong> in Banaras (Varanasi). That was a fact, but Dr Pande unravelled the reason for it. &#8216;While Aurangzeb was passing near Varanasi on his way to Bengal, the Hindu Rajas in his retinue requested that if the halt was made for a day, their Ranis may go to Varanasi, have a dip in the Ganges and pay their homage to Lord Vishwanath. Aurangzeb readily agreed.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8216;Army pickets were posted on the five mile route to Varanasi. The Ranis made journey on the palkis [palanquins]. They took their dip in the Ganges and went to the Vishwanath temple to pay their homage. After offering puja [worship] all the Ranis returned except one, the Maharani of Kutch. A thorough search was made of the temple precincts but the Rani was to be found nowhere.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">&#8216;When Aurangzeb came to know of this, he was very much enraged. He sent his senior officers to search for the Rani. Ultimately they found that statue of Ganesh [the elephant-headed god which was fixed in the wall was a moveable one. When the statue was moved, they saw a flight of stairs that led to the basement. <em>To their horror they found the missing Rani dishonoured and crying deprived of all her ornaments. The basement was just beneath Lord Vishwanath&#8217;s seat.&#8217;</em><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><em>The Rajas demanded salutary action, and &#8216;Aurangzeb ordered that as the sacred precincts have been despoiled, Lord Vishwanath may be moved to some other place, the temple be razed to the ground and the Mahant [head priest] be arrested and punished&#8217;. (B N Pande, Islam and Indian Culture, Khuda Bakhsh Oriental Public Library, Patna, 1987)</em><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Dr Pande believed in the innate goodness of human nature. Despite all that senseless hate and periodical outbreak of <em>anti-Muslim violence</em> after independence, he remained an optimist. When one of the worst riots took place in 1979 in Ahmadabad, in which more than 2,000 Muslims were killed and 6,000 houses burnt, Dr Pande travelled there to see whether there was &#8216;any humanity still alive&#8217;.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Yes, it was in one locality, Mewabhai Chaal, where he found that all the houses had been burnt down. Did they all belong to Muslims? No. Only 35 belonged to Muslims; some 125 belonged to Hindus, he was told. So, it meant, the arsonists came in two different waves; one destroying the Muslim houses and the other the Hindu houses? No, it was only one wave, said Kalayan Singh. That one, there, he pointed out to smoke billowing from what used to be his house and his tyre-shop. He was a Hindu and he had lost property and business worth 200,000 rupees.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The miscreants had asked him to point out the Muslim houses so they could spare the Hindu houses. Kalyan Singh refused, and watched as the mob set fire to all the houses &#8211; including his own. How could I betray my Muslim neighbours? he asked Dr Pande rhetorically.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Dr Pande also went to the Muslim students hostel. One-third of its residents were Hindus. &#8220;Come out all you Hindu students,&#8221; yelled a murderous mob gathered outside the hostel. No, we won&#8217;t, shouted back the Hindu students and locked the gate from inside. In the event, the entire hostel was evacuated by the army and then left to the mob to loot and burn. The Hindu students were told they could take with them their books and research papers. Dr Pande met a young DSc scholar, named Desai, who had left behind his more than three years&#8217; labour, a ready-for-typing dissertation, to be burnt by the arsonists. Desai said he couldn&#8217;t think of saving his thesis while some of his Muslim friends were in similar position with their theses. A noble soul! Dr Pande who had been looking for humanity found it there as well.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">The inhumanity did not lie in the Indian nature, but the nature had fallen victim to the evil heritage of colonial history. Few realised how 1000 years of their history had been stolen from them. Many tended to buy the fake and doctored version handed down to them as part of their colonial heritage. Some even saw a little political advantage in this trade. Dr Pande heard a leading <em>Hindu Mahasabha politician and religious leader, Mahant Digvijaynath</em>, telling an election meeting that it is written in the Qur&#8217;an that killing a Hindu was an act of goodness (thawab). Dr Pande called upon the Mahant (High Priest) and told him that he had read the Qur&#8217;an a few times but didn&#8217;t find such a statement in it, and he had, therefore, brought with him several English, Urdu and Hindi translations of the Qur&#8217;an; so would he kindly point to him where exactly did the statement occur in the Qur&#8217;an?<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Isn&#8217;t it written there? said the Mahant. I haven&#8217;t found it; if you have, please tell me, replied Dr Pande. Then what does it say? It speaks about love and brotherhood, about the oneness of mankind. What&#8217;s jihad then? What is jizyah? How then India got partitioned? The Mahant went on asking, and Dr Pande kept on explaining, hoping the Mahant would correct himself. However, the Mahant&#8217;s ideas were fixed, in prejudice and in ignorance.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Dr Pande himself had been a senior member of the ruling Congress party which he had joined at a very young age. He was a disciple of Gandhi, a friend of Nehru; he had taken part in each and every non-cooperation movement against the British and gone to jail eight times. The Congress was supposed to be an all-Indian nationalist platform and yet Dr Pande&#8217;s party was hardly free from the bias and ignorance of a cleverly deconstructed history. The rise of militant Hindutva tendency is only recent, but before it all became overt, the Congress itself was doing the same, albeit a little covertly. All the horrific anti-Muslim carnage took place during more than four decades of Congress rule. The doors of the <em>Babari Mosque</em> were opened for Hindu worship during the tenure of Nehru&#8217;s grandson, Rajiv Gandhi. The Mosque itself was pulled down during the regime of another Congress Prime Minister P V Narasimha Rao.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Dr Pande was, however, just one individual. That made his work all the more important, not just from the Muslim but from the point of view of the entire country. India&#8217;s deconstructed history is like a time bomb; unless it is defused, India cannot survive in one piece. Not for very long.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Bishambhar Nath Pande</strong> born on 23 December 1906 in the Madhya Pradesh of Umreth; member UP Legislative Assembly (1952-53); member UP Legislative Council (1972-74); twice member of the upper house, Rajya Sabha (1976 and 1982); Governor of Orissa state (1983-88); recipient of the highest national award Padma Shri (1976); author of several books, including The Spirit of India and The Concise History of Congress; died in New Delhi, 1 June 1998.<br />
</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://theindianmuslim.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/062515_0556_themuslimru1.png" alt="" /><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:10pt;">Courtesy: Impact International, London, Vol 28, July 1998, Copyright © 1998, All Rights Reserved.</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/" data-wpel-link="internal">The Muslim rule in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/the-muslim-rule-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘It’s a myth that Muslim rulers destroyed thousands of temples’</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 05:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Revati Laul The next time you are stuck in a conversation on whether India was ruled by oppressive Muslim kings or not, whether Hindus were converted en masse to Islam in medieval India, just &#8216;Richard Eaton&#8217; the phenomenon and you will get your answers Richard Eaton is the Wikipedia, the Google and, many would &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/" data-wpel-link="internal">‘It’s a myth that Muslim rulers destroyed thousands of temples’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Revati Laul</p>
<p><em>The next time you are stuck in a conversation on whether India was ruled by oppressive Muslim kings or not, whether Hindus were converted en masse to Islam in medieval India, just &#8216;Richard Eaton&#8217; the phenomenon and you will get your answers<br />
</em></p>
<p><span id="more-744"></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-203407 alignright" src="http://www.tehelka.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Richard-Eaton.jpg" alt="Richard Eaton" width="250" height="362" /></p>
<p class="wp-caption-text" style="text-align:right;">
<p><a title="Posts tagged with Richard Eaton" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/richard-eaton/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="color:blue;font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;text-decoration:underline;">Richard Eaton</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"> is the Wikipedia, the Google and, many would argue, the last word on medieval and Islamic history in <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. His bibliography is too vast to list, but the vast repertoire includes <em>Islamic History As Global History</em>, <em>The Rise of Islam</em><br />
<em>and the Bengal Frontier</em>, <em>1204-1760</em> and <em>Social History of the Deccan</em>, <em>1300-1761</em>: <em>Eight Indian Lives</em>. After the destruction of the <a title="Posts tagged with Babri Masjid" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/babri-masjid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Babri Masjid</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and a myriad speculative conversations around how many temples Muslim rulers had destroyed in <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, Eaton decided to count. That became a book titled <em>Temple Desecration and Muslim States in Medieval <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></em>. In other words, he is the best myth-buster there is and that&#8217;s precisely what he did to the audiences at THiNK. Eaton explains why it&#8217;s crucial today for us to get our history right. Especially on the period he writes about.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>EDITED EXCERPTS FROM AN INTERVIEW</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>You are now working on a magnum-opus history of medieval <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, often construed as &#8216;the Muslim period&#8217;. Can you explain why the descriptor &#8216;Muslim period&#8217; doesn&#8217;t work for you?</strong><br />
The book I&#8217;m working on now is called <em>The Lion and the Lotus</em>. The lion represents Persia and the Lotus, <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. It&#8217;s the story of two intersecting megapolises — Persian and Sanskrit. The idea is to escape the trap of looking at this period as the endless and dreary chapter of Hindu-Muslim interaction, if not conflict, which is the conventional and historically wrong approach.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Can you explain why this is historically wrong?</strong><br />
Because religion is anachronistic. Contemporary evidence does not support the assumption that religion was the primary sign or indicator of cultural identity. That is a back projection from the 19th and 20th centuries, which is not justified by the evidence. For example, a word that was typically used to describe rulers who came from beyond the Khyber Pass was not &#8216;musalmaan&#8217; but rather Turushka or Turk. An ethnic, not religious, identity. What&#8217;s fascinating is that the early Turkish rulers, the Ghaznavids, began as foreigners and conquerors; over time, they were behaving more and more like Rajput dynasties. Like Mahmud of Ghazni, for instance. He took the basic credo of Islam — &#8220;There is no god but Allah&#8221; — translated that into Sanskrit and put it down on the coinage to be freely minted in north-western <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. It was an attempt to take Arabic words and structure them into Sanskrit vocabulary. This is a history of assimilation and not imposition. In Vijayanagar in the Deccan, you will find that most of the government buildings were built with arches and domes. You think you are inside a mosque but you are not. Vijayanagar had Hindu kings. This means that the aesthetic vision of <a title="Posts tagged with Iran" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/iran/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Iran</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> has seeped into <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> so much now that it&#8217;s accepted as normal.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>What about the masses in this period from 1000 to 1800 AD, who were Hindu?</strong><br />
Okay, let&#8217;s talk about ordinary people. You find that languages like Telugu, Bengali, Kannada and Marathi have absorbed a huge amount of Persian vocabulary for everyday concerns. Take another example from the Vijayanagar empire in the south. I talk about south <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> because that&#8217;s where Islam did not have as long a penetration as in the north. The Vijayanagar kings had these long audience halls described as hundred-column and thousand-column palaces — <em>hazaarsatoon</em>. A concept that goes all the way back to Persepolis where you literally do have a hundred columns. You take the floor plan of Persepolis, <a title="Posts tagged with Iran" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/iran/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Iran</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, in the 4th century BC, which is pre-Islamic, and place it side by side with the floor plan of a palace at Vijayanagar. It&#8217;s exactly the same. Neither was built by Muslims. Persepolis was built by Zoroastrians in the 3rd or 4th century BC. And Vijayanagar was built by Hindus in the 14th century AD. Neither has anything to do with religion, but both have everything to do with power. It&#8217;s like the present day spread of Coca Cola or Tuborg beer. It&#8217;s aspirational but not religious. And it all happens over a period of time.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Which is why you also don&#8217;t like the use of the word &#8216;conversions&#8217; for this period? You say conversions suggest a pancake-like flip, which is not how Islam spread. What do you mean by that?</strong><br />
I hate the use of the word &#8216;conversions&#8217;. When I was studying the <a title="Posts tagged with growth" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">growth</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> of Islam in Punjab, I came across a fascinating text on the Sial community. It traces their history from the 14th to the 19th century. If you look at the names of these people, you will find that the percentage of Arabic names increased gradually between the 14th and 19th centuries. In the early 14th century, they had no Arabic names. By the late 14th century, 5 percent had Arabic names. It&#8217;s not until the late 19th century that 100 percent had Arabic names. So, the identification with Islam is a gradual process because the name you give your child reflects your ethos and the cultural context in which you live. The same holds true when you look at the name assigned to god. In the 16th century, the words Muslims in Bengal used for god were Prabhu or Niranjan etc — Sanskrit or Bengali words. It&#8217;s not until the 19th century that the word Allah is used. In both Punjab and Bengal, the process of Islamisation is a gradual one. That&#8217;s why the word &#8216;conversion&#8217; is misleading — it connotes a sudden and complete change. All your previous identities are thrown out. That&#8217;s not how it happens. When you talk about an entire society, you are talking about a very gradual, glacial experience.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>You also examined at length the destruction of temples in this period. What did you find?</strong><br />
The temple discourse is huge in <a title="Posts tagged with India" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">India</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and this is something that needs to be historicised. We need to look at the contemporary evidence. What do the inscriptions and contemporary chronicles say? What was so striking to me when I went into that project after the destruction of the <a title="Posts tagged with Babri Masjid" href="http://www.tehelka.com/tag/babri-masjid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><span style="color:blue;text-decoration:underline;">Babri Masjid</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> was that nobody had actually looked at the contemporary evidence. People were just saying all sorts of things about thousands of temples being destroyed by medieval Muslim kings. I looked at inscriptions, chronicles and foreign observers&#8217; accounts from the 12th century up to the 18th century across South Asia to see what was destroyed and why. The big temples that were politically irrelevant were never harmed. Those that were politically relevant — patronised by an enemy king or a formerly loyal king who becomes a rebel — only those temples are wiped out. Because in the territory that is annexed to the State, all the property is considered to be under the protection of the State. The total number of temples that were destroyed across those six centuries was 80, not many thousands as is sometimes conjectured by various people. No one has contested that and I wrote that article 10 years ago.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>Even the history of Aurangzeb, you say, is badly in need of rewriting.</strong><br />
Absolutely. Let&#8217;s start with his reputation for temple destruction. The temples that he destroyed were not those associated with enemy kings, but with Rajput individuals who were formerly loyal and then become rebellious. Aurangzeb also built more temples in Bengal than any other Mughal ruler.<br />
</span></p>
<p><em>(Published in Tehelka Magazine, Volume 10 Issue 47, Dated 23 November 2013)</em></p>
<p>http://www.tehelka.com/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/?singlepage=1</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/" data-wpel-link="internal">‘It’s a myth that Muslim rulers destroyed thousands of temples’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/25/its-a-myth-that-muslim-rulers-destroyed-thousands-of-temples/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
