<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>sutra &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sutra/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 13:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 10:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cow urine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exreta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gomutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panchgavya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Srinivas Kakkilaya The cow is, at the least, an animal domesticated by man for help in agricultural activities.[1]  Although the mighty machines now used in farming have made these animals irrelevant in agriculture, valiant attempts are being made, at least in India, to preserve the exalted position of the so called ‘second mother’ &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/" data-wpel-link="internal">Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by <a title="Posts by Srinivas Kakkilaya" href="http://nirmukta.com/author/kakkilaya/" rel="author noopener external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Srinivas Kakkilaya<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The cow is, at the least, an animal domesticated by man for help in agricultural activities.[1]  Although the mighty machines now used in farming have made these animals irrelevant in agriculture, valiant attempts are being made, at least in India, to preserve the exalted position of the so called ‘second mother’ [2] or even ‘mother of the world’ [3,4].<br />
<span id="more-1761"></span><br />
<span id="more-568"></span> The stringent agitations to protect the ‘cow-mother’ [4,5] and even riots and murders of dalits for the sake of the cow,[6,7] suggest that the human life is far less important than a dead cow in this part of the world.[7] This extraordinary reverence for the cow has led to the development and marketing of many ‘products’ made from the secretions and excretions of the cow, with claims that these products may be more ‘lucrative’ than even the dairy.[8]
<strong>‘Cow Products’</strong></p>
<p id="ufgaZfF"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-7216  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604.png" alt="" width="295" height="195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604.png 417w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604-300x199.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 295px) 100vw, 295px" /></p>
<p>The list of ‘products’ developed from the milk and excreta of the cow is quite long. <em><a href="http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Panchagavya<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></em>and cow urine distillate (<em><a href="http://www.yogashram.in/June%202006.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">gau arka<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></em>) are the most quoted of these preparations.<br />
<em>Panchagavy</em> is a blend of five (<em>pancha</em>) products obtained from the cow (<em>gavya</em> = from <em>gau</em>) – the dung, urine, milk, ghee and curd.[9,10] Three preparations of cow’s urine, namely <em>gau-mutra asav</em> (fermented preparation), <em>gau-arka</em> (or distillate) and <em>Ganavati </em>(or tablet) are also used as medicines.[8,11] Two US patents have also been obtained for the <em>gau -arka</em> [11] and this fact has been highlighted over and over again.<br />
Various products from the cow have been suggested as a successful remedy against more than hundred diseases, from fever to cancer.<strong>[8,11,12] </strong><em>Panchagavya</em> is most reverentially used as a ‘body and soul cleanser’, following the birth or death of a family member. It has also been suggested as a medicine and more profusely as a pesticidal spray for plants and as a soil enriching manure.[10]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>Very recently, panchagavya has been suggested as a remedy for chikungunya as well.[13] Cow’s urine has been used in the preparations of hair oil, shampoo, skin cream etc.[8] Preparations like soap, nasal powder, body powder, body cream, incense sticks, tooth powder etc. have been prepared from the cow dung and recommended for medical use[8]. Probably to add sanctity to the entire gamut of these ‘medications’, it has been claimed that Indian pure breed cows have <a href="http://www.yogashram.in/June%202006.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">‘immunology power’<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> from 90% to 98% while the cows of mixed breed have less than 40%.[11]</blockquote>
<p><strong>The ‘evidence&#8217;:</strong><br />
Curious to know about <em>Panchagavya</em>, I asked an Ayurveda physician about its utility. She briefed me about all the virtues of the <em>gau mutra</em> (cow’s urine), <em>gau maya</em> (cow dung) and <em>Panchagavya</em>, quoting the Charaka Samhita. But how can we, living in the 21st century,  rely on an ancient text to justify the use of these excreta, I wondered. All these have been well studied by Charaka, she told me. May be, but the concept of biochemical molecules (and the modern biochemical analysers) and of microbes (and the means of isolating them) were non-existent during Charaka’s time, I countered. But the cow’s urine hasn’t changed since Charaka’s time, she averred. I was dumbstruck!<br />
Most articles on the virtues of cow’s excreta extensively quote from scriptures and the Charaka Samhita. Here are some of these arguments:</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<ul>
<li>The cow is our mother and we are her children. Therefore cow urine is beneficial.[8,11]</li>
<li>Diseases are caused by imbalance of elements bile, mucous and air and cow urine balances elements.[8]</li>
<li>Amongst urines, cow urine is best.[8]</li>
<li>Ganga resides in the cow urine and it contains copper and gold salts, which are elixirs. It does not decay, older the cow urine, the more useful it is.[8]</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Recently a lot has been written about the patents for cow urine; one obtained on the basis of laboratory studies (on culture plates and cell lines) on the usefulness of cow urine distillate in enhancing the efficacy of antibiotics and anti cancer drugs, [14,15] and the other patent obtained for cow urine therapy.[16] There are reports of the use of cow’s urine therapy from Myanmar [17] and of a cow’s urine concoction used as a traditional remedy for convulsive seizures in Nigeria.[18] There have also been reports of studies on the cow’s urine distillate in gouty arthritis, lymphocyte and polymorphonuclear cells and carbon tetrachloride poisoning, all done on experimental animals in small numbers.[19-22] These results have been extrapolated freely and wild conclusions have been drawn about the ‘magical powers’ of the cow’s urine in treating almost all the diseases afflicting mankind today.[14,17] Even the Department of Animal Husbandry of the Ministry of Agriculture, Government of India, has published reports that seek to promote the marketing of cow’s urine as a therapeutic agent.[23]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The facts:</strong></p>
<p>Faced with this blitzkrieg of marketing of cow’s urine and the real danger that cow’s urine and other products of cow’s excreta may be pushed into the throats of hapless patients, with active support from the govt., agencies., it is time we look into the facts.<br />
One need not go far to see the hypocrisy of the ‘cow urine promoters’ than have a look at the ayurveda texts themselves, extensively quoted as the primary source of support for the utility of cow’s urine as a therapeutic agent. All three major ancient texts of ayurveda, by Charaka (1<sup>st</sup>-2<sup>nd</sup> century), Susruta (3<sup>rd</sup> –4<sup>th</sup> century) and Vagbhata (7<sup>th</sup> century) mention of the therapeutic uses of beef[24,25] as well, but this fact is no where mentioned by the proponents of cow’s urine. Eating beef is a sin and drinking cow’s urine or eating its dung brings health, if these self-styled guardians of ancient Indian tradition are to be believed.</p>
<p>What about the much touted patents for cow’s urine? A patent is a set of exclusive rights granted by a state to an inventor to prevent or exclude others from making, using, selling, offering to sell or importing the invention.[26] Nothing more, nothing less. A patent in itself cannot be the proof for the utility of any product. It is hardly surprising that while International patents have been registered for cow’s urine and its products, no such patent has been obtained from the Govt. of India. An Indian patent may not make enough and weighty news, but an international patent, on the other, helps to claim that even ‘foreigners’ have accepted the virtues of cow’s urine!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p id="xfXbjMs"><img decoding="async" width="300" height="215" class="size-full wp-image-7218  alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412d2c9613.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>All the studies available in the literature about the therapeutic efficacy of cow’s excreta are small studies conducted in the labs and on animals or tissues. There are no reports of any controlled, double blind clinical studies in humans, other than some anecdotal reports and claims by the practitioners of ‘cow therapy’ and all these so called claims of research appear dubious by any scientific standards.[27] Most of these papers contradict their own claims: the claims made about the gold and copper salts in urine, for example, are not supported by the data provided by the protagonists themselves.[8,28]
<p>Urine is urine, the liquid waste that is filtered by the kidneys and excreted through the urinary system. It contains many solutes and biological products that are unnecessary for the living body and hence excreted and also some substances secreted by the urinary tract to facilitate this excretion. Chemical constituents of human and animal urine are almost alike.[28,29] For example, Urokinase is an enzyme secreted into the urine to prevent its clogging; today, it is extracted from human urine and used to dissolve clots in the coronary arteries in patients who suffer a heart attack.[30] Does this justify drinking one’s own urine in case of a heart attack? Far from it. Is cow’s urine safe for mankind? There are reports of severe adverse effects, even fatal, of drinking cow urine concoctions, further supported by experimental evidence.[31] Cow’s urine can also be a source of infectious diseases, especially leptospirosis, [32] that can spread through oral mucosa. The claim that cow’s urine and cow dung have antiseptic properties is not only baseless, but also dangerously misleading. While cow dung (and all fecal matter) is teeming with bacteria excreted from the intestines, several bacteria have been isolated from <em>Panchagavya </em>too.[33,34] Application of these bacteria-rich excreta onto wounds may lead to life threatening sepsis. Only those who are absolutely ignorant about such facts can daringly market cow’s excreta as antiseptics, but the tragedy is that some practitioners of modern medicine, blinded by their faiths in their ‘spiritual heads’ or <em>‘Mathadhipathis’</em> also appear to support such nonsense.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Conclusions:<br />
</strong><br />
It is clear that cow’s urine and other excreta are only the waste products rejected by the animal’s body and are similar to the excreta of other animals and therefore, there is absolutely no reason why the cow’s urine or other excreta should be venerable over those of humans beings or other animals.</p>
<p>The claims of the efficacy of cow’s excreta (and their products) in the treatment of almost every disease are not supported by any evidence and there are no clinical trials reported on the use of these products in human beings. With reports available about the possible adverse effects of the use of cow’s excreta, it is shocking that such products are being allowed to be not only marketed but also trumpeted, even supported by the agencies of the govt. of India, as the ‘cure-for-all’ wonder drugs.</p>
<p>Propaganda regarding the utility of cow’s excreta largely emanates from the obscurantist and Hindu fundamentalist forces and appears to be designed to condemn the ordinary human beings into ingesting cow’s excreta under the alibi of ‘treatment’ and ‘long life’. This is not surprising at all, given the several instances of the down trodden dalits forced into eating even human excreta by the same fundamentalists.[35]
<p>Eulogising the cow (and not buffalo and other cattle that are equally ‘useful’) as ‘second mother’, ‘God mother’, ‘mother of the world’ etc., largely because it provides milk,[11] (and hopefully not because of its excreta) raises a fundamental question about the concept of motherhood itself: Do we love and respect our own mothers solely because we have been breastfed and is motherhood only about milk?</p>
<p>This entire exercise of marketing the cow’s products and promising huge economic benefits (a claim not supported by any data) of keeping the cows even after they have passed the age of secreting milk  is part of the grand design to prevent the slaughtering of the cows so as to deprive the poor sections of the society from quality meat as well as some economic benefits of marketing the beef. But sustaining the livestock is proving to be very costly for the environment, with a large share of global warming attributed to the livestock.[36,37] It is time we take a rational view of all the issues involved.<br />
<strong>References:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Cattle. The Wikipedia Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Discover how cows have altered human life, human biology, and the geography of the world Availalbe at <a href="http://www.pbs.org/wnet/nature/holycow/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.pbs.org/wnet/nature/holycow/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Subhuman Das. Indian Cows: Blessed Bovines! <a href="http://hinduism.about.com/library/weekly/aa101800a.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://hinduism.about.com/library/weekly/aa101800a.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.vishwagou.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.vishwagou.org/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Cow Protection Available at <a href="http://www.vhp.org/protectthecow.php" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.vhp.org/protectthecow.php<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Taneja N. Mangalore ‘Riots’. People’s Democracy. October 22, 2006; 30(43) Available at <a href="http://pd.cpim.org/2006/1022/10222006_nalini.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://pd.cpim.org/2006/1022/10222006_nalini.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Rajalakshmi TK. Slaughter of the Dalits. Frontline November 09 – 22, 2002;19(23) Available at <a href="http://www.hinduonnet.com/fline/fl1923/stories/20021122003703800.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hinduonnet.com/fline/fl1923/stories/20021122003703800.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>
<p align="left">Cow Urine: Principles &amp; Applications Available at <a href="http://www.hkrl.com/cowurine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hkrl.com/cowurine.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
</li>
<li>Panchagavya. Available at <a href="http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Natarajan K. Panchagavya: How to Make. Available at <a href="http://www.agricultureinformation.com/forums/organic-farming/15995-panchagavya-how-make.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.agricultureinformation.com/forums/organic-farming/15995-panchagavya-how-make.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Seminar on mother cow and Panchagavya. Available at <a href="http://www.goshala.com/articles/panchagavya.php" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.goshala.com/articles/panchagavya.php<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>http://www.goshalaindia.com/scientific-propeties.html</li>
<li><a href="http://www.daijiworld.com/news/news_disp.asp?n_id=48836&amp;n_tit=Belthangady%3A+Live+Naturally%2C+Be+Free+From+Ailments+-+Raghaveswara+Bharathi" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.daijiworld.com/news/news_disp.asp?n_id=48836&amp;n_tit=Belthangady%3A+Live+Naturally%2C+Be+Free+From+Ailments+-+Raghaveswara+Bharathi<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Dhama K, Chauhan RS, Singhal L. Anti-cancer activity of cow urine: Current status and future directions. International Journal of Cow Science 2005;1(2) Available at http://indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor:ijcs&amp;volume=1&amp;issue=2&amp;article=001</li>
<li>Khanuja SPS et al. Use Of Bioactive Fraction From Cow Urine Distillate (‘Go Mutra’) As A Bio-Enhancer Of Anti-Infective, Anti-Cancer Agents And Nutrients Available at <a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/EP1330253.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.freepatentsonline.com/EP1330253.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Jain VK. Cow Urine Therapy And Herbal Medicinal Composition With Cow Urine And Method Of Manufacturing The Same World Intellectual Property Organisation, International Patent No WO/2002/096440 Available at <a href="http://www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp?IA=IN2001000136&amp;WO=2002096440&amp;DISPLAY=DESC" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp?IA=IN2001000136&amp;WO=2002096440&amp;DISPLAY=DESC<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Awale et al. An amazing cow’s urine therapy in Myanmar. J Trad Med. 2006;23:178-83 Available at <a href="http://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/jtm/23/5/178/_pdf" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/jtm/23/5/178/_pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Elegbe RA, Oyebola DD. Cow’s urine poisoning in Nigeria: cardiorespiratory effects of cow’s urine in dogs. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 1977;71(2):127-32.</li>
<li>Influence of “Divine Cow Powder” on Peripheral Tissues of Acute Gouty Arthritis Acta Universitatis Traditionis Medicalis Sinensis Pharmacologiaeque Shanghai 2007 <a href="http://www.shvoong.com/medicine-and-health/1597348-influence-divine-cow-powder-peripheral/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.shvoong.com/medicine-and-health/1597348-influence-divine-cow-powder-peripheral/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Dipanwita Dutta, S Saravana Devi, K Krishnamurthi, T Chakrabarti Anticlastogenic effect of redistilled cow’s urine distillate in human peripheral lymphocytes challenged with manganese dioxide and hexavalent chromium. Biomed Environ Sci. 2006 Dec ;19 (6):487-94 <a href="http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:17319276" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:17319276<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>K Krishnamurthi, Dipanwita Dutta, S D Sivanesan, T Chakrabarti. Protective effect of distillate and redistillate of cow’s urine in human polymorphonuclear leukocytes challenged with established genotoxic chemicals Available at <a href="http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:15602821" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:15602821<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Achliya GS, Kotagale NR, Wadodkar SG, Dorle AK. Hepatoprotective activity of panchagavya ghrita against carbontetrachloride induced hepatotoxicity in rats Indian journal of pharmacology 2003;35(5):308-311 Available at <a href="http://cat.inist.fr/?aModele=afficheN&amp;cpsidt=15240774" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://cat.inist.fr/?aModele=afficheN&amp;cpsidt=15240774<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Sunil Mansinghka Bi Products Of Cattle – Organic Manure And Cow Urine – Medicines – Draught – Gas – Electricity. Available at <a href="http://dahd.nic.in/ch5/chap5.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://dahd.nic.in/ch5/chap5.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Jha DN. Paradox of the Indian Cow: Attitudes to Beef Eating in Early India. Available at <a href="http://www.indowindow.net/sad/article.php?child=17&amp;article=11" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.indowindow.net/sad/article.php?child=17&amp;article=11<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Cathy Wong Ayurvedic Foods for Your Type: How to Eat for Your Dosha. Available at <a href="http://altmedicine.about.com/cs/2/a/ayurveda.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://altmedicine.about.com/cs/2/a/ayurveda.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Patent. Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Research paper and observation. Dr. Jain’s Cow urine Therapy. Available at http://www.cowurine.com/research-paper.html</li>
<li>The Main Elements of Cow Urine and Their Functions. Dr. Jain’s Cow urine Therapy. Available at http://www.cowurine.com/main-element-of-cow.html</li>
<li>Putnam DF. Composition And Concentrative Properties Of Human Urine. Available at <a href="http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/19710023044_1971023044.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/19710023044_1971023044.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Urokinase. Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urokinase" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urokinase<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Oyebola DD, Elegbe RA. Cow’s urine poisoning in Nigeria. Experimental observations in mice. Available at Trop Geogr Med. 1975 Jun;27(2):194-202.</li>
<li>Sharma S, Vijayachari P, Sugunan AP, Sehgal SC. Leptospiral carrier state and seroprevalence among animal population – a cross-sectional sample survey in Andaman and Nicobar Islands. Epidemiology and Infection 2003;131:985-989</li>
<li>Akinde SB, Obire O. Aerobic heterotrophic bacteria and petroleum-utilizing bacteria from cow dung and poultry manure World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology 2008;24(9):1999-2002</li>
<li>Bhat SS, Vinu AK, Naidu R. Association of Diverse Groups of Bacteria with ‘Panchagavya’ and their Effect on Growth Promotion of Coffee Seedlings. The Association for Science and Information on Coffee (ASIC): Proceedings of ASIC Conferences – 20th Colloquium : Agronomy Available at <a href="http://www.asic-cafe.org/pdf/abstract/PA224_2004.pdf" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.asic-cafe.org/pdf/abstract/PA224_2004.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Siriyavan Anand. India Shining with Hindu Diet: Cow urine and dung for caste hindus, Human shit and piss for dalits Available at <a href="http://www.chowk.com/ilogs/65586/48030" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.chowk.com/ilogs/65586/48030<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Rearing cattle produces more greenhouse gases than driving cars, UN report warns <a title="http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming" href="http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Livestock’s Long Shadow–Environmental Issues and Options <a title="http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf" href="http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/" data-wpel-link="internal">Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Hinduism?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 08:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[33 gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrisitanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[definition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism oldest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindusim vs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iskon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat rai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polytheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shankaracharya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shashtra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind? At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Written by Ibn Muhammad<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">What, in the first place, has Hinduism to say about God and His attributes, and what kind of worship does it teach mankind?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">At the very threshold, we are met with the formidable difficulty that Hinduism is not one religion but many religions jumbled together under a single name. It is a hodge-podge or conglomeration of many mutually conflicting religions, and is not the child, so to say, of any one father. Those who practice it differ very much from one another in their faith and practice. Hinduism includes in it Vedism, Brahmanism, Sivaism, Vishnuism, Polytheism, Pantheism, Idolatory in is greatest forms, Tree-Worship, Serpent-Worship, Demon-Worship and so on.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span id="more-5644"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is not easy therefore to give a definition of Hinduism,  &#8220;Hinduism and its gods,&#8221; says Sir Alfred Lyall, &#8220;are a troubled sea, without shore or visible horizon, driven to and fro by the winds of boundless credulity and grotesque invention. A tangled jungle of disorderly superstitions, ghosts and demons, demi-gods and deified saints, household gods, tribe gods, local gods, universal gods, with their countless shrines and temples, and din of their disordent rites, deities who abhor a fly&#8217;s death, those who delight still in human victims, and those who would not either sacrifice or make offerings, such religious chaos&#8221;. <strong><sup>[1]</sup></strong><br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Authoritative Books not one but many</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A further difficulty regarding Hinduism lies in the fact that all its professors have no common sacred Book or Books to depend upon for their doctrines. Some refer to Vedas as the basis of their faith. Others rest their faith on the Shrutis, a term which includes not only the four Vedas but their Brahmanas and Upanishads as well. The Mahabharata styles itself as the fifth Veda, containing the quintessense of all the rest. Other Hindus agains follow the teachings of the Puranas. The present day educated Hindus are mainly depending upon the Bhagavad Gita, a philosophical treatise, for their guidance in matters of faith. We shall therefore briefly inquire into the contents of all these books to see what they teach about God and the way in which man should worship Him.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>The Religion of the Vedas</h3>
<h4>(a) Nature Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Vedism, or the Religion of the Vedas, teaches the worship of the deified forces or phenomenon of Nature, such as Fire, the Sun, Wnd and Rain. Here is the opening verse of the Rigveda, the oldest Veda, of which the others are mere repetitions and borrowing:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निमीळे पुरोहितं यज्ञस्य देवं रत्वीजम |  होतारं रत्नधातमम || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;I Laud Agni, the great high priest, god, minister of sacrifice, the herald, lavishest of wealth.&#8221; [Rigveda Mandal 1: Sookt 1: Mantra 1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The whole of the Veda goes on in this strain throughout in the hymns collected for different purposes. The contrast between the opening  verse of the Rigveda which teaches Polytheism, and that of the Jewish Bible and of the Holy Qur&#8217;an which teach Monotheism, cannot fail to be noted even by the most superficial reader. Thus the Jewish Pentateuch begins,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>בראשית ברא אלהים את השמים ואת הארץ׃</strong><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.&#8221; [Genesis 1:1]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Holy Qur&#8217;an strikes the key note of its whole teaching in a still more profound manner, unparalleled in other religions:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 18pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"> &#8211; </span><span style="font-family: Traditional Arabic;">الْحَمْدُ للَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَـلَمِينَ &#8211; الرَّحْمَـنِ الرَّحِيمِ &#8211; مَـلِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;In the name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. All Praise is due to Allah, Lord of the Worlds, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful. Master of the Day of Judgement.&#8221;[Surah Al-Fatiha 1:1-4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Thus Vedism teaches the worship of the powers of Nature.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(b) Polytheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That it teaches polytheism is also evident from the expression used in the same verse and in all the succeeding verses as well:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निः पूर्वेभिर्र्षिभिरीड्यो नूतनैरुत | स देवानेह वक्षति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;He (Agni) shall bring hitherward the gods.&#8221; [Rigveda 1:1:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्ने यं यज्ञमध्वरं विश्वतः परिभूरसि | स इद्देवेषु गछति ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Verily goes to the gods.&#8221;[verse 4]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अग्निर्होता कविक्रतुः सत्यश्चित्रश्रवस्तमः | देवो देवेभिरा गमत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;May Agni, priest, the god, come hither with the gods.&#8221; [verse 5]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The number of gods in Hindu Pantheon is given as 33 in one place (Rigveda 1:34:11), which says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></strong></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>आ नासत्या तरिभिर एकादशैर इह देवेभिर यातम मधुपेयम अश्विना | परायुस तारिष्टं नी रपांसि मर्क्षतं सेधतं दवेषो भवतं सचाभुवा ||</strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Come, O Nasatyas, with the thrice-eleven Gods; come, O ye Asvins, to the drinking of the meath. Make long our days of life, and wipe out all our sins: ward off our enemies; be with us evermore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Similarly it is mentioned in Rigveda 8:30:2,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>इति सतुतासो असथा रिशादसो ये सथ तरयश्च तरिंशच्च | मनोर्देवा यज्ञियासः || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Thus be ye lauded, ye destroyers of the foe, ye Three-and-Thirty Deities, The Gods of man, the Holy Ones.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Rigeveda 10:52:6 the number is 3,339. It says,<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>तरीणि शता तरी सहस्राण्यग्निं तरिंशच्च देवा नवचासपर्यन | औक्षन घर्तैरस्त्र्णन बर्हिरस्मा आदिद्धोतारं नयसादयन्त || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Deities three thousand, three hundred and thirty-nine, have served and honoured Agni, Strewn sacred grass, anointed him with butter, and seated him as Priest, the Gods&#8217; Invoker.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Later Hinduism has gone still further by saying that there are no less than 33 crores of them.<br />
</span></p>
<h4>(c) Pantheism</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Why not then say that everything is God, and God is everything? The Purusha Sukta (Rigveda 10:90) which every orthodox Brahmin is expected even now to recite daily in his prayers shows that Pantheism is also taught in the later portions of the Vedas:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>पुरुष एवेदं सर्वं यद भूतं यच्च भव्यम | उताम्र्तत्वस्येशानो यदन्नेनातिरोहति || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;This Purusha(i.e. Brahma or God) is all that yet has been and all that is to be.&#8221; [verse 2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The caste system which has proved the curse of India is likewise taught in the same hymn:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>बराह्मणो.अस्य मुखमासीद बाहू राजन्यः कर्तः | ऊरूतदस्य यद वैश्यः पद्भ्यां शूद्रो अजायत || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The Brahmana was his (Purusha&#8217;s) mouth. Of both his arms was the Kshatriya made. His thighs became the Vaishya. From his feet the Sudra produced.&#8221;[verse 12]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Religion of the Upanishads</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Upanishads reject the Karma, Kanda or Salvation by means of sacrifices and other rituals taught in the four Vedas and Brahmanas, and advocate the Gnana-Kanda or the theory of Salvation by knowledge. Hence they consist of speculations about the individual souls (atma) and the Supreme soul (Param-atma), and about the relationship subsisting between them, their aim being to get rid of man&#8217;s earthly existence by absorption of the individual soul into the World Soul through correct or true knowledge. They teach that the Universe or Nature (Prakriti) is unreal or <em>Maaya</em>, that is to say, it does not really exist but it only an illusion of the mind. What really exists in the Supreme Soul or Brahman, and the individual souls are all emanations from Him and identical with Him. Only they do not know it, as Brahman has invested Himself/Itself with the <em>Maaya</em>, and they also are under the influence of the same mystic power. The individual souls can be disillusioned only by means of Correct knowledge, and as soon as this consummation is reached, they know themselves to be Brahman, and get absorbed into Him. The famous formula referring to this theory is <strong><em>&#8216;Tat tvam asi&#8217;</em></strong> </span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">तत् त्वम् असि </span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;That art thou&#8217;, whoever knows this &#8216;becomes the All&#8217;. Even the gods are not able to prevent him from becoming it. For he becomes their self. <em>[Brihadaranyak Upanishad 1:4:6]</em><br />
</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This theory is known as the Vedanta, the essence of the teaching of the Vedas, and has taken an immense hold on the minds of the people and lent a deeper colour to all subsequent literature. A Christian missionary asked a Brahmin, &#8220;Who and where is Brahman?&#8221; &#8220;He is talking to you,&#8221; was the prompt reply.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">A Vedantist once began to dilate upon the truth of his belief in the presence of a king and vehemently maintained that the whole world was <em>Mithya</em> or unreal, imaginary: whereupon an elephant was ordered to be brought quite near to him and the man fled in terror. &#8220;Why do you run away for your life? The elephant is <em>Mithya</em>&#8221; said the king. But the Vedantist proved himself equal to the occasion and without a moment&#8217;s hesistation replied that the running away too was <em>Mithya</em>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Such is the fool&#8217;s paradise in which most of the misguided Hindus live. The expression that is often heard on their lips, and which has unfortunately recently been made famous by Dr. Zakir Naik through his televised public talks:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><em>EKAM EVA ADVITIYAM</em><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">meaning &#8216;One only without a second&#8217;<br />
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It does not mean that they believe in the &#8216;Only One True God&#8217; but it is the Vedantic or Pantheistic formula which asserts that the only real existence of the World Soul and the identity of the individual souls within it, totally denying the existence of the phenomenal world.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Puranas</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The characteristic of popular Hinduism of today is the belief in Divine incarnations, idolatory and caste. Popular Hinduism believes in the doctrine of Trimurti or Hindu Trinity as Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva, in their characteristic of the Creator, Preserver and Destroyer of the Universe.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Vishnu Worship</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The distinct feature of Vishnu worship is the incarnation of God. When wickedness in the world increases Vishnu is said to take upon himself the form of an animal or man in order to be able to protect the good and to punish the bad. The principle incarnations He is said to have so far assumed are those of (1) a fish, (2) a tortoise, (3) a Boar, (4) a man-lion (5) a Dwarf, (6) a Brahmin hero called Parasu Ram, (7) a Kshatriya Prince, the hero of Ramayana, (8) a shepherd Prince Krishna and (9) a Kshatriya heretic, Buddha.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Krishna declares:<br />
</span></h4>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;On an occasion of marriage, or of enjoying a woman, or when life is in danger, or when one&#8217;s entire property is about to be taken away, or for the sake of a Brahmin, falsehood may be uttered. These five kinds of falsehood have been declared to be sinless. On these occasions falsehood would become truth and truth would become falsehood.&#8221; [Mahabharata Book 8; Karna Parva; Section 69]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Cow Worship</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is natural for Indians to set a high value upon the cow on account of its utility, but the worship the Hindus pay to it is irrational and absurd to a degree. It is considered to be the most sacred of all animals. Every part of its body is considered to be inhabited by some deity or other. Even its excreta are considered to be most sacred. Its urine is looked upon as the best of all holy waters; a sin destroying liquid which sanctifies everything it touches, while nothing purifies like cow-dung. The ashes of its dung sprinkled over a sinner are able to convert him into a saint.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Veneration of Cow in Hindu Culture</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Present day Hindu culture is pivoted solely on the cow. Its material and spiritual concepts are both engulfed in cow worship. Such an animal worship is known as zoolatry. This is a vestide of animistic cultures among whom the worship of monkeys, sheep, elephants, cows and even snakes was prevalent. Animal worship culminated in the taking of human beings for gods so that the silhouettes were stamped on the coins and painted on the flags, and upon their honour depended the glory and honour of their realms.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Among cultivators cow worship is not a strange thing. In many countries, notably, India, Iran and Egypt, it was prevalent. Among Hindus veneration of the cow is referred to in the Vedas as Puranas and in Hindu Jurisprudence and folklore. In the Vedas several verses refer to saluting and prostrating before the cow as the following sections illustrate:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Prajapati and Parameshthin are the two horns, Indra is the head, Agni the forehead, Yama the joint of the neck. King Soma is the brain, Sky is the upper jaw, Earth is the lower jaw&#8230; All worlds and all the gods are as the cow from head to foot.&#8221; [Atharvaved Kaand 9: Sookt 7]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;You are being created and have been created for salutations and prostrations. Salutations and prostration to you, O image of God, to your hair, to your hooves.&#8221; [Atharva 10:10]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Curiously enough, the Vedic Rishis likened the chanting of their mantras (hymn) to the lowing of the cows:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"><strong>अभि विप्रा अनूषत गावो वत्सं न मातरः | इन्द्रं सोमस्य पीतये || </strong><br />
</span></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;As the cows moo in the presence of their calves so do Brahmins recite their mantras while drinking the soma juice in the presence of Indra devta.&#8221; [Rigveda 9:12:2]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In old Vedic timesthe pious people picked out the grain from the cow-dung, and then ate it. They also squeezed out its water and drank it (Mahabharata). Its urine was considered a source of redemption of sins and a means of cow-dung bathed with water extracted thus. Krishna Ji revered the bull by stroking its back before mounting it. In short, in Hindu religion the cow in venerated to an extent which gods and godesses and even God Himself does not merit.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Cow-Worship and the humiliation of Man</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">It is to be noted that the sacredness of the cow as compared with the scant regard for human life has come to this that Swami Dayanand Saraswati in accordance with the Vedas, opines that the blood of thousands or hundreds of thousands of humans, may be shed to please these animals; (See his translation of Yajurveda 33:14 and Rigveda 1:121:10)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">In Vedic times, there lived an untouchable people in a village named Kikat, in todays Bihar. The used to rear cattle. Obviously to the Aryans this was a crime. So they invoked their god Indra to wage war against them and loot their cows.<br />
</span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"></span></p>
<p id="VJgEpTj"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="620" height="145" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7245 " src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9.png 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2417b2d28b9-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"> </span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;O Indra, what do the cows make for you among the Kikatas. They neither yield milk for your offerings, nor do they warm the vessel of libation. Bring to us these cows, bring to us also the wealth of Pramagand (their King). O Brave one, grant us the possessions of the people of low status.&#8221; [Rigveda 3:53:14]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">On the basis of this clear prnouncement, non-Aryans and untouchables have no right to keep cows. Aryans and Brahmins whenever they wish can kill them and appropriate their possessions. Hindu culture thus becomes the culture of the progress, civilization and welfare of the Aryan people alone.<br />
</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Status of the Cow</h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The fact remains that Hindu culture is based on the cow. Actually it is cow-worship as may be inferred from the discussion so far. As the Noble Qur&#8217;an states,<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;And their hearts absorbed (the worship of) the calf because of their disbelief.&#8221; [Surah Baqarah 2:93]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The cow is also called mother and this is a relic of the age of ignorance. In primitive times when the mother of a young child died, the child too would die of malnutrition after two or three days. The father did not know how to save the child&#8217;s life as a substitute for the mother&#8217;s milk was not known. By chance, some wise person thought of the idea of giving goat&#8217;s milk to the child. As the goat was easier to control and milk than the cow, goat&#8217;s milk was used to save the infant&#8217;s life. Later on the cow was tamed for this purpose. From then on the polytheists began to call the cow &#8216;mata&#8217; i.e. mother. But other animals as well, such as goats, sheep, camels, supply milk as substitute for mother&#8217;s milk; yet they are never called &#8216;mother&#8217;. Strangely enough, in this age of science when so many baby-foods have been invented, none of these is called &#8216;mother&#8217;, yet wealthy and educated Hindus still apply this epithet to the cow alone.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The nation which cannot differentiate between a cow&#8217;s tail and a man&#8217;s head, lives in an extreme abyss of culture. The cow is at the utmost an animal, while even the most degraded man, being still a human being, is yet far superior to a cow.<br />
</span></p>
<h3>Religion of the Gita</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Since Mahabharata fails to serve as a handy and useful book of the essence of Hinduism, the present day educated Hindus are adopting the Bhagvat Gita as their guide.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">Like all the other scriptures this famous poem too fails to teach True Religion to mankind. It is a highly Philosophic poem just as ill-suited to teach Religion as Berkley&#8217;s <em>Principle of Human Knowledge </em>or Milton&#8217;s <em>Paradise Lost</em> can be. The principle of its composition is Eclecticism and tries to combine Sankhya, Yoga, and Vedanta teaching into one whole to support the Vaishnava theory of Krishna&#8217;s deification.But is does promote ideas like Polytheism and Caste. Krishna claims to be the author of the caste system in India:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;The four Castes were created by me according to the appointment of qualities and works.&#8221; [Gita 4:13]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The Gita does not insist on the worship of the One and Only True God but promotes belief in polytheism:<br />
</span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Those who worship gods go to the gods&#8221; [9:25]
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">&#8220;Worship the gods thereby; The gods shall yield thee grace.&#8221; [3:3]
</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">That there are inconsistencies in the Bhagvad Gita is admitted today even by Hindu scholars. For example at Chapter 9, stanza 29 Krishna declares that &#8216;none is hateful to me, none dear.&#8217; And yet the remarkable verses at the close of Chapter 12 contradict it, &#8216;Linked by no ties to earth, steadfast in Me, That man I love&#8217;. At Gita Chapter 5, stanza 15 it is said, that &#8216;the Lord receives the sin and merit of none.&#8217; Yet at Chapter 5, stanza 29, and again at Chapter 9, stanza 24, Krishna calls himself &#8216;the Lord and enjoyer&#8217; of all sacrifices and penances. How, it may well be asked, can the Supreme Being &#8216;enjoy&#8217; that which he does not even &#8216;receive&#8217;?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">The doctrine of transmigration is the basis from which the argument of Bhagvad Gita takes its start. Matter and spirit are without beginning (13:20). God (Krishna-Vishnu) is eternal, almighty, unborn, without beginning, the great Lord of the World (10:3). He is different not only from the fleeting world, but also from the changeless and indestructible energy of all beings. Vishnu is born from age to age (4:6-8). Krishna-Vishnu is wholly distinct from Brahma and Brahman is distinctly a lower deity than Krishna (11:15,37). In 12:1-7, the two classes, those who believe in a personal God Krishna-Vishnu, i.e. theists, and those who believe in Brahma ,i.e. pantheists are contrasted, and preference is given to former. In other words, final bliss is difficult of attainment for those who follow the Vedas and seek the heaven of Brahma. All external observances and duties prescribed by the Vedas are held to be mischievous and thrown overboard (7:20; 18:34,66). The Vedas and the works enjoined by them cannot win one the vision of the Divine (11:48,53). What a contempt is expressed for the Vedas in the following words: &#8220;Steady understanding does not belong to those, whose minds are drawn by that flowery talk (i.e. Vedas) which is full of ordinances of specific acts for the attainment of pleasures and power, and which promises birth as the fruit of acts- that flowery talk which those unwise ones utter, who are enamoure of Vedic words, who say there is nothing else, who are full of desires, an whose goal is heaven. The Vedas merely relate to the effects of the three qualities; do you, O Arjuna! rise above those effects of the three qualities.&#8221; (2:42-45). Thus the Vedas are being spoken of in very disparaging terms and the followers of Krishna were inimical to the Vedas.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;">This was in brief about Hinduism and in our future articles all the topics discussed here would be dealt with in detail separately.<br />
</span></p>
<p><img alt="" /></p>
<h5>REFERENCES</h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: 12pt;"><strong>[1] </strong><em>Asiatic Studies</em>, Vol 1, pp 2, 3<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
