<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>prophet muhammad &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/prophet-muhammad/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 14:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aravsthan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bow down]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circumambulate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajre aswad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idol worship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idolater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lingam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makkeshwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims worship the kaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[namaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shave head beard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shivling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sulaiman razvi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ujjain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vikramaditya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi [This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time] The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Written by Sulaiman Razvi<br />
</span></p>
[This article is incomplete, This article will be scrutinized, inshallah I will do it as soon as I get time]
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">The Holy Kaba was built by Prophet Adam A.S and was rebuilt Ibrahim A.S. It is known as Baith Allah or the House of Allah. The Kaaba is a direction for prayer. However some Islamophobes especially some Hindus allege that Muslims worship the Kaaba or the Black Stone and they accuse Muslims of being idolaters. First of all they have to know what exactly is Idol worship, only then they should accuse Muslims of Idolatry. Idol worship is a veneration or worship of the Idol of any God. Islam is known for its staunch monotheistic stand. Islam prohibits Idol worship, It is mentioned in the Qur&#8217;an,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span id="more-161"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">22:30 &#8221;…so shun the abomination of idols, and shun the word that is false.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">14:35 Remember Abraham said: &#8220;O my Lord! make this city one of peace and security: and <span style="text-decoration:underline;">preserve me and my sons from worshipping idols</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">5:90 O ye who believe! Intoxicants and gambling, <span style="color:red;">(dedication of) stones</span>, and (divination by) arrows, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">are an abomination― of Satan&#8217;s handiwork</span>: eschew such (abomination), that ye may prosper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Hadith,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Abu Dawood (Kitab Al-Aqdiyah) [24:3592] Narrated Khuraym Ibn Fatik: The Apostle of Allah (peace be upon him) offered the morning prayer. When he finished it, he stood up and said three times: False witness has been made equivalent to attributing a partner to Allah. He then recited: &#8220;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">So avoid the abomination of idols</span> and avoid speaking falsehood as people pure of faith to Allah, not associating anything with Him.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba or Black Stone to be God. Kaaba is a direction,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…when a person making supplication (du&#8217;a) faces the sky–just as those performing the prayer (Salat) face the Ka&#8217;bah, since the sky is the qiblah of those who supplicate, as the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Ka&#8217;bah is the qiblah of those who perform the prayer</span>…&#8221;-(Sahih Muslim bi Sharh al-Nawawi. 18 vols. Cairo 1349/1930. Reprint (18 vols. in 9). Beirut: Dar al-Fikr, 1401/1981, 5.24)<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8216;<span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8216;Allah&#8217;s direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah</span>. (And if thou shouldst follow their desires) their religion and direction of prayer (after the knowledge which hath come unto thee) that the Religion of Allah is Islam and His direction of prayer is the Ka&#8217;bah&#8221;– Tanwir al Miqbas min Tafsir ibn Abbas 2:120<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">People used to stand on the Kaaba and give Azaan. Kaaba has been rebuilt several times, it was brought down by the Sahabas. Can any Hindu even think of destroying idol of their god? Ibn Az Zubayr brought Kaaba down to rebuild it and later it was again brought down and rebuilt by Ibn Hajjaj,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;he (Ibn Az Zubayr) decided to bring the Ka`bah down. The people hesitated to bring it down, fearing that the first person to climb on the House would be struck down. A man went on top of the House and threw some stones down, and when the people saw that no harm touched him, they started doing the same. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">They brought the House down to ground level</span>…`Abdul-Malik wrote back, `We do not agree with Ibn Az-Zubayr&#8217;s actions. As, for the Ka`bah&#8217;s height, leave it as it is. As for what he added from the Hijr, bring it down, and build the House as it was before and close the door.&#8217; <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Therefore, Al-Hajjaj brought down the House and rebuilt it as it was</span>.&#8221;- Tafsir Ibn Kathir [<a href="http://www.qtafsir.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=303&amp;Itemid=36" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Source<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Idolaters won&#8217;t stand on their idols nor they will destroy their Idols. How can such claims be made that Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone when Quran and Hadiths clearly prohibit any form of Idol worship? Hazrat Umar R.A said,<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…No doubt, I know that you are a <strong>stone</strong> and can neither benefit anyone nor harm anyone. Had I not seen Allah&#8217;s Apostle kissing you I would not have kissed you.&#8221; Sahih Bukhari, Kitab al Hajj 26, Hadith no 667.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be God. Muslims do not worship the Kaaba. When some Hindus are told these facts they say,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:#c00000;font-size:12pt;">&#8221;They too, whom you call Idol worshippers, do not regard the image as God. They profess to worship God behind the Idol/image&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">How true it is, let&#8217;s analyse. Hindu scriptures clearly states that &#8216;You should establish an Idol of God and worship it for the Idol is God himself&#8217;. Whatever we or the Islamophobes says carries no weight unless it is backed by some evidence, let&#8217;s have a look at what Hindu scripture have to say about it because if they are accusing us of Idolatry then our way of worship must be similar with idol worshippers.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Garuda Purana 12.17 Then the son should place upon the <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">bed a golden image, and having worshiped it</span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.24.19 O sinless one! <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Establish my image in this city and worship it</span><br />
</span>three times, morning, mid-day and evening carefully and with devotion<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 3.13.49 These Saktis, capable of bestowing all the desires, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">will be worshipped in Pratimas(images of clay, etc.)</span> in the whole of India.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Vishnudharmottara Purana, Kanda 3, Adhyay 93, 2 in the former three ages, Krta, Treta, and Dvapara men were able to see a god directly but in the Kali age ment have lost that faculty; <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">therefore they have to worship them (the gods) in an image</span>.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Devi Bhagavatam 11.23.21-33 … one is to worship one&#8217;s own Deity <span style="color:red;"><strong>in front</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">of fire or the </span><strong>image of any god</strong></span>…<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">This shows that the Idol must be in front of the worshipper.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">BhrGhSuPari Grihasutra 2.14.2 <span style="color:red;">Having prepared the image of the god and worshipping it </span>with the unbroken rice and flowers as available&#8230;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;It (clay) should be washed well and pasted with scented poweder and milk. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The idol should be made</span> with the hands on a raises platform. All the limbs, joints, etc. should be perfectly shaped with the respective weapons of the deity concerned. It should be seated on Padmasana (lotus pose) <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">and worshipped respectfully</span>&#8221;.-Shiva Purana 1.1.16.6-7, Tr. J.L. Shastri<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;O my child, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">one should worship the beautiful and universally auspicious idol (of Devi) </span>which is the destroyer of great demons placing it on a car (chatior)&#8221;.-Devi Purana 30.6cd-7ab, Tr. R.S. Bhattacharya<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Harivamsa Purana, Vishnu Parva 2.74.52 Those who <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">make my idol with stones taken from you and worship [it]</span> daily with devotion shall eventually attain my path.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">These verses clearly commands Hindus to worship the Idol of their god, but Quran nor any Hadith tells us to worship the Kaaba. Hindu texts and Scholars say that Idol is God himself. Pratima means Idol, image, picture of god but Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKON translates Pratima as Deity Form or Deity because he considers the Idol to be another form or incarnation of God. This fact is enough to prove that Muslims do not worship the Kaaba as Quran, Hadiths nor Muslims says Kaaba is Allah (S.W.T). Let me quote few verses from Hindu scriptures and passages written by Hindu scholars on this issue,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;…think of the name as Brahman, and meditate upon it, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">just as people worship the idol, thinking it to be Vishnu Himself</span>.- Chandogya Upanishad Commentary by Shankarcharya on 12.1.4 ,The Upanishads and Sri Sankara&#8217;s Commentary, Volumes 4-5, p.200.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">It is mentioned in Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagavad Purana),<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">dravyaiḥ prasiddhair mad-yāgaḥ <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>diṣv amāyinaḥ bhaktasya ca yathā-labdhair hṛdi bhāvena caiva hi<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11.27.15 <span style="color:red;">One should worship Me in My Deity forms [Pratima/Idol]</span> by offering the most excellent paraphernalia. But a devotee completely freed from material desire may worship Me with whatever he is able to obtain…</span><span style="font-size:14pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">śailī dāru-mayī lauhī lepyā lekhyā ca saikatī mano-mayī maṇi-mayī <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">pratimā</span>ṣṭa-vidhā smṛtā<br />
</span></p>
<p><a href="http://vedabase.com/en/sb/11/27/12" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagavat Purana</span><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><span style="font-size:12pt;"> (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.12 <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The Deity form[Idol] of the Lord is said to appear in eight varieties</span> — stone, wood, metal, earth, paint, sand, the mind or jewels.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: Śrīla Jīva Gosvāmī explains that certain Deity forms, such as those made of sand, are manifested for a brief time to fulfill a personal desire of the worshiper. Those, however, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">who desire to attain pure love of God should worship the permanent form of the Deity (made, for instance, of marble, gold or brass)</span>, and they should maintain continual worship. In Kṛṣṇa consciousness there is no scope for neglecting the worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Bhagwat Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 11.27.48 <span style="color:red;">Whenever one develops faith in Me in <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>My form [Idol] as the Deity</strong></span> or in other bona fide manifestations one should <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>worship Me in that form</strong></span></span>. I certainly exist both within all created beings and also separately in My original form, since I am the Supreme Soul of all.<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>Swami Prabhupada states</strong>: The Supreme Personality of Godhead is worshiped according to the faith of a particular worshiper. The Deity form, arcā, is specifically mentioned here because Deity worship is essential for spiritual progress. <span style="color:red;">Śrīla Bhaktisiddhānta Sarasvatī Ṭhākura mentions that inexperienced persons may think that the Deity [Idol] is meant for the sense gratification of the worshiper, since superficially the Deity [Idol] is made of external substances such as marble or brass</span>. But through the process of installing the Deity by <span style="color:red;"><strong>chanting of authorized mantras, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">one invites the Supreme Personality of Godhead to enter the Deity form [Idol]</span>.</strong></span> By regulated, faithful worship one gradually <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>understands that the Deity [Idol] is completely nondifferent from the Supreme Lord Himself</strong></span>…<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;"><br />
</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;But, greater is the difficulty of those whose minds cling to the Unmanifested; for the goal of the Unmanifested is hard for the embodied being to reach.&#8221; Gita 12:5<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse &#8221;Therefore, the bhakti-yogi accepts the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity of Krishna as worshipable</span> because there is some bodily conception fixed in the mind, which can thus be applied. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">Of course, worship of the Supreme Personality of Godhead in His form within the temple is not idol worship</span>. There is evidence in the Vedic literature that worship may be saguna and nirguna—of the Supreme possessing or not possessing attributes. Worship of the Deity in the temple is saguna worship, <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">for the Lord is represented by material qualities</span>. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But the form of the Lord, though represented by material qualities such as <span style="color:red;">stone, wood or oil paint, is not actually material. That is the absolute nature of the Supreme Lord</span></span>…God has an authorized <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">representation in the Deity form [Idol]</span>, which is called arca-vigraha. This arca-vigraha is an incarnation of the Supreme Lord&#8221;.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Swami Prabhupada on Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagavatam) 4.30.27:<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"><span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">The form of the Lord as worshiped in the temples is called arca-vigraha or arcavatara, the worshipable form [Idol Worship],</span><br />
<span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">the Deity incarnation</span>. This facility is offered to neophyte devotees so that they can see the real form of the Lord face to face and offer their respectful obeisances and sacrifices in the form of arca. Through such facilities the neophytes gradually invoke their original Krsna consciousness. <span style="color:red;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Deity worship in the form of temple worship is the most valuable benediction </span><strong>given by the Lord to beginners</strong></span>. All neophytes must therefore engage in the worship of the Lord by keeping the arca-vigraha (arcavatara)[Idol] at home or in the temple.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another Hindu scholar named Swami Sivananda writes,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;<span style="color:red;">Though the image is worshipped</span>, <span style="color:red;">the devotee feels the presence of the Lord <span style="text-decoration:underline;">in it</span></span> and pours out his devotion unto it.…<span style="color:red;">When you worship an image</span>, you do not say: &#8220;This image has come from Jaipur. It was brought by Prabhu Singh. Its weight is 50 lbs. It is made of white marble. It has cost me Rs. 500/-.&#8221; <span style="color:red;"><strong>You superimpose all the attributes of the Lord on the image and pray</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">: &#8220;</span><strong>O</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Antaryamin (Inner Ruler)! </span><strong>You are</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> all-pervading. You are omnipotent, omniscient, all-merciful. You are the source for everything. You are self-existent. You are Sat-Chit-Ananda. </span><strong>You</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"> are eternal, unchanging. You are the Life of my life, Soul of my soul! Give me light and knowledge! Let me dwell in Thee for ever.&#8221;</span></span> When your devotion and meditation become intense and deep, you do not see the stone image. You behold the Lord only who is Chaitanya. <span style="color:red;">Image-worship is very necessary for beginners</span>…For a beginner, Pratima is an absolute necessity. <span style="color:red;"><strong>By worshipping an idol</strong>, Isvara is pleased</span>…<span style="color:red;">Even so, the Lord is highly pleased when a small portion of His Virat (cosmic) body is worshipped. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">An idol is a part of the body of the Lord</span></span>. The whole world is His body, Virat form. The devotion goes to the Lord<span style="color:red;">. The worshipper superimposes on the image the Lord and all His attributes</span>. He does Shodasopachara for the idol, the sixteen kinds of paying respects or service to the Lord…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The idol speaks. It will answer your questions and solve your problems</strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">. The God in you has the power to awaken the latent </span><strong>Divinity in the idol</strong></span>…<span style="color:red;"><strong>The awakened Divinity in the idol</strong></span><br />
<span style="color:red;">acts as a guardian angel blessing all, conferring the highest good on those who bow to it…</span><br />
<span style="color:red;">The image in the temple at Tirupati assumed human form and gave witness in the court to help His devotees</span>.- All About Hinduism, By Sri Swami Sivananda, p.70-4<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;To the worshipper <span style="text-decoration:underline;">who believes the symbol, any kind of image is the body of the Lord under the form of stone, clay, brass, picture, Saligrama, etc. Such worship can never be idolatry</span>. <span style="color:red;">All matter is a manifestation of God. God is present in everything which exists</span>. Everything is an object of worship, for all is a manifestation of God who is therein worshipped.&#8221; – All About Hinduism, By Swami Sivananda, p.72<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Muslims do not believe the Kaaba to be Allah nor do we adore the Kaaba as the Hindus does to their Idols thinking it to be god himself,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;"> Bhagavat Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam) 11:30:7 There we should bathe for purification, fast, and fix our minds in meditation. <span style="color:red;text-decoration:underline;">We should then worship the demigods by bathing their images</span>, anointing them with sandalwood pulp, and presenting them various offerings<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">So it is evident from all these verses that the Idolaters indeed think their Idols to be God. Another bogus claim made by some Hindus is that Kaaba was actually a Hindu temple and the Black Stone is actually Shiva Lingam. There is nothing to refute as there is no evidence which proves their point. There is absolutely no evidence at all. This hoax was started by a self-proclaimed historian (popularly known as Mythistorian by experts) who believed that all religious monuments and religions are corrupted form of Hinduism and that Christianity is altered version of Kishna Neti and Islam is the altered version of the Sanskrit word Ishalayam. He gave fake reference from an imaginary book created by him. Surprisingly Hindus believes this book exis and even quote, well, Islam is such a beautiful religion that anyone would like to link their religion with it. The Mythistorian&#8217;s work is full of mistakes and does not contain a single fact. He was ignorant of history. He made such poor remarks on other religions, for example he claimed that the Muslim&#8217;s Namaz is originally a Sanskrit word called Namah. I wonder whether he did some research or just wrote his frustrations. The Arabic word for prayer is Salah. Namaz is an Urdu word originated from Farsi, the word Namaz is used by Muslims of Indian subcontinent for prayer. He and his claims have been refuted by Imran Khan in his Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba Is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. Readers can go through the blog and see the idiotic claims made by Hindu nationalist. Shri Shri Ravi Shankar had also made such claims but later in a debate with Dr. Zakir Naik he honestly acknowledged that his claims are incorrect. There is no evidence at all that could suggest the Kaaba was a Hindu temple. There is also no preserved history which could suggest that Hindus lived in Makka or went there. Even a Muslim can make such claims. For example,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">&#8221;Hindu God Ram was a normal Muslim, his name is altered version of the Arabic word Akram. His brother Luxman was also a Muslim his original name was Luqman, and his close disciple was Humam Bajar Ali which was changed to Hanuman Bajrang Bali. The Hindu God Krishna was also a Muslim his real name was Karim Shah. Shiva was also a Muslim his original name was Shuaa&#8221;. </span></p>
<p>So does it make them Muslims?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Another bogus claim made by Hindus is that the Black Stone is Shiva Lingam. How can this be so when both these have different meanings and their own origin. The meaning and origin of Shiva Lingam is discussed briefly in the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">An Analysis of Lingam</a>. As far as Black Stone is concerned. The Arabic word is Hajre Aswad. Hajr means stone, Aswad means black. While Lingam means make erected organ and Yoni denotes female genital organ. According to the tradition, the Hajre Aswad (Black Stone) was white and was sent from heaven,<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Sunan Al Tirmizi Sayyidina Book of Hajj 9, Hadith 878 &#8221;Ibn Abbas narrated that Allah&#8217;s Messenger (SAW) said, &#8220;The <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Black Stone was sent down from Paradise</span> and it was more <span style="text-decoration:underline;">white than milk</span>, but the sins of the children of Adam turned it black.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt;">Hindus try to link Yoni (Literally female genital which is the base of Shivling) with the silver frame of Hajre Aswad. They are not aware of the fact that the silver frame was not present during the time of Prophet Muhammad (P.B.U.H). When the Black Stone was broken into pieces during a war, Its fragments were cemented into a silver frame by Abd Allah Ibn Zubayr. The Black Stone is from Heaven (Tirmizi 878) whereas Yoni (Female genital or Shivling&#8217;s base) worship was initiated after the curse. There are two stories concerning its origin. First one is when the Sage Bhrigu was dishonoured by Shiva as Shiva was busy with his wife Parvati so Bhrigu cursed him to be worshipped in Linga and Yoni form which he desired the most, another story is that Shiva was cursed by the sages to be worshipped in Penis form for seducing their wives, Shiva&#8217;s male organ fell down to earth and burned everything, Shiva told Brahma and Vishnu that it will become calm only when Parvati takes hold of it in Yoni (female genital) form. For more information, read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/analysis-of-lingam/" data-wpel-link="internal">Analysis of Lingam</a>. So how can some people claim Black Stone is Hindu Idol when both these have their own origin and definition? Some Hindu brothers are easily deceived by Islamophobes. One should not blindly follow what the person is saying. It is incorrect to liken Shivling with Black Stone because ShivLingam is risen out from the Vulva shaped base known as Yoni whereas Black Stone is not and Shiva Lingam is not cemented into the walls of temple like the Black Stone. There is no evidence of Lingam worship in Arabia nor there is a mention of such Idol. I request the readers to read the Blog <a href="http://kaabaisnotahindutemple.blogspot.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Kaba is Not a Hindu Temple<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> as I don&#8217;t want to add any repetitive refutations.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size:13pt;text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></span><span style="font-size:12pt;"><strong>:-</strong> It is inappropriate to say that Muslims worship the Kaba or Black stone since Idol worship means worshipping the Idol thinking it to be God himself. Kaba is only a direction for worship. Quran nor the Hadith tell us to worship the Kaaba, Islam strictly prohibits idol worship.<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/" data-wpel-link="internal">Do Muslims worship the Kaaba or Black Stone?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/23/do-muslims-worship-the-kaaba-or-black-stone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Killing Infidels in Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 05:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[answering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aryavarta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beheading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahmadvish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital punishment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayananad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disbelievers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposing Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extremism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinduism exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innocent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ISIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jihad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kafir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kikata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murdering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non believers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plunder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puranas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaughtering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthabouthinduism.wordpress.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truthofhinduism.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ved nindak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war booty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Also read new article Killing Infidels in Hinduism Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-7331" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg" alt="" width="517" height="384" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-300x223.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1024x760.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-768x570.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-1536x1141.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/05/tolerance-towards-non-Hindus-other-religions-Scriptures-2048x1521.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /></p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Also read new article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Hinduism</a></p>
<p>Some fanatic Hindus who are unaware of the violent passages in their book often mock other religious texts by misinterpreting them. They have no idea how violent Vedas are. Vedas are terror manual which turns humans into savages. Many tribes were destroyed as a result of the violent passages in Vedas. As per Vedas, you must kill a person who rejects Vedas, who hates Vedas and Ishwar, who does not worship, who does not make offerings to ishwar, who insults god (Blasphemy), one who oppresses a Brahmin etc. There are several passages in Vedas which calls for death of disbelievers. I am mostly using Arya Samaji translations of Satya Prakash Saraswati, Satyakam Vidyalankar, Devi Chand, Vaidyanath Shastri, Kshemkarand Das Trivedi, Swami Dayanand Saraswati, Shripad Damodar Satvalekar, and orthodox translations of Swami Karpatri and Shri Ram Sharma Acharya (Gayatri Parivar) and I will be using Griffith’s translation as well followed by Hindi translation of Hindu scholars. In the Vedas you will find numerous words to denote non-Hindus such as Adeva, Adevayu which means Godless, anindra which means against Indra, Ayajyu, Ayajvan which means unsacrifcing, Abrahman, Anyavrata which means followers of other gods, apavrata, avrata which means riteless, devanid which means haters of gods, Brahmadvish which means haters of devotion and those who denounce Vedas.</p>
<p><span id="more-746"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.13.9 “May you (O love divine), the beholder of the path of enlightenment, purifying our mind and destroying the infidels who refuse to offer worship, come and stay in the prime position of the eternal sacrifice.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.6.3 “May the fire divine chase away those infidels, who do not perform worship and who are uncivil in speech. They are niggards, unbelievers, say no tribute to fire divine and offer no homage. The fire divine turns those godless people far away who institute no sacred ceremonies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.63.5 ”Augmenting the strength of resplendent self, urging the waters and rejuvenating all noble acts and destroying the infidels.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p><strong>One who does not offer Sacrifice is inhuman</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.70.11 “May your friend, the cloud, hurl that infidel down from heaven who differs from us in rites and rituals, is inhuman, who does not observe fire sacrificials, and who does not show reverence to Nature’s bounties.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.97.9 “O Lord of knowledge, this laudation is for you…destroy the godless and the malice of our enemy.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Killing Avrata,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.73.8 &#8220;&#8230;he, the all-wise, looks over all worlds; he censures those who are hostile in action, and who do not offer sacrifices and render no public good.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.84. 8 When will he trample, like a weed, the man [Infidel] who hath no gift for him…</p>
<p>Yaska writes,</p>
<p>Nirukta 5.17 When, with his foot, will he trample the unworshipping man like a mushroom</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.64.1-2 “May our hymns please you; O lord of resolute will power, please display your bounty. May you drive off the infidels. May you crush with your foot the niggard churls who offer no homage. You are powerful; there is none so powerful as you are.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.2.10 “May you roaring flames, O adorable Lord, be manifest in the sky as sharp weapons, to destroy infidels. In his exhilaration may his shining splendour inflict destruction. The godless hands try to bind him from all sides but do not succeed.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.79.10 “The powerful flowing elixir…It is the conferer of wealth, the king of vigour; It crushes malignities and harasses the enemies.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.76.11 “Both the heaven and earth shudder when you, O the resplendent Lord, uttering your fearful roar, crush down the infidel.” Tr. Satya Prakash Sarawati</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.21.3 ‘Let this war drum made of wood, muffled with leather straps, dear to all the persons of human race and bedewed with ghee, speak terror to our foemen.”Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="464" height="205" class="wp-image-7290" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi1.png?w=464" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.png 464w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x133.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.19.6 ‘May you bring near to us those who stand aloof; may you strike terror into our foes; o pure flowing elixir, please transfer their riches to us.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati and Satyakam Vidyalankar</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 17.33 “He is an ideal commander of the army, who is swift, keeps his arms sharpened, fearless like a strong bull, a zealous killer of foes, strikes terror in men…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 4.31.7 “Let the King [Varuna] and Manyu, the warm emotion give us the wealth of both kinds-earned and gathered. Let our enemies overwhelmed with terror in their mind and spirit and defeated in their design run away.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p>Yaska Acharya also writes about terror,</p>
<p>Nirukta 10.21 …These are hemistichs. Like a spear hurled, it inspires terror (among enemies) or courage (among friends)…</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.36 “We learned persons accept as our ruler, thee, the introducer of new plans for our advancement, the master of loyal subjects, the embodiment of virtue, the most advanced in noble qualities and acts, the queller of the irreligious…” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 7.44 “…This fourth warrior, full of delight, should subdue the irreligious foes.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 13.12 “O king, make progress in thy duty of administration, extend happiness to the virtuous. O terrible chastiser, burn down the irreligious foes. O splendid person, humiliate and consume utterly like dried up stubble, him, who encourages our foe.” Tr. Devi Chand</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.23 He who dwells fixed in the atmosphere, smiting the blasphemers of the god that do not sacrifice, to him be reverence with ten sakvarî−stanzas!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="59" class="wp-image-7291" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi2.png?w=601" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x29.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Killing Women and Children</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 11.2.21 Do not covet our cattle, our men, our goats and sheep! Bend thy course elsewhere, O strong god (ugra), slay the offspring of the blasphemers! <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="602" height="111" class="wp-image-7292" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi3.png?w=602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.png 602w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 5.20.4-5 “Let this war-drum victorious in the battle, loudly roaring and becoming the means of seizing whatever may be seized, be seen by all. Let this war-drum utter wonderful voice and let the army-controlling man capture the possessions of the enemies. Amid the conflict of the deadly weapons let the woman of enemy waked by the roar and afflicted run forward in her terror hearing the resounding and far reaching voice of the wardrum, holding her son in her hand.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="577" height="107" class="wp-image-7293" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi4.png?w=577" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.png 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.118.8 So, Agni, with thy glowing face burn fierce against the female fiends, Shining among Uruksayas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="508" height="100" class="wp-image-7294" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi5.png?w=508" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4.png 508w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-4-300x59.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>VEDIC GOD STEALS</strong></p>
<p><strong>GOD STEALING LIKE A THIEF</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “To him, who is the performer of all deeds, the possessor and giver of strength, the truly powerful Lord, we offer devotional prayers. He a highwayman, snatches wealth from the godless exploiters and gives it to honest devotees.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Griffith’s translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.103.6 “…The Hero, watching like a thief in ambush, goes parting the possessions of the godless.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.93.4 Agni and Soma, famed is that your. prowess wherewith ye stole the kine, his food, from Paṇi…<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="513" height="96" class="wp-image-7295" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi6.png?w=513" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5.png 513w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-5-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.61.25 “The elixir of divine love flows onward, chasing the malignant, and driving off the withholders of wealth and thus it proceeds to the holy abode of the resplendent Lord.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.19.9 ‘O bounteous Lord, pious devotees, skilled in reciting hymns, sing their songs to you for your adoration. May you select us also to join them who by their homage to you, have become entitled to appropriate the riches of infidels‘. Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.75.12 ‘Leave us not in this conflict as a bearer of load; snatch up the wealth of infidels and give it to us.’ Tr. Satya Prakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.4.5 “…May you come to bless our fire ritual. May you having scattered all our adversaries, bring to us the possessions of our foeman.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Here god is prayed to eliminate the rivals and to bring their wealth. Yaska writes on this verse,</p>
<p>Nirukta 4.5 “Having destroyed all assailants, bring to us the treasures of our enemies, i.e. having destroyed the forces of our adversaries, bring to us the treasures or the food from the homes of our enemies.”- Nirukta 4.5</p>
<p><strong>ALL NON HINDUS ARE DEMONS, BARBARIANS.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="417" height="523" class="wp-image-7296" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/tolerance-hinduism-buddhism-jainism-zoroastrianism-false-religions-untitld.jpg?w=417&amp;h=523" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole.jpeg 417w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2014-05-tole-239x300.jpeg 239w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px" /></p>
<p>The reason it is important to know who are Demons in Hinduism is because Hindu apologists find no problem with violent verses in the Veda because it says to kill ‘Demon’, they just say that these verses are referring to Demons and not to non-Hindus and try to get rid of the argument. As I said earlier Hindu apologists usually takes violent verses in lighter vein because it says to kill demons. Vedas are said to be eternal, now the question is if those verses were applicable only to Demons then it means that those verses have become useless now. So why God revealed such verses for limited period of time in the eternal book?</p>
<p>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote,”The Dwijaas( the twice-born) – Braahmanaas, Kshatriyas, Vaishyaas are called Aryas, while the Shudras are called Anaryas, or Non-Aryas.”ATHARVA VEDA 19:62. In the face ofthese Vedic authorities how can sensible people believe in the imaginary tales of the foreigners. In the Devaasurawars, Prince Arjuna and King Dashrathaand others of Aryavarta used to go to the assistance of the Aryas in order to crush the Asuras. This shows that the people living outside Aryavarta were called Dasyus and Malechhaas… Besides, Manu also corroborates our position. He says, “The countries other than Aryavarta are called Dasyus and Malechha countries.” MANU 10:45, 2:23. The people living in the north-east, north, north-west were called Rakshasas.” Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</p>
<p>Dasyu and Rakshasa mean demon. Here Swami Dayanand quoting Manu Smriti says that all people living outside Aryavrata and those who do not belong to four castes are demons (Rakshasa, Dasyu) and barbarians (Mleccha). According to Hindu Dharma all the non Hindus are demons and barbarians. Here is the full translation of Manu Smriti,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 10.45 All those tribes in this world, which are excluded from (the community of) those born from the mouth, the arms, the thighs, and the feet (of Brahman), are called Dasyus, whether they speak the language of the Mlekkhas (barbarians) or that of the Aryans.</p>
<p>Now some say that this doesn’t refer to Non-Hindus but to caste Hindus who lost their status on account of their neglecting their religious rites which lead them to loss of caste. They aren’t convinced even after providing explanation by their own scholar. Maybe they didn’t read verse 43 of this chapter 10 which says that by neglecting sacrifices the Dvijas made their successive generation fell to the status of Shudra not Dasyu. If Brahmins, Kshatriya, Vaishya and Shudra losing their caste made them Dasyu, the question is why they aren’t regarded as outcaste but as Dasyu? Because verse 43 and 45 aren’t correlated. Verse 45 is plain and clear that those tribe outside the pale of four Varnas are Dasyu and non-Hindus aren’t included in the four castes. Manu Smriti 10.45 also refutes the claim of apologists who claim that Dasyu means non-Human beings since Manu 10.45 states that Dasyu can be from four castes also who has abandoned their Vedic religion (if we go by the explanation of apologists) since they claim that Dasyu refers to demons only. Hindu scriptures from Veda to Purana mentions demon, so where are all those demons now? Dayanand Saraswati wrote,</p>
<p>“You can still see that the description of Raakshasas given therein tallies with the ugly appearance of the negroes of today.” <strong>Satyarth Prakash, by Dayanand Saraswati, Ch 8, page 266, Tr. Chrinajiva Bhardwaja</strong></p>
<p>So he is comparing Rakshasa with present day Negroes (black people) we can ascertain from this line that people living in north east and north west were not really monsters but were native people who are described in such racist manner. Swami Prabhupada also wrote,</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes: “…An atheist is called a demon, and it is a fact that even a person born of good parents can turn into a demon by bad association…” <strong>Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.3.6</strong><br />
<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.3.6<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>An Indologist wrote about Dasyu,</p>
<p>“The picture of the dasyu that emerges from these passages is quite different from that of the raksas. There is nothing about taking the form of a bird and flying by night, no mention of disrupting sacrifices, and no connection with black magic. The dasyus seem to be human beings of a different race from the Aryans and of a different (adevic and abrahamanic) religion. The mention of the proper names of various dasyus who are defeated for (or by) certain Aryan princes (e.g. Dabhiti) also makes the dasyu sound more like historical figures. There are occasional mentions of taking land from the dasyus (RV 4.38.1). The mention of dasyus in connection with fortresses (pur-) is also a characteristic which is in contrast to the raksases. Raksases do not build fortresses and fight from them. It seems quite safe to agree with the general conclusion of Vedic scholars that dasyu refers to the indigenous people of the land whom the invading Aryans conquered or absorbed.” <strong>by Wash Edward Hale, p.154, Asura in Early Vedic Religion, Published by Motilal Banarsidass Publisher, 1986.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Moreover the Aryans were engaged in battle against the Dasyus and the reason given is Dasyus sings no [Vedic] hymns; Dasyus are riteless, Dasyus have alien laws; Dasyus differs from rites and rituals and doesn’t observe fire sacrifices; Dasyus are faithless, niggars, without belief, sacrifice and worship. The main reason given to fight them is that Dasyus do not offer any gifts to Vedic deities and Indra was often invoked to wage a war against the Dasyu. Refer my article <a href="/index.php/2019/03/20/violence-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing infidels in Hinduism</a> for references. Dasa and Dasyu has been synonymously used in the Vedas. The Persian word <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dahae" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Dahae<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> maybe related to the Dasyu tribe mentioned in the Vedas. “The Dahae were a Scythian people of ancient Central Asia. A confederation of three tribes – the Parni, Xanthii and Pissuri – the Dahae lived in an area now comprising much of modern Turkmenistan. The area has consequently been known as Dahestan, Dahistan and Dihistan” [end quote]. The word Parni is also believed to be the Iranian word for Panis tribe. The Panis and Dasyu may be have been closely related to each other that’s the reason they are mentioned together in Rig Veda 7.6.3; 5.34.6. Many <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dasa" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Indologists<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> have also opined that Dasa were a tribe of humans not demons. Apologist pathetic response would be that Dasyu in the Veda are described as having numerous eyes and hands which is a proof that they were demons. Even Rishis who are said to be humans are described in some texts as of having three heads, Vedic deities as of having face of horse, animal getting pregnant after drinking semen of Rishis, does that prove that Rishis and Vedic deities were also demons? Hindus have a long history of using epithets against other religions, the Aryans used to consider Dasyu as Anasa which literally translates to noseless but it actually means flat nosed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to Panis tribe. Panis too are described as Demons, but Yaska in Nirukta also calls them Merchant (Nirukta 2.17). Panis tribe were rich traders and they were consistently attacked by Aryans to plunder them since they did not patronize the priests who then invoked Vedic gods to attack Panis. Apologists gives lame excuse, when defending verses about killing and plundering Panis tribe, all that they say is Panis were demons and doesn’t explain the part where Aryans plundered them and were the first to fight the Panis tribe. If they were demons then why Aryans were so eager to get their donations? Veda reiterates that Panis brings no gifts to Vedic deities, so why crave for their wealth if they were so demonic in nature? Veda also mentions a member of Panis community named Bribu who is praised in Rig Veda 6.45.31 because he is said to have gifted many cows to Rishi Bhardwaj (Manu Smriti 10.107) in which he is referred to as a carpenter. Now all of a sudden a Panis member is praised, what’s the reason? Because the reason to kill and plunder them is clearly given in Atharva Veda 20.93.2 that the Panis brings no gifts, had they given donations like Panis Bribu then they would’ve been spared and would’ve also been praised in the Vedas. Panis were rich merchants, they also had carpenters they used to rear cattle, engaged in trade and amassed wealth. These are the characteristics of humans not demons.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kikata too were plundered like Dasyu and Panis tribes because they didn’t observe Vedic rituals and didn’t make donations to Vedic deities. Veda also mentions Zoroastrians and calls them demons (Asura). The Asuras mentioned in Vedas are non other than Zoroastrians. They are actually Ahura worshippers (Zoroastrians). Vedic religion and Zoroastrianism are roughly of the same age they have many similarities like Vedic Yagna is called Yasna in Zoroastriniasm, Soma is Homa, Deva in Veda are positive while Daeva in Zoroastrianism is neutral to negative, Zoroastrian text also mentions Aryans. From Rig Veda Mandal 1 to 7, Vedic deities are also called as Asur but the definition when applied to Vedic deities is ‘Mighty’. When the Aryans moved from Central Asia to India they brought with them the memories, thus the word Asura is used till Rig Veda Mandal 7 as a praiseworthy word. And then it was turned negative and was also used later to describe enemies residing in eastern part of India such as Bengal and Assam like Asura king Naraka of Pragiyotisapura in Assam or Mahishasura. There’s also a tribe in India named <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/meeting-the-asurs-a-marginal-tribe-in-eastern-india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Asur people<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> who claim themselves to be descendants of Mahishasura.</p>
<p>People of Lanka in Ramayana has been described as Demons. Hanuman burned hundreds of demons inhabiting Lanka for no fault of their when Ram’s enmity was towards Ravana and not towards inhabitants of Lanka. Ramayana makes no mention of humans residing in Lanka but refers to the people of Lanka as demons. Go to Sri Lanka and tell me how many demons you found there or at least try to find their bones.</p>
<p>Now let’s move on to the Puranas, which is the most important point here. Many Puranas especially Vishnu Purana book 3 chapters 17 &amp; 18 states that demons embraced Buddhism and Jainism. The reason I quote Vishnu Purana again and again is because two chapters of this scripture are dedicated in denigrating Buddhism and Jainism and gives a picture of how Hinduism perceives other religions. Hindu text says that demons embraced Buddhism. Their disciples and disciples would continue to preach this religion. Now as you may know Buddhism’s history is not unknown like Hinduism’s. We know who its founder was and when Buddhism was founded, we know that its founder really existed and was not a mythological figure. Buddhism was founded in the 6<sup>th</sup> century B.C. It was a time when humans had started recording history. So you tell me did any Greek, Roman or any traveller ever recorded that demons used to live in India and they embraced Buddhism as stated in Hindu scriptures? So what Hindus did is nothing but demonization of their enemies. Hinduism recognizes many tribes and Dasyus, Panis, Yavana… were among them and they have been demonized because as mentioned in Manu (10.45) all those who do not belong to four castes are Dasyu and Malechas. Now some also justify violent verses of Vedas saying that all violent verses about killing godless, riteless, those who do not offer gifts actually refers to demons and not to human beings and that demons were averse to humanity. An Asura named Rambha who was the father of Mahishasur was a devotee of Vedic deity Agni. Vishnu Purana bk 3 ch 17-18 states that demons were Vedic followers who couldn’t be killed unless they apostatizes from Vedic Dharma and embraces other religions like Buddhism and Jainism. So what these incidents prove is that even demons could follow Vedic religion but still that wouldn’t make them Hindus or Humans since Hinduism believes in birth based and only those belonging to four castes can be considered Vedic followers. So this refutes the claim that demons were averse to Devas or Humanity.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Sutras,</p>
<p>Apastamba Sutra, Prasna I, Patala 9, Khanda 27.11 The expression Krishna Varna, ‘the black race,’ is truly Vedic. In the Rig-veda it usually denotes the aboriginal races, and sometimes the demons.</p>
<p>Vedas also states that the one who offers no worship is inhuman, wicked, evil, miser etc.,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.20.5 “Preserve us from the reproach of every one, who makes no offerings, is vicious and wicked and who utters ill words, so that we may be free (from anxiety).” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Shouldn’t Ishwar be friendly with entire creation? Why Ishwar is friendly only with those who make offerings? Was it invented by Rishis to get wealth in the name of god? What about the poor people who don’t even have money to feed their children. Will Ishwar forgive them or punish them as he commands to kill those who doesn’t pour gifts.</p>
<p><strong>Beheading the Demons (Non Hindus)</strong></p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.2.10 “…Here do I cut off the neck of the Raksas, who hateth us, and whom we hate’, he says; there are two people, he whom he hates and he who hates him; verily straightway he cuts their necks…”</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 1.7.7 O Agni, bring thou hitherward the Yatudhanas bound and chained. And afterward let Indra tear their heads off with his thunder-bolt.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="625" height="102" class="wp-image-7297" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi7.jpg?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-300x49.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px" /></p>
<p>Yajur Veda 5.26 By impulse of God Savitar I take thee with arms of Asvins, with the hands of Peahen.Thou art a woman. Here I cut the necks of Rakshasas away. Barley art thou. Bar off from us our haters, bar our enemies…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="554" height="210" class="wp-image-7298" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi8.jpg?w=554" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1.jpeg 554w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-1-300x114.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.26.3 Thou didst impel the sage to win the daylight, didst ruin Śuṣṇa for the pious Kutsa.The invulnerable demon’s head thou clavest when thou wouldst win the praise of Atithigva.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7299" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi9.jpg?w=612" width="505" height="123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2.jpeg 612w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-2-300x73.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 8.14.13 With waters’ foam thou torest off, Indra, the head of Namuci, Subduing all contending hosts.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7300" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi10.jpg?w=625" width="514" height="88" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3.jpeg 625w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-3-300x51.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>DEATH TO THOSE WHO DOESN’T POUR GIFTS TO ISHWAR</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.44.11 “Give us not, O showerer of benefits, to the wicked. Relying upon your friendship, O Lord of riches, may we remain unharmed. Many are the boons you distribute amongst men; may you demolish those who make no libation, and root out those who present no offerings.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.176.4 Slay everyone who pours no gift, who, hard to reach, delights thee not. Bestow on us what wealth he hath: this even the worshipper awaits.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="94" class="wp-image-7301" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi11.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-6-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p><strong>PLUNDERING THE PROPERTIES OF PEOPLE WHO DO NOT OFFER GIFTS</strong></p>
<p>Ishwar commands to plunder the property of people who do not offer gifts and then to kill them.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 1.81.9 …Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="500" height="161" class="wp-image-7302" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi12.png?w=500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7.png 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-7-300x97.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.2 Crush with thy foot the niggard churls who bring no gifts. Might art thou: There is not one to equal thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="512" height="104" class="wp-image-7303" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi13.png?w=512" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8.png 512w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-8-300x61.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 “Thou, Soma, boldest wealth in kine which thou hast seized from niggard churls: Thou calledst forth the outspun thread.” Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p>English translation by Arya Samaji scholar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 9.22.7 &#8220;O elixir of bliss, you hold the wealth of kine which you win from the greedy persons; you are the force behind the extended thread (of creation).&#8221; Tr. Svami Satya Prakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>This verse refers to the Panis tribe, according to some scholars the Panis tribe were also part of the Vedic society but were plundered and killed because they made no offerings to Ishwar, this is why they are considered Niggards. But Yaska gives a different meaning, Yaska writes that Panis tribe were Demons. One is not to be deluded by the usage of the word Demon here as Demons and Barbarians are those who does not follow the Veda or who lives beyond the boundaries of Aryavarta. The Vedic followers are commanded here to crush the Panis tribe only because they make no offerings to Vedic Gods. There are more evidences to show that tribes were plundered and killed just because they made no offerings to Vedic gods.</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.56.6 These people, Indra, keep for thee all that is worthy of thy choice. Discover thou, as Lord, the wealth of men who offer up no gifts: bring thou to us this wealth of theirs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="470" height="193" class="wp-image-7304" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi14.png?w=470" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9.png 470w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-9-300x123.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px" /></p>
<p><strong>Plundering Godless (Adeva)</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.138.4 He boldly cast down forts which none had e’er assailed: unwearied he destroycd the godless treasure-stores. Like Sun and Moon he took the stronghold&#8217;s wealth away, and, praised in song, demolished foes with flashing dart.</p>
<p>Following is the Hindi translation by Arya Samaji scholar Shripad Damodar Satwalekar</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1101" height="197" class="wp-image-7305" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68.jpeg 1101w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-300x54.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-1024x183.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/word-image-68-768x137.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1101px) 100vw, 1101px" /></p>
<p><strong>Dark races</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;Through your fear, O universal fire, the dark evil forces, though of many minds, come under a control, having abandoned their possessions. Adorable Lord, may you shine upon all men and blaze, consuming the cities of their foes.&#8221; Tr. Svami Satyaprakash Sarasvati</p>
<p>Another clear translation,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.5.3 &#8220;For fear of thee forth fled the dark-hued races, scattered abroad, deserting their possessions, When, glowing, O Vaiśvānara, for Pūru, thou Agni didst light up and rend their castles.&#8221; Tr. Ralph T.H. Griffith</p>
<p><strong> Ishwar Behaving like a Thug</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.93.5 “When two large, mutually defiant hosts, emulous in corporal vigour, contest, may you destroy the godless in favour of the god fearing and in favour of the person who pours out devotional sentiments.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Rig Veda 4.25.7 (Indra), the drinker of the effused Soma, contracts no friendship with the wealthy trader who offers not any libation ; he takes away his wealth ; destroys him when destitute; but he is a special (friend) to him who presents the libation and oblation.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="463" height="148" class="wp-image-7306" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi15.png?w=463" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10.png 463w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-10-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 5.34.8 When Indra, the possessor of opulence, discriminates between two men, both wealthy, and exerting themselves (against each other) for the sake of valuable cattle, he takes one of them [The one who performs Yajna] as his associate, causing (his adversaries) to tremble, and the agitator (of the clouds), together with the Maruts, bestows upon him herds of cattle.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="548" height="121" class="wp-image-7307" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi16.png?w=548" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11.png 548w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-11-300x66.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 548px) 100vw, 548px" /></p>
<p>Other verses shows that Ishwar provides protection to those who make offerings to him, but Ishwar slays the person who doesn’t worship or make offerings. Why is Ishwar behaving like a thug? Shouldn’t Ishwar be equal and friendly to everyone irrespective of their offerings? All the verses I quoted above orders to kill those who make no offerings, there are several instances in Vedas wherein tribesmen were killed just because they made no offering to Ishwar,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O bounteous Lord, of what avail are the cattle of infidels to you. Neither they yield milk nor do these faithless persons kindle sacred fire. May you bring wealth of these unbelievers to us and give us possession of people of low mortality and crush them.” Tr. SayaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>This verse is referring to the Kikata tribe who were plundered by Vedic heroes and killed. Maharishi Yaska explains this as,</p>
<p>Nirukta 6.32 What are the cows doing in Kikata? Kikata is the name of a country where the non-Aryans dwell. Non-Aryan tribes are (so called because it is said),’What have they done? Or their assumption is that religious rites are useless. They neither get the milk to mix with the soma, nor kindle fire.</p>
<p>Here the Vedic god is invoked to plunder the cows of of Kikata people and to plunder the wealth of the king of Kikata tribe. As I said earlier, many tribes were plundered and looted by Vedic gods just because they made no offering to Ishwar, Kikata and Panis tribes are few examples. Here is another translation by Arya Samaj,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.14 “O learned king! you possess admirable wealth, what do the cattle do among the atheists because they have no faith in the Vedic teachings and rites or in place inhabited by them. They yield no milk to mix with the Soma, and do not perform the Yajna with the ghee of the cows. Therefore, bring them to us, so that we may use them for hospitality (giving the milk mixed with Soma) to teachers and preachers. Give us wealth taken away from the wicked persons for the use of those who hailing from a good family come to us. Remove far away from us a man who uses his power for doing mean or inglorious acts or keep him under us.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p><strong>Swami Dayanand Saraswati wrote on this verse</strong>, “As the cows do not grow among the wicked atheists, in the same manner, Dharma and other virtues do not grow among the persons lacking faith. Among the enlightened persons atheists can never have the upper hand. Therefore, good scholars should blot out atheism.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO HATE ISHWAR AND WHOM ISHWAR  HATES</strong></p>
<p>The entire hymn of Atharva 2.19 is dedicated in burning those who hate Ishwar and to whom Ishwar hates,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.19.1 Burn thou, O Agni, with that heat of thine against the man who hates us, whom we hate.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="189" class="wp-image-7308" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi17.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-12-300x110.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.15 “…By him we attack on him who hates us and whome we abhor. We overthrow and slay him through this knowledge, through this act and through this fatal weapon.” Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.5.25 …from earth we bar him who hates us and whom we hate.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="515" height="137" class="wp-image-7309" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi18.png?w=515" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13.png 515w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-13-300x80.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="483" height="316" class="wp-image-7310" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi19.png?w=483" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14.png 483w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-14-300x196.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Arya Samaj commentary states that a, ‘Man [Brahmin] should satisfy himself by killing his enemies with the miraculous powers given by God’.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="457" height="79" class="wp-image-7311" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi20.png?w=457" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15.png 457w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-15-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 457px) 100vw, 457px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.53.21 “O resplendent Lord, brave and opulant, protect us this day against our foes with many and excellent defences, may the vile wretch who hates us fall before us; May the breath of life depart from him whom we hate.” Tr. SatyaPrakash Saraswati</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 15.15 This one in front, golden-tressed, with sunbeams; the leader of his host and his chieftain are Rathagritsa and Rathaujas, and Puñjikasthalâ: and Kratusthalâ his Apsarases. Biting animals are his weapon, homicide his missile weapon; to them be homage: may they protect us, may they have mercy upon us. In their jaws we place the man whom we hate and who hates us.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="539" height="204" class="wp-image-7312" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi21.png?w=539" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16.png 539w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-16-300x114.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 539px) 100vw, 539px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 10.3.3 This charm shall conquer and cast down thy foemen. <strong>Be thou the first</strong> to slay the men who hate thee.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="248" class="wp-image-7313" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi22.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-17-300x145.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>Is it right to kill someone just because they hate you or Ishwar? What kind of God is Ishwar who commands to kill the person who just hates him. The above verse explicitly says to be the first one to kill those who just ‘Hate’ you. Is this justifiable? If you just oppress a Brahmin you are liable to be killed according to Vedas, but the Brahmin can kill you, deprive you of your property, there is no sin in this, but oppressing a Brahmin is a grave sin in Vedas,</p>
<p>‘Atharva Veda 13.3.1 ‘…O Rohita (King) agitate destroy and entangle in snares the man doing wrong to Brahman.” , Tr. Vaidyanath Shastri.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="427" class="wp-image-7314" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi23.png?w=494" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-18-300x259.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.52 Rend, rend to pieces, rend away, destroy, destroy him utterly. Destroy Angirasi! the wretch who robs and wrongs the Brahmans, born.</p>
<p>Poor Shudra’s fate is to be oppressed by Brahmins,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 8.417 A Brahmana may confidently seize the goods of (his) Sudra (slave); for, as that (slave) can have no property, his master may take his possessions.</p>
<p>Maharishi Manu says that a Brahmin can even kill anyone who hurts him without bringing notice to the King,</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.31-33 A Brahmana who knows the law need not bring any (offence) to the notice of the king; by his own power alone be can punish those men who injure him. His own power is greater than the power of the king; the Brahmana therefore, may punish his foes by his own power alone. Let him use without hesitation the sacred texts, revealed by Atharvan and by Angiras; speech, indeed, is the weapon of the Brahmana, with that he may slay his enemies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THOSE WHO REJECT AND HATE VEDAS</strong></p>
<p>Atharva Veda 12.5.62 “Rend, rend to bits, rend through and through, scorch and consume and burn to dust, the one who rejects the Vedas”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="493" height="118" class="wp-image-7315" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi24.png?w=493" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19.png 493w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-19-300x72.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 493px) 100vw, 493px" /></p>
[This verse is translated from the Hindi Bhasya]
<p>Arya Samaj commentary states:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="442" height="58" class="wp-image-7316" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi25.png?w=442" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20.png 442w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-20-300x39.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px" /></p>
<p>“Godly persons shall always be ready to kill irreligious people”</p>
[Kshemkarandas Trivedi (Arya Samaj) on Atharva Veda 12.5.62, page 576]
[Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p576.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>He writes on Atharva Veda 12.5.54</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="455" height="145" class="wp-image-7317" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi26.png?w=455" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21.png 455w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-21-300x96.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px" /></p>
<p>‘‘Vedic followers should destroy infidels“- Kshem Karan Das Trivedi on Atharva Veda 12.5.54, page 574 [Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Hindu god Vishnu says,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.17 When the glorious Vishnu heard their prayers he emitted from his person an illusory form wliich he gave to the celestials and said. “This illusory form shall so deceive the Daityas, so that being led astray from the path of the Vedas, they may be put to death ; for all gods, demons and others, who shall transgress the authority of the Veda, shall perish by my prowess which I exercise for the preservation of the universe. Go then ; be not affraid ; this illusory form shall go before you. celestials, it shall be of great service to you, this day.</p>
<p>Veda also commands to kill the enemies of Vedas,</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 2.12.6 …Burn down the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="469" height="248" class="wp-image-7318" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi27.png?w=469" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22.png 469w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-22-300x159.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" /></p>
<p>Griffith has translated the word Brahmadvish as “Haters of Prayer/devotion” which is also correct but the definition “Those who hate Vedas” is precisely correct, other correct definition is ‘Enemies of Vedas’. Dayanand Saraswati founder of Arya Samaj gives the following meaning,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="185" height="26" class="wp-image-7319" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-23.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi28.png?w=185" /></p>
<p>“Brahmadivsh = The enemies of Vedas and Ishwar.</p>
[Rig Veda Dayanand Saraswati Hindi Bhasya, Mandala 2, page 323]
<p>Vidya Martanda also endorsed his Guru’s definition,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="503" height="148" class="wp-image-7320" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi29.png?w=503" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24.png 503w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-24-300x88.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 503px) 100vw, 503px" /></p>
[Rig Veda, By Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda, Vol 3, p.469, Published by Sarvadeshik Arya Pratinidhi Sabha, April 2002 Reprint]
<p>Satya Prakash Saraswati defines Brahmadvish as,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="565" height="87" class="wp-image-7321" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi30.png?w=565" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25.png 565w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-25-300x46.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 565px) 100vw, 565px" /></p>
[Rig Veda Samhita, by Satya Prakash Saraswati and Vidyalankar, Vol 4, page no 1294, Published by Veda Pratishthana, New Delhi, 1977]
<p>Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON gives the following meaning,</p>
<p>‘‘One who is envious of the Vedas, of a qualified Brahmana or of the Brahmana caste is called Brahma-dvis”</p>
[Krishna The Supreme Personality of Godhead: A Summary Study of Srimad-Bhagavatam’s Tenth Canto, Part 2, by A.C Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada, page 304, Publisher Bhaktivedanta Trust, 2003 Edition]
<p>Besides Pandit Jaydev Sharma also translates it as ‘The enemies of Vedas’, Almost every commentator and translator has given the same meaning.</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.4 “O God and learned person! you take the people to the target through the path of religion and justice and protect them. If you commit a sin, the soul or God is not infested with it. Those who denounce the Vedas and God, you cast your anger on them. Therefore, we should admire your greatness.” Tr. Acharya Dharma Deva Vidya Martanda (Arya Samaj).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="514" height="222" class="wp-image-7322" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi31.png?w=514" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26.png 514w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-26-300x130.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.93.1 …destroy the enemies of Vedas</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="502" height="185" class="wp-image-7323" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi32.png?w=502" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27.png 502w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-27-300x111.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8 …burn down the enemies of God, Vedas and the malice…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="481" height="248" class="wp-image-7324" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi33.png?w=481" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28.png 481w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-28-300x155.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 481px) 100vw, 481px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.52.3 …cast your destroying weapon for the destruction of the enemies of Veda, wealth and crops.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="497" height="352" class="wp-image-7325" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi34.png?w=497" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-29-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 20.96.4 …he slays, unasked, the enemies of Vedas.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="505" height="243" class="wp-image-7326" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi35.png?w=505" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30.png 505w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-30-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.22.8; 6.52.3, Atharva veda 20.96.4; 2.12.6 are translated into English from the Hindi Bhashya.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>KILLING THE BLASPHEMERS</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.72.1 …ye killed all darkness and the Gods’ blasphemers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="479" height="93" class="wp-image-7327" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi36.png?w=479" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31.png 479w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-31-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 479px" /></p>
<p>It is mentioned in Bhagwad Purana (Srimad Bhagvatam)</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam 4.4.17 Sati continued: If one hears an irresponsible person blaspheme the master and controller of religion, one should block his ears and go away if unable to punish him. But if one is able to kill, then one should by force cut out the blasphemer’s tongue and kill the offender, and after that one should give up his own life.</p>
<p>ISKCON scholar writes on this verse,</p>
<p>“If possible she should have cut out Daksha’s tongue because he blasphemed Lord Siva. In other words, since Lord Siva is the protector of religion, a person who vilifies him should be killed at once, and after killing such a person, one should give up one’s life…The instruction set forth here in Srimad-Bhagavatam is that one should not tolerate at any cost the activities of a person who vilifies or blasphemes an authority. If one is a Brahmana he should not give up his body because by doing so he would be responsible for killing a Brahmana; therefore a Brahmana should leave the place or block his ears so that he will not hear the blasphemy. If one happens to be a Kshatriya he has the power to punish any man; therefore a Kshatriya should at once cut out the tongue of the vilifier and kill him. But as far as the Vaisyas and Sudras are concerned, they should immediately give up their bodies.” [<a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"> http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.4.17 <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 6.61.3 Thou castest down, Sarasvati, those who scorned the Gods…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="478" height="120" class="wp-image-7328" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi37.png?w=478" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32.png 478w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-32-300x75.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 2.23.14 Burn up the demons with thy fiercest flaming brand, those who have scorned thee in thy manifested might…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="492" height="147" class="wp-image-7329" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png" alt="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi38.png?w=492" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33.png 492w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-0602-33-300x90.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 492px) 100vw, 492px" /></p>
<p>Recommended reading <a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/vedas-and-world-peace-part-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedas and World Peace part 2</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing Infidels in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 18:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadiths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niyog pratha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed &#160; This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts . Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &#38; Agniveer. Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Arial;">Written by Neer Mohammed<br />
</span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts .</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5641"></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &amp; Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see whether Agniveer will quit Vedic Dharm or not?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In his present article on women, Agniveer makes so many bogus claims. In this series of articles we are going to analyze them one by one.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his recent article on women in Hinduism he makes these claims on Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1. Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">3. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span>. People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations. But neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4. On contrary, many a prophets of Christianity and Islam got children from slave-girls <span style="text-decoration:underline;">but never made them their wives!</span> Prophet Abraham is supposed to have even attempted to abandon his slave-girl to death after having child from her. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria. God only knows the veracity of these stories and support for sex-slavery in Bible and Quran. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">5. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But as far as Vedas are concerned, any relation apart from one single wife/husband is clearly considered to be cause of miseries.&#8221;</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">6. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling. However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">7. Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>Before analyzing these claims about Niyog in detail, let us see what Swami Dayanand had to say about Niyog.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>ALL THE POINTS TAKEN HERE ARE FROM SATYARTHA PRAKASH TRANSLATED  BY Shri Dr. Chrianjiva Gharadwaya.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 129</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1.Re-marriage is <span style="text-decoration:underline;">absolutely prohibited in the case of a twice born man or woman (i.e., one belonging to a Brahman, Kshatriya or Vaishya Class</span> . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. The following are the principal evils of remarriage:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">a.Diminution of love between the husband and the wife, since either of them can desert the other whenever he or she so desires, and marry another person.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">b.On the death of one party, the other will take away the property of his or her deceased consort when he or she marries again. This will give rise to family disputes. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">c.If a widow re marries, many a noble family will be blotted out of existence, and its property destroyed (by constant alienation).</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">d.Re-marriage involves loss of true conjugal love and infraction of duty towards the departed husband or wife. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 130</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> 3.Q. ~ If one of the parties dies leaving no male issue, even then the family line will become extinct. Besides, if re-marriage be not allowed, the widows and widowers will resort to adultery and fornication, procure abortion, and will commit wicked deeds of a kindred nature. For these reasons re-marriage is desirable. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ No. If the widows and widowers desire to practice Brahmacharya, no such evil consequences will accrue. Again, if the widow or widower adopts a boy of her and his Class, the family line will be continued and there will be no danger of adultery being restored to. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Those, however, who cannot control their passions may beget children by having recourse to Niyoga. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>So lets us see what the niyoga is</em> [writer]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4.Q. ~ What are the differences between re-marriage and Niyoga?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ 1.After marriage the bride leaves her paternal roof, lives with her husband, and her relations with her relations with her father&#8217;s family cease to be very close; on the contrary. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The widow (in case she contracts Niyoga) continues to live in her deceased husband&#8217;s house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2.The children begotten of marriage inherit the property of their mother&#8217;s husband, whereas, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">offspring begotten of Niyoga on a widow are not regarded as children of the begetter and consequently they don&#8217;t take his surname, nor can they be claimed by him. They are spoken fo as the children of their mother&#8217;s deceased husband, take his surname, inherit his property and live in his house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">3.Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations (after the stipulated period). </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">4.The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>5,.The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>PAGE 131</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ Do the same laws apply to Niyoga and marriage, or are they different in each case?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ They are little different. A few differences have already been enumerated, and here are some more:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>A married couple can produce children up to the limit of ten, while that connected by Niyoga cannot produce more than two or four.A married couple always lives together but not that connected by Niyoga..</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Let the widow rear the children for two or three years and hand them to her husband by Niyoga, in case it has been entered into for his behalf. In this way a widow can give birth to two children for herself and two for each of the four husbands by Niyoga. Similarly a widower can beget two children for himself and two for each of the four wives by Niyoga. Thus ten children in all can be produced by means of Niyoga. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">This is what the Veda declares:-&#8220;O thou who art fit to procreate and art strong, do thou raise upon the married wife or upon these widows, with whom thou hast <span style="text-decoration:underline;">contracted Niyoga</span>, good children, and make them happy. Do thou beget with on thy married wife ten children, and consider her the eleventh (memberof the family). O woman! Let ten children be raised on thee by the married husband or thy <span style="text-decoration:underline;">husbands by Niyoga</span> and do thou consider thy husband as the eleventh (member of thy family).&#8221; Rig Veda 10: 85, 48.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 133</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~Should the relation of Niyoga be entered into with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a different Class as well? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ A woman should contract Niyoga with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a higher Class, that is, a Vaishaya woman with a Braahman, a Kshatriya or aVaishaya; a Kshatriya woman with Kshatriya or a Braahman; a Brahman woman with a Braahman. The object of this is that the spermatic fluid should always be of a man of the same Class as the woman or of a higher Class, never </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 134</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ are there any Vedic and Shaastric authorities in favor of Niyoga, as there are in support of the marriage institution? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ <em>&#8220;O man and woman <span style="text-decoration:underline;">(connected by Niyoga</span>), just as a widow, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him</span>, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>O widow! Dothou give up thinking of they deceased husband and choose another from among living men. But thou must understand and remember that if thou should contractest Niyoga for the benefit of thy second husband with whom thou are united by performing the ceremony of joining hands, the child resulting from this union shall belong to him; but if thou interest into relation of <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> for thy benefit, the child shall be thine. Do thou bear this in mind. Let thy husband by <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> also follow this law.&#8221; RIG VEDA 18,8. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>Do thou O woman that givest no pain to thy husband or devar (husband by Niyoga), art kind to animals in this Order of householders, walk assiduously in the path of righteousness and justice, art well-versed in all the shaastraas, hast children and grandchildren, givest birth to valiant the brave boys, desirest a second husband (by Niyoga), and bestoweth happiness on all, accept a man of they choice as thy husband or devar , and always perform the Homa which is the duty of every householder.&#8221; ATHARVA VEDA 14:, 2, 18. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>The sage Manu also sanctions the marriage of <strong>virgin widows</strong>. Says he <span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8220;A virgin widow may marry the younger or the elder brother of her deceased husband</span>.&#8221; MANU. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> </em>PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>A man may also contract <strong>Niyoga with eleven women</strong> (one after the other), just as a woman may enter into the relation of <strong>Niyoga with eleven men</strong> (one after the other), as sanctioned by the Veda in the following text:- </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45. </strong></span></em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 137</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> <em>Q. ~ Can a woman contract Niyoga only after the death of her husband or even when he is alive? </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> A. ~ <strong>This relation can be entered into even in the lifetime of the husband (or of the wife</strong>). Here is Vedic text n support of this view. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> &#8220;When a man is incapable of producing children, let him address his wife as follows:- O thou that art desirous of getting children do not expect me to raise offspring upon thee. Do thou, therefore, seek another husband.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 10, 10.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Similarly when a woman on account of some chronic disease is rendered incapable of bearing children, let her address the following words to her husband. &#8220;My lord! Do not expect me to bear any children. Do thou, therefore, contract Niyoga with a widow.[THESE WORDS ARE NOT PART OF MANTRA THEY HVE BEEN ADDED BY SWAMI JI-WRITER]</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 138</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">The sage Manu declares:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;If a husband has gone abroad in furtherance of some righteous cause, </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">let his wife wait for eight years;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for he acquisition of knowledge and glory, for six years; </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for the pursuit of material ends, for three years. If after the expiry of the prescribed periods he does not turn up, she may contract Niyoga and obtain children.&#8221; MANU 9: 76. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;if the wife be sterile, let the husband wait for eight years after marriage;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if all of her children die, for ten years,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>if she bears only daughters and no sons, for eleven years</strong></span>,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <strong>if she be a termagant, let him forsake her immediately, and enter into Niyoga with another lady and beget children upon her.&#8221; MANU 9: 81</strong>. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Likewise if the husband be very cruel, let his wife forsake him, and bear children by Niyoga who will succeed to the property of her husband by marriage.[THESE ARE NOT PART OF VEDIC LAWS-i.e manu smriti] </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q.~ Monogamy being the rule (i.e., if one man be allowed to have only one wife, and one woman only one husband) what will a person do, if the wife be encienti ir afflicted with some chronic disease, or if the husband be a valetudinarian and either of them cannot control himself or herself on account of extreme youth? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 140 </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ We have answered this objection while treating of Niyoga. <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife and she is pregnant, he may contract Niyoga with a (widow) and beget offspring on her, but let him never misconduct himself with a prostitute or commit adultery.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 142</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8230; <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>Niyoga is clearly allowed by the Veda.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Above we read some laws related to niyog and remarriage which iare laid by Swami Dayanand Saraswati which he backs up through Vedas, Manusmriti and other scriptures. He even gives historical refrences from Mahabharata [<em>it is to be noted agniveer reject these refrences,now its upto reader to decide who is write and who is wrong</em>] and gives various qualities of Niyoga.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his belief the alleged reformer has claimed re-marriage as faulty and Niyog as justified and appropriate .</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand pointed back on remarriage issue as goofy, nonsense and childish . Further more as the great writer has mentioned that if a man or a woman remarries their faith/religion will be lost/destroyed but due to Niyog their basic faith will be pure and safe. Isn&#8217;t this nonsensical? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">What kind of <em>patidharam</em> is this in which if a woman remarries will loose or destroy his faith and if she maintains 11 other sexual relationships she will be safe and clean?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">If a wife is alive and due to certain reasons the husband is  incapable to reproduce, this doesn&#8217;t mean that he lacks sexual desire. If a man has sexual desire but is incapable of producing offspring and his wife approaches another men for niyog, then where and how will the husband fulfill his sexual desire?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Given a thought, everwhere he mentions about begetting a male child only after niyog, but according to the science there is 50% possibility can  be a birth of a girl child. <em>[This is another proof of wishing a male child  in Vedas which we will see later on,and it may also be noted that swami ji permits  Noyog for begetting a male child even if a daughter is present.] </em>In such circumstances where a girl child is born, the rules and conditions governing Niyog have not been mentioned </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji said that  &#8220;Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations after the stipulated period. The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.then for two or three years women have to take care of child.&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Now mark, isn&#8217;t it like lower animal activity in which after having sex only the female has to take care of the children? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As Swami has mentioned, if a woman goes on producing girl babies, still MAN can have a male child by doing niyog. Here the point to be noted is, if a woman keeps giving birth to a girl, then its not the woman but the man who is to be blamed. This is a scientific fact that the determination of gender is done by a male and not by female.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As written, if spoken bluntly, Niyog can be done if a wife is pregnant and husband seeks a sexual relationship and if a husband is ill for long time and the wife wants to have sexual relationship. In such cases they can look for proper partners and go for Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Aren&#8217;t the law, virtue and values not being locked up here? Is the not the meaning of Niyog FREE SEX? Can you imagine any society which is of more low standard than this? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">One more thing to note is what Swami Dayanand states, &#8220;that even <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife  is pregnant</em> he wants to have sexual relationship in such case he  can look for proper partners &amp; go for Niyog</strong></span>.&#8221; Now if the necessity of Niyog was only to bear children (which it is not), why go for free sex during the wife&#8217;s pregnancy?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand in order to confirm the truthfulness, authenticity and practicality gave two examples from the period of Mahabharata. It is written that Vyas had Niyog with wives of those  persons with unique semen and derived offsprings. By Niyog process, Ambika derived Dhritrashtrya, Ambalika derived Pandu and a servant derived Vidur. Another example is of the wives of King Pandu&#8217;s women Kunti and Madri. Due to the reason of incapability in production of Pandu both his wives derived offspring by Niyog. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">[<em>it is quite contrary to the view held by Agniveer that the refrence from Mahabharata is interpolation</em>]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As said in Mahabharat, what to say about Niyog, child even with a non-married woman  was considered good and venerable. The two wise &amp; great men Ved viyas and Bheeshm pitamah&#8217;s origin is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Secondly, in Mahabharat time, in a society one woman could be a wife of 5 brothers e.g. Draupadi the wife of Pandav is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Thirdly, according to what is written in Mahabharata, in this era, even without woman&#8217;s communication only men were able give birth to children. Mahabharat&#8217;s major character guru Dronacharya&#8217;s origin is a proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fourthly, in this period children were born by magical methods e.g. origin of Draupadi. Therefore, in such a society what was the need for Niyog? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">To give it a thought, under what rules Ved Vyas ji did Niyog and why did he do Niyog with three women at the same time?<span style="color:red;"><br />
</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fifthly, why did Kunti give birth to 4 children by Niyog activity on contrary to the rules? Kunti gave birth to Karan, Yudhishtir, Bheem and Arjun and all of them were called as pandu. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Sixthly, in those days when niyog was considered innocent and good then why did kunti float Karan in the river because of shame ?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Seventhly, who were those men with whom kunti had Niyog and derived offspring? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji has prohibited polygamy, where as its said that in that  in Mahabharata civilization &#8220;bahuvivah&#8221; was allowed. The society where swamiji has made niyog evident, should that only be considered as high and template?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In Sathyarth Prakash (doubt removal edition) Pandit Jwalaprasad Sharma produce few more examples in support of Niyoga. He says that in ancient period women used to derive off-springs by accepting the semen of Rishi-Munim, wise, great men by Niyog. All the evidences shown by Pandit ji are from Mahabharat period only. Was Mahabharat the only old (vaidik) period? Was Niyog the only need of Rishis?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Its ironical that with the (vaidik) incantation Swami ji demonstrated niyog tradition  with same incantation (mantra) various wise men and lecturers have demonstrated widow remarriage . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Pandit Omprakash has pointed, for widow remarriage, in his book <em>&#8220;vaidik sahitya aur sanskriti ka swaroop&#8221;</em> he has written that in vedic society there was  permission of widow remarriage.  In the mantra  ( rig ved 10-18-8)  he has given his summary as follows –</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;Hey woman! Leaving this dead husband again make arrival into the living military. accept the future husband,  who wishes to marry you&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">It&#8217;s a whacking, shameful topic where a wise man and a society reformer should support remarriage and widow remarriage, but here the supposed reformers defend niyog practice and showed it useful for the future. Isn&#8217;t it&#8217;s a sign of a wiseman&#8217;s sleazy psychology? In the movies of today that show various stars, even in them we don&#8217;t get to see subject movies on these practices and favor. Leaving swami dayanand , all other wise men and reformers belonging to navjagrun ,favored remarriage.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">LET US NOW SUMMARIZE THE VIEW OF AGNIVEER AND SWAMI JI. READERS WILL SEE THAT AGNIVEER  IS TRYING TO HIDE THE TRUTH AND IS GOING AGAINST SWAMI JI AND ALSO SATYARTHA PRAKASH [APTLY MITHYA PRAKSH OR BIBLE OF HATE].<br />
</span></p>
<div>
<table style="border-collapse:collapse;" border="0">
<colgroup>
<col style="width:199px;" />
<col style="width:351px;" /></colgroup>
<tbody valign="top">
<tr>
<td style="padding:5px;border:outset .75pt;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>AGNIVEER</strong></span></p>
</td>
<td style="border-top:outset .75pt;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>SWAMI DAYANAND JI</strong></span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Niyog is clearly allowed by the Vedas</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How can it be so as Rigved 10-85-48, 10-40-2, Atharvaved 14-2-18, etc mention Niyog.</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;">
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;O man and woman (connected by Niyoga), just as a widow, co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">LET US SEE FEW MORE CLAIMS OF AGNIVEER </span><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong><span style="color:#002060;">CLAIM 1:</span> People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">It is to be noted that only Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj  who accept Niyog had interpreted Vedic verses in support of Niyog. I had provided a reference of Pandit Omkar who saw those texts as supporting widow remarriage.  Also Mr. Agniveer in his usual hateful style tries to attack the Muslims by saying, &#8220;The meaning of this mantra (Rig 10-18-8) provided has been slightly distorted and misinterpreted to suit one&#8217;s mindset of hatred.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Thus Agniveer is calling Swami Dayanand&#8217;s view as a <strong>mindset of hatred and suting his agenda</strong>. Cheers!<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 2: Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria</strong>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Having seens the laws of Niyog it is the height of shamelessness of agniveer to look for Niyog in  Islamic and Christian scriptures.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Mother Mariah, was the WIFE of Prophet Muhammad as clearly mentioned in Hadith accounts. Agniveer as usual takes his readers for a ride by not providing any references.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 3: Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How ironical it is that pregnancy of wife becomes an emergency situation (as claimed by Swamiji)  and and Niyog is only gain a son even if a daughter is present? How pitiful?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In conclusion, I want to assert that Niyog is a curse and bad practice, it cannot be suitable for any period. The state of a women in India was extremely pitiable. It  feels like certain rishis, munis and  other men made  certain rules and regulations, where in woman was treated like a breakfast pl<span style="color:black;">ate and and thing of lust only.</span> Niyog  tradition made a woman no less than a prostitute. Like you have already read above, a widow can have niyog with 10 men. The two words widow and prostitute if taken with the same meaning, it won&#8217;t be unfair. A movie called &#8220;water&#8221; released in 2000 which was picturized on the bad condition of  widow women which was controversial and was banned. The movie was based on historical facts where widows were shown as prostitutes. Since widowed women are considered as inauspicious, they go to pilgrimage places like Kaashi, Vrindavan etc and sing religious chants and beg to earn a living. Even in these days there are nearly 16000 widows living in Kaashi.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Let us respect women, work for their empowerment and allow remarriage instead of this cursed practice of Niyog.<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
