<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>rebuttal &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/rebuttal/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 13:39:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Is Taj Mahal a Hindu Temple?</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/11/03/taj-mahal-hindu-temple/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 13:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pn oak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puroshottom nageshwar oak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebuttal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiv mandir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tejo mahalya]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2017/11/03/taj-mahal-hindu-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi Contents Introduction Mughal court historians on purchase of land and commencement of building of Taj Mahal Mughal court historians on construction of Taj Mahal from its foundation Travellers witnessing construction of Taj Mahal Modern historians on this issue Farmans of Shah Jahan to Raja Jai Singh Leakage of dome not cracks &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/11/03/taj-mahal-hindu-temple/" data-wpel-link="internal">Is Taj Mahal a Hindu Temple?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-1152 aligncenter" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/taj-mahal.png" alt="" width="499" height="281" /></p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p><span id="more-1098"></span></p>
<p><a name="top"></a></p>
<h1>Contents</h1>
<p><a href="#1" class="broken_link">Introduction</a></p>
<p><a href="#2" class="broken_link">Mughal court historians on purchase of land and commencement of building of Taj Mahal</a></p>
<p><a href="#3">Mughal court historians on construction of Taj Mahal from its foundation</a></p>
<p><a href="#4" class="broken_link">Travellers witnessing construction of Taj Mahal</a></p>
<p><a href="#5" class="broken_link">Modern historians on this issue</a></p>
<p><a href="#6" class="broken_link">Farmans of Shah Jahan to Raja Jai Singh</a></p>
<p><a href="#7" class="broken_link">Leakage of dome not cracks</a></p>
<p><a href="#9">Shivling in closed 22 rooms of Taj Mahal?</a></p>
<p><a href="#8" class="broken_link">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="1"></a>Introduction</h1>
<p>Taj Mahal is a marvellous structure built by Shahjahan in memory of his late wife Mumtaz Mahal. The word Taj means Crown and Mahal means Palace hence Taj Mahal means Crown of the Palace but in the Mughal period Taj Mahal wasn&#8217;t called by that name, its original name is Rauza-i-Munawwara which means The Illumined Tomb and this name also occurs in Mughal documents. The Taj Mahal is a beautiful display of the Islamic architecture in India with minarets and tombs. In 1983, it became a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The Taj Mahal attracts 2-4 million visitors annually, with more than 200,000 from overseas. 21.23 crores is collected by the Central government from Taj Mahal&#8217;s entry fees as per 2015 Ministry of Tourism. It always remains in top 10 landmarks of the world. But some people in India cannot digest the greatness of this magnificent palace. Undoubtedly Taj Mahal is the pride of India and instead of taking pride in this Indian monument some right wingers claim the Taj Mahal to be a Shiva temple. I researched about this some 4 years ago and went through all the articles written by right wingers on Taj Mahal but didn&#8217;t find even a single evidence or historical document proving that the Taj Mahal is a Hindu temple. Union Culture Minister Mahesh Sharma said that &#8216;<a href="http://zeenews.india.com/news/uttar-pradesh/no-evidence-to-prove-taj-mahal-was-a-hindu-temple-mahesh-sharma_1828699.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">No evidence to prove Taj Mahal was a Hindu temple&#8217;<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. And it&#8217;s not just the minister from Hindu nationalist party but even the Archaeological Survey of India told an Agra court that the &#8216;<a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/taj-mahal-is-a-tomb-and-not-a-temple-asi-tells-court/story-TaVPTc0ppaTzgbzpyrihsM.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Taj Mahal is a tomb, not a Shiv Temple&#8217;<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. Right Wing historian P.N. Oak even took this matter to the Supreme Court in 2000 where it was thrown out as no more than a &#8220;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/aug/30/taj-mahal-muslim-tomb-not-hindu-temple-indian-court-told" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">bee in his bonnet<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>&#8220;. So this claim has been rejected by the Judiciary, Government and Archaeological Survey of India. Right Wingers&#8217; basis for this argument is not any historical document but a book written by a right wing historian named P.N. Oak. P.N. Oak is popularly known as a &#8220;Mythistorian&#8221; who put forth some ridiculous and pathetic claims like the Vatican City has Hindu origin and the Vatican is a distorted Sanskrit term for Vatika, The word Islam too is a distorted Sanskrit word for Ishalayam and Christianity is a distorted term for Kishan Neeti. You can ascertain his reliability and knowledge from these claims alone but for right winger historians, he is their role model who &#8216;exposed&#8217; many lies. I went through many of right wing articles which is based on P.N. Oak&#8217;s work and didn&#8217;t find a single evidence about Taj being a Hindu temple rather they try to prove it as a palace of Raja Jai Singh and rather than providing evidence they indulge in questioning the existing evidence of Taj Mahal being a tomb. In this article I shall try to refute some of the main claims of right wingers.</p>
<p>Mumtaz Mahal&#8217;s original name was Arjumand Banu Begum and Mumtaz Mahal was a title was given by Shahjahan which means Jewel of the Palace. She had been accompanying her husband while he was fighting a campaign in the Deccan Plateau where she died due to some delivery complications. Mumtaz Mahal died in the year 17 June 1631 and was buried temporarily in Baradari pavilion in Zainabad garden at Burhanpur before shifting her body to Akbaradabad (Agra) permanently in the place known today as Taj Mahal. It is said that it was difficult to transport white marbles from Makrana (Rajasthan) to Burhanpur hence Akabarabad (Agra) was chosen as the final destination of the queen. Mumtaz Mahal&#8217;s body was taken to Agra escorted by her son Shah Shuja.</p>
<p>It is ridiculous to claim that the Taj Mahal is a Hindu temple because the structure of Taj Mahal with domes and minarets itself is a foolproof evidence of Taj Mahal being an Islamic structure. It were Muslims (especially Mughals) who introduced such architecture in India, there exists no such structure that predates the Mughals or other Muslim rulers.</p>
<p>The land on which Taj Mahal is built originally belonged to Raja Jai Singh which was purchased by Shah Jahan prior to the construction after exchanging four palaces for the land. Though Raja Jai Singh voluntarily gifted the land but Shahjahan awarded him 4 other Havelis for it,</p>
<p>From the Farman of Emperor Shah Jahan of 1633-34 AD</p>
<p>The extract of the Farman taken from page 53 and 54 the book &#8220;Mughal Documents AD.1628-59&#8221;, Volume-II compiled and translated by S.A.I. Tirmizi and published by Manohar Publishers, Delhi, 1995 Edn., reads as follows: &#8220;56. Farman of Shah Jahan addressed to Raja Jai Singh informs the Raja that in lieu of the plot of land acquired for the construction of the mausoleum of Mumtaz Mahal the following four Havelis have been granted to him (Jai Singh):</p>
<p>1. Haveli of Raja Bhagwan Das.</p>
<p>2. Haveli of Madhav Singh.</p>
<p>3. Haveli of Rupsi Bairagi.</p>
<p>4. Haveli of Chand Singh, son of Suraj Singh. The zimn on the reverse bears the risala of Afzal Khan and waqia of Makramat Khan. (MIM.IV,p.165; DLFMN,p.55,CHDKD.pp.176-177).&#8221;</p>
<p>Some mentions that four <em>Haveli</em>s were exchanged for the <em>Haveli</em>, and some say that <em>Khana</em> (House) of Jai Singh (originally belonging to Man Singh) was exchanged with four <em>Haveli</em>. And that&#8217;s the whole basis of this so called Tejo Mahalya. Had some common sense been applied here then such questions wouldn&#8217;t have arose in the minds of right wingers. There&#8217;s a huge difference between Haveli/Khana and Mahal. As I said earlier that right wingers claim it to be Hindu temple and then tries to prove it as a palace of Raja Man Singh. Whether it is Man Singh&#8217;s palace or a mausoleum built by Shahjahan will be proved in this article.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="2"></a>Mughal court historians on purchase of land and commencement of building of Taj Mahal</h1>
<p>Now let&#8217;s read what Mughal court historians of Shah Jahan period wrote. Muhammad Amin Qazwini a Mughal court historian of Shah Jahan&#8217;s time wrote, <strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;In short, after six months her blessed corpse was dispatched to the Abode of the Caliphate, Akbarabad, escorted by the branch of the tree of sovereignty and caliphate&#8230;As there was on the southern side of Akbarabad, adjoining the city, on the bank of the river Jumna, a tract of land (zamini), which formerly (sabiqa) was the house (khana) of Raja Man Singh, but at this time was in the possession of his grandson Raja Jai Singh, and which from the point of view of eminence and pleasantness appeared to be worthy of the burial of that one whose residence is Paradise, it was selected for this purpose. And the Raja as a token of his sincerity and devotion, donated the said land (zamin) and considered this to be the source of happiness. Howeer, His Majesty, in exchange (iwad) for that, granted to the Raja a lofty house (khana-i-&#8216;ala) which belonged to the crown estate. And even though the Raja&#8217;s consent was obvious, the Emperor obtained permission for the repose of that companion of the Houris of Paradise.</p>
<p>And it was decided that her auspicious body should be buried in that heart-pleasing land (zamin); but until its arrival at the Abode of the Caliphate, everywhere on the roads, there should be distributed food and drink and innumerable coins should be given in alms to the poor and the deserving&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.41-42, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Muhammad Amin Qazwini also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;And in that bountiful and heart pleasing land (zamin) a Paradise like tomb (rauza) was laid out (tarah afgandand) and a dome (gumbad) of exalted foundation (buniyan) and a magnificent edifice (imarat) was founded (bina nihadand) the like and peer of which the eye of Age has not seen beneath these nine vaults of heaven&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.42, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.</strong></p>
<p>So it is clear from Muhammad Amin Qazwini&#8217;s account alone that Shah Jahan purchased a tract of land (Zamini). The translators have even given the Persian word <em>Zamin</em> and everyone may be familiar with this word. Another court historian named Abd al-Hamid Lahori wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;As there was a tract of land (zamini) of great eminence and pleasantness towards the south of that large city, on which there was before this the mansion (manzil) of Raja Man Singh, and which now belonged to his grandson Raja Jai Singh, it was selected for the burial place (madfan) of that tenant of Paradise. Even though Raja Jai Singh considered the acquisation (husul) of this to be his good fortune and a great success, by way of utmost care, which is absolutely necessary in all important things, particularly in religious matters, a lofty mansion from the crown estates (khalisasharifa) was granted to him in exchange (&#8216;iwad).&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.43, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.</strong></p>
<p>Abd al-Hamid Lahori also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;And plans were laid out (tarah afganand) for a magnificent building (&#8216;imarat-i-alishan) and a dome (gumbadi) of lofty foundation (rafi-buniyan), which for height (dar bulandi) will, until the Day of Resurrection, remain a memorial to the sky high&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.43, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.</strong></p>
<p>Abd&#8217;al Hamid Lahori says the same as Qazwini that a <em>Zamin</em> (tract of land) was purchased which formerly had the house of Raja Man Singh and goes on to say that plans were laid out for a magnificent building with lofty foundation (Rafi Buniyan) and a tomb (Gumbad). Hindi speakers maybe familiar with the word Buniyad here.</p>
<p>Muhammad Salih wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;When a period of six months had expired after this grief gathering event, prince Muhammad Shah Shuja was appointed to convey the holy dead body of that Queen of angelic temperament to the Abode of the Caliphate Akbarabad&#8230;After reaching Akbarabad, it was entrusted to earth in the heaven like tract of land (sarzamin-i-bihisht-a&#8217;in) situated to the south side of the Abode of the Caliphate, overlooking the river Jumna, which had belonged to Raja Man SIngh; and to acquire it, His Majesty, the Caliph ranked, had given in exchange (&#8216;iwad) a mansion (manzil), loftier than the said mansion, to his grandson Raja Jai Singh. And on the top of the illumined grave, at first in haste (az ru-i-tajil), a small domed building&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.43, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.</strong></p>
<p>Muhammad Salih also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;Subsequently, in that heaven-like tract of land (sarzamin), the heavenly linth (asman asas was laid for a mausoleum (rauza) of lofty foundation (&#8216;ala bunyan), which, in strength and loftiness and high dignity and magnificence of rank, is the honor of the terrestial world, which is completely of white marble slabs, and which has arranged round it a pleasing garden having the marks of Paradise. On one side of it, a lofty mosque was built and on the other side, a replica thereof, a guest house (mihman khana) of lofty expanse&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, p.44, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.</strong></p>
<p>Muhammad Salih implies the same that there was a house or mansion before there and it was exchanged with much loftier palaces and on that <em>Sarzamin</em> (heaven like tract of land) a <em>Rauza</em> i.e. mausoleum was laid of lofty foundation (&#8216;Ala Bunyan). All these historians states that a mausoleum was built on that land, but the right wing has their answer ready to counter this, they claim that it may have taken 1-2 years to demolish the existing &#8216;Palace&#8217; of Raja Man Singh. Right wingers should first prove that there stood a palace prior to the construction of Taj Mahal. Most of the sources proves that it was merely a <em>Haveli</em> not Mahal and there&#8217;s a huge difference between these two. A large land was purchased for the purpose of building a mausoleum, it could be that the <em>Haveli</em> stood somewhere in the corner which was either demolished or was in ruins before Taj Mahal was planned to be build there. The following topic clears every doubt which mentions the &#8216;Laying the foundations&#8217; by digging down to &#8216;the water table&#8217;.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="3"></a>Mughal court historians on construction of Taj Mahal from its foundation</h1>
<p>Abd al Hamid Lahori wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;At the beginning of the fifth year of the exalted accession, the excavation was started for the laying of the foundation (Bunyan) of his sublime edifice which is situated overlooking the Jamuna river flowing adjacent to the north, and when the spade-wielders with robust, arms and hands strong as steak, had with unceasing effort excavated down to the water table, the ingenious masons and architects of the astonishing achievements most firmly built the foundation (Asas) with stone and mortar up to the level of the ground (sath i zamin).</p>
<p>And on top of this foundation, there was raised a kind of platform (chabutara-asa) of brick and mortar in one solid block (yak lakht), measuring 374 cubits (zira) long by 140 wide and 16 hihg, to serve as the plinth (kursi) of this exalted mausoleum.</p>
<p>And from all parts of the empire, there were assembled great numbers of skilled stonecutter, lapidaries, and inlayers, each one an expert in his art, who commenced work along with other craftsmen&#8230;.In the center of the second platform, the building (imarat) of the heavenly lofty and Paradise like mausoleum was constructed on the plan of a Baghdadi octagon (tarah i musamman i bagdhdadi), 70 cubits in diameter, on a base plinth (kursi) one cubit in height.</p>
<p>Situated in the exact center of the building, the domed hall (gunbad) over the sepulchre (margad) of that recipient of divine grace has been finished with white marble within and without. From the floor (Sath) to the curvature (Zih), the hall under the dome is octagonal in shape, with a diameter of 22 cubits. The curvature is ornamented with muqarnas motifs, while fro the cornice to the inner summit of the dome which is at a height of 32 yards from the floor of the building, there are arranged marble slabs cut in a geometric moulded pattern (galib kari)…- <strong>Badshahnama, By Abd al Hamid Lahori, Tr. Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, English excerpts taken from the book Taj Mahal: the illumined tomb : an anthology of seventeenth-century Mughal and European documentary sources, p.65-66.</strong></p>
<p>Muhammad Salih wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;In the fifth year of the exalted accession, the foundation of this edifice of heavenly foundations, compared to which, the solidity and height of the foundation of the seven heavens of Shaddad do not form even one-thousandth part, was laid overlooking the Jumna river, which flows to its north. And the bottom of its foundation (buniyad) have been excavated down to the water, wonder-working masons raised its foundation in utmost strength, [filling it] with stone and mortar, and brought it up to the ground level. And upon this foundation, the plinth (kursi) of that tomb whose equal among buildings, with respect to its plinth and height, profusion of decoration and ornamentation, and spaciousness and expanse, does not exist on the surface of the earth was constructed of bricks and mortar all in one piece (yak lakht), 374 yards long and 140 wide, and raised to [a height of] 14 yards. The front of this plinth was decorated with finely cut red stone, in which much craft of carving and inlay work had been employed; and its floor was also made of red stones joined edge-to-edge (girahbandi) with each other. And in the middle of this plinth (kursi), another platform was raised, which is faced with white marble, all in a single block (yak-lakht), even and square, 120 yards on a side and 7 cubits (zara&#8217;) high. And in the center of this second platform, the edifice of the sky-touching heaven like mausoleum, having a diameter of 70 cubits and a plinth of one yard, was constructed on the Baghdadi-octagonal plan. The dome (gumbad) over the illumined grave, which is in the exact center of this building, was finished wholly of white marble, both inside and outside. It is octagonal form the floor level (sath) to the curvature (zih), with a diameter of 22 cubits; and the curvature [of the dome] has been decorated with mauqarnas motifs&#8230;And above this has been raised a gauva-shaped (amrudi-shakl) dome, to estimate even the slightest degree of whose foundation (az qiyaz-i-qadar-i-asas), would confound even the engineer (muhandis) of Wisdom.&#8221; <strong>Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.78 by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="4"></a>Travellers witnessing construction of Taj Mahal</h1>
<p>Several travellers witnessed construction of Taj Mahal, I will be mentioning those travellers who visited Agra during and after the construction of the Taj Mahal. Among the travellers, Peter Mundy&#8217;s account is perhaps the most valuable, since he was the only European eyewitness to the first years of actual excavation and construction that began in early 1632. Peter Mundy arrived in India in 1628 and stayed about five years or eight years as per some historians. He was at Agra in 1631 from January 1 till the year 1632. Historians are unanimous on this account that he arrived in Agra in the year 1631 prior to the construction of Taj Mahal which means that he really witnessed the construction of Taj Mahal from its foundation. Thus with his account it can be easily proved that Taj Mahal was built by Shah Jahan, Hence due to this reason, right wingers are questioning travellers&#8217; accounts just like the lawyer of the villain questions eye witnesses in Bollywood movies. These travellers mentions &#8220;Taj Mahal&#8221; instead of Rauza-i-Munawwara which was the original name, according to modern historians, travellers probably picked this name from local residents of Agra who called it Taj Mahal. When they got to know the name from local residents, didn&#8217;t the local residents of Agra told them about a Hindu temple being converted into a Mausoleum? Were the travellers so dumb as to not distinguish between construction and remodelling or renovation? It is for this reason that right wingers questions about travellers has no weight and is appeasing only to the minds of people who subscribes to views of right wing ideology.</p>
<p>Peter Mundy wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;The Kinge is now buildinge a Sepulchre for his late deceased Queen Tage Moholl (Mumtaz Mahal) (as much to say att the brighntess of the Moholl), whome hee dearely affected, haveing had by her 9 or 10 children, and thought in her life tyme to use noe other women (which is strange if true consideringe their libertie in that kinde). He intends it shall excell all other. The place appoynted [is] by the river side where shee is buried, brought from Brampore [Burhanpure] where shee dyed accompanying him in his warrs, as shee did all the tyme of his troubles.</p>
<p>There is alreadye about her Tombe a raile of gold. The buildinge is begun and goes on with excessive labour and cost, prosecuted with extraordinary dilligence, Gold and silver esteemed comon Metall, and Marble but as ordinarie stones. Hee intends, as some thinck, to remove all the Cittie hither, cawesinge hills to be made levell because they might not hinder the prospect of it, places appoynted for streets, shopps, etts. dwellings, commaunding Merchants, shoppkeepers, Artificers to Inhabit [it] where they being to repaire and called by her name, Tage Gunge [Taj Ganj].<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.291-2, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Spelling mistakes above are not made by me, it is reproduced as it is without any rectification. Right wingers claim that &#8220;Peter Mundy confirms that the &#8220;Tajmahal had been a noteworthy building even before Shahjahan&#8221;, I have mentioned passage by Peter Mundy, now you tell me where does he say that the Taj Mahal was a noteworthy building even before Shah Jahan? Works of Peter Mundy is available to all yet right wingers has this courage of distorting his words to prove their point. The fact that Peter Mundy arrived in Agra in January 1631 i.e. before the commencement of building of Taj Mahal itself is a proof of Taj Mahal been built by Shah Jahan. Had Shah Jahan merely remodelled it, Peter Mundy would&#8217;ve mentioned that the king is converting a palace or temple into a Mausoleum but he instead writes that &#8220;The Kinge is now building, a Sepulchre for his late deceased Queen Tage Moholl&#8221; and he also writes &#8220;The building is begun and goes on with excessive labour and cost&#8221; which proves that it was Shah Jahan who build the Taj Mahal and refutes the claim of right wingers. Another question raised is that Mundy writes there is already a rail of gold around her tomb which he is perhaps referring to the gold railing around her grave. In this way right wings are distorting and twisting facts instead of providing historical documents for their claim. The fact that right wingers are arguing about &#8216;gold railing about her tomb&#8217; itself is a proof of poor research by them, railings are installed around grave not around tomb, one can Google railings around grave to get an idea of what they are and where they are placed. Mughal court historian Qazwini clearly mentioned that,</p>
<p>&#8220;And the gold railing, on which the inscription, knobs and most of the flowers are inlaid in enamel, and which required 40,000 tolas of gold, equivalent in cost to an amount of six lakhs of rupees, was brought by Bebadal Khan, the superitendent of the goldsmith&#8230;the railing was set up and aforesaid handing lamps and constellation-orbs were suspended above that descending place of divine pardon [i.e., the Queen&#8217;s grave].</p>
<p>And on all the four sides of the platform of the plinth (chabutara-i-kursi) of the building of the holy tomb, the foundation (bunian) of whose dome (gumbad) had not yet come up above the ground (zamin), sky-wide tents and around them vast conopies (shamiyana-ha) were raised.&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.52, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong></p>
<p>Lahori wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;And it was ordered that the screen, which had required 40,000 tolas of gold, and was worth six lakhs of rupees, should be set up round the grave (turbat) of that one enshrined in divine mercy, and the constellation-orbs and hanging lamps suspended above the resting-place (marqad) of that recipient of divine light.</p>
<p>And orders were also issued to erect, on the platform of the plinth (chabutara-i-kursi) of the building (&#8216;imarat) of that tomb (mazar) having the vestige of Paradise, the foundation of whose dome (asas-i-gumbad) had not yet come above the ground&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.53, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong></p>
<p>Begley and Desai wrote that &#8220;Since Mundy left Agra for Surat on the 4th of March 1632 (N.S.), his mention of the gold railing suggests that it had been completed well before the Second &#8216;Urs at the end of May.</p>
<p>Father Sebastien Manrique was briefly in Agra in January 1641 when Taj Mahal was under construction. He wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;The other Mausoleum, the work, as I remarked, of the Emperor Corrombo [Shah Jahan], dedicated to the unhappy memory of his chief and most beloved wife and Begoma, stands at the opposite end of the town. At this time it was still incomplete, the greater part of it remaining to be done, according to the plan drawn up and what was discussed, and I will therefore only deal with so much of it as was then finished. This consisted of a handsome, lofty, quadrangular wall of hewn stone of a reddish hue, the wall well proportioned as to height. The summit of the wall is crowned with strong spikes made of the same stone, instead of the usual battlements. At the four corners of the great wall stood four Palaces, built of great handsome blocks of white marble, which had been brought there from over forty leagues away, for the erection of these edifices. Some of these blocks, which I met on the way, when visiting Biana City, were of such unusual size and length that they drew the sweat of many powerful teams of oxen and of fierce-looking, big-horned buffaloes, which were dragging enormous, strongly made wagons, in teams of twenty or thirty animals.</p>
<p>This great wall embraced a huge square-shaped enclosure, in the center of which rose a vast, lofty, circular structure, from the middle of which this famous Geometer, by drawing equal lines, constructed a perfect circle with less trouble than Archimedes of Syracuse. This circular building is, moreover, made of glittering white marble.</p>
<p>On this building, as well as other works, a thousand men were usually engaged, overseers, officials and workmen&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.292-3, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong></p>
<p>Manriques makes the claim that the architect was Geronimo Veroneo which is now discredited and the claim was revised in this century by H. Hoste, &#8220;Who Planned the Taj?&#8221; Begley and Desai wrote about Francois Bernier that &#8216;As mentioned in the Introduction, the European sources on the Taj Mahal are both sparse and generally unreliable. The most detailed and sympathetic description is that of Bernier, but as his first visit to Agra was in 1659, he was not a witness to the actual construction. Dated July 1663, his description was first set down as a letter, guiding the reader through the different parts of the monument, which he felt deserves much more to be numbered among the wonders of the world than the pyramids&#8217;. Francois Bernier&#8217;s description of Taj Mahal is too long and by mentioning it I don&#8217;t think it will yield any benefit. It is just to show that traveller who visited Agra after completion of Taj Mahal wrote in their works, Francois Bernier wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;I shall finish this letter [of July 1663] with a description of the two wonderful mausoleums which constitute the chief superiority of Agra over Delhi. One was erected by Jehan-Guyre [Jahangir] in honor of his father Ekbar [Akbar]; and Chah-Jehan [Shah Jahan] raised the other to the memory of his wife Tage Mehele [Mumtaz Mahal], that extraordinary and celebrated beauty, of whom her husband was so enamoured that it is said he was constant to her during life, and at her death was so affected as nearly to follow her to the grave&#8230;The last time I visited Tage Mehale&#8217;s mausoleum I was in the company of a French merchant, who, as well as myself, thought that this extraordinary fabric could not be sufficiently admired. I did not venture to express my opinion, fearing that my taste might have become corrupted by my long residence in the Indies; and as my companion was come recently from France, it was quite a relief to my mind to hear him say that he had seen nothing in Europe so bold and majestic&#8230;I leave you to judge whether I had not sufficient ground for asserting that the mausoleum of Tage Mehale is an astonishing work. It is possible I may have imbibed an Indian taste; but I decidedly think that this monument deserves much more to be numbered among the wonders of the world than the pyramids of Egypt&#8230;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.295-8, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Jean-Baptiste Tavernier visited Agra in the winter of 1640-41, and it is true that he didn&#8217;t witness the commencement as he visited Agra nine years after the construction began. But He was there during the construction. He wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;Of all the tombs at Agra, that of the wife os Shahjahan is the most splendid. He purposely made it near the Tasimacan, where all foreigners come, so that the whole world should see and admire its magnificence. The Tasimacan [Taj-i-Makan] is a larga bazar, consisting of six large courts all surrounded with porticoes, under which are chambers for the use of merchants, and an enormous quantity of cottons are sold there.</p>
<p>The tomb of Begam, or sultan queen, is at the east end of the town by the side of the river in a large square surrounded by walls, upon which there is a small gallery, as on the walls of many towns in Europe. This square is a kind of garden divided into compartments like our parterres, but in the places where we put gravel there is a white and black marble. You enter this square by a large gate, and at first you see, on the left hand, a beautiful gallery which faces in the direction of Mecca, where there are three or four niches where the Moufti comes at fixed time to pray&#8230;.I witnesses the commencement and accomplishment of this great work, on which twenty two years have been spent, during which twenty thousand men worked incessantly; this is sufficient to enable one to realize that the cost of it has been enormous. It is said that the scaffoldings alone cost more than the entire work, because, from want of wood, they, as well as the supports of the arches, had all to be made of brick; this has entailed much labour and heavy expenditure. Shahjahan began to build his own tomb on the other side of the river, but the war with his sons interrupted his plan, and Aurangzeb, who reigns at present, is not disposed to complete it&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.298-299, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Niccolao Manucci another European traveller wrote,</p>
<p>Shahjahan gave orders for the construction of the mausoleum [of Mumtaz Mahal] opposite the royal palace at Agrah with great expenditure. It is in two stories, in the lower being deposited the body of his beloved wife. No one may see this sepulchre, for it is in charge of women and eunuchs.<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.299, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Jean De Thevenot wrote,</p>
<p>King Gehanguir caused one to be built for King Ecbar his Father, upon an eminence of the Town. It surpasses in magnificence all those of the Grand Signoirs, but the fairest of all, is that which Cha-Gehan Erected in honour of one of his Wives called Tadhe-Mehal, whome he tenderly loved, and whose death had almost cost him his life. I know that the Learned and curious Mr. Bernier hath taken memoirs of it, and therefore I did not take the pains to be exactly informed of that work. Only so much I&#8217;ll say that this King having sent for all the able Architects of the Indies to Agra, he appointed a Council of them for contriving and perfecting the Tomb which he intented to Erect, and having settled Salaries upon them, he ordered them to spare no cost in making the finest Mausoleum in the World, if they could. They completed it after their manner, and succeeded to his satisfaction.</p>
<p>The stately Garden into which all the parts of that Mausolum are distributed, the great Pavillions with their Fronts, the beautiful Porches, the lofty dome that covers the Tomb, the lovely diposition of its Pillars, the raising of Arches which support a great many Galleries, Quilochques and Terrasses, make it apparent enough that the Indians are not ignorant of Architecture. It is true, the manner of it seems odd to Europeans; yet it hath its excellency, and though it be not like that of the Greeks and other Ancients, yet the Fabrick may be said to be very lovely. The Indians say that it was twenty years in building, that as many Men as could labour in the great work were employed, and that it was never interrupted during that long space of time.<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.299-300, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Right wingers makes arbitrary claims about these travellers and want us to believe that these travellers were tricked into believing the remodelling of Taj Mahal as construction. I mean were all these travellers to naïve that they couldn&#8217;t distinguish between construction and converting a temple into a tomb? Many travellers inquired about the Taj Mahal with the locals who told them details about the Taj Mahal such as time period of its construction etc. and even picked the name &#8220;Taj Mahal&#8221; from local residents. So didn&#8217;t the local residents told them about a temple or Rajput palace being converted into a mausoleum?</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="5"></a>Modern historians on this issue</h1>
<p>Giles Tillotson wrote,</p>
<p>&#8221;An altogether more desperate bid to assign a new meaning to the Taj has been made by P.N. Oak in a book with the intriguing title The Taj Mahal is a Hindu Palace (1968). In this startling piece of pseudo-scholarship, Oak soberly protests that the Taj is not a, as we have all supposed, a seventeenth-century Muslim tomb but a much earlier Hindu structure, &#8216;Perhaps built in the 4th century to serve as a palace&#8217;.</p>
<p>His starting point is the passage in the Padshanama describing Shah Jahan&#8217;s purchase of the site for the Taj, land that belonged through inheritance to the maharaja of Amber, Jai Singh I (the same ruler who was later required to assist with the supply of marble and masons). The passage clearly states that there was a house or mansion on this land, which had been built by an ancestor of Jai SIngh&#8217;s, so the Maharaja received compensation in the form of comparable properties. Oak interprets this to mean that the existing house became the tomb: with the addition merely of a few Quranic inscription over its doorways, the older palace was converted to its new use. So the universally admired Taj is not, after all, one of the greatest glories of Islamic civilization but further proof of the wonders of ancient Hinduism.</p>
<p>No evidence is offered in support of its redating by thirteen centuries. Jai Singh&#8217;s ancestor who built the Manzil, Raja Man Singh, lived in the sixteenth century and was a contemporary and colleague of Akbar&#8217;s, but this evidently keeps the whole matter too close to the Mughals for Oak&#8217;s comfort. The fourth century is safely pre-Islamic. Of course this is preposterous: the only stone architecture surviving in India from such an early date is either rock cut or monolithic, not structural. The technical know how to create a building with the structural form of the Taj simply did not exist in pre Mughal India. It would be like assigning a fourth century date to a photograph, or a combustion engine. Later in his book Oak seems to drop this claim, giving the building instead a twelfth century date, and an original functions as a Shiva temple.</p>
<p>Whatever date and use he opts for (and the argument has shifted about quite a bit with successive editions of the book) he meets the same objection on the basis of the building&#8217;s style. If it is not a Mughal building, how does it come to bear such strong affinities with other Mughal buildings, such as their earlier tombs and Shah Jahan&#8217;s palaces in Agra and Delhi? Oak has his answers ready: the fact that it looks like them is proof that they too are all converted Hindu buildings. &#8216;Muslim rulers in India did not raise even a single mansion, canal, fort, palace, tomb or mosque whether of red stone or marble. They only appropriated Hindu buildings and misused them.&#8217; If we still have the breath and energy for further argument, we might ask how he accounts for the similarities between those buildings in India generally thought to be Islamic and the buildings of west Asia. Those, he says, are all &#8216;products of Hindu architecture&#8217; as well, evidence that Hindu architecture was the first international style.</p>
<p>I was once gently reprimanded by a senior colleague for paying Oak the compliment of bothering to engage with his book at all. It is plainly a work of fantasy and they author&#8217;s barely concealed motive to denigrate Islamic civilization is distasteful. The convoluted passages in which he quotes and wilfully misinterprets texts and inscriptions might be useful as an illustration, to alert students to the methods of phoney scholarship. It contains nothing else that is instructive&#8230;It is of course a sort of compliment to the Taj that it spawns polemics like Oak&#8217;s. So many people seem to want to claim it for their own, because it is so obviously worth having, and they will happily be misled by the slightest clue that seems to bring it closer to them.&#8221; <strong>Taj Mahal, by Giles Tillotson, p.112-15, Published Harvard University Press, 12-Nov-2012</strong></p>
<p>Giles Tilotson on the issue with the name &#8216;Taj Mahal&#8217;,</p>
<p>&#8220;But then, one might ask, just how Mughal is the name &#8216;Taj Mahal&#8217; anyway? It is usually said that the name derives from Mumtaz Mahal, the title given to the empress, which means &#8216;select of the palace&#8217;. There is room for doubt about this: &#8216;Taj&#8217; need not be an abbreviation of &#8216;Mumtaz&#8217; since it is itself perfectly good Persian word meaning &#8216;crown&#8217;. It is also worth noting that the building is not called &#8216;Taj Mahal&#8217; in the contemporary Mughal sources. Abdul Hamid Lahauri, the author of the Padshanama, the official history of Shah Jahan&#8217;s reign, calls it &#8216;Rauza i Munawwara&#8217;, meaning &#8216;the illumined or illustrious tomb&#8217; (where rauza implies specifically a tomb in a garden).</p>
<p>It was Francois Bernier and other Europeans observers who witnessed its construction who first called it the Taj Mahal. It seems unlikely that they invented te same name: perhaps they picked it up from the residents of Agra. They called the empress &#8216;Taj Mahal&#8217; too, which suggests they believed the tomb was named after her.&#8221; <strong>Taj Mahal, by Giles Tillotson, p.14, Published Harvard University Press, 12-Nov-2012</strong></p>
<p>Another historian named Diana Preston wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;Yet all accounts of the construction of the tomb, whether by court historians or by European observers such as Peter Mundy who were present when building started, make clear that work started from the foundations up. The chronicler Lahori talked of &#8216;Laying the foundations&#8217; by digging down to &#8216;the water table&#8217;. Peter Mundy noted that &#8216;the building is begun&#8230;&#8217; if there had been any previous major structure on the site, other observers who had visited Agra before Mumtaz&#8217;s death would have recorded it. Europeans such as the Jesuit Father Monserrate, who visited Agra several times in 1580-82, or Sir Thomas Roe, who gave such a detailed description of Agra and court life in the early seventeenth century, and Francisco Pelsaert, the Dutch trader who visited Agra in 1620-27 and enumerated the gardens and palaces along the Jamuna, made no mention of any pre-existing building. Although the royal archives of the raja of Amber, who donated the land for the building, refer to building projects, including temples, elsewhere, they contain no reference to any such construction in Agra. Furthermore, the Hindu architectural features of the Taj, such as the chattris, are more likely to derive from the synthesis of Hindu and Islamic styles so apparent in Moghul architecture from Akbar&#8217;s time onward.</p>
<p>The claim that the building was a Shiva temple particularly puzzles India scholars, both because temples cannot be sold after construction and Shah Jahan would not have committed such an inauspicious act as seizing the land, and because the rajas of Amber belong to a particular branch of the Hindu religion that would not have worshipped at a Shiva temple. Perhaps even more conclusively, no know Hindu temple looks at all like the Taj Mahal.&#8221; <strong>Taj Mahal: Passion and Genius at the Heart of the Moghul Empire, Diana Preston, p.279, Published by Walker, 12-Feb-2008</strong></p>
<p>Renuka Nath wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;Many European travellers came to Agra between 1580 and 1668. Their accounts help us in reconstructing the history of medieval India, particularly when the Persian chronicler is branded as a biased courtier and is rejected as unreliable. Father Monserrate who was at Fatehpur Sikri for about three years (1580-83) visited Agra several times but he does not make the slightest mention of a Taj Mahal or any such similar construction. Ralph Fitch came to Agra in 1585 and has left a detailed description of the city but he too does not speak of the Raj Mahal or a Taj mahal. William Hawkins stayed in Agra for about five years (1608-13). He has described the tomb of Akbar at Sikandara which was then under construction but he does not allude to any building of the Taj-Mahal&#8217;s stature on the river-side.&#8221; <strong>Agra and Its Monumental Glory, by Renuka Nath, p.94, Published by Taraporevala, 1977 &#8211; Agra (India)</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;The Jesuits established a church, a school, a hospital and a graveyard at Agra and their transactions supply valuable information. But no mention of a Taj Mahal has been made by them in any of their communications.&#8221; <strong>Ibid<br />
</strong></p>
<p>She also wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;In view of the Persian sources and the accounts of foreign travellers, particularly Peter Mundy, Travernier, Manucci, and Bernier, reinforced by the unmistakable architectural evidence, the assumption that the Taj Mahal was originally a Rajput palace and was converted into a tomb as claimed by some, is completely absurd and without warrant.&#8221; The Immortal Taj Mahal, by Renuka Nath, p.94, Published by D.B. Taraporevala Sons &amp; Co. Private LTD, 1972</p>
<p>Royina Grewal wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;A friend of a friend, makes an astonishing comment. &#8216;The Taj Mahal, he announces, &#8216;was in fact a Hindu temple built by Raja Man Singh. Shah Jahan simply converted it into a tomb for his wife by adding few Islamic elements such as calligraphy.&#8217; I have heard of this completely untenable theory but never dreamt I would meet an adherent. In the year 2000, the Supreme Court of India dismissed a petition that sought to declare that the Taj Mahal was a Hindu temple and issued a reprimand&#8230;He goes on to inform me that the Taj Mahal is actually Tej o Mahalya, a temple consecrated to Shiva in his manifestation as Agreshwar Mahadev, Lord of Agra. &#8216;This,&#8217; he says, &#8216;has not been much publicized because the government did not want to hurt the feelings of the Muslims. But there are 109 points that prove this was so. First of all, the name Taj Mahal is not found in any Mughal document.&#8217;</p>
<p>I attempt to explain that the mausoleum was originally referred to as &#8216;Rauzah i Mumtaz Mahal&#8217;, a name certainly occurs in Mughal records of the time. The appellation Taj Mahal came into common use under the British when Taz or Taje Mahal, based on abbreviations of the empress&#8217;s name common among Europeans, was corrupted into the present form&#8230;&#8217;So you see, &#8216;He concludes triumphantly, &#8216;Shah Jahan did not build the Taj Mahal. He desecrated the Tej o Mahalya temple, removed the idols and replaced them with cenotaphs and only add the inscriptions from the Koran, which took twenty two years to inscribe.&#8217;</p>
<p>I bring up the obvious objection to this theory. If such a magnificent structure existing at such an early date, there would have been mention of it in some chronicle, Hindu, Mughal or even in the accounts of earlier European travellers&#8230;there is no doubt whatsoever that work on the mausoleum began from the excavations of its foundation. A court historian summed it up, &#8216;&#8230;Plans were laid out for a magnificent building, and a dome of lofty foundation which&#8230;will, until the day of resurrection, remains a memorial to the sky high aspiration of his Majesty&#8230;and which for strength will display the firmness of the intentions of its builder&#8230;&#8221; <strong>In the Shadow of the Taj: A Portrait of Agra, Royina Grewal, p.177-79, Published by Penguin Books India, 2007</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="6"></a>Farman of Shah Jahan to Raja Jai Singh</h1>
<p>There are two Farmans of Shah Jahan to Raja Jai Singh, one is dated 20 September 1632 and requests Raja Jai Singh to expedite shipments of marble, almost certainly intended for Akbarabad, by advancing wages to the stonecutters and rental for carts, against reimbursement from the state treasury; the Raja is further enjoined to cooperate fully with the Emperor&#8217;s designated agent, Mulukshah, who has been dispatched to Amber. Construction of Taj Mahal had already begun months before this Farman, it was ordered to Jai Singh so as to ease the supply of white marbles from Makrana which was under Raja Jai Singh.</p>
<p>Another Farman is dated 3 February 1633, or less than five months after the preceding document. The Emperor again urges Raja Jai Singh to expedite the shipment of large quantities of marble from Makrana quarries, here specified as being for the &#8216;buildings&#8217; (ba-imarat-ha) at Akbarabad. A different agent, Sayyid Ilahdad, was been appointed to proceed to Amber to arrange for some 230 carts on reverse of the farman.</p>
<p><a href="http://thegreaterindia.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/20171102_140401.jpg" class="broken_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-1101" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/20171102_140401.jpg" alt="" width="443" height="713" /></a></p>
<p>&#8220;To the best of equals and grandees, the pride of peers and contemporaries, worthy of attention and favors, the sincere, loyal and devoted servant Raja Jai Singh. Having been distinguished and exalted by imperial favors, he should know that we have dispatched Mulukshah to Amber to have white marble brought out from the new quarry (kan-i-jadid).<br />
And We hearby order that, whatever the number of stone-cutters (sang-bur) and cart-on-hire (araba-i-kiraya) for loading the stone that may be required by the aforesaid Mulukshah, the Raja should make them available to him; and the wages of the stone-cutters and the rent-money of the carts, he will provide with funds from royal treasurer (tahwildar). It is imperative that the pride of peers and contemporaries should assist Mulukshah in all ways in this regard; and they should consider this a matter of utmost importance, and not deviate from this order.&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.163, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-1153" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/farman-2.png" alt="" width="419" height="612" /></p>
<p>&#8220;To the best of equals and grandees, the pride of peers and contemporaries, worthy of attention and favors, the sincere, loyal, devoted high-born (khanazad) servant Raja Jai Singh. Having been distinguished and exalted by imperial favors, he should know that, since large numbers of carts are required to transport white marble to the buildings (ba-imarat) at the Abode of the Caliphate Akbarabad, and since before this, an exalted and auspicious imperial order was issued addressed to the cream of equals concerning this, at this juncture, as added emphasis, We have appointed Sayyid Ilahdad to proceed to Amber and other places, as detailed herewith in the endorsement (dimn) [on the reverse side], and engage the required carts on hire (arab-i-kiraya), in accordance with the list written under each place (mahal). And whatever number of carts the Raja has previously made available from those places for carting the white marble from the Makrana quarry, having adjusted it against the total number, he should make the balance available to the aforesaid [Sayyid Ilahdad], who will escort them to the Makrana quarry…&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.165, by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Now the question is, if the palace was merely remodelled then why such large quantities were required as if building a completely new palace?</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="7"></a>Leakage in dome not cracks</h1>
<p>Another allegation put forth by right wingers is that a letter dated 1652 of Hazrat Aurangzeb mentioning that some repairs were needed for the tomb. And this is misrepresented by right wingers to show that why repairs were needed for the newly built Taj Mahal? Begley and Desai had clarified this long ago in their book that,</p>
<p>&#8220;Also published in this anthology is a new translation of the well-known letter of Prince Aurangzeb, dated Muharram 1063/December 1652, mentioning that some repairs were needed to the tomb, which had leaked in several places during the previous rainy season. When certain lapses in the Persian text of this letter are corrected, it seems clear that the problem with the dome was water leakage and not cracks, as some writers have construed this passage.&#8221;<br />
<strong>Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb: An Anthology of seventeenth century Mughal and European Documentary Sources, Introduction xxxi, by Wayne Edison Begley, Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989.<br />
</strong></p>
<p>The Farman shows that,<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-1154" src="http://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/farman-translated.png" alt="" width="328" height="529" /></p>
<p>The Farman translated by Begley and Desai reads as follows,</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;The building (&#8216;imarat) of this shrine enclosure (hazira) of holy foundation are still firm and strong (ustwar), exactly as they were completed under [His Majesty&#8217;s] illumined presence, except that the dome over the fragment sepulchre (marqad) leaks during the rainy season in two places on the north side. Likewise, the four arched portals (pishtaq), several of the recessed alcoves (shahnashinam) of the second story (martaba), the four small domes, the four northern vestibules (suffa) and subchambers of the seven arched plinth (kursi-i-habtdar) have become dampened (darnarn). The marble-covered terrace of the large dome has leaked in two or three places during this past rainy season, and has been repaired. Let us see what happens in the coming rainy season. The domes of the mosque and the assembly-hall (jama&#8217;at-khana) leaked in the rainy season as well, and have also been repaired.&#8221;<br />
<strong>as mentioned in Taj Mahal: The Illumined Tomb, p.175 by Wayne Edison Begley and Ziyaud-Din A. Desai, Published by Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture, 1989</strong></p>
<p>Now it clearly states that everything is same as it was completed under Shah Jahan. And except for some leakage there was no crack or major repair needed as presented by right wingers. There is also one important sentence which you may have missed, it&#8217;s the mention of leakage of mosque and assembly hall. Do right wingers claim that the mosque too was built by Raja Man Singh? If not then its leaking along with the Taj Mahal proves that they were constructed at the same time.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="9"></a>Shivling in closed 22 rooms of Taj Mahal?</h1>
<p>Another claim made by right wingers is that there are 22 rooms which are sealed with a purpose and if opened will prove the theory of Taj Mahal being a Hindu temple. ABP News made a expose on this issue in their show named Viral Sach in which they questioned two historians and a former director of Archaelogical Survey of India and all of them said that there are no rooms in Taj Mahal however former director of Archaelogical Survey of India Dr. Amrendra Nath said that there are no such rooms but there exists cells in the plinth which are closed for security purpose and they are opened daily for cleaning. Watch the video,</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJnZtVER7nE</p>
<p>Link for the video<br />
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJnZtVER7nE</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<h1><a name="8"></a>Conclusion</h1>
<p>If it took approx. 20 years for Shah Jahan just to convert it into a mausoleum then it may have taken nearly a century for Man Singh to build such marvellous palace. Around 30 villages were endowed for the maintenance of Taj Mahal which includes monthly salaries, expenses of food and drink which have been set apart for the keepers, attendants, inmates and servants of the palace. So how Raja Man Singh or Jai Singh maintained their &#8216;Tejo Mahalya&#8217;? How many villages did they endow for its maintenance? This needs to be answered by right wingers. The whole argument of right wingers is based on the sentence of Abd al-Lahori that four palaces were given for the Manzil or Haveli of Raja Jai Singh, though we have already read that a tract of land (zamini) was chosen for the construction of Taj Mahal and foundation was dug up to the water table, in Badshahnama page 403 he says that &#8216;va zamin-e dar nihayat rifat va nuzzat hat ki junoob roya aan mishra jame ast&#8217;, which roughly translates as a piece of land was selected for her [Mumtaz Mahal] burial.</p>
<p>Europeans such as Jesuit Father Monserrate visited Agra several times between the years 1580-82 but never mentioned about a building like Taj Mahal. Sir Thomas Roe who gave detailed description of Agra never mentioned about Taj Mahal. Franciso Pelsaert the Dutch trader who visited Agra in 1620-27 enumerated the gardens and palaces made no mention of any building like Taj Mahal. Ralph Fitch came to Agra in 1585 and left a detailed description of the city and he too doesn&#8217;t speak of the Tejo Mahalya or Taj Mahal. William Hawkins stayed in Agra for about five years 1608-13, He described the tomb of Akbar at Sikandara but makes no mention to any building of the Taj Mahal&#8217;s stature.</p>
<p>Peter Mundy lived in Agra between 1631-2 that is prior and during the construction of the Taj Mahal and witnessed its construction. Father Sebastien Manrique who visited Agra in 1641 witnessed the construction of Taj Mahal and says that it was still incomplete. Jean Baptise Tavernier visited Agra in 1640-1 and witnessed the construction of Taj Mahal.</p>
<p>Niccolao Manucci though I am not sure, he visited Agra after the completion of Taj Mahal. Francois Bernier visited Agra after the completion of Taj Mahal and mentions about it in detail. Jean De Thevenot who also visited Agra after completion of Taj Mahal mentions about it and he inquired about the Taj Mahal from the locals who told him that it took twenty years to build it but no one told about any such thing like a temple being converted into a tomb.</p>
<p>So we see that, foreign travellers who visited Agra before construction of Taj Mahal makes no mention about it, while those who visited Agra during and after the construction of Taj Mahal mentioned about it. As I said earlier, right wingers are questioning the account of these travellers just like the lawyer of villain in a Bollywood movie questions eye witnesses rather than providing historical documents or any evidence for their claims. They need to answer exactly when Tejo Mahalya was build? Even P.N Oak changed his own statement on this issue, who were the architects? In exact which year was the construction commenced? How many labours it took to build Tejo Mahalya? How much it did it cost? Mughal documents even mentions the name of calligraphers, supervisors, goldsmith, artisans, cost of specific structure and in which year it was build why no such document exists about Tejo Mahalya? From where did Raja Man Singh get the marble for the construction of Tejo Mahalya? Mughal documents about large quantities of marble being transported from Makrana exists, why such large quantities were required just for remodelling of a Hindu temple into a tomb? Why Raja Jai Singh was silent about a temple being converted into a tomb? Why didn&#8217;t he revolt? Did Raja Jai Singh come from a branch of Hinduism who worshipped Shiva? Why didn&#8217;t he mention about his ancestral palace or a temple being converted into a tomb? Why no foreign traveller mentions about Taj Mahal before Shah Jahan started building it? Why Tejo Mahalya&#8217;s architectural style is so strikingly similar to Islamic architecture? Why no Hindu building such as Taj Mahal exists prior to the advent of Muslim rulers? And most important question, Why no historical document exists about Tejo Mahalya?</p>
<p>Right wingers need to answer these questions before even claiming the Taj Mahal to be a Hindu temple or Rajput palace. Right wingers have stooped so low of doing character assassination of Shah Jahan with fake stories like he killed Mumtaz Mahal&#8217;s first husband to marry her, whereas Shah Jahan was the first husband of Mumtaz Mahal. They fell in love and their marriage was fixed when Shah Jahan was 15 and Mumtaz was 14 and they were engaged on 5<sup>th</sup> of April 1607 and marriage took place 5 years after i.e. on 10<sup>th</sup> May 1612. Mumtaz was his third wife and he married 2 wives to strengthen political ties. Another allegation is that Shah Jahan married the sister of Mumtaz Mahal after her death which is not true, according to historians, Shahjahan gave up all lavish food, clothes, he wept so much that he got eye problems, even one of the traveller Thevenot writes that his grief over his dead wife almost cost him his life. And one more allegation in order to depict Shah Jahan as a ruthless ruler is that he cut off the hands of 20 thousand workers so that no such palace shall be made after that. The fact is that this is nothing more than a tale which has no truth in it. So all these facts only proves that the Taj Mahal is indeed a mausoleum build by Shah Jahan for his beloved wife Mumtaz Mahal.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><a href="#top">top</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/11/03/taj-mahal-hindu-temple/" data-wpel-link="internal">Is Taj Mahal a Hindu Temple?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 06:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[braham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contradiction in vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scholar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ishwar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prabhupada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prajapati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebuttal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refuted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi &#160; The Qur’an states that Allah has created everything, the Bible states that God has created it, every religion whether Islam or Christianity takes a firm stand about the creator of the universe. But Vedas seems to be confused as to who created the universe. Vedas doesn’t answer who is the &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Qur’an states that Allah has created everything, the Bible states that God has created it, every religion whether Islam or Christianity takes a firm stand about the creator of the universe. But Vedas seems to be confused as to who created the universe. Vedas doesn’t answer who is the creator. There is no unanimous statement about who really created the universe among Hindus, some say Shiva created this entire universe, some say Vishnu or his avatars created it, some claim Brahma created it, All these stories are of Puranas and Upanishads, but we have to see only what the Vedas says about the creator because Vedas are the oldest scripture of Hinduism. Vedas also makes blunder about the process of creation. I won’t be explaining Vedic verses briefly, verses are pretty easy to understand. Readers themselves can draw conclusions after reading the verses. I am using Hindi translations of Swami Karpatri, Shri Ram Sharma and Shripad Damodar.</p>
<p><span id="more-1192"></span></p>
<p>Veda mentions different gods as the creator of the universe, Rig Veda 2.20.1; 2.13.5 says Indra created the earth, Rig Veda 10.82.1 and Yajur Veda 17.25 says Vishwakarma created the heaven and earth, Rig Veda 10.190.3 says Dhatar created the heaven, earth, sun and the moon. Atharva Veda 9.5.20 says that the breast of the God Aja became the earth, we read in Purusha Sukta that the feet of the lord became the earth, all these Vedic verses contradict each other. Atharva Veda 13.1.6 states that Rohita created the heaven and earth. A verse states that Prajapati created the universe, another verse in Yajur Veda 14.30 states that Prajapati prayed to a Divine Speech and thence earth and heaven were produced. Some also say the creation took place after the association of father and daughter mentioned in Rig Veda 10.61.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Who created living creatures?</strong></p>
<p>Vedas is confused about who created the humans or all creatures, It’s mentioned in Yajur Veda</p>
<p>Yajur Veda 14.28 With one they praised; creatures were produced…With five they praised; beings were created</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="465" height="154" class="wp-image-7269" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra1.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201.png 465w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-300x99.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 465px) 100vw, 465px" /></p>
<p>According to scholars, Prajapati prayed to a divine speech and after that creatures were produced, So Prajapati is the creator of living beings here. Rig Veda says it were Vedic deities Indra and Varuna who created all living creatures,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 7.82.5 O Indra-Varuna, as ye created all these creatures of the world by your surpassing might…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="443" height="167" class="wp-image-7270" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra2.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1.png 443w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-1-300x113.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 443px) 100vw, 443px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Atharva Vedas has another story, it says Vedic god Rohita created the creatures,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 13.1.52 Rohita made the earth to be his altar, heaven his Dakshina. Then heat he took for Agni, and with rain for molten butter he [Rohita] created every living thing [or universe].</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let’s analyse the Purusha Sukta. Purusha Sukta is often quoted to show the process of creation. Some Hindu scholars even say that scientists must read Purusha Sukta to know about the creation and cosmos, they say this Sukta is very unique. I can’t figure out what’s so unique about this Sukta. Later I found that its uniqueness lies in its riddles, It has so many contradictions. It’s about gods sacrificing Purusha and each of his body part becomes the creation. The word Purusha here may or may not denote Man. Purusha is literally translated as Man, but majority of scholars translates it (in this verse) as Supreme Soul (God), according to Mahidhara and Sayana it is Spirit or Man, other scholars translates it as Almighty God and Universe. If Purusha is the Almighty god then how come the Almighty God (Purusha) himself was born? Veda says,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.5 From him Viraj was born; again Purusa from Viraj was born…</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7271" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra3.png?w=625" width="570" height="139" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2.png 418w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-2-300x73.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The word Viraj or Virat here is translated by some as universe. But scholars have different opinion on this word. Majority of scholars including Sayana and Mahidhara say it’s an egg. Some say it’s the egg from which the universe or Men were born, some also say it’s known as Adi Purusa. The word Viraj occurs in Atharva Veda 11.4.12 as Prana (Vital Spirit), in Atharva Veda 9.2.5 Viraj is translated as milch cow, and by Arya Samaj scholars as Splendid Speech [Goddess]. Some interpret Rig Veda 10.90.5 as, The almighty God created Viraj, and Viraj then created the Men (Purusha) or living creatures, they translate the latter word Purusha literally as Men. This is wrong since the creation of men and other living beings occurs in verses 8, 10 and 12. There is also a reference (Manu 3.195) which shows that Viraj had sons. Maharishi Manu also makes blunder about the creation which contradicts Vedas also, but on this Viraj issue he tries to make it simple saying that it was Brahma who produced Viraj, He writes</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 1.31-32 But for the sake of the prosperity of the worlds he caused the Brahmana, the Kshatriya, the Vaisya, and the Sudra to proceed from his mouth, his arms, his thighs, and his feet. Dividing his own body, the Lord became half male and half female; with that (female) he produced Virag.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So this affirms the statement of some scholars who say that Purusha is the unborn Almighty God and from him Viraj was born. But it makes the situation more complex because Vedas states in the beginning only Viraj was present and from him Purusha was born,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 19.6.9 In the beginning rose Viraj: Purusha from Viraj was born. As soon as he was born he spread westward and eastward o’er the earth.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="574" height="62" class="wp-image-7272" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra4.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3.png 574w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-3-300x32.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 574px) 100vw, 574px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now this is senseless and as complicated as the saying ”What came first the chicken or the egg?” This is a clear contradiction, because Purusha is unborn they say and from Purusha, Viraj was born. But this verse states the In the beginning rose (Sambhavat) Viraj and from him Purusha was born. To strengthen my argument I would like to quote next two verses of Atharva Veda 19.6.9 which would also clear the mist,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Atharva Veda 19.6.10-11 When Gods performed the sacrifice with Purusha as their offering. Spring was the butter, summer was the fuel, autumn was the gift. That sacrifice, first-born Purusha, they hallowed with the sprinkled Rains. The Deities, the Sadhyas, all the Vasus sacrificed with him.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="602" height="141" class="wp-image-7273" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra5.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4.png 602w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-4-300x70.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So this shows that the sacrificed Purusha was born from Viraj. Purusha was the first to take birth from Viraj. So how is it possible that the Almighty God (Purusha) himself was born from an egg (Viraj)?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Who was Sacrificed?</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.6 When Gods prepared the sacrifice with Purusa as their offering, Its oil was spring, the holy gift was autumn; summer was the wood.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="109" class="wp-image-7274" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra6.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-5-300x54.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Krishna Yajur Veda,</p>
<p>Krishna Yajur Veda 6.3.5 The Sadhya gods were in this world and nothing else living. They offered Agni as a sacrifice to Agni [Fire], for they found nothing else to offer; thence indeed these creatures were born; in that he casts the fire on the fire after producing it, (it serves for) the propagation of offspring.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>How the creation of universe (or of earth) took place?</strong></p>
<p>While Purusha Sukta is often quoted, The Rig Veda 10.72 hymn is often ignored by the scholars. Both have similarity and difference. The similarity is that both these Suktas talk about how the creation took place and the difference is that both these Suktas give a complete different picture about creation of universe. According to Purusha Sukta the earth was gendered from the Almighty god’s feet (Rigved 10.90.14), while the 72<sup>nd</sup> hymn states that the earth was born from a tree,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.72.1-4 Let us proclaim with a clear voice the generations of the gods (the divine company), who, when their praises are recited, look (favourably on the worshipper) in this latter age. Brahmanaspati filled these (generations of the gods) with breath as a blacksmith (his bellows) in the first age of the gods the existent was born of the non-existent. In the first age of the gods the existent was born of the non-existent; after that the quarters (of the horizon) were born, and after them the upward-growing (trees). The earth was born from the upward-growing (tree), the quarters were born from the earth; Daksha was born from Aditi, and afterwards Aditi from Daksha. – Tr. Wilson</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="467" height="277" class="wp-image-7275" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra7.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6.png 467w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-6-300x178.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Founder of Arya Samaj Swami Dayanand Saraswati argued against the creation of universe out of nothing. He criticized the Qur’an’s concept of creation out of nothing which is similar to this 72<sup>nd</sup> hymn of Rigved Mandal 10. Hindu scholars gave more importance to the Purusha Sukta and rejected the 72<sup>nd</sup> Sukta. Both these Suktas of the same Rig Veda are contradictory.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>So who really created the universe?</strong></p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.90.6 When <strong>Gods</strong> prepared the sacrifice with Purusa as their offering, Its oil was spring, the holy gift was autumn; summer was the wood.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="494" height="90" class="wp-image-7276" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra8.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7.png 494w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-7-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p>Vedas doesn’t give the list of gods who sacrificed Purusha. But it’s mentioned in Atharva Veda 13.1.55 that Rohita brought the world which rose from the sacrifice (of Purusha). It either means that Rohita alone sacrificed Purusha or Rohita was among the gods or Rishis who sacrificed Purusha. Rohita is considered a sage in that verse. It’s mentioned in Rigved,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.129.6-7 Who verily knows and who can here declare it, whence it was born and whence comes this creation? The Gods are later than this world’s production. Who knows then whence it first came into being? He, the first origin of this creation, whether he formed it all or did not form it, Whose eye controls this world in highest heaven, <strong>he verily knows it, or perhaps he knows not</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="448" height="351" class="wp-image-7277" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.png" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/081514_0918_vediccontra9.png?w=625" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.png 448w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8-300x235.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 448px) 100vw, 448px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda’s English translation,</p>
<p>”[6] Who knew the way? Who there declared Whence this arose? Projection whence? <strong>For after this projection came the gods</strong>. Who therefore knew indeed, came out this whence?</p>
[7] This projection whence arose, Whether held or whether not, He the ruler in the supreme sky, of this He, O Sharman! knows, or know not He perchance”- Rig Veda 10.129.6-7, Tr. Swami Vivekananda. [Source: <a href="http://www.swamivivekananda.org.in/main/e-library/hymns/the-hymn-on-creation/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.swamivivekananda.org.in/main/e-library/hymns/the-hymn-on-creation/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When Gods are later than this world’s production then who sacrificed Purusha? As we read in Purusha Sukta that it were the Gods who sacrificed Purusha. According to Vedas It was only after the sacrifice of Purusha that entire universe including this world came into existence. Manu also alludes that the Rishis were born after the creation of universe (Manu 1.34-35). So how is it possible that this creation took place without the gods? And who really sacrificed Purusha then?</p>
<p>When the Vedas which was believed by every Hindu god as highest authoritative text doesn’t have the answer about who really created the universe, then why do you believe it to be the word of god? Some may try to twist and turn these verses to hide the fallacies of Vedas, but truth will remain truth. They may deceive themselves but intellectuals will definitely find the truth. It is clear that the composer or God of Vedas is not the creator. Vedas juggles about the creator, but it’s not difficult to find the real creator of this world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/15/vedic-contradiction-how-the-creation-came-into-existence/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Contradiction: How the Creation came into Existence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Response to No Corruption in Vedas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Responses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindu scrupture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interpolated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kashyap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu smriti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preserved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebuttal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rishi 999]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scholars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sukta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad The &#8216;once upon a time&#8217; stories do not appeal to me anymore. Pick up any such story and it is a pure fiction. No wonder kids love such stories. Agniveer&#8217;s latest response (should it be even called a response) is purely fictional, a castle of lies to deceive the ordinary people &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to No Corruption in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Ibn Muhammad</p>
<p>The &#8216;once upon a time&#8217; stories do not appeal to me anymore. Pick up any such story and it is a pure fiction. No wonder kids love such stories. Agniveer&#8217;s latest response (should it be even called a response) is purely fictional, a castle of lies to deceive the ordinary people and a desperate attempt to repair his lost credibility. The so-called response deals more with teaching ways of mockery than a serious response to our research article. By addressing about half of the article to senseless insults, he hoped to distract his blind followers from the seriousness of our article. He invents some &#8216;Panchatantra&#8217; stories which have no space in a scholarly discussion. I do not have this time and energy to write similar stuff. I only concern myself to what is being said, instead of who is saying it.</p>
<p><span id="more-901"></span></p>
<p>The lies of Agniveer start outright when he says,</p>
<p>A recent attempt has been by writing articles based on extremely outdated claims to prove that Vedas are also textually corrupted. <strong>We initially chose to ignore this long-rejected stupid research.</strong> We thought that someone else would counter it along with flat-earth theory while we focus on other prominent tasks. But considering the widespread promotion that is being provided to this viewpoint by petro-dollar power holders, we thought to have at least a short analysis debunking the myth. Because in an era of misinformation, truth is often nothing but a lie shouted thousand times!</p>
<p>Did Agniveer really ignore my article? I published my article on March 16, 2011. There was a consternation in the Vedic camp. See the comments section of Agniveer. Then, I made a video on the main points of my article. The video can be seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ueydb0yQN_g" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">here<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. Since Agniveer is no scholar of the Vedas, he must have tried first to somehow refute me. When he couldn&#8217;t he appealed more knowledgeable Arya Samajis for help. Agniveer started a new separate thread in the Arya Samaj community on orkut. Here is the link to the thread.</p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131015022445/http:/www.orkut.co.in/CommMsgs?cmm=146924&amp;tid=5600429116996922782" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.orkut.co.in/CommMsgs?cmm=146924&amp;tid=5600429116996922782<br />
<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>As you can see Agniveer desperately appealing for help from his associates. The associates, being more wise than Agniveer, felt the gravity of my arguments. One associate advised Agniveer not to be hasty and come to Bilaspur and learn the Vedas properly. But Alas, Agniveer, who is an IIT pass-out considered it below his dignity to go and learn the Vedas properly. The hasty rebuttal he has published on his website clearly exposes his shallow knowledge of the Vedas.</p>
<p>You can also notice in the link given above, that there is a lot of infighting among Hindus on the exact nature of shaakhaas (branches). They started to cut each others viewpoints and poke fun at each other. If the very brains to whom Agniveer went begging for help could not solve the problem, you can imagine of what quality the borrowed rebuttal of Agniveer would be.</p>
<p>Agniveer is so scared of our website that he dared not mention the <a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/textual-corruption-of-the-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal"><strong>source article</strong></a> which he was refuting. He never mentioned my name. This speaks volumes of the spirit inculcated in him by the Vedas. At least he should have let his audience know what he is refuting. Instead he chose to paraphrase my arguments so that they look ordinary. Agniveer hopes to keep his blind followers in the dark. But for how long. The wind of truth will soon blow apart the structure of lies.</p>
<p>Ignoring the unnecessary rants of Agniveer, I would directly go into the subject and expose the asinine arguments of Agniveer.</p>
<p><strong>What is the total number of Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer has resorted to mighty deception to somehow do away with this vital question which will shake the very foundations of the Arya Dharma/Hinduism call it what you like. It seems that this IIT pass-out has to be taught the fundamentals of counting. Let me give you an example, to rip apart his tapestry of deception.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>If you consider only knowledge, Vedas is only 1. If you consider <strong>Para and Apara</strong> knowledge (liberating and mundane knowledge), then Vedas are 2. If you focus on <strong>Knowledge, Action and Contemplation</strong>, Vedas are 3. If you consider <strong>Rik, Yajuh, Sama, Atharva</strong>, Vedas are 4. If you consider each mandala of Rigveda as separate, then there are 10 Rigvedas. Similarly we have 40 Yajurvedas. If you take each mantra as a different Veda, you have more than 20,000 Vedas.</p>
<p>So number does not matter. They all point to same set of mantras.</p>
<p>What deception?</p>
<p>Consider the letters of the English alphabet. How many letters are there in the English alphabet? Every good student will answer 26. But one IIT pass-out says, &#8220;it depends&#8221;. If you consider only <strong>alphabet</strong> there is only 1. If you consider  <strong>vowels and consonants </strong>there are 2. If you consider <strong>&#8216;the English alphabet&#8217;</strong> there are 17. If you consider <strong>a, e, i, o, u</strong> there are 5. If you consider <strong>b, c, d, f, g, h, j, k, l, m, n, p, q, r, s, t, v, w, x, y, z</strong> there are 21.</p>
<p>So number does not matter. They all point to the same set of letters.</p>
<p>Does not this IIT pass-out need to be sacked from his job immediately if he is employed? Should not his degree be declared fraudulent? Is this man not a danger to society who can sell his integrity to defend some primitive texts? He cannot even differentiate between the words &#8216;number&#8217; and &#8216;type&#8217;. This  simpleton IIT pass-out has been so shocked by our research that he has lost all sense. I had  heard a joke on engineers, but did not know that engineer was the great Agniveer himself.</p>
<p><strong>Ques: Prove that 2/10=2.</strong></p>
<p>Art student : Out of syllabus<br />
Commerce student : Question hi galat hai<br />
Medical student : It&#8217;s strange yaar, ye kaise ho sakta hai?<br />
Agniveer : It is very easy</p>
<p>2=two<br />
10=ten,</p>
<p>Therefore,  2/10 = two/ten</p>
<p>cancelling (t) we get</p>
<p>wo/en—- (1)</p>
<p>W=23rd letter of the alphabet<br />
O=15th letter of the alphabet<br />
E=5th letter of the alphabet<br />
N=14th letter of the alphabet</p>
<p>therefore,</p>
<p>w+o=23+15=38<br />
&amp; e+n=5+14=19<br />
.<br />
Substituting these values in (1)</p>
<p>wo/en = 38/19 = 2<br />
<strong><br />
Hence proved!</strong></p>
<p>And the blind followers of Agniveer shout, &#8220;Hail Agniveer Ji&#8221;.</p>
<p>Let me remind Agniveer that when I asked the question, <strong>&#8216;What is the total number of Vedas?&#8217;</strong>, I meant <strong>&#8216;What is the total number of Veda Samhitas?&#8217;</strong> By the title <strong>&#8216;Textual corruption of the Vedas&#8217;</strong> is implied <strong>&#8216;Textual corruption of the Veda Samhitas&#8217;</strong>.</p>
<p>Having said that let us post mortem the dead refutation of Agniveer.</p>
<p>Agniveer has conveniently evaded the testimony of Mahabharata that Vedas were stolen from Brahma, demonstrating their insecurity. It also proved that Vedas were NOT memorized. Agniveer has ignored this. After all Mahabharata has also been written by his own ancestors. Is it not an insult to his ancestors, to accept their one work and reject the other?</p>
<p><strong>The Number of Veda Samhitas</strong></p>
<p>Traditionally the number of Veda Samhitas has been fixed as 4 viz. Rigveda, Yajurveda, Samaveda and Atharvaveda. But this reply does not tell the whole story. Why? Things will become more clear when you will read all of this article.</p>
<ol>
<li>The Rigveda, containing hymns to be recited by the hotr;</li>
<li>The Yajurveda, containing formulas to be recited by the adhvaryu or officiating priest;</li>
<li>The Samaveda, containing formulas to be sung by the udgātr.</li>
<li>The Atharvaveda, a collection of spells and incantations, apotropaic charms and speculative hymns.</li>
</ol>
<p>One information must be remembered. The words Rigveda, Yajurveda, Samaveda and Atharvaveda are NEVER mentioned in the Veda Samhitas. All these names have been given by Brahmins to identify the books. The earlier terms referred to the different styles of composition, They were:</p>
<ol>
<li>ricah, stanzas of praise</li>
<li>yajunsh, liturgical stanzas and formulas</li>
<li>saman, melodies</li>
<li>atharvangirasah, blessings and curses.</li>
</ol>
<p>But the collection which now goes by the name of Rig-veda contains in its later parts &#8216;blessings and curses&#8217;, as well as &#8216;stanzas of praise&#8217;, together with most of the stanzas which form the text to the saman melodies of the Sama-veda. Similarly the Atharva-veda contains ricah, &#8216;stanzas of praise, and yajunshi, &#8216;liturgical stanzas&#8217; mostly worked over for its own purposes, as well as its characteristic &#8216;blessings and curses&#8217;. The Yajur-veda also contains matter of the other Vedic types in addition to liturgical formulae. The Sama-veda is merely a collection of certain ricah or &#8216;stanzas of praise&#8217;, taken with variations and additions from the Rig-veda, and set to tunes indicated by musical notations.</p>
<p>So each Veda Samhita is a mixture of all types of mantras. Thus, Rigveda can be called Samaveda , Atharvaveda and vice-versa. Atharvaveda can be called Rigveda or Yajurveda. Same is the case with other Veda Samhitas.</p>
<p>Now to our burning question,<strong> what is the total number of Veda Samhitas?</strong></p>
<p>Let me use the statement of Patanjali Rishi as the base to solve this question. In the Mahabhashya, he says,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7536" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-33.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp1.png" width="452" height="116" /></p>
<p>The four Vedas, <strong>along-with their parts</strong> diffuse into many forms. There are 101 Shakhas of Yajurveda, 1000 of Samaveda, 21 of Rigveda and 9 of Atharvaveda.</p>
<p>Adding these numbers we get a figure of 1131 Shaakhaas. Agniveer has not responded to this basic question in a clear and coherent manner.  His dilemma can be understood. This is an issue which shakes the foundations of Vedic Dharma.. The Guru of Agniveer, when asked about this issue said,</p>
<p><strong>Q. How many Shaakhaas (branches) are there of the Veda?</strong></p>
<p>A. Eleven hundred and twenty-seven.</p>
<p><strong>Q. What are Shaakhaas (branches)? </strong></p>
<p>A. The expositions are called shaakhaas.</p>
<p><strong>Q. We hear of learned people speaking of the different parts of the Veda as shaakhaas. Are they wrong?</strong></p>
<p>A. If you think over it a little, you will understand that they are in the wrong, because all the Shaakhaas are attributed to Rishis such as Ashwalaayani and others, whilst the authorship of the Veda is ascribed to God. It other words, as the author of the four Vedas is believed to be God, so are Rishis held to be the authors of the shaakhaas, such as Ashwalaayani. And besides, all the shaakhaas take Veda texts and expound them, while in the Veda texts only are given. Therefore, the four Vedas – the books of Divine revelation – are like the trunk of a tree, whose branches (shaakhaas) are the books, such as Ashwalaayani, <strong>written by Rishis and not revealed by God</strong>… [Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 7]
<p>There is not a shred of evidence to prove that there are 1127 Shaakhaas of the Veda.  Patanjali Rishi CLEARLY says 1131 Shaakhaas.No classical text mentions 1127 Shaakhaas. The Swami is clearly lying here.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>Oh No. Not again. Branch refers to a particular recension style of Vedas to emphasize certain aspects and making it relevant to existing time and society. <strong>Branches or Shakhas are not eternal</strong>. But original Vedas have been preserved as they were even till today.</p>
<p>The quotation of Maharishi Patanjali is very clear. <strong>The four Vedas are made of 1131 parts and these parts are the Shaakhaas and these Shaakhaas include those which are held as originals by Agniveer.</strong> Shaakal Shaakha (present Rigveda) is already included in the 21 Shaakhas of Rigveda. So, according to the confession of Agniveer even that is not eternal.</p>
<p>However, the answer to the question, &#8216;What is the total number of Veda samhitas?&#8217; is very simple. There are 1131 Veda Samhitas which on the basis of the mantra types are divided into 4. The 1131 Shaakhaas can be understood as 1131 versions of Vedas. To make it simple for you, Rigveda has 21 VERSIONS, Yajurveda has 101 VERSIONS, Samaveda has 1000 VERSIONS and Atharvaveda has 9 VERSIONS. The bogus claims of Agniveer are buried by this simple FACT that<strong> each Shaakhaa had its own Samhita, Brahman, Aranyak and Upanishad.</strong> So dear readers, what does this tell you? Either Agniveer does not know his own religion or he is lying. If it is the later it is devilish and if it is the former it is inexcusable.</p>
<p>Out of these 1131 VEDA SAMHITAS 1120 Samhitas are lost. In other words, 99% of the Vedas are LOST.</p>
<p>Notice that Swami Dayanand Saraswati says that Shaakhaas are expositions of the ORIGINAL Vedas. But Agniveer is then lying when he says,</p>
<p>&#8220;Now some fools argue that why are original Vedas are also called by name of Shakhas. The answer is that the name of Shakha is derived from the Rishi who ensured its preservation from generation to generation. Some Rishis chose to promote the variations so as to propagate their meaning among masses and specialized students. Some volunteered to continue preserving the original Vedas so that more Shakhas could be created in future. Why should we not acknowledge these Rishis? Hence Shaakal chose to preserve the Rigveda, Madhyandin chose to preserve Yajurveda, Shaunak chose to preserve Atharveveda and Kauthum chose to protect Samaveda. These refer not only to individuals but entire traditions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Can Agniveer bring any valid proof to justify his claim? There is not a shred of evidence to prove what Agniveer said. Where do classical scholars of Hinduism claim that only Shaakal Samhita is the original? That is a challenge to Agniveer. If Shaakal Rishi preserved the &#8216;original&#8217; Rigveda (Shaakal Shaakha), why are the Samhitas, Brahmans, Aranyaks and Upanishads different for each Shaakha? Agniveer is compelled to promote unorthodox ideas to defend his sect.</p>
<p>Take the following examples of <strong>Rigveda Shaakhas</strong>.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Shakha</strong></td>
<td><strong>Samhita</strong></td>
<td><strong>Brahmana</strong></td>
<td><strong>Aranyaka</strong></td>
<td><strong>Upanishad</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Shaakala</strong></td>
<td>Shaakala Samhita</td>
<td>Aitareya Brahmana</td>
<td>Aitareya Aranyaka</td>
<td>Aitareya Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Baashkala</strong></td>
<td>Kaushitaki Samhita</td>
<td>Kaushitaki Brahmana</td>
<td>Manuscript exists</td>
<td>Kaushitaki Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Shankhayana</strong></td>
<td>Sankhayana Samhita</td>
<td>Shankhayana Brahmana</td>
<td>Shankhyana Aranyaka</td>
<td>edited as a part of the Aranyaka</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Shukla Yajurveda Shaakhaas</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Shakha</strong></td>
<td><strong>Samhita</strong></td>
<td><strong>Brahmana</strong></td>
<td><strong>Aranyaka</strong></td>
<td><strong>Upanishad</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Madhyandina (VSM)</strong></td>
<td>Vajasneyi Samhita (Madhyandin) <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131015022445/http:/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deshastha_Brahmin" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><br />
<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></td>
<td>Madhyandina Shatapatha (SBM)</td>
<td>survives as Shatapatha XIV.1-8, with accents.</td>
<td>Brihadaranyaka Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Kanva (VSK)</strong></td>
<td>Vajasneyi Samhita (Kanva)</td>
<td>Kanva Shatapatha (SBK)(different from madhyandina)</td>
<td>survives as book XVII of SBK</td>
<td>Brihadaranyaka Upanishad (different from above)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Krishna Yajurveda Shaakhaas</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Shakha</strong></td>
<td><strong>Samhita</strong></td>
<td><strong>Brahmana</strong></td>
<td><strong>Aranyaka</strong></td>
<td><strong>Upanishad</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Taittiriya</strong></td>
<td>Taittiriya Samhita</td>
<td>Taittiriya Brahmana and Vadhula Br. (part of Vadhula Srautrasutra)</td>
<td>Taittiriya Aranyaka</td>
<td>Taittiriya Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Maitrayani</strong></td>
<td>Maitrayani Samhita</td>
<td>Not Available</td>
<td>virtually same as the Upanishad</td>
<td>Maitrayaniya Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Caraka-Katha</strong></td>
<td>Katha Samhita</td>
<td><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131015022445/http:/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Citation_needed" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right"><sup> </sup><span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></td>
<td>Katha Aranyaka (almost the entire text from a solitary manuscript)</td>
<td>Kathaka Upanishad, Katha-Shiksha Upanishad</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&nbsp;</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>As you can see, each Shaakha has its own Samhita. There is no one Samhita. Agniveer, therefore, is clearly lying on this important issue and why should he not lie when his guru, Moolshanker, condones lying to defend their Dharma. Swami Danayanad commenting on Shakanacharya says,</p>
<p>&#8220;Now it must be understood that if it was the belief of Shankar that God and the human soul were identical and that the world was an illusion, it was not good; <strong>but if he had avowed this doctrine simply in order to refute Jainism more successfully, it was a little good.</strong>&#8221; [Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 11]
<p>So. Agniveer has already got his license to deceive.</p>
<p>Let me elaborate on the nature of the disputes between various Shaakhaas to bury Agniveer&#8217;s deceptive arguments once and for all.</p>
<p><strong>Nature of Disputes between various Shaakhaas with special reference to Yajurveda</strong></p>
<p>Comparing all the available manuscripts of the Yajurveda, we come to know that they are NOT mere expositions of the so-called originals. Rather, they contain many different mantras than those found in others. Broadly classified, Yajurveda has two branches, Krishna and Shukla. The former is predominant in South India and the latter in North India. At the time of Patanjali Rishi, the Kathaka Samhita was predominant as stated in Mahabhashya 4:3:101.</p>
<p>The different Samhitas differ in the number of mantras, arrangement of mantras, etc. Following is the brief list of the variations:</p>
<p>1. The very first mantras of all Samhitas are variant. For example see the image below.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="545" height="586" class="wp-image-7537" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-34.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-34.png 545w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-34-279x300.png 279w" sizes="(max-width: 545px) 100vw, 545px" /></p>
<p>2. The last mantra of these Samhitas is also different.</p>
<p>3. There is huge difference in the total number of mantras of all these Samhitas. Vajasneyi Samhita  (Madhyandin) has 1974 mantras, Taittiriya has 1018, Maitrayani has 458, and Katha has 640 mantras.</p>
<p>4. More than 50% of Vajasneyi Samhita is imported from Rigveda. Swami Dayanand, has accepted this fact in the 33rd and 34th chapters of his Yajurveda translation. On this basis, the Vedic scholars are of the opinion that intermixing of the mantras of Yajurveda and Rigveda has actually broken the Yajurveda chain. The mutual coherence of the themes of Yajurveda has been lost and by extension the meanings have also been lost.</p>
<p>All these differences between various Samhitas of Yajurveda reveal the fact that these Samhitas are not the expositions of a so-called original Veda. Rather, these are different versions of one Yajurveda floating around. The true version cannot be found and the mutual rivalry between these versions is not hidden. The followers of one Samhita used to condemn the followers of another Samhita. For example, Shatapath Brahmana 1:7:1:3 condemns the recitation of Taittiriya Samhita.</p>
<p>&#8220;They then let the calves join their mothers. He thereupon touches (each) calf (in order to drive it away from the cow), with the formula , &#8216;The winds are ye!&#8217;–for, indeed, it is this wind that here blows, it is this (wind) that makes swell all the rain that falls here; it is it that makes those (cows) swell; and for this reason he says &#8216;the winds are ye!&#8217; Some people add here the formula,<strong> &#8216;Going near are ye!&#8217;</strong><br />
<strong>but let him not say this</strong>, because thereby another (an enemy) approaches (the sacrificer).&#8221;</p>
<p>Shatapath Brahman here is referring to Taittiriya Samhita 1:1:1:1, which contains the addional words &#8216;Going near are ye&#8217; or &#8216;Ye are approachers&#8217;. In other words, Shatapath Brahman is condemning the recitation of Taittiriya Samhita as FALSE.  Similarly, at many other places in the Shatapath Brahman, Taittiriya Samhita is criticized. How can the likes of Agniveer explain this censure of Taittiriya Samhita by Shatapath Brahman?</p>
<p>This Shaakha issue is now settled. All Shaakhaas are EQUAL contenders of being the originals. Thus there are 1131 Veda Samhitas and now we have 11 Samhitas left. Agniveer has no authority to claim exclusive originality.</p>
<p><strong>Missing Verses</strong></p>
<p>After the collection and codification of Vedas, many different manuscripts gained currency amongst the Brahmin groups. The number of mantras in every manuscript continued to be changed. The current version of Rigveda was collected by Shaakal Rishi and was thus called Shaakal Samhita. It is divided into 10 Mandals (Books).</p>
<p>Nirukt 7:8 mentions the following,</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu in the ten books of the Rigveda.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, in the entire Rigveda, there is not a single mantra jointly praising Agni and Vishnu.  What is meant by joint oblation here? An oblation is an offering (Late Latin oblatio, from offerre, oblatum, to offer), a term, particularly in ecclesiastical usage, for a solemn offering or presentation to God. Where is an offering jointly made to Agni and Vishnu, we would like to see? This is a clear evidence that the Rigveda at the time of Yaska Muni had the joint oblation offered to Agni and Vishnu, but it is not found in today&#8217;s Rigveda, demonstrating corruption of the text.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>1. Nirukta wasn&#8217;t preserved in the way Rigveda was. So Rigveda is much more authoritative, especially after scrutiny by even the skeptics as mentioned above.</p>
<p>What a scholarly reply? Is Agniveer prepared to delete all references of Nirukt form his website and throw Nirukt in the dustbin? Why are they still publishing and spreading a polluted book, if it really is polluted? The desperation of Agniveer can be understood. When Rigveda is being blown apart by Nirukt here, Agniveer is choosing the lesser of the two evils and casting doubt on Nirukt to save Rigveda, the source of Hinduism. However, this answer is just not satisfactory. Agniveer first needs to prove that this particular reference of Nirukt is wrong and give evidences of the same. If he is unable to do so, then Rigveda has been obviously changed. He also has to publicly announce that Nirukt is a false book and should not be used to establish anything. Hindu scholars should announce the same in public.</p>
<p>But wait a minute, let Agniveer&#8217;s deception be exposed by his own deception guru, aka Swami Dayananda. In his Magnum Opus, Satyarth Prakash, the Swami lists several books which should be read and others which should be avoided. And guess what? He just rips Agniveer apart. The Swami says,</p>
<p>&#8220;We can liken this to digging up a whole mountain and finding a penny-worth of gold; whilst the study of the books of the great sages can be well likened to the diving of a man into the sea and finding most valuable pearls in one plunge.<br />
3. Then let them read <strong>Nighantoo and Nirukta</strong> (books on Vedic Vocabulary and Philology) by Yaska in six to eight months, but not waste years of their valuable time over Amarkosha and other such books written by atheists.&#8221; [Satyarth Prakash, Chapter 3]
<p>and further down he gives a long list of books to be avoided,</p>
<p>&#8220;The books to be avoided are:-</p>
<p>1. Grammar:-a.Katantra, b. Saaraswata, c. Chandrika, d. Mugdhabodha. e. Kaumudi, f. Shekhar, g. Monorma, etc.<br />
2. Dictionary – Amarkosha, etc.<br />
3. Prosody – Urittaratnakar, etc.<br />
4. Shiksha is the Science which teaches the proper pronunciation of words and laws of euphony. Atka Shiksham Pravakshyami Pranamyan matam yatha.<br />
5. Jotisha (astronomy) – Shighrabodha, Mahurta, Chintaamani, ettc. books on astrology.<br />
6. Poetry – Naya ka bheda, Kuvabja nand, Raghuvansha, Maagha, Kiratarjunira, etc.<br />
7. Mimansa – Dharmasindhu, Vratarka, etc.<br />
8. Visheshika – Tarkasangraha, etc.<br />
9. Nyaya -Yogdishaa, etc.<br />
10. Yoga – Hathapradipka<br />
11. Saankhya – Yagavashishtha, Pancha dashi<br />
12. Medical Service – Sharangdhar.<br />
13. Smriti – all Smritis except the Manu Smirit arring the interpolated verses.<br />
14. all Tantras, Puranaas, Upapuraanaas, Ramaayaana by Tulsi Das, Rukmani Mangala, etc., and all books 9of this kind) written in Bhaashaa.</p>
<p>They ought to be looked upon as snares; once caught in them a student can never know the truth.</p>
<p><strong>Is there no truth to be found in these books?</strong></p>
<p>A.~ There is a sprinkling of truth mixed with a large amount of rubbish, myths and fabrications; but as even the best food mixed with poison is to be avoided, so should these books.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ah! These golden words must be pinned on the walls of Agniveer&#8217;s house. Agniveer has already poisoned many articles on his poisonous website with Nirukta, which according to him is false but not according to his guru. I know Agniveer is merely using deception to refute me, but deep in his heart he must be really ashamed that he condemned the great Nirukt in public.</p>
<p>Then, Agniveer is taking recourse to Indologists to save the Vedas. However, Hindu scholars themselves opine that Vedas have suffered heavy changes. Pandit Ram Gvind Trivedi writes in the preface to his translation of Rigveda,</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="538" height="150" class="wp-image-7538" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-35.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp3.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-35.png 538w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-35-300x84.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 538px) 100vw, 538px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;According to one Mantra of Rigveda (10:114:8), we come to know that it has 15,000 Mantras. However, when we count the total Mantras, we get 10,469 Mantras. It is possible that  like a large portion of the books of Vedic literature and Vedas were destroyed by the anti-religious, similarly,  Mantras too suffered destruction for many reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Agniveer only partially quotes Indologists to deceive the people. Let him taste the same Indologists now.</p>
<p>Prof. Maurice Bloomfield writes in the Introduction to his Hymns of the Atharvaveda,</p>
<p>&#8220;<strong>The nineteenth book is a late addendum, in general very corrupt</strong>; its omission (with the exception of hymns 26, 34, 35, 38, 39, 53, and 54) does not detract much from the general impression left by the body of the collection. The seventeenth book consists of a single hymn of inferior interest. <strong>Again, books XV and XVI, the former entirely Brahmanical prose, the latter almost entirely so, are of doubtful quality and chronology.</strong> Finally, books XIV and XVIII contain respectively the wedding and funeral stanzas of the Atharvan, and are largely coincident with corresponding Mantras of the tenth book of the Rig-veda: they are, granted their intrinsic interest, not specifically Atharvanic.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dr. A.A. Macdonell echoes the same views about Atharvaveda in his book A History of Sanskrit Literature,</p>
<p>&#8220;<strong>The last two books are manifestly late additions.</strong> Book XIX. consists of a mixture of supplementary pieces, <strong>part of the text of which is rather corrupt.</strong> Book XX., with a slight exception, contains only complete hymns addressed to Indra, which are borrowed directly and without any variation from the Rigveda. The fact that its readings are identical with those of the Rigveda would alone suffice to show that it is of later date than the original books, the readings of which show considerable divergences from those of the older Veda. <strong>There is, however, more convincing proof of the lateness of this book.</strong> Its matter relates to the Soma ritual, and is entirely foreign to the spirit of the Atharva-veda. <strong>It was undoubtedly added to establish the claim of the Atharva to the position of a fourth Veda</strong>, by bringing it into connection with the recognised sacrificial ceremonial of the three old Vedas. This book, again, as well . as the nineteenth, is not noticed in the Praticakhya of the Atharva-veda. <strong>Both of them must, therefore, have been added after that work was composed.</strong> Excepting two prose pieces (48 and 49) the only original part of Book XX. is the so-called kuntapa hymns (127-136). &#8221;</p>
[A History of Sanskrit Literature, A. A. Macdonell, Printed in 1900, Page 188]
<p>Dr. Macdonell even exposes the Rigveda in the following words,</p>
<p>&#8220;The importance of the latter as a criterion of the authenticity of verses in the Rigveda is indicated by the following fact. <strong>There are six verses in the Rigveda not analysed in the Pada text, but only given there over again in the Samhita form. This shows that Sakalya did not acknowledge them as truly Rigvedic, a view justified by internal evidence.</strong> This group of six, which is doubtless exhaustive, stands midway between old additions which (Sakalya recognised as canonical, and the new appendages called Khilas, which never gained admission into the Pada text in any form.&#8221;</p>
<p>The six verses he is referring to are, Rigveda 7:59:12, 10:20:1, 10:121:10 and 10:190:1,2,3.</p>
<p>Now, Agniveer should also get rid of Atharvaveda and well as these six verses, when the Indologists are confirming it.</p>
<p>Agniveer, the misled fanatic wrote,</p>
<p>2. The Vishnu of Vedas is same as the Agni. Both refer to same Singular Supreme Entity. Only the misled see polytheism in Vedas. So joint oblation to Vishnu and Agni is applicable to any mantra that can be interpreted to imply those characteristics of Supreme that are common in meaning of Agni and Vishnu. This is a research subject for those who have skills to contemplate deeply on mantras. There is nothing conflicting in it. At best one can say that – Since I don&#8217;t know anything about Vedas because knowing that would put me in Hell, hence I cannot understand it.</p>
<p>The topic of Vedic deities is a separate one, which is beyond the scope of this article. However, to briefly respond to the bogus claims of Agniveer, he is trivializing the text of the Vedas because he thinks it is his personal property and he can twist it as he likes. Extending his bogus argument, Agnim ile purohitam can be changed to Vaishnam ile purohitam and there will be no difference. May be  Maharishi Agniveer has an intention of producing his own Samhita of Rigveda and is therefore propounding unorthodox views to deceive the people. He is going to the extent of calling Yaska Acharya &#8216;misled&#8217; because Yaska speaks of plural deities in the Vedas. Notice the original words of Yaska, &#8220;There is a <strong>joint oblation</strong> offered to Agni <strong>and</strong> Vishnu in the ten books of the Rigveda.&#8221; No person in his right mind can say that Yaska is speaking of the same deity. If Agni and Vishnu were same, then the words &#8216;joint oblation&#8217; become absurd. Agniveer is considering himself smarter than classical Hindu scholars. He is free to do all the research he needs, but he will evidently fail.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>&#8220;3. Interestingly the very people who are currently raising this childish allegation are the ones who also attempt to prove that Vedas talk of only one Single God. But they use this argument when they want to prove that Vedas and their modern scripture both talk of the same Singular God, but because their scripture is latest, hence that latest version should be followed. Hence everyone should start believing in their religion to escape Hell.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is another proof that Agniveer is not in his right mind. Who is he talking about? Where have I ever claimed that Vedas talk of only one Single God? Agniveer needs to spend time and study my articles thoroughly before writing nonsense. I have time and time again emphasized that Vedas teach only NATURE WORSHIP, DARK POLYTHEISM AND PANTHEISM. I suggest that readers read my article <a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/what-is-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">What is Hinduism?</a> to know my position on the conception of &#8216;gods&#8217; in Vedas. May be Agniveer is dreaming that I am affiliated with IRF. I do not endorse the research of IRF on Hinduism, specially the concept of God in Hinduism. Dr. Zakir Naik is wrongly propagating that Vedas speak about one God, but then again, he bases his arguments on the works of Arya Samaj. I intend to write a separate article refuting the notion that Vedas speak of one Supreme God.</p>
<p><strong>Suggested Reading </strong></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/concept-of-god-in-arya-samaj-protestant-hinduism-part-1/" data-wpel-link="internal">Concept of Gods in Arya Samaj (Protestant Hinduism) -Part 1</a></p>
<p><a href="/index.php/2014/01/01/concept-of-god-in-arya-samaj-protestant-hinduism-part-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Concept of Gods in Arya Samaj (Protestant Hinduism) -Part 2</a></p>
<p><strong>Corruption in recitation</strong></p>
<p>The oral tradition of the Vedas (Śrauta) consists of several pathas, &#8220;recitations&#8221; or ways of chanting the Vedic mantras.The padapatha consists of dividing the sentence into individual pada or words. The kramapatha consists of pairing two words at a time. There has been a lot of corruption in the former recitation. I will give some examples to demonstrate this.</p>
<p><strong>Example 1</strong></p>
<p>Yask Muni, the author of Nirukt and Nighantu, writes that Vaayah is one word [See Nirukt 6:28]. But in the Shaakal Shakha&#8217;s (Rigveda&#8217;s) padapatha, it has been divided and hence became meaningless. Rigveda 10:29:1 is the place which has made the mistake.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="152" class="wp-image-7539" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-36.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp4.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-36.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-36-300x80.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;As sits the young bird on the tree rejoicing, ye, swift Pair, have been roused by clear laudation,…&#8221;</p>
<p>Yaska himself criticizes Shakalya and says,</p>
<p>&#8220;Sakalya has analyzed <strong>Vaayah </strong>into <strong>Vaa </strong>and <strong>yah</strong>, then the finite verb would have had the accute accent and the sense have been incomplete.&#8221;</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote ,</p>
<p>Whether we take the word as &#8216;Va + Yah&#8217; or Vayo, they both are pronounced in exactly the same manner. Same is true for &#8216;Ma + Iha + Naasti&#8217;. However in Vedic mantras, these words come us Vayo and Mehanaasti. Scholars can have disputes over how the word should be interpreted. This is a research topic. Depending on their views, they can have different Pada Paatha or break-up of the words. <strong>Perhaps during Yaska&#8217;s time, someone broke the word in wrong manner and hence he had to counter it.</strong> Similar to the way even we have to counter the most outdated concepts even today despite the availability of thoroughly verified and edited Vedas!</p>
<p><strong>Pada Paatha is NOT original Vedas. </strong>It is one way of preserving Vedas. There are 9 more. Refer <a href="http://agniveer.com/2697/no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://agniveer.com/2697/no-textual-corruption-in-vedas/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>. If an error comes in Pada Patha, it is corrected by comparing with other methods. And hence today, there is no doubt over what the original Vedic mantras are. (Thanks to efforts of sages like Yaska from time to time.) I recommend looking at editions of Pt Damodar Satvalekar which is accepted widely as the most corrected published version.</p>
<p>Agniveer is again shooting himself in the foot. This IITian can&#8217;t  even read properly. Yaska has not countered a &#8216;someone&#8217;, but Sakalya himself. &#8220;<strong>Sakalya</strong> has analyzed <strong>Vaayah </strong>into <strong>Vaa </strong>and <strong>yah</strong>, then the finite verb would have had the accute accent and the <strong>sense have been incomplete</strong>.&#8221; The  question  here is not whether pada patha is the original or not. The important thing to notice here is that Agniveer&#8217;s &#8216;original&#8217; Rigveda is under fire from Yaska. Yaska is exposing the mistake of Shaakal Samhita. So, agniveer is caught deceiving again. The false reading of Rigveda has continued to our time also and agniveer is reading the same.</p>
<p>Regarding <strong>Mehanaasti</strong>, Yaska is again showing how Sakalya is wrong and Gargya the author of Samaveda pada patha is right. So, Agniveer is lying here too.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Rigveda</strong></p>
<p>Shaakal Rishi is called as the collector of Rigveda. He had a number of students, who later expressed many differences and compiled their own versions of Rigveda. numbering upto 21. There are major differences between the Shaakal and Baskal samhitas of Rigveda. The Śākala recension has 1,017 regular hymns, while the Bāṣkala samhita has a total of 1025 hymns.  Thus, around  some 50 mantras are missing in Śākala samhita. There are differences even over the total number of mantras.</p>
<p>The detailed analysis of the mantra differences in Rigveda will be dealth in a separate article.</p>
<p><strong>Different versions of Yajurveda</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>1. Black or Krishna Yajurveda is a branch (Shakha) and not original Yajurveda. It contains original mantras modified along with historical and explanatory descriptions to suit research interests of specific kind. Shukla or White Yajurveda refers to those branches of Yajurveda that modify the original mantras if required but do not add additional texts. The Madhyandini Yajurveda of Shukla Branch is the original Yajurveda and rest are its variations.</p>
<p>Another bogus claim devoid of any solid proof. I have already shown the nature of disputes between various Samhitas of Yajurveda. Refer to that discussion. There is no proof that only the Madhyandin Samhita is the original and not the others. Agniveer is conditioned to believe that Madhyandin is the original. What Agniveer is considering as original is considered an exposition in South India and vice versa. Agniveer deceptively ignored the meat of my argument. Anyway i will repeat it to sink it into his mind.</p>
<p><strong>Difference between Krishna (Black) and Shukla (White) Yajurveda</strong></p>
<p>The Vishnu Purana gives the following explanation of their names : Vaisampayana, a pupil of the great Vyasa, was the original teacher of the Black Yajur-Veda. Yajnavalkya, one of his disciples, having displeased him, was called upon by his master to part with the knowledge which he had acquired from him. He forthwith vomited the Yajur-Yeda. The other disciples of Vaisampayana, assuming the form of partridges (tittiri), picked up from the ground its several dirtied texts. From this circumstance it received the name of Taittiriya Krishna Yajur-Veda.</p>
<p>Yajnavalkya afterwards, by the performance of severe penances, induced the Sun God to impart to him those Yajur texts which his master had not possessed. The Sun God then assumed the form of a horse (Vajin), and communicated to him the desired texts. Hence the Sanhita was called Vajasaneyi, and also White (or bright) because it was revealed by the Sun God.</p>
<p>There was a lot of hostility between the two groups.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>So in case you do not have access to original Yajurveda, start with a branch. That would be much more easy to approach due to explanations and simplifications. And when you have mastered them, you can have the taste of the original. The keen minds who are less paranoid and more zealous can approach the original directly as well!</p>
<p>Thus, as per Maharishi Agniveer, making the Madhyandin Samhita available online for common public is a mistake. They need to first read the man made books and then the original. But wait, did we not already see that Shatapath Brahman condemns Taittiriya Samhita as false. So why is Agniveer promoting false texts? May be he has some hidden agenda.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>2. Ishopanishad is nothing but the 40th Chapter of Yajurveda as <strong>it appears in a particular branch of Black Yajurveda</strong> with some modifications. Because this is the greatest text on spiritualism and philosophy and mother of all other texts like Geeta, other Upanishads and even Darshans, it has a special place in Vedic literature. Being mother of all Upanishads, it is called Isha Upanishad. Only a paranoid can explain why he or she thinks that Isha Upanishad cannot be part of Yajurveda.</p>
<p>The deceptive game of Agniveer continues.  Agniveer just claimed in point number 1 that Black or Krishna Yajurveda is a branch (Shakha) and not original Yajurveda. But here he is taking recourse to  this very shaakha in order to establish the validity of the Ishopanishad. I told you he is a deceiver.</p>
<p>Further, according to Agniveer&#8217;s Arya Samaj, Upanishads are NOT Shruti (revealed). Then, how come has this Upanishad been added to the Veda Samhita? Maharishi Agniveer gives this reason; &#8220;Because this is the greatest text on spiritualism and philosophy and mother of all other texts like Geeta, other Upanishads and even Darshans, it has a special place in Vedic literature.&#8221;</p>
<p>The same argument is given by orthodox Hindus as well in favour of the other Upanishads being revealed texts. Why then does Agniveer not consider other upanishads as revealed also? By interpolatng an Upanishad into the Vedic samhita, Agniveer is proving that Vedas are devoid of spirituality and that man-made texts like Ishopanishad is superior to Vedas. We have always been saying that Vedic Samhitas are simply useless. Upanishads are far better than Veda Samhitas.</p>
<p>Now you can judge who is a paranoid.</p>
<p>Agniveer evades vital questions</p>
<p>In dealing with my arguments about the problems with the Yajurveda texts, Agniveer evaded answering many points with the hope that his blind followers will never check the article properly. Agniveer was so scared of the truth that he did not even give the link of our article and neither mentioned the source article he was refuting. All this exposes his grand claims that he is for truth and truth alone.</p>
<p>Questions which Agniveer did not answer:</p>
<p>1. Agniveer did not answer about the schism between the people of Black and White Yajurveda.</p>
<p>2. He did not respond to the differences between the two rival samhitas, in the number and arrangement of mantras.</p>
<p>2. Agniveer also ignored the argument that a lot of Brahamanas have been inserted into the text of the Yajurveda. For example, Adhyay 24 is entirely a Brahman; Adhyay 30: verses 7 through 15 are all Brahmanas and not Mantras. Agniveer did not respond to this. What are Brahmanas doing in Shukla Yajurveda, which he holds as original? Shatapath Brahmana 4:2:3:7-8 testifies to this interpolation of Brahmans in the Samhita as follows:</p>
<p>7. He draws it without (reciting) a puroruk; for the puroruk is a song of praise, since the puroruk is a Rik, and the song of praise is Rik; and the libation is Sâman; and what other (formula) he mutters, that is Yagus. <strong>Formerly these same (puroruk verses) were apart from the Riks, apart from the Yagus, and apart from the Sâmans</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>8. The devatas said, &#8216;Come, let us place them among the Yagus:</strong> thus this science will be still more manifold.&#8217; Accordingly they placed them among the Yagus, and thenceforward this science was still more manifold.</p>
<p>This rips aparts the deception of Agniveer that Madhyandin Samhita is the original.</p>
<p><strong>How Arya Samaj corrupts the Vedas?</strong></p>
<p>1. In the Yajurveda Bhasya of Dayanand Ji, Adhyay 9, Mantra 20 has been distorted by adding the word Gamyaat, which is not to be found in the text. Where did this word come from?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="441" height="546" class="wp-image-7540" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp5.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37.png 441w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-37-242x300.png 242w" sizes="(max-width: 441px) 100vw, 441px" /></p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>1. Did Swami Dayanand add the word in the mantra? No. The word is found only in Hindi translation in some editions. Now Swami Dayanand used to dictate meaning in Sanskrit to his pundits who would then translate it in Hindi as well as transcribe what he said.</p>
<p>But even if he or his pundit added the word in explanation, then you should be thankful to him for attempting to simplify things instead of taking exceptions.</p>
<p>2. Even if Swami Dayanand added the word in the mantra, that does not make Yajurveda corrupted. It only means that Swami Dayanand made an error. When did Vedas or Agniveer or Swami Dayanand claim that humans are fully perfect?</p>
<p>There is a marked contradiction between point 1 and 2. If point 1 is correct then point 2 is incorrect and vice versa. The Swami has added the word in bracket which means he is hoping to deceive people that this is part of the text. All the words in brackets mean they are part of the text. Agniveer would do well to remove this error (read deception) from the market.</p>
<p>2. Comparing the Yajurveda of Gayatri Parivar and Arya Samaj, there are many mantras missing in one or another of the versions. For example, the 25th Chapter of Gayatri Parivar Yajurveda has 47 mantras. Even the Yajurveda of Ralph Griffith has 47 mantras. But, the Arya Samaj version has an additional Mantra 48.</p>
<p>Agniveer, the new Maharishi, wrote,</p>
<p>1. So your anger is towards additional <strong>bonus </strong>that Arya Samaj translation gives you, if I understand properly. This means that you admit original Vedas to be a subset of existing Vedas with one less mantra. Hence there is no <strong>loss</strong> of information at least.</p>
<p>This type of bonus is present in other samhitas of Yajurveda as well, according to you. Then, all your above arguments simply stand nullified by this one. Dear readers, do you remember what Agniveer wrote earlier? If you have forgotten, I will republish the golden words,</p>
<p>&#8220;Black or Krishna Yajurveda is a branch (Shakha) and not original Yajurveda.<strong> It contains original mantras modified along with historical and explanatory descriptions to suit research interests of specific kind. Shukla or White Yajurveda refers to those branches of Yajurveda that modify the original mantras if required but do not add additional texts. </strong>The Madhyandini Yajurveda of Shukla Branch is the original Yajurveda and rest are its variations.&#8221;</p>
<p>So, according to Maharishi Agniveer, Black or Krishna Yajurveda is not original because it contains many bonuses. Therefore, I thank Agniveer for adding a bonus mantra in his so-called original and proving that his Yajurveda IS NOT ORIGINAL ANYMORE. The corollary would be like this. If one bonus mantra of Arya Samaj makes no difference to the text, then the many bonus mantras of other Samhitas proves that they are more desrving to be called originals.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>2. Now if we review this mantra, is it against rest of the Vedas in its message? If not, then what is the cause of concern. If you get one additional sentence in Einstein&#8217;s text on relativity that was written later by an editor but only emphasizes what Einstein says in rest of the paper, how is that a problem?</p>
<p>Are the bonuses of the other samhitas against their own mantras? Then what are you telling us they are not originals? What is the cause of concern? By giving Einsteins example, you are digging your own grave. No sane person would ever edit the TEXT of Einsteins work. They will only add their explanation and they would mention that this is an explanation and not written by Einstein, so that people do not confuse it with Einsteins words. But you have added the &#8216;new bonus mantra&#8217; in the TEXT and without even mentioning in the footnote that it is not in the original. This is called fraud and we should not trust fraud people. What say you Maharishi Agniveer? Also if other Shaakhaas added explanations, which obiously do not contradict the text, are you not riding in the same boat?</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>3. This is an objection only for those who think that if they mug up the book of divine and say a big sorry for all their misdeeds and laziness to Supreme Lord, they would easily get Heaven full of virgins. But for Vedic followers, there are no shortcuts to success. You have to practice what you learn in actions and keep exploring the truth within. And when you have liberated yourself from ignorance significantly, you would well have re-ignited the Vedas within. <strong>So one harmless mantra in one edition makes absolutely no difference.</strong> The only cause of concern could have been if the verse misled you, which it does not.</p>
<p>Let Maharishi Agniveer  produce some evidence for the false charges he has made. Where have we ever said that just by muggin up the Quran and doing misdeeds will give us heaven? Where does the Noble Quran say so? How do we know that ONLY ONE HARMLESS MANTRA has been added to the text? If you can add a mantra to the text, it shows that Vedas can be made by man. Agniveer Ji, I already knew Vedas were nothing special and are man made. If the verse does not mislead me, so is the case with other Samhitas.</p>
<p>Regarding virgins of Vedic Swarga, Maharishi Agniveer can read my artcles,</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-an-overview-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Paradise: An Overview</a></li>
<li><a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/vedic-paradise-the-inside-story/" data-wpel-link="internal">Vedic Paradise: The Inside Story</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Did Agniveer say that for Vedic followers there are no shortcuts to success? Maharishi! haven&#8217;t you read the Vedas? If you haven&#8217;t, let me tell you the Vedic shortcuts of entering Paradise.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="489" height="234" class="wp-image-7541" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp6.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38.png 489w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-38-300x144.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 489px) 100vw, 489px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Strongest is this, performed, of sacrifices: he has reached heaven who has prepared Vishtāri. [Atharva Ved 4:34:5]
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="491" height="232" class="wp-image-7542" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp7.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39.png 491w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-39-300x142.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 491px) 100vw, 491px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;High up in heaven abide the Guerdon-givers: they who give steeds dwell with the Sun forever. They who give gold are blest with life eternal. They who give robes prolong their lives, O Soma.&#8221; [Rig Veda – 10:107:2]
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="571" height="107" class="wp-image-7543" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp8.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40.png 571w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-40-300x56.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 571px) 100vw, 571px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Panchodana, when cooked, transports, repelling Nirriti, to the world of Svarga. By him may we win worlds which Sūrya brightens.&#8221; [Atharva Ved 9:5:18]
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="519" height="119" class="wp-image-7544" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-41.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp9.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-41.png 519w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-41-300x69.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 519px) 100vw, 519px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;…This wealth I place among the Brāhmans, making a path that leads to heaven among the Fathers.&#8221; [Atharva Ved 11:1:28]
<p>To sum up, according to most mantras in Atharva Ved, feeding the Brahmins with milk and rice (Kheer), offering goats, gold, and other Dakshina earns one Paradise. Displeasing a Brahmin gives you a one way ticket to Hell.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>4. By the way, the 25th Chapter has only 47 mantras and that is accepted by one and all. <strong>Some publishers publish an additional mantra due to relevance of context. Perhaps someone inserted it years ago and then no printer bothered to or rather was not competent enough to scrutinize it.</strong> Please send us the name of the publisher and we shall write to him to correct the mistake. Or even you can write so referring to this article.</p>
<p>So, now you are saying it is not a &#8216;bonus mantra&#8217;? What happened dear? Let it remain there. Why bother to correct this &#8216;mistake&#8217;? If you needed a Muslim to tell you that mischief has been done to the Vedic text, then you all need to hang yourselves in shame. For 150 years you let the verse remain in the text and want to remove it now? Someone rightly said, Arya Samajis are the biggest frauds. The &#8216;bonus mantra&#8217; is given by all Arya publishers. I can only imagine, how many such mantras would have been made up &#8216;due to relevance of the context&#8217;. Poor Yajurveda. I think Agniveer should now follow Taittiriya Samhita. His Madhyandin has disappointed me. Notice that Agniveer is contradicting himself in the same mantra. On one hand he says that the &#8216;PUBLISHERS&#8217; added it due to relevance of context and on the other hand he is mocking them by saying they are not competent. If they WILLINGLY added it why will they scrutinize it?</p>
<p>3. In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 26, mantra 26, the word <strong>Ayohatay<br />
</strong> was changed to <strong>Apohatay.</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>1. This is a printing mistake. Real word is Ayohate (अयोहते). Now in Devanagri script, Ya (य) and Pa (प) appear almost similar. Such errors are found in several places in Vedas because the first time they were being printed, they were being typeset from hand-written manuscripts. However Pt Damodar Satvalekar did a great job of scrutinizing all published mantras with manuscripts and manuscripts with various Paatha methods to give to us extremely authentic editions of Rigveda.</p>
<p>2. But thankfully, the meaning does not change because that was based on actual word.</p>
<p>Come on Maharishi Agniveer. You blame every mischief of your guru on the poor printers. If it was a printing error, why did the Swami translate <strong>Apohatay</strong> and not <strong>Ayohate</strong>? He translated it as &#8216;gold&#8217; instead of the actual meaning &#8216;iron&#8217;. Who are you deceiving? The Swami Brahmachari was looking for gold instead of worthless iron. Changing 1 into 11 is the old habit of Grocers. When caught out they said, &#8220;Oh man! This is only a writing error.&#8221;</p>
<p>4. In Yajurveda Bhashya of Dayanand Ji Adhyay 39, mantra 5, the word <strong>Vishyandmaane </strong>was changed to <strong>Vishpandmaane.</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>Refer previous allegation.</p>
<p>How can you refer it to previous point, when this is a separate fraud? The swami has translated <strong>Vispand</strong> and not <strong>Visyand</strong>. Vispand (विष्पन्द ) means throbbing and Vishyand (विष्यन्द) means trickling. Only a fool will call it a printing error. Swami has taken Visyand deliberately to mistraslate it.</p>
<p>5. The longer ending in Yajurveda 13:58 has been deleted from Arya Samaj version, but exists in the Gayatri Parivar version .</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>It does not matter whether this text is there or not. The meaning of the phrase is implied in overall meaning of the mantras continued from Chapter 12 itself up to this last mantra of Chapter 13. So for sake of completion of meaning you can put the phrase, and for sake of brevity you can skip it. A conservative approach would be to keep it. but if focus is to understand meaning alone, it can be skipped. <strong>We suggest having the phrase for sake of completeness.</strong></p>
<p>If Veda is revealed text according to you, do you mean the Words of God do not matter? Is your God a lunatic who reveals texts in vain? I told this to a Sanatan Dharmi friend. He became upset and said, &#8220;Who the hell is Agniveer to suggest what should be Vedas and what not?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Corruption of Samaveda</strong></p>
<p>Samaveda is heavily borrowed from the Rigveda. It consists of a collection of hymns, portions of hymns, and detached verses, all but 75 taken from the Sakala Sakha of the Rigveda, the other 75 belong to the Bashkala Sakha, to be sung, using specifically indicated melodies, called Samagana. There are differences regarding the exact number of mantras in the Samaveda. As I said earlier,  according to Patanjali&#8217;s statement, &#8220;sahasravartma samvedah&#8221; सहस्रवर्त्म<br />
समवेदः, &#8220;There are thousand branches of Samaveda&#8221;. However, only three survive:</p>
<ul>
<li>the Kauthuma Shakha is current in Gujarat, Uttar Pradesh, Orissa and since a few decades in Darbhanga, Bihar,</li>
<li>the Jaiminiya in the Karnatak, Tamilnadu and Kerala,</li>
<li>and the Rāṇāyanīya in the Maharastra.</li>
</ul>
<p>The total mantras in the Jaimniya Shakha is 1687. Kauthama Shakha has 1869 mantras . Thus, 182 mantras are missing from Kauthama Shakha. An analysis of both these versions reveals lots of Paath-Bhed (variant readings). Besides this, there is a difference in number of songs attributed to different branches. Shri Satvalekar in his preface to Samaveda Samhita has given the following table of songs (Samagana).</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong> </strong></td>
<td><strong>Songs of Jaiminiya Branch</strong></td>
<td><strong>Songs of Kauthamiya Branch</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gramgeyo-gān:</td>
<td>1233</td>
<td>1197</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Aranyageya-gān:</td>
<td>291</td>
<td>294</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ooh-gān:</td>
<td>1802</td>
<td>1026</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Oohya-gān:</td>
<td>356</td>
<td>205</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total</td>
<td>3681</td>
<td>2722</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>We can easily see that the Samaganas of Jaiminiya Version are 1000 more than those of Kauthamiya Version.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>We have already mentioned that Kauthum Rishi preserved the original Samaveda. Refer the previous discussion on branches.</p>
<p>Further, Samaveda songs make no sense for the disturbed mind. They represent the melodies that generate from within when one reaches a high level of enlightenment and exalted state. Jaimini branch offers more variety and you can experiment with them to find what melody touches you the most. However keep caution – avoid spicy food, meat, alcohol, anger, frustration, hatred etc, study other Vedas as well and practice meditation. Without foundation of this, you may be simply wasting your time.</p>
<p>When will Agniveer stop lying? What is the proof that only Kauthama Samhita is original? Whether Samaveda songs make sense or not is no response to the argument of textual corruption. Samaveda is a mere waste of ink and paper. All except 75 mantras are copied from Rigveda&#8217;s Shaakal samhita. The remaining are from Baashkal. Now, if Baashkal is not the original Samhita, then the 75 mantras of Samaveda are also fake.</p>
<p><strong>Corruption in Atharvaveda</strong></p>
<p>Atharvaveda, also known as Brahmaveda is considered the youngest amongst all other Vedas.</p>
<p>Following is an exmaple of textual corruption in the Atharvaveda.</p>
<p>Atharvaveda Khand 20 and Sookt 127 is part of the Kuntap Sooktas. In the third mantra of this Sookt there has been  an alteration. The Atharvaveda of Arya Samaj and Gayatri Parivar both have it as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="365" height="67" class="wp-image-7545" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-42.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp10.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-42.png 365w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-42-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 365px) 100vw, 365px" /></p>
<p>The word preceeding <strong>Maamahe</strong> is <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. However, in the Atharvaveda of Pandit Raja Ram Shashtri of Arya Samaj as well as the Atharvaveda printed in Germany, the text differs as follows:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="317" height="56" class="wp-image-7546" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-43.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp11.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-43.png 317w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-43-300x53.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 317px) 100vw, 317px" /></p>
<p>Here the word preceeding <strong>Maamahe </strong>is <strong>Rishye </strong>and not <strong>Eeshaai</strong>. This makes a difference in the meaning of the mantra.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>Again a case of printing mistake due to bad handwriting in Devanagri manuscript or error by typist. The correct word is &#8216;Ishaya&#8217;. Printing mistakes are not attributable to original texts.</p>
<p>This is not a printing error. Prof. Whitney mentions the variation in the footnote of this word. This is a manuscript variation. That is why all European scholars such as Griffith, Whitney, Bloomfield translate it as Seer or Rishi. Agniveer would do well to learn the Vedas properly instead of blaming all  manuscript mistakes on the poor printers.</p>
<p>Points left unanswered by Agniveer</p>
<p>Patanjali Rishi, in his Mahabhasya, has given the first words of all the four Vedas. Patanjali quotes SHANNODEVEE RABHISHTAYE as the first verse of the Atharvaveda. However, Atharvaveda now begins with the verse YE NNISHATPAAH PARIYANTA. SHANNODEVEE RABHISHTAYE now appears as the first verse of the 6th Sukta of the first Kanda or in aggregate the 26th verse. This shows that  25 mantras have been interpolated in the beginning of Atharvaveda.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Shatapath Brahman 13:4:3:4-8 in the context of the Ashvamedha sacrifice; after the Yagya (ritual) is completed, the householders should be instructed in Rigveda of the first day. old men should be instructed in Yajurveda on the second day, handsome youths should be instructed in Atharvaveda on the third day and handsome maiden should be instructed in Angirasveda on the  fourth day. Angirasveda is attributed to Rishi Angiras who is in the fourth generation after Rishi Atharva. There is no mention of Samaveda in this reference of Shatapath Brahman.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>I shall not comment on what exactly this reference from Shatpath means. But even if we take it at face value:</p>
<p>1. Samaveda is not mentioned because Samaveda cannot be simply listened like other Vedas. Samaveda is all about emotions and meditation. <strong>Further, bulk of mantras in Samaveda are already in Rigveda. So there is no purpose of listening them again. </strong>However if the same mantras are meditated upon with emotions and sung, new revelations would come. But this is not in context of the ritual described. You need to separately practice this art.</p>
<p>Yes, how can you comment because your knowledge of Vedas has taken a big beating by now.</p>
<p>Agniveer is right that bulk of the mantras in Samaveda are already in Rigveda. Agniveer himself confessed that Samaveda is useless and mere waste of paper, ink and time, because it is mere repetition of Rigveda.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>2. Even if Rishi Angiras was born 4th generation from Rishi Atharva (I shall not comment on authenticity of this history), how does it matter? Names of Rishis depict their deeds and specializations and not the names in their Class X pass certificate. So a specialist in Atharvaveda can name himself Rishi Atharva. Similarly another Rishi can use synonym of Atharva ie Angiras and use as his name. This is similar to we using Agniveer as our name. Now just because we call ourselves Agniveer, it does not mean that we are the author of all the mantras in Vedas that have word &#8216;Agni&#8217;.</p>
<p>Agniveer cannot comment on the authenticity of this history because he doesn&#8217;t know any history. There are no preserved records of the imaginary authors of the Vedas. The point to be noted is that it is technically absurd to call the same Veda by different names in the same sentence, just because the gender is different. Rest of the claims of Agniveer are without any evidence.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>4. Atharvaveda and Angirasveda refer to same text. They are also called Chhanda in some places. Atharvaveda has the privilege of multiple names because it is an all-rounder. It adopts from Rik, Yajuh and Sama Vedas are brings forth their applied aspects. To there are multiple dimensions to it deserving multiple names.</p>
<p>The correct view is that Atharvaveda is divided into two parts, Atharvaved and Angirasved. Atharvaved as a whole is a later addition to the canon of Vedas, interpolated by Brahmins. Even within Atharvaved, Angirasved portion is a late addition. Agniveer has produced no evidence for the multiple names of Atharvaved.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>But if this be the argument for Vedas being corrupted then Quran is perhaps the most corrupted text in the world. Because Quran is referred by a huge number of names in Quran itself. The word Quran was later adopted for the text by fighting followers long after death of the peace-loving founder. The founder never knew that this book would be called Quran. Quran is also referred by names reserved for Jewish and Christian texts in Quran itself! That is why some scholars conclude that original Quran refers to Bible or Old Testament or some unchangeable text which was existing ever prior to Testaments and was much bigger in size. This a matter of scholarly debate and we shall leave it to scholars.</p>
<p>Exactly, the Quran has many names WITHIN the text itself. There was no fighting between the companions over the names. Agniveer is just throwing red herrings to distract the attention of the readers from the main topic. Prophet Muhammad (pbuh) always referred to it as Al-Quran (The Quran). Agniveer neither has knowledge of Vedic Dharma nor of Islam. His credibility is already destroyed. Commenting on the comments of the ignorant does not fetch anything. The topic is about Vedas so bringing the Quran into the picture is evidence that Agniveer has really no factual response to the clear textual corruption of Vedas. Our research has been substantial, reasonable and rational.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer has problems with my usage of the word &#8216;accusation&#8217;. I already know, after thorough study, that Vedas are false and corrupt. Hence I am justified in using the word &#8216;accusation&#8217;. &#8216;To accuse&#8217; according to dictionary means &#8216;to charge with a shortcoming or error.&#8217; Check <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/accuse" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">this link<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> to know more.</p>
<p>All Maharishi Agniveer can do is go into hairsplitting a simple word and build more castles of lies and deception. You can think why Agniveer is so upset here. Obviously because the foundations of Vedic Dharma are being shaken here.</p>
<p>Agniveer writes more lies,</p>
<p>4. To take this argument to an extreme, let us state something. Even if all the allegations…sorry &#8216;<strong>accusations</strong>&#8216; stand, still that would NO WAY AFFECT the Vedic religion. This is because the very essence of Vedic religion is to <strong>not</strong> blindly and literally translate any text as recipe for life.</p>
<p>To know about the truth of Vedic Religion, go through our disection of Vedas on our website. You  will know the reality with references and exact quotes.</p>
<p>Agniveer wrote,</p>
<p>Vedic texts are like Science textbooks for us and not a roadside Mantra-Tantra book that promises to help us getting job, marriage, money, destruction of enemy, mesmerism over lover, invisibility, control of Jinna and ghosts etc by blankly reciting certain mantras on microphone and moving some bones.</p>
<p>Sorry, if you think Vedas are akin to Jhaad Phoonk of Pagla Baba Banarasi, or Ajmer Sharif ka Jaadu, or Shahdara Wale Miyanji ke Totke or something similar, you are at a wrong place. Get these addresses from any Railway Station rather than daring to open the minds to think honestly. Or perhaps your own scripture might be a good replacement for these Babas and Miyans.</p>
<p>All you have to do is read the Vedas yourself and see the kind of primitive, superstitous book it is. Let me give you a sample of Mantra-Tantra and Jhaad Phoonk.</p>
<p>6. The mother shall sleep, the father shall sleep, the dog shall sleep, the lord of the house shall sleep! All her relations shall sleep, and these people round about shall sleep!<br />
7. O sleep, put thou to sleep all people with the magic that induces sleep! Put the others to sleep until the sun rises; may I be awake until the dawn appears, like Indra, unharmed, uninjured!</p>
<p>(Atharvaved 4:5:6-7)</p>
<p>These mantras in Atharvaveda are taught to the Robber. It is claimed that by chanting these mantras, all the family members of the house, which the robber intends to rob, will sleep so that the robber can  easily rob the house. Now, it is for you to decide what kind of knowledge is this? Obviuosly knowledge of fraud or in short fraud-veda.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="450" height="25" class="wp-image-7547" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-44.png" alt="http://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0654_testingresp12.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-44.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-vedkabhed-files-wordpress-com-2018-06-06021-44-300x17.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>P.S. Since this is a response article, we had to restrict it to the arguments presented. However, to prove the textual corruption of Vedas, one more article will be added soon with many more proofs and evidences. Stay tuned and thanks for reading! Beware of Fraud Maharishis.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/response-to-no-corruption-in-vedas-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Response to No Corruption in Vedas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
