<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Agnvieer &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/agnvieer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 06:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Rebuttal to Agnvieer: Why Islam is fanatic</title>
		<link>/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vedkabhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 16:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rebuttal: Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Agnvieer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Steve [This article is edited by the admin of VedKaBhed.Wordpress.com without the consent of Steve] Agniveer has written this article for his fellow hindu readers, but as usual he fails to proove Islam wrong. He has taken the arguments from Anti-Islamic websites, which again prooves his ignorance in Islamic knowledge &#38; understanding. Lets &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/" data-wpel-link="internal">Rebuttal to Agnvieer: Why Islam is fanatic</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Steve</p>
[This article is edited by the admin of VedKaBhed.Wordpress.com without the consent of Steve]
<p>Agniveer has written this article for his fellow hindu readers, but as usual he fails to proove Islam wrong. He has taken the arguments from Anti-Islamic websites, which again prooves his ignorance in Islamic knowledge &amp; understanding. Lets analyse some of his silly claims/arguments.<br />
<span id="more-190"></span></p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>Islam and Vedas have one thing in common – belief in one God, Ishwar or Allah. While Islam proclaims that there is no God but Allah, Vedas state that He is neither two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine , ten or more. He is only One.</p>
<p>However the similarities end there. Because while Vedas do believe in One Ishwar, they do not consider disbelief in One Ishwar – either Atheism or Polytheism as an unpardonable crime. Thus, even an Atheist or Polytheist would get good rewards for their good deeds and move ahead in their journey towards total bliss. And with time, as ignorance is removed, belief in One Ishwar shall emerge as a natural process. Thus there is no scope for forced belief in Vedas.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>My Response:</strong></p>
<p>Why do billions of Hindu&#8217;s worship 320 million God&#8217;s? which includes half animal &amp; half human god&#8217;s private parts etc if Vedas proclaim only one God. Actually this is a mere deception by agniveer , Vedas talk about 33 gods in reality. Read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/01/02/on-vedic-deities/" data-wpel-link="internal">On Vedic Deities</a> for more information on polytheism in Vedas.</p>
<p>How can a atheist be rewarded if he simply denies the existence of god, this is stupidity.</p>
<p>On one hand Agniveer says Vedas promote one true God, now he says polytheism is acceptable. How can polytheism be acceptable if there is one God, lets assume if there were many God&#8217;s there would have a deadly fight between them on the basis of authority. This is simply Ridiculous. Arya Samaji scholar named Pundit Kshemkaran Das Trivedi writes,<br />
<img decoding="async" src="https://vedkabhed.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/060218_0646_testinginfi26.png?w=455" alt="" width="455" height="145" /></p>
<p>‘‘Vedic followers should destroy infidels”- Kshem Karan Das Trivedi on Atharva Veda 12.5.54, page 574 [Source: <a href="http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://aryasamajjamnagar.org/atharvaveda_v2/pages/p574.gif<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>For more information read the article <a href="/index.php/2014/05/15/killing-infidels-in-vedas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Killing infidels in Vedas</a>. Being a Nastik (Atheist or infidel) is a gross sin in Hinduism and many Hindu texts prescribed death penalty for it. Agniveer is being Mayavi (Vedic fraud) here or else he must be ignorant of Vedas.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>Islam on other hand is brutal. It states that Allah can forgive all sins, but not Shirk – or refusal to believe in One Allah.</p>
<p>Thus, a person, how-so much noble and good intended, is destined for Hell if he is atheist or idol worshipper or polytheist.</p>
<p>One would wonder what is so criminal about not believing in Islamic version of Allah that even a rapist and murderer could be forgiven by Allah but not one who commits Shirk!</p>
<p>This concept of Shirk is the foundation of Islam – non-tolerance for any belief apart from that on Allah and Allah alone.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>My Response:</strong></p>
<p>If the only true God wants u to believe only in him, do you think it&#8217;s brutal.</p>
<p><em>A person, how-so much noble and good intended, is destined for Hell if he is atheist or idol worshipper or polytheist. </em>This is not true, if Allah wills to forgive anyone on the basis of his good deeds he will do so, only Allah knows what he will do and not you agniveer.</p>
<p>Rapist &amp; murders are to be given punishment here, but if someone escapes &amp; asks for forgiveness from Allah , its allah who has the authority to forgive him or punish him. If he does so much good after that incident of rape and asks for forgive, its allah who will decide. If a person does shirk, but on the last moment he believes in allah , he may be forgiven. There are punishment for every sin may it minor or major sin. However if a person goes through change of heart, wants to start a new life by leading a righteous life and asks for forgiveness before his death even for Shirk then he is forgiven. Agniveer has grossly misinterpreted the concept of forgiveness here. Doesn&#8217;t he know that even rapist, murdered are forgiven in Hinduism but not the murdered of a Brahmin, reviler of Vedas etc. The punishment for reviling God and Veda is only death as per Hindu text.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:.</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>Let us now also review the Quran and ensure that Quran does not teach this Shirk in any manner.</p>
<p>1. Surate Nisa 136 – One who does not believe in Allah and his angels, his books and prophets and Judgment Day is indeed completely misled.</p>
<p>Thus, here belief in Allah is not sufficient. One has to believe in these additional entities as well and hence Quran itself teaches Shirk.</p>
<p>2. Islam believes that only Allah was present in beginning and everything else including souls, angels, world was created later. This is different from the Vedic view that Ishwar, soul and Nature are all eternal and Ishwar manages creation to give appropriate results to souls as per their deeds.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>My Response</strong>:</p>
<p>1. Agniveer has shown his height of stupidity here. See how foolish he is.</p>
<p>Allah is saying you have to believe in him , <span style="color:red;">his<span style="color:black;"> books , <span style="color:red;">his<span style="color:black;"> angels and <span style="color:red;">his<span style="color:black;"> prophets. These are not additional entities, allah has created them, &amp; allah is asking ous to believe in them. Is this called shirk  ? , shirk is believing in other gods than allah. Here allah is himself asking ous to also believe in what he has created. </span><br />
</span></span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;">2. If Vedas say Ishwar , soul and nature are eternal, this is stupidity. A question arises that if all are eternal than who created soul , nature, universe &amp; ishwar himself? This implies Ishwar didn&#8217;t created soul , nature &amp; universe. It&#8217;s someone else job. As they are eternal and Ishwar cant stop them. Can Hinduism answer What was the motive behind creating this universe. Where as Islam says Allah created all things, and the cycle of life will end on judgement day. Agniveer himself writes &#8221;This is different from the Vedic view that Ishwar, soul and Nature are all eternal&#8221; Isn&#8217;t it like associating partners with Ishwar when Arya Samajis says Ishwar, Soul and nature are eternal?<br />
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="color:black;"><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></span></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>The flaw coming from Islamic belief of Allah being sole originator is that now Allah alone becomes the culprit for all misdeeds of Kafirs. He is responsible for crimes of Satan. This is because it is Allah who created them and designed their tendencies and their destiny and stored it in Loe Mahfooz. In many Ayats of Quran he has announced that He has already written their fates.</p>
<p>Also if Allah is living, and none was present apart from Allah to begin with, how were non-living things created from complete consciousness?</p>
<p>Thus the basic Islamic ideology brings Shirk or insult or allegation on Allah.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>My Response</strong>:</p>
<p>Allah has given free will to all human beings, they are free to do anything. Like Agniveer is doing stupidity, so humans can do anything as it is their will. If Humans have a free will , they are responsible of what they do &amp; God cannot be blamed for that. As allah knows everything about what a person will do , so he has already written that, whats wrong in this.</p>
<p>Allah is God he can create anything, he is not like Shiva who didnt knew that ganesh was his son. Moreover he didnt knew how to create ganesh&#8217;s head after being choped. Isn&#8217;t Ishwar responsible for the misdeeds of Humans as Ishwar has created the human body and this world from existing material and given them their respective jobs based on past Karma? It means all humans are programmed to do what they do in this world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>3. Coming back to Quranic Ayats, it is clear that belief only in Allah is not sufficient. So while Islam shouts a lot about Shirk meaning belief in anything apart from Allah, in reality belief in Prophet is also necessary apart from belief in Allah to save one from Hell.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<p>a. Surate Nisa 13-14 – Those who obey Allah and Rasul (Muhammad) alone will go to enjoy Heaven and those who do not will go to Hell.<br />
b. Al Imran 174 – Believe in Allah and Muhammad</p>
<p>c. Surate Mayda 92 – Obey Allah and Muhammad</p>
<p>d. Surate Noor 55 – Obey Muhammad and you may be forgiven.</p>
<p>e. Surate Nisa 66 – Believe in Muhammad because he brought truth</p>
<p>f. Ale Imran 30 – If you indeed believe in Allah, then be my (Muhammad&#8217;s followers). Allah will love you and forgive your sins.</p>
<p>g. One who rebels against Muhammad after this order and follows people other than Muslims shall be thrown into Hell.</p>
<p>Some Mullahs say that the message of Muhamamd was none other than message of Allah, so all these Ayats refer to Shirk against Allah alone.</p>
<p>But if that be so, what was the need of adding Rasul/ Muhammad in these ayats? And what about noble people like Vedantis, Arya Samajis etc who refuse to believe in Muhammad but are otherwise good people? What about those who condemn Muhammad for stories of lust and killing associated with him, but are noble people otherwise? Why should they go to Hell?</p>
<p>And if that be so, what remains to be proven to showcase Islam as a barbaric intolerant religion?</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>My Response:</strong></p>
<p>Agniveer has given wrong reference and also mistranslated the verses. Readers should check the references provided by Agniveer as they are all manipulated by Agniveer. If Allah is saying we have to believe the prophets , than we have to. Allah has sent his message through the Prophets, if we don&#8217;t believe the Prophets that implies not believing in Allah&#8217;s message. So it becomes necessary to believe the Prophets to whom Allah&#8217;s message has been revealed. That&#8217;s why Allah says obey him and the prophet, because it is only the prophets to whom the message of allah is revealed. The prophets are not believed as God, rather as messengers of god, where as shirk refers to as believing in other god accept Allah. Thats the reason why Rasul is added in the Ayats , if we dont believe the Rasuls than we are not believing in Allah&#8217;s message which they have brought.</p>
<p>Those who don&#8217;t believe Muhammad(p.b.u.h) simply means not believing in allah&#8217;s message.</p>
<p>Condemning Muhammad(P.B.U.H) is not right, as he was Allah&#8217;s messenger. He was Sinless , innocent &amp; masooom. He was the chosen one by Allah to give his message.  So it is not right to insult him with irrelevant arguments which doesn&#8217;t carry any weight.</p>
<p>Allah conveyed his message through the prophet hence it is said that the message of prophet is the message of Allah. It was not the prophet who made such rules or added verses from his thought but they were all divinely revealed by Allah, It is mentioned in the Quran,</p>
<p>53:3 and neither does he speak out of his own desire.</p>
<p>Agniveer should first prove that Vedas are the word of god, because when you read the Vedas, the speaker are all humans, there is hardly any where in Vedas which is addressed by Ishwar. It even contains verses of lecherous persons and prostitute, so what is the need of adding such people in Vedas?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>4. Why is Gabriel not included, if Muhammad is included? After all if Muhammad was agent of Allah, so was Gabriel- the angel who transmitted Allah&#8217;s message to Muhammad? Why does Kalma have Muhammad&#8217;s name but not that of Gabriel?<br />
<strong><em><br />
(Kalma is the Islamic proclamation that there is no God but Allah and Muhammad is his prophet. This is necessary to believe in to have passport to Heaven, regardless of all other good deeds.)</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>My Response</strong>:</p>
<p>Gabriel is not included because it is not gabriel who revealed the message of Allah to Humans, Gabriel only conveyed it to the prophet. If we will not believe in Muhammad then it implies not believing in Allah&#8217; message, as only to Muhammad the message was revealed. The prophet  gave the message of Allah to us &amp; not  Gabriel. Kalma asks Nuslims to believe in Allah as the only God, &amp; Muhammad(P.B.U.H) as his messenger, so it&#8217;s important to believe this basic principle</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Agniveer Wrote:</strong></p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>5. Islam makes it more clear in Surate Nisa 150, 151 that those who differentiate between Allah and Muhammad and say that they shall believe in some things but not on other, and want to have a middle path are true Kafirs. And we have prepared worst of punishments for them.</p>
<p>Thus in this Ayat, all scope of any understanding with Muslims except accepting Islam blindly is doomed forever in Hell!</p>
<p><em>What more is needed to perpetuate terrorism!</em></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>My Response:</strong></p>
<p>This verse does not mention Prophet Muhammad S.A.W, Agniveer has misinterpreted this verse also, it states,</p>
<p>4:150-1 Those who deny Allah and His messengers, and (those who) wish to separate Allah from His messengers, saying: &#8220;We believe in some but reject others&#8221;: And (those who) wish to take a course midway,-  They are in truth (equally) unbelievers; and we have prepared for unbelievers a humiliating punishment.</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Tafsir al Jalalayn</p>
<p>&#8221;Those who disbelieve in God and His messengers and seek to divide between God and His messengers, by believing in Him but not in them, and say, &#8216;We believe in some, of the messengers, and disbelieve in some&#8217;, of the others, and seek to adopt a way, a path, to follow, between them, [between] unbelief and belief.&#8221;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Tafsir ibn Abbas</p>
<p>(Lo! those who disbelieve in Allah and His messengers) meaning Ka&#8217;b and his followers, (and seek to make distinction between Allah and His messengers) with regard to prophethood and surrender to Allah, (and say: We believe in some) Scriptures and messengers (and disbelieve in others) in other scriptures and messengers, (and seek to choose a way) a religion (in between) between disbelief and faith;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Again Agniveer&#8217;s inconsistency &amp; ignorance in Islamic knowledge has been exposed. I dont understand why he copies from anti-islamics and makes up some irrelevant articles.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/" data-wpel-link="internal">Rebuttal to Agnvieer: Why Islam is fanatic</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2015/06/23/rebuttal-to-agnvieer-why-islam-is-fanatic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
