<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>manu &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/manu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 10:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cow urine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exreta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gomutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahabharata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panchgavya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramayana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Srinivas Kakkilaya The cow is, at the least, an animal domesticated by man for help in agricultural activities.[1]  Although the mighty machines now used in farming have made these animals irrelevant in agriculture, valiant attempts are being made, at least in India, to preserve the exalted position of the so called ‘second mother’ &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/" data-wpel-link="internal">Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by <a title="Posts by Srinivas Kakkilaya" href="http://nirmukta.com/author/kakkilaya/" rel="author noopener external" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Srinivas Kakkilaya<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>The cow is, at the least, an animal domesticated by man for help in agricultural activities.[1]  Although the mighty machines now used in farming have made these animals irrelevant in agriculture, valiant attempts are being made, at least in India, to preserve the exalted position of the so called ‘second mother’ [2] or even ‘mother of the world’ [3,4].<br />
<span id="more-1761"></span><br />
<span id="more-568"></span> The stringent agitations to protect the ‘cow-mother’ [4,5] and even riots and murders of dalits for the sake of the cow,[6,7] suggest that the human life is far less important than a dead cow in this part of the world.[7] This extraordinary reverence for the cow has led to the development and marketing of many ‘products’ made from the secretions and excretions of the cow, with claims that these products may be more ‘lucrative’ than even the dairy.[8]
<strong>‘Cow Products’</strong></p>
<p id="ufgaZfF"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-7216  alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604.png" alt="" width="295" height="195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604.png 417w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412643d604-300x199.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 295px) 100vw, 295px" /></p>
<p>The list of ‘products’ developed from the milk and excreta of the cow is quite long. <em><a href="http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Panchagavya<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></em>and cow urine distillate (<em><a href="http://www.yogashram.in/June%202006.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">gau arka<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></em>) are the most quoted of these preparations.<br />
<em>Panchagavy</em> is a blend of five (<em>pancha</em>) products obtained from the cow (<em>gavya</em> = from <em>gau</em>) – the dung, urine, milk, ghee and curd.[9,10] Three preparations of cow’s urine, namely <em>gau-mutra asav</em> (fermented preparation), <em>gau-arka</em> (or distillate) and <em>Ganavati </em>(or tablet) are also used as medicines.[8,11] Two US patents have also been obtained for the <em>gau -arka</em> [11] and this fact has been highlighted over and over again.<br />
Various products from the cow have been suggested as a successful remedy against more than hundred diseases, from fever to cancer.<strong>[8,11,12] </strong><em>Panchagavya</em> is most reverentially used as a ‘body and soul cleanser’, following the birth or death of a family member. It has also been suggested as a medicine and more profusely as a pesticidal spray for plants and as a soil enriching manure.[10]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>Very recently, panchagavya has been suggested as a remedy for chikungunya as well.[13] Cow’s urine has been used in the preparations of hair oil, shampoo, skin cream etc.[8] Preparations like soap, nasal powder, body powder, body cream, incense sticks, tooth powder etc. have been prepared from the cow dung and recommended for medical use[8]. Probably to add sanctity to the entire gamut of these ‘medications’, it has been claimed that Indian pure breed cows have <a href="http://www.yogashram.in/June%202006.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">‘immunology power’<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> from 90% to 98% while the cows of mixed breed have less than 40%.[11]</blockquote>
<p><strong>The ‘evidence&#8217;:</strong><br />
Curious to know about <em>Panchagavya</em>, I asked an Ayurveda physician about its utility. She briefed me about all the virtues of the <em>gau mutra</em> (cow’s urine), <em>gau maya</em> (cow dung) and <em>Panchagavya</em>, quoting the Charaka Samhita. But how can we, living in the 21st century,  rely on an ancient text to justify the use of these excreta, I wondered. All these have been well studied by Charaka, she told me. May be, but the concept of biochemical molecules (and the modern biochemical analysers) and of microbes (and the means of isolating them) were non-existent during Charaka’s time, I countered. But the cow’s urine hasn’t changed since Charaka’s time, she averred. I was dumbstruck!<br />
Most articles on the virtues of cow’s excreta extensively quote from scriptures and the Charaka Samhita. Here are some of these arguments:</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light">
<ul>
<li>The cow is our mother and we are her children. Therefore cow urine is beneficial.[8,11]</li>
<li>Diseases are caused by imbalance of elements bile, mucous and air and cow urine balances elements.[8]</li>
<li>Amongst urines, cow urine is best.[8]</li>
<li>Ganga resides in the cow urine and it contains copper and gold salts, which are elixirs. It does not decay, older the cow urine, the more useful it is.[8]</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Recently a lot has been written about the patents for cow urine; one obtained on the basis of laboratory studies (on culture plates and cell lines) on the usefulness of cow urine distillate in enhancing the efficacy of antibiotics and anti cancer drugs, [14,15] and the other patent obtained for cow urine therapy.[16] There are reports of the use of cow’s urine therapy from Myanmar [17] and of a cow’s urine concoction used as a traditional remedy for convulsive seizures in Nigeria.[18] There have also been reports of studies on the cow’s urine distillate in gouty arthritis, lymphocyte and polymorphonuclear cells and carbon tetrachloride poisoning, all done on experimental animals in small numbers.[19-22] These results have been extrapolated freely and wild conclusions have been drawn about the ‘magical powers’ of the cow’s urine in treating almost all the diseases afflicting mankind today.[14,17] Even the Department of Animal Husbandry of the Ministry of Agriculture, Government of India, has published reports that seek to promote the marketing of cow’s urine as a therapeutic agent.[23]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The facts:</strong></p>
<p>Faced with this blitzkrieg of marketing of cow’s urine and the real danger that cow’s urine and other products of cow’s excreta may be pushed into the throats of hapless patients, with active support from the govt., agencies., it is time we look into the facts.<br />
One need not go far to see the hypocrisy of the ‘cow urine promoters’ than have a look at the ayurveda texts themselves, extensively quoted as the primary source of support for the utility of cow’s urine as a therapeutic agent. All three major ancient texts of ayurveda, by Charaka (1<sup>st</sup>-2<sup>nd</sup> century), Susruta (3<sup>rd</sup> –4<sup>th</sup> century) and Vagbhata (7<sup>th</sup> century) mention of the therapeutic uses of beef[24,25] as well, but this fact is no where mentioned by the proponents of cow’s urine. Eating beef is a sin and drinking cow’s urine or eating its dung brings health, if these self-styled guardians of ancient Indian tradition are to be believed.</p>
<p>What about the much touted patents for cow’s urine? A patent is a set of exclusive rights granted by a state to an inventor to prevent or exclude others from making, using, selling, offering to sell or importing the invention.[26] Nothing more, nothing less. A patent in itself cannot be the proof for the utility of any product. It is hardly surprising that while International patents have been registered for cow’s urine and its products, no such patent has been obtained from the Govt. of India. An Indian patent may not make enough and weighty news, but an international patent, on the other, helps to claim that even ‘foreigners’ have accepted the virtues of cow’s urine!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p id="xfXbjMs"><img decoding="async" width="300" height="215" class="size-full wp-image-7218  alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/img_5f2412d2c9613.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>All the studies available in the literature about the therapeutic efficacy of cow’s excreta are small studies conducted in the labs and on animals or tissues. There are no reports of any controlled, double blind clinical studies in humans, other than some anecdotal reports and claims by the practitioners of ‘cow therapy’ and all these so called claims of research appear dubious by any scientific standards.[27] Most of these papers contradict their own claims: the claims made about the gold and copper salts in urine, for example, are not supported by the data provided by the protagonists themselves.[8,28]
<p>Urine is urine, the liquid waste that is filtered by the kidneys and excreted through the urinary system. It contains many solutes and biological products that are unnecessary for the living body and hence excreted and also some substances secreted by the urinary tract to facilitate this excretion. Chemical constituents of human and animal urine are almost alike.[28,29] For example, Urokinase is an enzyme secreted into the urine to prevent its clogging; today, it is extracted from human urine and used to dissolve clots in the coronary arteries in patients who suffer a heart attack.[30] Does this justify drinking one’s own urine in case of a heart attack? Far from it. Is cow’s urine safe for mankind? There are reports of severe adverse effects, even fatal, of drinking cow urine concoctions, further supported by experimental evidence.[31] Cow’s urine can also be a source of infectious diseases, especially leptospirosis, [32] that can spread through oral mucosa. The claim that cow’s urine and cow dung have antiseptic properties is not only baseless, but also dangerously misleading. While cow dung (and all fecal matter) is teeming with bacteria excreted from the intestines, several bacteria have been isolated from <em>Panchagavya </em>too.[33,34] Application of these bacteria-rich excreta onto wounds may lead to life threatening sepsis. Only those who are absolutely ignorant about such facts can daringly market cow’s excreta as antiseptics, but the tragedy is that some practitioners of modern medicine, blinded by their faiths in their ‘spiritual heads’ or <em>‘Mathadhipathis’</em> also appear to support such nonsense.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Conclusions:<br />
</strong><br />
It is clear that cow’s urine and other excreta are only the waste products rejected by the animal’s body and are similar to the excreta of other animals and therefore, there is absolutely no reason why the cow’s urine or other excreta should be venerable over those of humans beings or other animals.</p>
<p>The claims of the efficacy of cow’s excreta (and their products) in the treatment of almost every disease are not supported by any evidence and there are no clinical trials reported on the use of these products in human beings. With reports available about the possible adverse effects of the use of cow’s excreta, it is shocking that such products are being allowed to be not only marketed but also trumpeted, even supported by the agencies of the govt. of India, as the ‘cure-for-all’ wonder drugs.</p>
<p>Propaganda regarding the utility of cow’s excreta largely emanates from the obscurantist and Hindu fundamentalist forces and appears to be designed to condemn the ordinary human beings into ingesting cow’s excreta under the alibi of ‘treatment’ and ‘long life’. This is not surprising at all, given the several instances of the down trodden dalits forced into eating even human excreta by the same fundamentalists.[35]
<p>Eulogising the cow (and not buffalo and other cattle that are equally ‘useful’) as ‘second mother’, ‘God mother’, ‘mother of the world’ etc., largely because it provides milk,[11] (and hopefully not because of its excreta) raises a fundamental question about the concept of motherhood itself: Do we love and respect our own mothers solely because we have been breastfed and is motherhood only about milk?</p>
<p>This entire exercise of marketing the cow’s products and promising huge economic benefits (a claim not supported by any data) of keeping the cows even after they have passed the age of secreting milk  is part of the grand design to prevent the slaughtering of the cows so as to deprive the poor sections of the society from quality meat as well as some economic benefits of marketing the beef. But sustaining the livestock is proving to be very costly for the environment, with a large share of global warming attributed to the livestock.[36,37] It is time we take a rational view of all the issues involved.<br />
<strong>References:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Cattle. The Wikipedia Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattle<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Discover how cows have altered human life, human biology, and the geography of the world Availalbe at <a href="http://www.pbs.org/wnet/nature/holycow/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.pbs.org/wnet/nature/holycow/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Subhuman Das. Indian Cows: Blessed Bovines! <a href="http://hinduism.about.com/library/weekly/aa101800a.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://hinduism.about.com/library/weekly/aa101800a.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.vishwagou.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.vishwagou.org/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Cow Protection Available at <a href="http://www.vhp.org/protectthecow.php" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.vhp.org/protectthecow.php<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Taneja N. Mangalore ‘Riots’. People’s Democracy. October 22, 2006; 30(43) Available at <a href="http://pd.cpim.org/2006/1022/10222006_nalini.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://pd.cpim.org/2006/1022/10222006_nalini.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Rajalakshmi TK. Slaughter of the Dalits. Frontline November 09 – 22, 2002;19(23) Available at <a href="http://www.hinduonnet.com/fline/fl1923/stories/20021122003703800.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hinduonnet.com/fline/fl1923/stories/20021122003703800.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>
<p align="left">Cow Urine: Principles &amp; Applications Available at <a href="http://www.hkrl.com/cowurine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hkrl.com/cowurine.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
</li>
<li>Panchagavya. Available at <a href="http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thereligiousproducts.com/panchagavya.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Natarajan K. Panchagavya: How to Make. Available at <a href="http://www.agricultureinformation.com/forums/organic-farming/15995-panchagavya-how-make.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.agricultureinformation.com/forums/organic-farming/15995-panchagavya-how-make.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Seminar on mother cow and Panchagavya. Available at <a href="http://www.goshala.com/articles/panchagavya.php" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.goshala.com/articles/panchagavya.php<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>http://www.goshalaindia.com/scientific-propeties.html</li>
<li><a href="http://www.daijiworld.com/news/news_disp.asp?n_id=48836&amp;n_tit=Belthangady%3A+Live+Naturally%2C+Be+Free+From+Ailments+-+Raghaveswara+Bharathi" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.daijiworld.com/news/news_disp.asp?n_id=48836&amp;n_tit=Belthangady%3A+Live+Naturally%2C+Be+Free+From+Ailments+-+Raghaveswara+Bharathi<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Dhama K, Chauhan RS, Singhal L. Anti-cancer activity of cow urine: Current status and future directions. International Journal of Cow Science 2005;1(2) Available at http://indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor:ijcs&amp;volume=1&amp;issue=2&amp;article=001</li>
<li>Khanuja SPS et al. Use Of Bioactive Fraction From Cow Urine Distillate (‘Go Mutra’) As A Bio-Enhancer Of Anti-Infective, Anti-Cancer Agents And Nutrients Available at <a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/EP1330253.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.freepatentsonline.com/EP1330253.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Jain VK. Cow Urine Therapy And Herbal Medicinal Composition With Cow Urine And Method Of Manufacturing The Same World Intellectual Property Organisation, International Patent No WO/2002/096440 Available at <a href="http://www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp?IA=IN2001000136&amp;WO=2002096440&amp;DISPLAY=DESC" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp?IA=IN2001000136&amp;WO=2002096440&amp;DISPLAY=DESC<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Awale et al. An amazing cow’s urine therapy in Myanmar. J Trad Med. 2006;23:178-83 Available at <a href="http://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/jtm/23/5/178/_pdf" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.jstage.jst.go.jp/article/jtm/23/5/178/_pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Elegbe RA, Oyebola DD. Cow’s urine poisoning in Nigeria: cardiorespiratory effects of cow’s urine in dogs. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 1977;71(2):127-32.</li>
<li>Influence of “Divine Cow Powder” on Peripheral Tissues of Acute Gouty Arthritis Acta Universitatis Traditionis Medicalis Sinensis Pharmacologiaeque Shanghai 2007 <a href="http://www.shvoong.com/medicine-and-health/1597348-influence-divine-cow-powder-peripheral/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.shvoong.com/medicine-and-health/1597348-influence-divine-cow-powder-peripheral/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Dipanwita Dutta, S Saravana Devi, K Krishnamurthi, T Chakrabarti Anticlastogenic effect of redistilled cow’s urine distillate in human peripheral lymphocytes challenged with manganese dioxide and hexavalent chromium. Biomed Environ Sci. 2006 Dec ;19 (6):487-94 <a href="http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:17319276" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:17319276<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>K Krishnamurthi, Dipanwita Dutta, S D Sivanesan, T Chakrabarti. Protective effect of distillate and redistillate of cow’s urine in human polymorphonuclear leukocytes challenged with established genotoxic chemicals Available at <a href="http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:15602821" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://lib.bioinfo.pl/pmid:15602821<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Achliya GS, Kotagale NR, Wadodkar SG, Dorle AK. Hepatoprotective activity of panchagavya ghrita against carbontetrachloride induced hepatotoxicity in rats Indian journal of pharmacology 2003;35(5):308-311 Available at <a href="http://cat.inist.fr/?aModele=afficheN&amp;cpsidt=15240774" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://cat.inist.fr/?aModele=afficheN&amp;cpsidt=15240774<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Sunil Mansinghka Bi Products Of Cattle – Organic Manure And Cow Urine – Medicines – Draught – Gas – Electricity. Available at <a href="http://dahd.nic.in/ch5/chap5.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://dahd.nic.in/ch5/chap5.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Jha DN. Paradox of the Indian Cow: Attitudes to Beef Eating in Early India. Available at <a href="http://www.indowindow.net/sad/article.php?child=17&amp;article=11" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.indowindow.net/sad/article.php?child=17&amp;article=11<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Cathy Wong Ayurvedic Foods for Your Type: How to Eat for Your Dosha. Available at <a href="http://altmedicine.about.com/cs/2/a/ayurveda.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://altmedicine.about.com/cs/2/a/ayurveda.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Patent. Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Research paper and observation. Dr. Jain’s Cow urine Therapy. Available at http://www.cowurine.com/research-paper.html</li>
<li>The Main Elements of Cow Urine and Their Functions. Dr. Jain’s Cow urine Therapy. Available at http://www.cowurine.com/main-element-of-cow.html</li>
<li>Putnam DF. Composition And Concentrative Properties Of Human Urine. Available at <a href="http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/19710023044_1971023044.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/19710023044_1971023044.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Urokinase. Available at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urokinase" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urokinase<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Oyebola DD, Elegbe RA. Cow’s urine poisoning in Nigeria. Experimental observations in mice. Available at Trop Geogr Med. 1975 Jun;27(2):194-202.</li>
<li>Sharma S, Vijayachari P, Sugunan AP, Sehgal SC. Leptospiral carrier state and seroprevalence among animal population – a cross-sectional sample survey in Andaman and Nicobar Islands. Epidemiology and Infection 2003;131:985-989</li>
<li>Akinde SB, Obire O. Aerobic heterotrophic bacteria and petroleum-utilizing bacteria from cow dung and poultry manure World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology 2008;24(9):1999-2002</li>
<li>Bhat SS, Vinu AK, Naidu R. Association of Diverse Groups of Bacteria with ‘Panchagavya’ and their Effect on Growth Promotion of Coffee Seedlings. The Association for Science and Information on Coffee (ASIC): Proceedings of ASIC Conferences – 20th Colloquium : Agronomy Available at <a href="http://www.asic-cafe.org/pdf/abstract/PA224_2004.pdf" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.asic-cafe.org/pdf/abstract/PA224_2004.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Siriyavan Anand. India Shining with Hindu Diet: Cow urine and dung for caste hindus, Human shit and piss for dalits Available at <a href="http://www.chowk.com/ilogs/65586/48030" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.chowk.com/ilogs/65586/48030<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Rearing cattle produces more greenhouse gases than driving cars, UN report warns <a title="http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming" href="http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=20772&amp;Cr=global&amp;Cr1=warming<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
<li>Livestock’s Long Shadow–Environmental Issues and Options <a title="http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf" href="http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.virtualcentre.org/en/library/key_pub/longshad/A0701E00.pdf<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/cows-excreta-as-medicine-insult-to-humanity/" data-wpel-link="internal">Cow’s Excreta as Medicine: Insult to Humanity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 18:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brahma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female foeticide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadiths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[krishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekh ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulshankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niyog pratha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophet muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vishnu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in Hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Neer Mohammed &#160; This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts . Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &#38; Agniveer. Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer. Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:Arial;">Written by Neer Mohammed<br />
</span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>This series of articles on women in Hinduism will be in four parts .</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5641"></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 1- Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand Ji &amp; Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 2- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 3- Women in Hinduism: Lies of Agniveer.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="color:gray;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Part 4- Women in Hinduism: Let us see whether Agniveer will quit Vedic Dharm or not?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><br />
<span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">In his present article on women, Agniveer makes so many bogus claims. In this series of articles we are going to analyze them one by one.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his recent article on women in Hinduism he makes these claims on Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1. Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">3. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span>. People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations. But neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4. On contrary, many a prophets of Christianity and Islam got children from slave-girls <span style="text-decoration:underline;">but never made them their wives!</span> Prophet Abraham is supposed to have even attempted to abandon his slave-girl to death after having child from her. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria. God only knows the veracity of these stories and support for sex-slavery in Bible and Quran. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">5. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">But as far as Vedas are concerned, any relation apart from one single wife/husband is clearly considered to be cause of miseries.&#8221;</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">6. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling. However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:firebrick;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">7. Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>Before analyzing these claims about Niyog in detail, let us see what Swami Dayanand had to say about Niyog.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong>ALL THE POINTS TAKEN HERE ARE FROM SATYARTHA PRAKASH TRANSLATED  BY Shri Dr. Chrianjiva Gharadwaya.</strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 129</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">1.Re-marriage is <span style="text-decoration:underline;">absolutely prohibited in the case of a twice born man or woman (i.e., one belonging to a Brahman, Kshatriya or Vaishya Class</span> . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2. The following are the principal evils of remarriage:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">a.Diminution of love between the husband and the wife, since either of them can desert the other whenever he or she so desires, and marry another person.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">b.On the death of one party, the other will take away the property of his or her deceased consort when he or she marries again. This will give rise to family disputes. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">c.If a widow re marries, many a noble family will be blotted out of existence, and its property destroyed (by constant alienation).</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">d.Re-marriage involves loss of true conjugal love and infraction of duty towards the departed husband or wife. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 130</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> 3.Q. ~ If one of the parties dies leaving no male issue, even then the family line will become extinct. Besides, if re-marriage be not allowed, the widows and widowers will resort to adultery and fornication, procure abortion, and will commit wicked deeds of a kindred nature. For these reasons re-marriage is desirable. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ No. If the widows and widowers desire to practice Brahmacharya, no such evil consequences will accrue. Again, if the widow or widower adopts a boy of her and his Class, the family line will be continued and there will be no danger of adultery being restored to. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Those, however, who cannot control their passions may beget children by having recourse to Niyoga. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>So lets us see what the niyoga is</em> [writer]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">4.Q. ~ What are the differences between re-marriage and Niyoga?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ 1.After marriage the bride leaves her paternal roof, lives with her husband, and her relations with her relations with her father&#8217;s family cease to be very close; on the contrary. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The widow (in case she contracts Niyoga) continues to live in her deceased husband&#8217;s house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">2.The children begotten of marriage inherit the property of their mother&#8217;s husband, whereas, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">offspring begotten of Niyoga on a widow are not regarded as children of the begetter and consequently they don&#8217;t take his surname, nor can they be claimed by him. They are spoken fo as the children of their mother&#8217;s deceased husband, take his surname, inherit his property and live in his house. </span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">3.Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations (after the stipulated period). </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;">4.The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>5,.The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>PAGE 131</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ Do the same laws apply to Niyoga and marriage, or are they different in each case?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ They are little different. A few differences have already been enumerated, and here are some more:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>A married couple can produce children up to the limit of ten, while that connected by Niyoga cannot produce more than two or four.A married couple always lives together but not that connected by Niyoga..</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Let the widow rear the children for two or three years and hand them to her husband by Niyoga, in case it has been entered into for his behalf. In this way a widow can give birth to two children for herself and two for each of the four husbands by Niyoga. Similarly a widower can beget two children for himself and two for each of the four wives by Niyoga. Thus ten children in all can be produced by means of Niyoga. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">This is what the Veda declares:-&#8220;O thou who art fit to procreate and art strong, do thou raise upon the married wife or upon these widows, with whom thou hast <span style="text-decoration:underline;">contracted Niyoga</span>, good children, and make them happy. Do thou beget with on thy married wife ten children, and consider her the eleventh (memberof the family). O woman! Let ten children be raised on thee by the married husband or thy <span style="text-decoration:underline;">husbands by Niyoga</span> and do thou consider thy husband as the eleventh (member of thy family).&#8221; Rig Veda 10: 85, 48.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 133</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~Should the relation of Niyoga be entered into with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a different Class as well? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ A woman should contract Niyoga with a member of one&#8217;s own Class or with that of a higher Class, that is, a Vaishaya woman with a Braahman, a Kshatriya or aVaishaya; a Kshatriya woman with Kshatriya or a Braahman; a Brahman woman with a Braahman. The object of this is that the spermatic fluid should always be of a man of the same Class as the woman or of a higher Class, never </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 134</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q. ~ are there any Vedic and Shaastric authorities in favor of Niyoga, as there are in support of the marriage institution? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">A. ~ <em>&#8220;O man and woman <span style="text-decoration:underline;">(connected by Niyoga</span>), just as a widow, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him</span>, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>O widow! Dothou give up thinking of they deceased husband and choose another from among living men. But thou must understand and remember that if thou should contractest Niyoga for the benefit of thy second husband with whom thou are united by performing the ceremony of joining hands, the child resulting from this union shall belong to him; but if thou interest into relation of <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> for thy benefit, the child shall be thine. Do thou bear this in mind. Let thy husband by <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Niyoga</span> also follow this law.&#8221; RIG VEDA 18,8. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;<em>Do thou O woman that givest no pain to thy husband or devar (husband by Niyoga), art kind to animals in this Order of householders, walk assiduously in the path of righteousness and justice, art well-versed in all the shaastraas, hast children and grandchildren, givest birth to valiant the brave boys, desirest a second husband (by Niyoga), and bestoweth happiness on all, accept a man of they choice as thy husband or devar , and always perform the Homa which is the duty of every householder.&#8221; ATHARVA VEDA 14:, 2, 18. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>The sage Manu also sanctions the marriage of <strong>virgin widows</strong>. Says he <span style="text-decoration:underline;">&#8220;A virgin widow may marry the younger or the elder brother of her deceased husband</span>.&#8221; MANU. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> </em>PAGE 135</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;text-decoration:underline;"><em>A man may also contract <strong>Niyoga with eleven women</strong> (one after the other), just as a woman may enter into the relation of <strong>Niyoga with eleven men</strong> (one after the other), as sanctioned by the Veda in the following text:- </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45. </strong></span></em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 137</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> <em>Q. ~ Can a woman contract Niyoga only after the death of her husband or even when he is alive? </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> A. ~ <strong>This relation can be entered into even in the lifetime of the husband (or of the wife</strong>). Here is Vedic text n support of this view. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> &#8220;When a man is incapable of producing children, let him address his wife as follows:- O thou that art desirous of getting children do not expect me to raise offspring upon thee. Do thou, therefore, seek another husband.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 10, 10.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Similarly when a woman on account of some chronic disease is rendered incapable of bearing children, let her address the following words to her husband. &#8220;My lord! Do not expect me to bear any children. Do thou, therefore, contract Niyoga with a widow.[THESE WORDS ARE NOT PART OF MANTRA THEY HVE BEEN ADDED BY SWAMI JI-WRITER]</em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><strong><em>contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </em></strong></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 138</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">The sage Manu declares:-</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;If a husband has gone abroad in furtherance of some righteous cause, </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">let his wife wait for eight years;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for he acquisition of knowledge and glory, for six years; </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if for the pursuit of material ends, for three years. If after the expiry of the prescribed periods he does not turn up, she may contract Niyoga and obtain children.&#8221; MANU 9: 76. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;if the wife be sterile, let the husband wait for eight years after marriage;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">if all of her children die, for ten years,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>if she bears only daughters and no sons, for eleven years</strong></span>,</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em> <strong>if she be a termagant, let him forsake her immediately, and enter into Niyoga with another lady and beget children upon her.&#8221; MANU 9: 81</strong>. </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"><em>Likewise if the husband be very cruel, let his wife forsake him, and bear children by Niyoga who will succeed to the property of her husband by marriage.[THESE ARE NOT PART OF VEDIC LAWS-i.e manu smriti] </em></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Q.~ Monogamy being the rule (i.e., if one man be allowed to have only one wife, and one woman only one husband) what will a person do, if the wife be encienti ir afflicted with some chronic disease, or if the husband be a valetudinarian and either of them cannot control himself or herself on account of extreme youth? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> PAGE 140 </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;"> A. ~ We have answered this objection while treating of Niyoga. <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife and she is pregnant, he may contract Niyoga with a (widow) and beget offspring on her, but let him never misconduct himself with a prostitute or commit adultery.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">PAGE 142</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:teal;font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8230; <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>Niyoga is clearly allowed by the Veda.</em></strong></span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Above we read some laws related to niyog and remarriage which iare laid by Swami Dayanand Saraswati which he backs up through Vedas, Manusmriti and other scriptures. He even gives historical refrences from Mahabharata [<em>it is to be noted agniveer reject these refrences,now its upto reader to decide who is write and who is wrong</em>] and gives various qualities of Niyoga.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In his belief the alleged reformer has claimed re-marriage as faulty and Niyog as justified and appropriate .</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand pointed back on remarriage issue as goofy, nonsense and childish . Further more as the great writer has mentioned that if a man or a woman remarries their faith/religion will be lost/destroyed but due to Niyog their basic faith will be pure and safe. Isn&#8217;t this nonsensical? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">What kind of <em>patidharam</em> is this in which if a woman remarries will loose or destroy his faith and if she maintains 11 other sexual relationships she will be safe and clean?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">If a wife is alive and due to certain reasons the husband is  incapable to reproduce, this doesn&#8217;t mean that he lacks sexual desire. If a man has sexual desire but is incapable of producing offspring and his wife approaches another men for niyog, then where and how will the husband fulfill his sexual desire?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Given a thought, everwhere he mentions about begetting a male child only after niyog, but according to the science there is 50% possibility can  be a birth of a girl child. <em>[This is another proof of wishing a male child  in Vedas which we will see later on,and it may also be noted that swami ji permits  Noyog for begetting a male child even if a daughter is present.] </em>In such circumstances where a girl child is born, the rules and conditions governing Niyog have not been mentioned </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji said that  &#8220;Married people are required to serve and help each other, while those that contract Niyoga have to abandon all relations after the stipulated period. The relation of marriage is life-long, while the contract of Niyoga ceases to be operative after the desired object has been attained. The husband and the wife help each other in the performance of their house hold duties, while those that have that have contracted Niyoga discharge the duties of their respective households.then for two or three years women have to take care of child.&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Now mark, isn&#8217;t it like lower animal activity in which after having sex only the female has to take care of the children? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As Swami has mentioned, if a woman goes on producing girl babies, still MAN can have a male child by doing niyog. Here the point to be noted is, if a woman keeps giving birth to a girl, then its not the woman but the man who is to be blamed. This is a scientific fact that the determination of gender is done by a male and not by female.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As written, if spoken bluntly, Niyog can be done if a wife is pregnant and husband seeks a sexual relationship and if a husband is ill for long time and the wife wants to have sexual relationship. In such cases they can look for proper partners and go for Niyog.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Aren&#8217;t the law, virtue and values not being locked up here? Is the not the meaning of Niyog FREE SEX? Can you imagine any society which is of more low standard than this? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">One more thing to note is what Swami Dayanand states, &#8220;that even <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong><em>If a man be not able to control his passions while his wife  is pregnant</em> he wants to have sexual relationship in such case he  can look for proper partners &amp; go for Niyog</strong></span>.&#8221; Now if the necessity of Niyog was only to bear children (which it is not), why go for free sex during the wife&#8217;s pregnancy?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami Dayanand in order to confirm the truthfulness, authenticity and practicality gave two examples from the period of Mahabharata. It is written that Vyas had Niyog with wives of those  persons with unique semen and derived offsprings. By Niyog process, Ambika derived Dhritrashtrya, Ambalika derived Pandu and a servant derived Vidur. Another example is of the wives of King Pandu&#8217;s women Kunti and Madri. Due to the reason of incapability in production of Pandu both his wives derived offspring by Niyog. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">[<em>it is quite contrary to the view held by Agniveer that the refrence from Mahabharata is interpolation</em>]</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">As said in Mahabharat, what to say about Niyog, child even with a non-married woman  was considered good and venerable. The two wise &amp; great men Ved viyas and Bheeshm pitamah&#8217;s origin is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Secondly, in Mahabharat time, in a society one woman could be a wife of 5 brothers e.g. Draupadi the wife of Pandav is a solid proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Thirdly, according to what is written in Mahabharata, in this era, even without woman&#8217;s communication only men were able give birth to children. Mahabharat&#8217;s major character guru Dronacharya&#8217;s origin is a proof. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fourthly, in this period children were born by magical methods e.g. origin of Draupadi. Therefore, in such a society what was the need for Niyog? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">To give it a thought, under what rules Ved Vyas ji did Niyog and why did he do Niyog with three women at the same time?<span style="color:red;"><br />
</span></span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Fifthly, why did Kunti give birth to 4 children by Niyog activity on contrary to the rules? Kunti gave birth to Karan, Yudhishtir, Bheem and Arjun and all of them were called as pandu. </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Sixthly, in those days when niyog was considered innocent and good then why did kunti float Karan in the river because of shame ?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Seventhly, who were those men with whom kunti had Niyog and derived offspring? </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Swami ji has prohibited polygamy, where as its said that in that  in Mahabharata civilization &#8220;bahuvivah&#8221; was allowed. The society where swamiji has made niyog evident, should that only be considered as high and template?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In Sathyarth Prakash (doubt removal edition) Pandit Jwalaprasad Sharma produce few more examples in support of Niyoga. He says that in ancient period women used to derive off-springs by accepting the semen of Rishi-Munim, wise, great men by Niyog. All the evidences shown by Pandit ji are from Mahabharat period only. Was Mahabharat the only old (vaidik) period? Was Niyog the only need of Rishis?</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Its ironical that with the (vaidik) incantation Swami ji demonstrated niyog tradition  with same incantation (mantra) various wise men and lecturers have demonstrated widow remarriage . </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Pandit Omprakash has pointed, for widow remarriage, in his book <em>&#8220;vaidik sahitya aur sanskriti ka swaroop&#8221;</em> he has written that in vedic society there was  permission of widow remarriage.  In the mantra  ( rig ved 10-18-8)  he has given his summary as follows –</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;Hey woman! Leaving this dead husband again make arrival into the living military. accept the future husband,  who wishes to marry you&#8221;</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">It&#8217;s a whacking, shameful topic where a wise man and a society reformer should support remarriage and widow remarriage, but here the supposed reformers defend niyog practice and showed it useful for the future. Isn&#8217;t it&#8217;s a sign of a wiseman&#8217;s sleazy psychology? In the movies of today that show various stars, even in them we don&#8217;t get to see subject movies on these practices and favor. Leaving swami dayanand , all other wise men and reformers belonging to navjagrun ,favored remarriage.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">LET US NOW SUMMARIZE THE VIEW OF AGNIVEER AND SWAMI JI. READERS WILL SEE THAT AGNIVEER  IS TRYING TO HIDE THE TRUTH AND IS GOING AGAINST SWAMI JI AND ALSO SATYARTHA PRAKASH [APTLY MITHYA PRAKSH OR BIBLE OF HATE].<br />
</span></p>
<div>
<table style="border-collapse:collapse;" border="0">
<colgroup>
<col style="width:199px;" />
<col style="width:351px;" /></colgroup>
<tbody valign="top">
<tr>
<td style="padding:5px;border:outset .75pt;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>AGNIVEER</strong></span></p>
</td>
<td style="border-top:outset .75pt;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle">
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>SWAMI DAYANAND JI</strong></span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Vedas have no mention of Niyog</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Niyog is clearly allowed by the Vedas</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Neither is it a Vedic order nor a compulsory practice in Aryan society.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;" valign="middle"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How can it be so as Rigved 10-85-48, 10-40-2, Atharvaved 14-2-18, etc mention Niyog.</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">As for Mahabharat, well thats a historical text full of interpolations and written in an era when the Vedic values were already dwindling.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;">
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">Kunti and Maadri, wives of king Pandu had recourse to Niyoga. Vyas, on the death of his brothers, Chidraangad and Vichitravirya </span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">contracted Niyoga with their wives and begot Dhritraashtra on Ambikaa, Paandu on Ambaalika and Vidur on a Shoodra woman. </span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:outset .75pt;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">However evidence in matter of Dharma can come only from Vedas. So kindly cite Vedic references.</span></td>
<td style="border-top:none;border-left:none;border-bottom:outset .75pt;border-right:outset .75pt;padding:5px;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;…….take unto thyself the eleventh husband by Niyoga.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 85, 45.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">&#8220;O man and woman (connected by Niyoga), just as a widow, co-habits with her husband by Niyoga and produces children for him, and a wife co-habits with her husband by marriage and produces children for him, likewise (it may be asked) where both of you were during the day and during the night, and where you slept, who you are, and what your native place is.&#8221; RIG VEDA 10: 40, 2. </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">LET US SEE FEW MORE CLAIMS OF AGNIVEER </span><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong><span style="color:#002060;">CLAIM 1:</span> People have interpreted vedic verses to create social custom of Niyog to prevent prostitution in emergency situations.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">It is to be noted that only Swami Dayanand and Arya Samaj  who accept Niyog had interpreted Vedic verses in support of Niyog. I had provided a reference of Pandit Omkar who saw those texts as supporting widow remarriage.  Also Mr. Agniveer in his usual hateful style tries to attack the Muslims by saying, &#8220;The meaning of this mantra (Rig 10-18-8) provided has been slightly distorted and misinterpreted to suit one&#8217;s mindset of hatred.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Thus Agniveer is calling Swami Dayanand&#8217;s view as a <strong>mindset of hatred and suting his agenda</strong>. Cheers!<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 2: Niyog Pratha was a social custom to beget a child that <span style="text-decoration:underline;">was prevalent in all societies</span> and more so in Biblical and Quranic society.. <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Bible, Quran and Hadiths are full of such references</span>. Prophet Muhammad is supposed to have the only son from his slave Maria</strong>.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Having seens the laws of Niyog it is the height of shamelessness of agniveer to look for Niyog in  Islamic and Christian scriptures.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Mother Mariah, was the WIFE of Prophet Muhammad as clearly mentioned in Hadith accounts. Agniveer as usual takes his readers for a ride by not providing any references.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><strong>CLAIM 3: Niyog is optional not compulsory and in emergency situation only.</strong><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">How ironical it is that pregnancy of wife becomes an emergency situation (as claimed by Swamiji)  and and Niyog is only gain a son even if a daughter is present? How pitiful?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:9pt;">In conclusion, I want to assert that Niyog is a curse and bad practice, it cannot be suitable for any period. The state of a women in India was extremely pitiable. It  feels like certain rishis, munis and  other men made  certain rules and regulations, where in woman was treated like a breakfast pl<span style="color:black;">ate and and thing of lust only.</span> Niyog  tradition made a woman no less than a prostitute. Like you have already read above, a widow can have niyog with 10 men. The two words widow and prostitute if taken with the same meaning, it won&#8217;t be unfair. A movie called &#8220;water&#8221; released in 2000 which was picturized on the bad condition of  widow women which was controversial and was banned. The movie was based on historical facts where widows were shown as prostitutes. Since widowed women are considered as inauspicious, they go to pilgrimage places like Kaashi, Vrindavan etc and sing religious chants and beg to earn a living. Even in these days there are nearly 16000 widows living in Kaashi.</span><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;"><br />
</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-family:Times New Roman;font-size:12pt;">Let us respect women, work for their empowerment and allow remarriage instead of this cursed practice of Niyog.<br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/women-in-hinduism-conflict-between-swami-dayanand-and-internet-aryas/" data-wpel-link="internal">Women in Hinduism: Conflict between Swami Dayanand and Internet Aryas</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Manu and the Shudras</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 10:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caste System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chandala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand saraswati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lowecaste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[status of shudra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[untouchables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>[This is a 31 page hand written Ms. of Dr. Ambedkar. The chapter has no title. It is also left incomplete. The title is suggested—editor.] I The reader is now aware that in the Scheme of Manu there were two principal social divisions : those outside the Chaturvarna and those inside the Chaturvarna. The reader &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/" data-wpel-link="internal">Manu and the Shudras</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[[This is a 31 page hand written Ms. of Dr. Ambedkar. The chapter has no title. It is also left incomplete. The title is suggested—editor.]
<strong><br />
</strong><span id="more-1632"></span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:330px;">I</h3>
<p>The reader is now aware that in the Scheme of Manu there were two principal social divisions : those outside the Chaturvarna and those inside the Chaturvarna. The reader also knows that the present day Untouchables are the counterpart of those outside the Chaturvarna and that those inside the Chaturvarna were contrasted with those outside. They were a composite body made up of four different classes, the Brahmins, the Kshatriyas, the Vaishyas and the Shudras. The Hindu social system is not only a system in which the idea of classes is more dominant than the idea of community but it is a system which is based on inequality between classes and therefore between individuals. To put it concretely, the classes i. e. the Brahmins, Kshatriyas, Vaishyas, Shudras and Antyajas (Untouchables) are not horizontal, all on the same level. They are vertical i.e. one above the other. No Hindu will controvert this statement. Every Indian knows it. If there is any person who would have any doubt about it he can only be a foreigner. But any doubt which a foreigner might have will be dissolved if he is referred to the law of Manu who is the chief architect of the Hindu society and whose law has formed the foundations on which it is built. For his benefit I reproduce such texts from the Manu Smriti as go to prove that Hindu society is based on the principle of inequality.<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:300px;"><strong>II</strong></h3>
<p>It might be argued that the inequality prescribed by Manu in his Smriti is after all of historical importance. It is past history and cannot be supposed to have any bearing on the present conduct of the Hindu. I am sure nothing can be greater error than this. Manu is not a matter of the past. It is even more than a past of the present. It is a ‘living past’ and therefore as really present as any present can be.<br />
That the inequality laid down by Manu was the law of the land under the pre-British days may not be known to many foreigners. Only a few instances will show that such was the case.<br />
Under the rule of the Marathas and the Peshwas the Untouchables were not allowed within the gates of Poona city, the capital of the Peshwas between 3 p. m. and 9 a. m. because, before nine and after three, their bodies cast too long a shadow; and whenever their shadow fell upon a Brahmin it polluted him, so that he dare not taste food or water until he had bathed and washed the impurity away. So also no Untouchable was allowed to live in a walled town ; cattle and dogs could freely enter but not the Untouchables<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1">[1]</a><br />
Under the rule of the Marathas and the Peshwas the Untouchables might not spit on the ground lest a Hindu should be polluted by touching it with his foot, but had to hang an earthen pot round his neck to hold his spittle. He was made to drag a thorny branch of a tree with him to brush out his footsteps and when a Brahman came by, had to lie at a distance on his face lest his shadow might fall on the Brahman<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2" class="broken_link">[2]</a><br />
In Maharashtra an Untouchable was required to wear a black thread either in his neck or on his wrist for the purpose of ready identification.<br />
In Gujarat the Untouchables were compelled to wear a horn as their distinguishing mark<a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3" class="broken_link">[3]</a>.<br />
In the Punjab a sweeper was required while walking through streets in towns to carry a broom in his hand or under his armpit as a mark of his being a scavenger<a href="#_ftn4" name="_ftnref4" class="broken_link">[4]</a>.<br />
In Bombay the Untouchables were not permitted to wear clean or untorn clothes. In fact the shopkeepers took the precaution to see that before cloth was sold to the Untouchable it was torn &amp; soiled.<br />
In Malabar the Untouchables were not allowed to build houses above one storey in height<a href="#_ftn5" name="_ftnref5">[5]</a> and not allowed to cremate their dead<a href="#_ftn6" name="_ftnref6" class="broken_link">[6]</a>.<br />
In Malabar the Untouchables were not permitted to carry umbrellas, to wear shoes or golden ornaments, to milk cows or even to use the ordinary language of the country<a href="#_ftn7" name="_ftnref7" class="broken_link">[7]</a>.<br />
In South India Untouchables were expressly forbidden to cover the upper part of their body above the waist and in the case of women of the Untouchables they were compelled to go with the upper part of their bodies quite bare<a href="#_ftn8" name="_ftnref8" class="broken_link">[8]</a>.<br />
In the Bombay Presidency so high a caste as that of Sonars (gold- smiths) was forbidden to wear their Dhoties with folds<a href="#_ftn9" name="_ftnref9" class="broken_link">[9]</a> and prohibited to use <em>Namaskar</em> as the word of salutation#.</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p># The following letter will be interesting to the reader as it throws a flood of light as to whether the Dhamia prescribed by Manu was or was not the law of the land-</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p>&#8221; To<br />
Damulsett Trimbucksett<br />
Head of the Caste of Goldsmiths.<br />
&#8221; The Hon &#8216;ble the President in Council having thought proper to prohibit the Caste of Goldsmiths from making use of the form of salutation termed Namaskar, you are hereby pre-emptorily enjoined to make known this order and resolution to the whole caste and to take care that the same be strictly observed.<br />
By order</p>
<p style="padding-left:390px;"> Secretary to Government</p>
<p style="padding-left:390px;"> sig. W. Page</p>
<p>Bombay<br />
9th August 1779.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>                                                              Resolution of Government </strong><br />
<strong>                                                               Dated 28th July 1779.</strong><br />
&#8221; Frequent disputes having arisen for some time between the Brahmins and Goldsmiths respecting a mode of salutation termed &#8221; Namaskar &#8221; made use of by the latter, and which the Brahmins allege they have no right to perform, and that the exercise of such ceremony by the Goldsmiths is a great breach and profanation of the rights of the Gentoo {Hindu] Religion, and repeated complaints having been made to us by the Brahmins, and the Peishwa also having several times written to the President, requesting the use of the Namaskar might be prohibited to the Goldsmiths-Resolved as it i« necessary. This matter should be decided by us in order that the dispute between the two castes may be put an end to, and the Brahmins appear to have reason <em>for</em> their complaint, that the Goldsmiths be forbidden the use of the Namaskar, and this being a matter wherein the Company&#8217;s interest is not concerned, our Resolution may be put on the footing of a compliment to the Peishwa whom the President is desired to make acquainted with our determination.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Under the Maratha rule any one other than a Brahmin uttering a Veda Mantra was liable to have his tongue cut off and as a matter of fact the tongues of several Sonars (goldsmiths) were actually cut off by the order of the Peshwa for their daring to utter the Vedas contrary to law.<br />
All over India Brahmin was exempt from capital punishment. He could not be hanged even if he committed murder.<br />
Under the Peshwas distinction was observed in the punishment of the criminals according to the caste. Hard labour and death were punishments mostly visited on the Untouchables<a href="#_ftn10" name="_ftnref10" class="broken_link">[10]</a>.<br />
Under the Peshwas Brahmin clerks had the privilege of their goods being exempted from certain duties and their imported corn being carried to them without any ferry charges; and Brahmin landlords had their lands assessed at distinctly lower rates than those levied from other classes. In Bengal the amount of rent for land varied with the caste of the occupant and if the tenant was an Untouchable he had to pay the highest rent.<br />
These facts will show that Manu though born some time before B. C. or sometime after A. D. is not dead and while the Hindu Kings reigned, justice between Hindu and Hindu, touchable and untouchable was rendered according to the Law of Manu and that law was avowedly based on inequality.<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<h3 style="padding-left:300px;"><strong>III<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>This is the dharma laid down by Manu. It is called Manav Dharma i. e. Dharma which by its inherent goodness can be applied to all men in all times and in all places. Whether the fact that it has not had any force outside India is a blessing or a curse I do not stop to inquire. It is important to note that this Manav Dharma is based upon the theory that the Brahman is to have all the privileges and the Shudra is not to have even the rights of a human being, that the Brahman is to be above everybody in all things merely by reason of his high birth and the Shudra is to be below everybody and is to have none of the things no matter how great may be his worth.<br />
Nothing can show the shamelessness and absurdity of this Manava Dharma better than turning it upside down. I know of no better attempt in this behalf than that of Dr. R. P. Pranjape agreat Educationist, Politician and Social reformer and I make no apology for reproducing it in full—</p>
<p style="padding-left:240px;"><strong>Peep Into the Future<a href="#_ftn11" name="_ftnref11"><strong>[11]</strong></a></strong></p>
<p>This piece Was written against the Non-Brahmin Parties which were then in power in the Bombay and Madras Presidency and in the Central Provinces. The Non-Brahmin parties were founded with the express object of not allowing a single community to have a monopoly in State Service. The Brahmins have a more or less complete monopoly in the State services in all provinces in India and in all departments of State. The Non-Brahmin parties had therefore laid down the principle, known as the principle of communal ratio, that given minimum qualifications candidates belonging to non-Brahmin communities should be given preference over Brahmin candidates when making appointments in the public services. In my view there was nothing wrong in this principle. It was undoubtedly wrong that the administration of the country should be in the hands of a single community however clever such a community might be.<br />
The Non-Brahmin Party held the view that good Government was better than efficient Government was not a principle to be confined only to the composition of the Legislature &amp; the Executive. But that it must also be made applicable to the field of administration. It was through administration that the State came directly in contact with the masses. No administration could do any good unless it was sympathetic. No administration could be sympathetic if it was manned by the Brahmins alone. How can the Brahmin who holds himself superior to the masses, despises the rest as low caste and Shudras, is opposed to their aspiration, is instinctively led to be partial to his community and being uninterested in the masses is open to corruption be a good administrator ? He is as much an alien to the Indian masses as any foreigner can be. As against this the Brahmins have been taking their stand on efficiency pure &amp; simple. They know that this is the only card they can play successfully by reason of their advanced position in education. But they forget that if efficiency was the only criterion then in all probability there would be very little chance for them to monopolise State service in the way and to the extent they have done. For if efficiency was made the only criterion there would be nothing wrong in employing Englishmen, Frenchmen, Germans &amp; Turks instead of the Brahmins of India. Be that as it may, the Non-Brahmin Parties refused to make a fetish to efficiency and insisted that there must be introduced the principle of communal ratio in the public services in order to introduce into the administration an admixture of all castes &amp; creeds and thereby make it a good administration. In carrying out this principle the Non-Brahmin Parties in their eagerness to cleanse the administration of Brahmindom while they were in power, did often forget the principle that in redressing the balance between the Brahmins and non-Brahmins in the public services they were limited by the rule of minimum efficiency. But that does not mean that the principle they adopted for their guidance was not commendable in the interests of the masses.<br />
This policy no doubt set the teeth of many Brahmins on edge. They were vehement in their anger. This piece by Dr. Paranjpe is the finest satire on the policy of the non-Brahmin Party. It caricatures the principle of the non-Brahman party in a manner which is inimitable and at the time when it came out, I know many non-Brahmin leaders were not only furious but also speechless. My complaint against Dr. Paranjpe is that he did not see the humour of it. The non-Brahmin Party was doing nothing new. It was merely turning Manu Smriti upside down. It was turning the tables. It was putting the Brahmin in the position in which Manu had placed the Shudra. Did not Manu give privileges to Brahmin merely because he was a Brahmin ? Did not Manu deny any right to the Shudra even though he deserved it ? Can there be much complaint if now the Shudra is given some privileges because he is a Shudra ? It may sound absurd but the rule is not without precedent and that precedent is the Manu Smriti itself. And who can throw stones at the non-Brahmin Party ? The Brahmins may if they are without sin. But can the authors and worshippers, upholders of Manu Smriti claim that they are without sin? Dr. Paranjpe&#8217;s piece is the finest condemnation of the inquity that underlies this Manav Dharma. It shows as nothing else does what a Brahmin feels when he is placed in the position of a Shudra.</p>
<h3 style="padding-left:360px;">IV</h3>
<p>Inequality is not confined to Hindus. It prevailed elsewhere also and was responsible for dividing society into higher and lower free and servile classes. (Left incomplete in Ms—ed.)</p>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> Dr. Murray Milchell-Great Religions of India, p. 63</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2" class="broken_link">[2]</a> Bombay Gazetteer. Vol. XII. p. 175.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3" class="broken_link">[3]</a> Ency R.&amp;. E. Vol. IX p. 636 (b).</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref4" name="_ftn4">[4]</a> Punjab Census Report 1911 p. 413</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref5" name="_ftn5" class="broken_link">[5]</a> Bhattacharya-p. 259.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref6" name="_ftn6">[6]</a> Madras Census 1891 .p. 299</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref7" name="_ftn7" class="broken_link">[7]</a> Bhatacharya-Hindu Castes-p. 259.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref8" name="_ftn8" class="broken_link">[8]</a> Madras Census 1891 p. 224</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref9" name="_ftn9" class="broken_link">[9]</a> This mode of wearing dhoties was referred for Brahmins only. The Shudras were to wear it without folds.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref10" name="_ftn10" class="broken_link">[10]</a> G. B. <em>Vom &amp;.Off&#8217;icial Wrling sof Mot Hstuart Elphinst OM.</em> 1884.pp.310-ll.</h6>
<h6><a href="#_ftnref11" name="_ftn11" class="broken_link">[11]</a> Reproduced from-Gujarali Punch-May 1921 (Not quoted in the Ms.—ed.)</h6>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/01/manu-and-shudras/" data-wpel-link="internal">Manu and the Shudras</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
