<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>children &#8211; VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/children/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Truth About Hinduism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Overpopulation</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hindus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overpopulation in india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vedas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; by Sulaiman Razvi India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-7484" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg" width="382" height="322" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-300x253.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-1-768x647.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 382px) 100vw, 382px" /></p>
<p>by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>India is the second most populated nation after China with 1.2 Billion people. Hinduism encourages begetting several sons. Hindus started propaganda against Indian Muslim community, one of them being the population explosion. According to Hindus, Muslims would soon become majority in India. The joke is on you if you believe 14% population would become majority couple of years. I fail to understand why Hindus are so scared of becoming minority? Aren’t Hindus living as minority in Muslim majority countries like Malaysia, Indonesia, UAE and Bangladesh without facing any sort of discrimination which non Hindus face in India? Are they scared that once the become minority they would be treated the same way they treat minorities and Dalits presently in India? On the one hand they spread fear mongering that Muslims would soon become majority but on the other hand they are indulged in changing demographics of states which sizeable Muslim population. Muslims were once a majority community in Jammu and were reduced to minority via ethnic cleansing in Jammu massacre by Kashmiri Hindus more particularly by the Dogra Hindus. Attempts are made to change demographics of Muslim majority Kashmir and same is happening with states like Bengal and Assam which has 30% each Muslim population, these states were excluded from Inner Line Permit which means Hindus coming from Bangladesh and Pakistan would not be settled in any North-Eastern states of India but in these two states Bengal and Assam. It was decided that people with more than 2 children would not get government jobs in Assam, this was cleverly implemented as Hindus as Total Fertility Rate less than 2 in Assam while Muslims have higher than 2. But such law was not implemented in states like Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, Rajasathan… where Hindu fertility rate is higher than 2. Assam Chief Minister from BJP Hemanta Biswa specifically <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/assam-implement-two-child-policy-avail-govt-schemes-cm-himanta-biswa-sarma-1817189-2021-06-20" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">appealed<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> to the Muslim immigrants to adopt family planning. Two Child norm has been implemented in Assam and people with more than 2 children will not be able to avail some government benefits, but this law is not applicable to some Hindu classes such as SC, ST and the Tea tribe. He says he want upliftment Muslims from poverty by implementing the two child policy norm.Family planning has been a issue since independence but Hindutvadis want to implement two child policy norm in states which has Hindu TFR less than national average, two child policy would probably be implemented when Hindu TFR falls below 2.</p>
<p>Without wasting anymore time let’s see what Hindu scriptures says about population control. It is mentioned in RigVed,</p>
<p>Rig Veda 10.85.45 O Bounteous Indra, make this bride blest in her sons and fortunate. Vouchsafe to her ten sons, and make her husband the eleventh man. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="105" class="wp-image-7485" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand1.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-300x52.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p><span id="more-927"></span></p>
<p>Rig Veda 3.24.5 Grant, Agni, to the worshipper wealth rich in heroes, plenteous store, Make thou us rich with many sons. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="601" height="82" class="wp-image-7486" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png" alt="http://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/060114_1818_hinduismand2.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1.png 601w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/http-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-2014-1-300x41.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Grihya Sutra,</p>
<p>Sankhayana Grihya Sutra 1.19.6 ‘Give birth to a male child; may after him (another) male be born; their mother shalt thou be, of the born, and (to others) mayst thou give birth…</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Upanishad,</p>
<p>Khandogya Upanishad, 1 Prapathaka, Kanda 5, verse 4. &#8216;Him I sang praises to, therefore art thou my only son,&#8217; thus said Kaushitaki to his son. &#8216;Do thou therefore sing praises to the breath as manifold, if thou wishest to have many sons.&#8217;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in the Purana that Hindu god Krishna had ten sons from each wife,</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagvatam (Bhagvat Purana) 10.61.1 Sukadeva Gosvami said: Each of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa&#8217;s wives gave birth to ten sons, who were not less than their father, having all His personal opulence.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes on this verse,</p>
<p>&#8221;Lord Kṛṣṇa had 16,108 wives, and thus this verse indicates that the Lord begot 161,080 sons&#8221; He also writes on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19</p>
<p>http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_10.61.1</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>He wrote,</p>
<p>&#8221;&#8230;The birth of a human being is a great science, and therefore reformation of the act of impregnation according to the Vedic ritual called Garbhādhāna-samskāra is very important for generating good population. The problem is not to check the growth of the population, but to generate good population on the level of Vidura, Vyāsa and Maitreya. There is no need to check the growth of population if the children are born as human beings with all precautions regarding their birth. So-called birth control is not only vicious but also useless.&#8221; A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.5.19 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.5.19<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>He also wrote,</p>
<p>“&#8230;In every state all over the world, such activities are encouraged by the government in the form of birth control. Women are supplied pills, and they are allowed to go to a clinical laboratory to get assistance for abortions. This is going on as a result of sense gratification. Actually sex life is meant for begetting a good child, but because people have no control over the senses and there is no institution to train them to control the senses, the poor fellows fall victim to the criminal offenses of sense gratification, and they are punished after death as described in these pages of Śrīmad-Bhāgavatam.” A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 3.30.21 <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_3.30.21<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" data-wpel-link="internal"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-7487" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg" alt="" width="2560" height="2208" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-scaled.jpeg 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-300x259.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1024x883.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-768x662.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-1536x1325.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-2-2048x1767.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></a></p>
<p>Shankaracharya Vasudevananda Saraswati of Badrikashram tells Hindu women to produce 10 children. <a href="http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report-now-shankaracharya-vasudevanand-says-hindus-must-produce-10-kids-for-narendra-modi-to-become-pm-again-2053573<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>https://scroll.in/latest/825148/rss-backed-seer-asks-hindus-to-have-10-children-says-god-will-take-care-of-them-toi</p>
<p>Hindu religious and political leader Sakshi Maharaj asks Hindu women to produce 4 children. <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-30706431<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a><br />
<a href="http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://time.com/3657201/hindu-women-4-kids-sakshi-maharaja/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>‘Hindus should beget four children till Uniform Civil Code is implemented’, says senior priest Swami Govindadev Giriji Maharaj of Bharat Mata Mandir in Haridwar<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindus-should-beget-four-children-till-uniform-civil-code-is-implemented-says-senior-priest-4954128/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Prachi says asked Hindus to have 4 children, not 40 puppies<br />
<a href="http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.news18.com/news/politics/prachi-puppies-sotimam-sot-965076.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How the Gita Press opposed birth control to shore up the Hindu population<br />
<a href="https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://scroll.in/article/750775/how-the-gita-press-opposed-birth-control-to-shore-up-the-hindu-population<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>To save religion, Hindus should follow &#8216;we 2, our 8&#8217; policy: religious guru Swami Prabodhananda Giri<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/current-affairs/010517/to-save-religion-hindus-should-follow-we-2-our-8-policy-religious-guru.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sadhvi Pragya Thakur appeals Hindus to have more children, says she will take care of them.<br />
<a href="https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://www.jansatta.com/trending-news/malegaon-blast-accused-sadhvi-pragya-appeal-to-hindus-that-do-more-babies-i-will-take-care-of-them/581952/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Now, Saffron leaders ask Hindus to have 10 kids to ensure survival of religion</strong><br />
seer Ramanandacharya Raghvachrya said Hindus were facing threat across the world. “Lord Krishna had 16,108 wives and he had 10 children from each of them. The world will be ruled by those who have maximum population. Lord Ram too had asked his brother Bharat to have more sons for protection of the religion“</p>
<p>Slogan of ‘hum do, hamare do’ will not work. Each Hindu family should have at least eight children,” said Kanhaiyya Das, a top priest from Ayodhya.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-others/now-saffron-leaders-ask-hindus-to-have-10-kids/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>Couple hands over 13th girl<br />
</strong> Kamli gave her 13th daughter to the Devarakonda Shishu Vihar.<br />
<a href="http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.deccanchronicle.com/nation/in-other-news/300117/nalgonda-couple-hands-over-13th-girl.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p><strong>One son, 13 daughters and counting — all for another boy</strong><br />
Kanu confesses that her body is now unable to bear the stress of pregnancies.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/gujarat-one-son-13-daughters-and-counting-all-for-another-boy-2773664/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Every Hindu family with five children will get Rs 2 lakh: Shiv Sena<br />
Each family that has five kids between 2010 to 2015 will get Rs 2 lakh.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://indianexpress.com/article/india/politics/every-hindu-family-with-five-children-will-get-rs-2-lakh-shiv-sena/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Produce more children, RSS tells Hindu couples<br />
<a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/other-states/Produce-more-children-RSS-tells-Hindu-couples/article14582028.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Make it 5 kids: BJP leader Shyamal Goswami from West Bengal to Hindu women<br />
<a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/make-it-5-kids-bjp-leader-from-west-bengal-hindu-women-sakshi-maharaj/1/413062.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the same time, there are also demands by leaders like Giriraj Singh and Baba Ramdev to implement two-child policy. Confusing, isn&#8217;t it? Let me explain it to you. Firstly one needs to question them why there&#8217;s a demand for 2 child policy and not 1 child policy?</p>
<p>How much a community reproduces is reflected in the fertility rate. The fertility rate of Muslims is 2.6 while that of Hindus is 2.1. Hindu religious and political leaders are exhorting Hindus to have more babies so that their population may increase, they hope that Hindus will produce more babies if they urge Hindus to have more babies, whereas there are also leaders like Giriraj and Ramdev who don&#8217;t see the possibility of Hindus having more babies, hence they want to implement 2 child policy as Hindus are already producing 2.1 children on average. So basically 2 child policy won&#8217;t affect them and only Muslims would be affected with the implementation. Event was held in Delhi on world population day attended by Hindu leaders and made inflammatory speeches against Muslims, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UnGuY2eFQr8" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Giriraj Singh said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> that &#8220;to tackle declining population of Hindus and to stop the increasing population of Non-Hindus we need a law.&#8221; From his statement, one can easily understand that he wants two-child policy because he is hopeless about Hindus producing more babies.</p>
<p>The day when Hindu fertility rate falls below 1.0 then demand for 1 child policy will grow. Hindu fanatics want others to produce less babies than them, they want others to eat what Hindus wants them to eat, they want others to learn what Hindus wants to teach them, in short, they are enforcing their religion on non-Hindus.</p>
<p>Hindu population in several Arab countries are going to more than double by 2050, imagine if Muslims harass Hindus there like Hindus are unnecessarily harassing Muslims using the bogus myth of Muslim population explosion. As per <a href="https://www.pewforum.org/2015/04/02/middle-east-north-africa/154-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">PEW Research<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, Hindu population in Muslim majority Middle East and North Africa is going to double.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="403" class="wp-image-7488" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-300x189.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s come to Pakistan and Bangladesh. Hindu population is consistently increasing in Bangladesh <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/hindu-population-in-bangladesh-increasing-sushma-swaraj-in-rajya-sabha-5266275/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/Bangladesh%E2%80%99s-Hindus-number-1.7-crore-up-by-1-p.c.-in-a-year-report/article14397035.ece" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> and Pakistan <a href="https://www.indiatvnews.com/news/india/hinduism-fastest-growing-religion-in-pakistan-saudi-arabia-51516.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">1<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/article/current-affairs/hindu-population-in-pakistan-has-grown-at-a-faster-pace-than-in-india-119032600520_1.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">2<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> whereas Hindu fanatics in India are busy peddling fake data of declining Hindu population in Pakistan and Bangladesh. As per Newslaundry Hindus in Pakistan were <a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/2015/01/09/the-vanishing-hindus-of-pakistan-a-demographic-study-2" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1.3% in 1951<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> after mass migration which increased to 1.85% in 1998 as per <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20140402081116/http:/www.census.gov.pk/Religion.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">Pakistan Government Census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, as per official census Hindu population in Pakistan in the year 1951 was 1.6%. According to the <a href="https://tribune.com.pk/story/2119692/1-pakistani-hindus-reject-indias-offer-citizenship/&amp;fbclid=IwAR1qaVQxi3WJOaJ57u4CRTPsxgSqMyi6d4_9CibaH8jKcyilmdNKhjwZ6Vg/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">1961 census<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, the non-Muslim population was recorded at 2.83%. A decade later in 1972, the census recorded non-Muslim population at 3.25% of the total population. That means, it increased by 0.42%. In the 1981 census, the non-Muslim population was 3.30%. In the next census carried out in 1998, it was recorded as 3.70% of the total population. Population after the mass migration should be taken into consideration not post Independence survey. The second wave of mass migration happened in Bangladesh after the 1971 Liberation war. There were approx 33% Muslims in Delhi, 57% in Punjab, 67% in Jammu (before Jammu massacre). Using these figures one cannot say that Muslim population has been reduced to 14%.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2232" height="2560" class="wp-image-7489" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-scaled.jpeg 2232w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-262x300.jpeg 262w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-893x1024.jpeg 893w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-768x881.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1339x1536.jpeg 1339w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-3-1785x2048.jpeg 1785w" sizes="(max-width: 2232px) 100vw, 2232px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Abortion is clearly prohibited in Hinduism</strong>,</p>
<p>Garuda Purana 1.105.48 &#8220;Willful abortion and hatred of the husband are great sins in women without any expiation. Hence, she shall be shunned from a distance.&#8221; Tr. Board of Scholars, edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Parasara Smriti 4.20 What sin is incurred in killing a Brahman, abortion causes a sin twice as great; there is no atonement for that sin. The abandonment of such a woman has been ordained by law.</p>
<p>Gautama Dharma Shastra 21.9. A woman becomes an outcast by procuring abortion, by connection with a (man of) lower (caste) and (the like heinous crimes).</p>
<p>Vasistha Samhita 28.7. Those versed in the sacred law state that there are three acts (only) which make women outcasts, (viz.) the murder of the husband, slaying a learned Brâhmana, and the destruction of the fruit of their womb.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now a days Hindus are mocking Muslims of having ten children which isn&#8217;t true, after reading this will they still criticize Muslims with such taunt? Maharishi Manu also had ten sons,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.2 …and the ten sons of the Manu will be Sukshetra, Uttarnaujas, Harisheńa, and others.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Devi Bhagvatam</p>
<p>Devi Bhagvatam 8.4.1-4 The Risi Narayana said :&#8211; The eldest son of Svayambhuva, Priyavrata served always his father and was very truthful. He married the daughter of the Prajâpati Vis&#8217;va Karma&#8230;He begat ten sons, very spiritual and well qualified and one daughter named Ûrjasvatî….</p>
<p>It is mentioned in Mahabharata,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 1.115 &#8220;Vaisampayana said, &#8216;Meanwhile, O Janamejaya, Dhritarashtra begat upon Gandhari a hundred sons, and upon a Vaisya wife another besides those hundred. And Pandu had, by his two wives Kunti and Madri, five sons who were great charioteers and who were all begotten by the celestials for the perpetuation of the Kuru line.&#8217;</p>
<p>Hindu god Shiva had eight children, Ganesha, Jalandhar, Kartikey, Ashok Sundari, Ayappa, Andhaka, Manasa, and Jyoti. So its not other religion but Hinduism which encourages couple to have more children. Hinduism considers women as a child production machine,</p>
<p>Mahabharata 5.39.67 &#8220;The fruits of the Vedas are ceremonies performed before the (homa) fire; the fruits of an acquaintance with the scriptures are goodness of disposition and conduct. The fruits of women are the pleasures of intercourse and offspring.&#8221; Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Narada Smriti 12.19 Women have been created for the sake of propagation, the wife being the field, and the husband the giver of the seed. The field must be given to him who has seed. He who has no seed is unworthy to possess the field.</p>
<p>Skanda Purana V.iii.103.9-16 “[Atri said]…It is cited by expounders of the Vedas that a woman is one who gives sexual pleasure and a son…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/05/12/hinduism-and-overpopulation-2/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Overpopulation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paedophilia in Hinduism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 17:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immorality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[age of marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arya samaj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child marriage in Hindu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dayanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eve teasing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinduism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homosexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lajpat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lekhram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanatan dharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shraddhanand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[torture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upanishad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yon shushan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zakir naik]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pedophilia in Hinduism (Updated) Written by Sulaiman Razvi Hinduism considers it a sin if the girl is not married before her puberty, it even says that forefathers of the girl shall drink blood of her monthly courses if she isn’t married before puberty. Hinduism also says that marriage of a girl before puberty sanctifies 21 &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Paedophilia in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7649" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.jpeg" alt="https://truthabouthinduism.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/women-child-marriage-paedphilia-facebook_1493731334107.jpg" width="361" height="481" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8.jpeg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/https-truthabouthinduism-files-wordpress-com-201-8-225x300.jpeg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 361px) 100vw, 361px" /></p>
<p>Pedophilia in Hinduism (<strong>Updated</strong>)</p>
<p>Written by Sulaiman Razvi</p>
<p>Hinduism considers it a sin if the girl is not married before her puberty, it even says that forefathers of the girl shall drink blood of her monthly courses if she isn’t married before puberty. Hinduism also says that marriage of a girl before puberty sanctifies 21 generations. Marriage of a Brahmin man with a Shudra girl is censured and Brahmin man marrying a Shudra is considered Vrisalapati and it is considered on par with marrying a girl whose menses has started, a man marrying a girl whose menstruation has started is also considered Vrisalapati. A girl who lives in her father’s house even after her menses begins to appear is considered a degraded girl. Smritis and Puranas says that a 30 years old man shall marry a girl of 12. Swami Prabhupada <a href="https://prabhupadabooks.com/conversations/1977/feb/mayapura/february/27/1977-1?d=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, “Even an eighty-years-old man can marry a sixteen-years-old girl.” This is how Hinduism encourages paedophilia. There is also evidence from Puranas to show that it was practised at the time it was composed. Child marriage and paedophilia was more prevalent in India before the Hindu law were codified. Despite making it illegal, child marriage is still practised,</p>
<p><span id="more-5646"></span></p>
<p>84% Of 12 mn married children under 10 are Hindus (Special to IANS)<br />
<a href="http://www.business-standard.com/article/news-ians/84-of-12-mn-married-children-under-10-are-hindus-special-to-ians-116060101132_1.html" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://www.business-standard.com/article/news-ians/84-of-12-mn-married-children-under-10-are-hindus-special-to-ians-116060101132_1.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>33 per cent of the world’s child brides are in India: Report based on last Census<br />
<a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/33-per-cent-of-the-world-s-child-brides-are-in-india-report-based-on-last-census/story-3qOjffxTckWSpyRNmtyD1J.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/33-per-cent-of-the-world-s-child-brides-are-in-india-report-based-on-last-census/story-3qOjffxTckWSpyRNmtyD1J.html<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>India has second highest number of child marriages as per UNICEF’s 2014 report.<br />
<a href="http://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-asia/46-of-south-asian-girls-marry-by-18-unicef/article6403721.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-asia/46-of-south-asian-girls-marry-by-18-unicef/article6403721.ece<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>As per 2016 report, 30% of women were married under the age of 18 years due to cultural impact.<br />
<a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/explained/child-marriage-women-india-census-data-2011-2826398/" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">http://indianexpress.com/article/explained/child-marriage-women-india-census-data-2011-2826398/<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>71% of those married in Uttar Pradesh are minor girls<br />
<a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/71-of-those-married-in-up-are-minor-girls/articleshow/56695717.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/lucknow/71-of-those-married-in-up-are-minor-girls/articleshow/56695717.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Sexual assault on children is on the rise in India, According to the National Crime Records Bureau a total of 12,363 cases of child rape were reported in the country during 2013 as compared to 8,541 in 2012 accounting for an increase of 44.7%. The maximum child rape cases were reported in Madhya Pradesh (2,112 cases) followed by Maharashtra (1,546 cases) and Uttar Pradesh (1,381 cases). These three states together accounted for 40.8% of the total child rape cases reported in the country.<br />
<a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Online-database-to-name-and-shame-pedophiles/articleshow/46869620.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Online-database-to-name-and-shame-pedophiles/articleshow/46869620.cms<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>But as usual Hindus won’t admit evils which exists in their society or religion and rather puts the blame on Muslims. Hindus says that child marriage were introduced in India by the Muslim invaders. But this claim is refuted by their own scholar Swami Vivekananda who acknowledged that Hinduism permits paedophilia,</p>
<p>“…A girl of eight is married to a man of thirty, and the parents are jubilant over it…. And if anyone protests against it, the plea is put forward, “Our religion is being overturned.” What sort of religion have they who want to see their girls becoming mothers before they attain puberty even and offer scientific explanations for it? Many, again, lay the blame at the door of the Mohammedans. They are to blame, indeed! Just read the Grihya-Sutras through and see what is given as the marriageable age of a girl. … There it is expressly stated that a girl must be married before attaining puberty. The entire Grihya-Sutras enjoin this…” The Complete Works of Swami Vivekananda, Volume 6/Epistles – Second Series/LXXI Rakhal [ <a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_6/Epistles_-_Second_Series/LXXI_Rakhal" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Complete_Works_of_Swami_Vivekananda/Volume_6/Epistles_-_Second_Series/LXXI_Rakhal<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>So now Hindus can’t deny that paedophilia is sanctioned by Hinduism and started because of Hinduism. Swami Prabhupada the founder of ISKCON wrote,</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada writes,</p>
<p>”…As soon as a woman attains the age of puberty, she immediately becomes very much agitated by sexual desire. It is therefore the duty of the father to get his daughter married before she attains puberty…” A.C. Bhaktivedanta Swami Prabhupada on Srimad Bhagavatam 4.25.42 [ <a href="http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.25.42" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://vanisource.org/wiki/SB_4.25.42<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
<p>Another Hindu scholar Sadhguru hints at child marriage,</p>
<p>“It’s a tragic situation. We should realise that we are a society in transition. There was a time when girls would be married at 15. Now they are not married till 25 and 30. So this is the peak of their hormones. In our mindset we are in the past, but in our physical situation, we are in the present. What is causing these rapes? Humans have their needs. If you keep them suppressed, they will do something violent. We need to address this on a much larger scale – hanging rapists or putting them behind bars, that is not the solution. Yes, it needs to be done when it happens. But more importantly as a society, we need to understand why.” <a href="http://www.newindianexpress.com/education/edex/Seven-minutes-with-the-Sadhguru/2016/06/13/article3475994.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">http://www.newindianexpress.com/education/edex/Seven-minutes-with-the-Sadhguru/2016/06/13/article3475994.ece <span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Brahma Purana states that a girl should be given in marriage when she is only four years old,</p>
<p>Brahma Purana: Gautami Mahatmya 95.7 ”After the fourth year and before the completion of the tenth year the marriage of his daughter must be performed scrupulously by the father.” Tr. Board of Scholars, Edited by J.L. Shastri</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7650" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4.jpeg" width="294" height="444" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4.jpeg 1095w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-198x300.jpeg 198w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-678x1024.jpeg 678w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-768x1161.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/08/word-image-4-1016x1536.jpeg 1016w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Rama married six years old Sita</strong></h2>
<p>As per Valmiki Ramayana, Rama is said to have married Sita when she was 6 years old,</p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Aranya Kanda 3, Sarga 47, Verses 3-5 “I am the daughter of noble-souled Janaka, the king of Mithila, by name I am Seetha, and the dear wife and queen of Rama, let safety betide you. On residing in the residence of Ikshvaku-s in Ayodhya for twelve years, I was in sumptuosity of all cherishes while relishing all humanly prosperities. In the thirteenth year the lordly king Dasharatha deliberated together with his imperial ministers to anoint Rama as Crown Prince of Ayodhya. When Raghava’s anointment was being organised my venerable mother-in-law known as Kaikeyi begged her husband Dasharatha for a boon. Restraining my veracious father-in-law by a good deed once done by her in his respect, Kaikeyi besought two boons from him, namely expatriation of my husband, and anointment of her son Bharata. ‘If Rama is anointed now, come what may I will not eat, sleep, or drink, and my life ends this way,’ thus Kaikeyi was adamantine, and the king and my father-in-law entreated her who is nagging with meaningful riches, but she did not make good on that entreaty. My great-resplendent husband was of twenty-five years of age at that time, and to me eighteen years are reckoned up from my birth.” Tr. Sri Desiraju Hanumantha Rao</p>
<p>If we do little maths here we understand that Sita was 18 years old when she went into exile with her husband and before the exile she had spent 12 years with her husband in the house of King Dashratha, so if we deduct the age of Sita at the time of exile (18 years of age) and number years she spent in the house of King Dasharath (i.e., 12 years) we get,<br />
18-12= 6 years old<br />
Sita after marrying at 6, lived in the palace of King Dashrath for 12 years. When she was sent to exile with her husband, she was 18 years old. The age difference between Rama and Sita was 7 years. Skanda Purana clearly states that Sita was married when she was only six years old,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana Book, III, Section 2, Chapter 30, Verses 8-9 “The bow of Isvara that was kept in the abode of Janaka, was broken. In his fifteenth year, O king, Rama married the six year old beautiful daughter of the king of Mithila, Sita who was not born of a womb. On getting Sita, Raghava became contented and happy.” Tr. Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare</p>
<p>Hindu scholars Ramswaroop Acharya Maharaj and Pandit Mahendra Pal Arya says Sita was married to Ram when she was 6 years old.</p>
<div style="width: 1220px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-5646-1" width="1220" height="686" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4?_=1" /><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" data-wpel-link="internal">/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4</a></video></div>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" data-wpel-link="internal">Download</a> this video.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Krishna married eight years old Rukmini and many prepubescent girls</strong></h2>
<p>As per Puranas, Krishna is said to have married prepubescent Rukmini when she was only eight years old. Although Hindu text doesn’t mention the age of Krishna at the time of his marriage with Rukmini but the way Hindu text describes him shows that he was an adult at the time of his marriage with prepubescent Rukmini. And other Puranas also shows his sexual intercourse after marriage which is enough to prove that he was a fully grown man.</p>
<p>As per Skanda Purana when Rukmini was born an ethereal voice told her father Bhishmaka that she should be given in marriage to four-armed one born on earth. When Rukmini reached the age of eight her father became worried about her marriage and about the ethereal voice that commanded him to give his daughter in marriage to four-armed one. Then in the meantime Damaghosa visited him and told him that his son Shishupala is considered four-armed one, then the marriage was fixed but Krishna carried away Rukmini and Rukmini had also fell in love with Krishna on first sight, But while Krishna was carrying Rukmini in chariot, Rukmini’s brother Rukmi stopped Krishna and they both fought each other resulting in Rukmi’s defeat. Krishna was about to kill Rukmi but Rukmini begged to forgive her brother and Krishna forgave him, Krishna tonsured Rukmi as per Bhagvad Purana. Then Krishna called all Brahmins born to sages and marriage ceremony took place. This is the summary of the Skanda Purana story, it’s little bit different than the story mentioned in Srimad Bhagavatam where Swayamvar was arranged and it was attended by many kings, But Srimad Bhagavatm doesn’t mention the age of either Rukmini or Krishna but it does say that Rukmini had not attained puberty at the time of her marriage with Krishna. It’s mentioned in Skanda Purana,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana Book V, Section iii, Chapter 142, Verses 8-79 “…The second child born was a daughter named Rukmini. At that time an unembodied ethereal voice told him, ‘O Bhismaka, this girl should be given to a Four-armed One (born) on this earth.’… As time passed on she became a girl of eight years. The king recollected the words of the embodied being and became worried. ‘To whom shall I give this daughter? Who will be the four-armed one?’… In the meantime Damaghosa, the chieftain of Cedi came there from the excellent mountain Raivata. He entered the royal palace where King Bhismaka was present. On seeing him arrived in the abode, the king duly adored him. He was taken to the Royal Court and given a proper seat. ‘This day has dawned meritoriously. I was eager to see you. O great king, my daughter has come to the age of eight years. The ethereal voice of an unembodied being has told that she should be given to a Four-armed one.’ On hearing the words of Bhismaka, Damaghosa said thus: ‘My son is well known in all the three worlds as Four-armed One (Caturbhuja). O Bhismaka, let this girl be given to Sisupala.’ On hearing the words of Damaghosa, O king, Rumini was betrothed to Sisupala by Bhismaka. The auspicious ceremonial beginning was made by Bhismaka, O Yudhisthira. All the kinsmen and members of the family who were staying far-off countries in every direction, were invited and they duly arrived…At the time of dusk, Rukmini, the bride of seductive charms, went out of the city accomplished by her female companions for the worship of Ambika. There she saw Hari, the Lord of Devas, in the guise of a cowherd. On seeing him, she was excited by the god of Love and became completely fascinated. On seeing her, Kesava said to Sankarsana, ‘On dear brother in my view the excellent jewel of a girl should be taken away.’ On hearing the words of Kesava, Sankarsana said: ‘Go ahead, O Krsna, O mighty one. Let the jewel of a girl be seized quickly. I shall follow you closely behind causing much havoc unto all these demons. On getting the consent of Sankarsana, Kesava, the slayer of Kesin, seized the girl, immediately put her on the chariot and went off…Rukma said: O Lord Kesava, unlucky and sinful that I am, I had hit your chest with arrows. It behoves you to forgive me. Formerly Janaki was given over to you by Janaka himself. Now, O lord of Devas, Rukmini is offered unto you by me. Marry her duly in accordance with the injunctions…When Rukma went back Krsna invited excellent Brahmanas. They were the seven mental sons of Brahma…In this manner the Slayer of Madhu honoured them duly and perfectly and then grasped the hand of Rukmini in marriage.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>So this proves that Krishna married Rukmini when she was only eight years old. Srimad Bhagavatam the most authentic Purana of Krishna devotees explicitly states that she had not attained puberty,<br />
Srimad Bhagavatam Canto 10, Chapter 53, Verse 51 “Beholding that charming princess Rukmini gifted with a beautiful waist, a countenance adorned with Kundalas, not attaining the age of puberty, with a golden mekhala beautifying her waist, with rising signs of womanhood, with moving eyes as if in fear…” Tr. J.M. Sanyal</p>
<p>Another translation,</p>
<p>Srimad Bhagavatam 10.53.51 “Smitten with love kindled (in their breast) by her, the illustrious warriors assembled (there) felt bewildered to behold the princess, who was possessed of a shapely (slender) waist and had not yet attained puberty, and who had a girdle of jewels thrown about her hips and in whom signs of womanhood were (just) manifesting themselves…” Tr. Gita press Publications</p>
<p>A Hindu scholar named Swami Venkatesananda wrote,</p>
<p>“After the wordhip Rukmini took part of the offerings she had made to the goddess, as a token of the goddess’s blessings. She then left the temple and was talking towards the waiting chariot. Rukmini, who was of exquisite beauty though she had not yet attained puberty, looked for Krsna among the assembled princes. These princes, who had been robbed of their senses by her great charm, had for the moment been paralysed, and stood gaping. As she was about to mount her chariot, Krsna sprang forward, grasped her hand and helped her to his own vehicle, while the princes still stood looking on helplessly. However, as Krsna’s vehicle moved towards Dvaraka, the princes, headed by Jarasandha, began to say to one another: ‘What a disgrace: while we great warriors were watching, the cowherds snatched away a princess!” <strong>The Concise Srimad Bhagavatam, By Swami Venkatesananda, page 292, Publisher SUNY Press, 1989</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other Puranic verses shows that she was engaged in child like sports,</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 105.1-10 “…The monarch Bhismaka observed his beautiful daughter engaged in child-like sports and increasing in splendour day by day like a digit of the moon in the midst of clouds. Considering it advisable to marry his youthful and lovely daughter…” Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So all these references proves that Rukmini was a prepubescent girl of eight years old. If anyone wants to refute this claim of mine then they should furnish reference clearly showing the age of Rukmini, other tricks of twisting facts will not be accepted.</p>
<p>Another thing is that, Krishna is said to have married 16100 princesses after liberating them from a demon named Narakasur. Hindu scriptures says that Krishna died in old age.</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 5.37.15-20 states that Krishna lived over a hundred years, some Hindu scholars says that he lived up to 120 or 125. Now please read it carefully, Devi Bhagavatam 2.28.1-23; Padma Purana 1.23.91-121 and Padma Purana 1.23.74b-87a states that Krishna’s 16100 wives were abducted by bandits or fishermen and they were made prostitutes after the death of Krishna, refer my article <a href="/index.php/2018/06/20/how-krishna-died-and-what-happened-to-his-wives/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="internal">How Krishna Died &amp; What Happened To His Wives?</a></p>
<p>Now the question is, why would anyone abduct old women for carnal purpose? There must have been many really young and beautiful girls in the city Dvaraka so why they were not abducted and instead Krishna’s wives were abducted? Obviously only young women would be abducted by perverts so Krishna’s 16100 must have been quite young when they were abducted or let’s assume that they were 30 years old when 100+ years old Krishna died. So let’s assume that Krishna had married them some 10 or 20 years before his death then that means those girls were 10 or 20 years old or perhaps less than 10 when 90+ year old Krishna married them, now such coincidence is impossible that all of 16100 princesses were of the same age there must have been a huge age gap between those princesses, some may have been under 10 when Krishna in his old age married them. So does that mean Krishna in old age married extremely youthful girls?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Shiva’s marriage with Parvati</strong></h2>
<p>Unlike the case of Ram and Krishna where age of brides is clearly mentioned, the case of Shiva’s is little complicated. Hindu texts does say that gods and sages fixed the marriage of Parvati with Shiva when Parvati was only eight years old. But doesn’t state her age at the time of her marriage. As per Puranas, When Sati the first wife of Shiva immolated herself, Shiva promised that he would not wed any other lady. But Sati reincarnated on earth as Parvati the daughter of king Himavat. The story has different versions in Skanda Purana, Shiva Purana and Vamana Purana. I shall mention them all. Stories in Shiva and Skanda Puranas are quite same. First I shall discuss the story mentioned in Shiva and Skanda Purana, I will try to make it as short as possible. Himavat along with Parvati went to Shiva and paid obeisance, while Shiva was meditating. Himavat asked Shiva that his daughter along with maids would serve him but Shiva refused. Sages had told Himavat that Parvati’s husband would be Shiva so Parvati started performing penance to gain Shiva as her husband. The duration of her penance is not mentioned, it could last for few months, a year or say for four years. But that doesn’t make any difference to a eight years old girl. Following verses are about when Parvati had not yet started her penance,</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudra Samhita, ParvatiKhanda, section III.8.51- “On hearing the story from Narada, Parvati bent down her head in bashfulness but her smile heightened the beauty of her face. On hearing the story, the lord of mountains stroked her fondly, kissed her on the head and placed her on his seat.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Placing a girl on seat is possible only if she is a child although previous verses clearly says that she was eight years old, it’s not possible to place on seat a full grown girl. Verses of Skanda and Shiva Purana shows that Parvati was only eight before she went to Shiva abode and later started performing her penance,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana I.i.20.1 “Lomasa said: The chaste girl grew up day by day and shone very much. Living in the house of Himalaya, she reached the age of eight years.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudrasamhita, Parvatikhanda, section III.11.1-2 “Brahma said:- O Narada, the daughter of the mountain, honoured in the three worlds, was brought up in the palace of Himacala. When she was eight years old, Siva distressed by Sati’s separation came to know of her birth. Keeping her wonderful memory within his heart He rejoiced much.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>Shiva Purana, Rudrasamhita, Parvatikhanda, section III.8.4-13 “Himavat said:- O sage Narada…Please read the horoscope of my daughter and tell me about her good and bad fortune. Whose beloved wife will my fortunate daughter be? Narada said: ‘O Mena, O king of mountains, this daughter of yours has all auspicious signs…There is an abnormal line also. Listen to the indication thereof. Her husband will be a naked Yogin, without any qualities. He will be free from lust. He will have neither mother nor father. He will be indifferent to honours. His dress and manners will be inauspicious…O sage, on hearing your words, and inferring that indications reffered to Siva, Parvati’s joy knew no bounds.” Tr. J.L. Shastri</p>
<p>When Shiva was pleased with Parvati’s penance he sent seven sages to Himavat to ask Parvati’s hand in marriage,</p>
<p>Skanda Purana I.i.23.3-9 “Why have all of you come? Tell me the reason for your visit. Then the Seven Sages said: ‘We have been sent by Mahesa. We have come to you in order to see the girl. O Mountain, understand us. Show us your daughter immediately.’ Saying ‘So be it’ to the group of Sages, Parvati was brought there. Himavan, the lord of Mountains, who loved his children, placed Parvati in his lap and said laughingly. ‘This is my daughter indeed. But listen to my words again. Siva is the most excellent one among ascetics. The destroyer of Madana is devoid of attachment. How does he by whom Smara (Madana) has been made Ananga (bodiless), seek a marriage alliance? Offering the daughter in marriage to the following persons is not recommended: one who is very near (i.e. closely related), one who is very far off, one who is extremely rich one, one who is devoid of wealth, one who is unemployed and a foolish fellow. One shall not offer one’s daughter in marriage to a stupid person, to a person who is devoid of attachment, to a self-esteeming person, to a sick man and to a madcap. Hence, O excellent…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p><strong>Ganesh Vasudeo Tagare writes on verse 5:</strong> “Evidence of child-marriage at the time of our text. Parvati who performed penance for a long time, must have been too old to sit in the lap of her father.”</p>
<p>This is a very important point. Parvati along with her father went to Shiva’s abode when she was eight years old, the duration of her penance is not mentioned so let’s assume that she performed penance for a year or let’s say for four years. Considering that her father placed her in his lap even after the penance so she must be very young girl at the time. Another point is that, When Narada and gods approached him and told him that his daughter would marry Shiva he was somehow convinced to give his eight years old daughter to Shiva without thinking about the age difference.</p>
<p>Now let’s have a look at Vamana Purana version about the marriage of Shiva and Parvati.</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 25.1 “Pulastya said Three daughters endowed with beauty and merit were born to Mena and a son named Sunabha was born as the fourth. [5-7] O sage, six years after their birth, the three daughters born to her, went out to perform penance, Gods saw those handsome girls. The austere Kutila who was as beautiful as the rays of the Moon was then taken to the heaven of Brahman by the Adityas and the Vasus. Then the gods said, ‘O Brahman, please tell us whether she will give birth to a son who will slay Mahisa.” Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>Vamana Purana 25.8-27 “The great god Brahman said, ‘This austere girl is not capable of holding the semen of Sankara. Leave this poor girl.’ But then O Narada, the enraged Kutila said to Brahmana, ‘O Lord, I shall so endeavour that I hold the semen of Sankara which is very difficult to be born…She too who was called Ragavati, was brought to heaven by the gods. Offering her to Brahman, Prajapati spoke to her in the same manner. Losing her temper, she too said, ‘Truly I shall undergo penance in such a manner that the slayer of Mahisa will become associated with my name. ‘Then the austere Mena knowing, as she did, that the two daughters had already left her, prevented her third daughter from taking to penance. And she exclaimed ‘Uma (O do not practice penance).’ Her mother the brillaint daughter of the Pitrs gave her daughter the name Uma. She then went to the forest…Then Brahman said, ‘She is undoubtedly the consort of Sankara, by whose lustre indeed you have been distracted and have become lustreless…” Tr. Anand Swarup Gupta</p>
<p>So the gods tried to marry 6 years old girl to Shiva. Swami Parmeshwaranand explains it as,</p>
<p>“Three daughters named Kutila, Ragini and Parvati and a son named Sunabha were born to Himavan by his wife Mena. The three daughters went to the Himalayas for penance, to get Siva as husband. They were not even six years old then. The Devas saw them. The Adityas and the Vasus took Kutila who was doing penance, to the world of the gods. All the gods gathered together and asked Brahma. “Oh Lord, be pleased to tell us if this girl will be able to hear a son who could kill Mahisasura”. Brahma replied. “This poor girl will not be capable of bearing the radiance of Siva. So let her go away.” Kutila got angry at Brahma and said “Lord, I will try to become fit to bear the unbearable radiance of Siva. Harken, I will do penance properly and please Visnu and make Siva bow his head. I take a vow to that effect.” Brahma became angry and told Kutila, “You, wicked Kutila, you did not succumb to my words. So by my curse you will be turned to water.” Kutila having been cursed by Brahma became water and began to flood the world of Brahma. Seeing the flow of water, Brahma made cause-ways on four sides with the Vedas of Rg, Yajus, Sama and Atharva. Thus being tied up she stays in the world of Brahma. The Devas took Ragini also before Brahma and put the same question. The reply of Brahma was the same as before. She also got angry and said to Brahma. “I will do great penance so as to enable to give birth to one in my family to be the killer of Mahisasura.” Brahma cursed her also. “You are deliberately disobeying my words which even Devas won’t gainsay. So you will become the colours of the twilight.” Thus, she became the fast colours of the twilight, and her body was divided among the Pleiades. (Vamana Purana, Chapter 51).” <strong>Encyclopaedic Dictionary of Puranas, Volume 1, p.237, by Swami Parmeshwaranand, Published by Sarup &amp; Sons, 01-Jan-2001</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><strong>Hindu scriptures promoting paedophilia</strong></h1>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.94 A man, aged thirty years, shall marry a maiden of twelve who pleases him, or a man of twenty-four a girl eight years of age; if (the performance of) his duties would (otherwise) be impeded, (he must marry) sooner.</p>
<p>Manu Smriti 9.88 To a distinguished, handsome suitor (of) equal (caste) should (a father) give his daughter in accordance with the prescribed rule, though she have not attained (the proper age).</p>
<p>Parasara Smriti 7.5-6 When the twelfth year is reached by the female child, if the guardian does not give her away in marriage, her fore-fathers drink, without interruption, during each succeeding month, whatever blood is passed in her courses. The mother, and the father, and likewise the eldest brother, all these three relatives will go to hell, if before menstruation they neglect to marry the girl.</p>
<p>Swami Prabhupada <a href="http://www.prabhupada.org.uk/articles1/48_53/48.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">said<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a>, “All my sisters were married within twelve years. My second sister, she became twelve years, and I heard my mother become so disturbed: &#8220;Oh, this girl is not being married. I shall commit suicide…And she was given to a boy, my brother-in-law, for the second marriage. Means that my brother-in-law lost his first wife, and still, he was twenty-one years old. My sister was twelve years old and brother-in-law was twenty-one. In the sastra&#8230; I do not know exactly what is that sastra, but they say that if the girl before marriage has menstruation, then the father has to eat that menstrual liquid. Means it is, mean, very strict. And if the father is not living, then the elder brother has to eat. (break) &#8230;ty of getting the girl married rests on the father. In the absence of the father, the eldest brother. The girl must be married. That is it. It is called daya, kanya-daya.”</p>
<p>Yama Samhita verse 22 “The father, who does give away [in marriage] his maiden-daughter after she has attained the twelfth year, drinks her menstrual blood, month after month.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Padma Prana VI.118.2-15 &#8220;&#8230;A man should marry his daughter as long as she has not attained puberty. Wise men recommend a girl&#8217;s marriage when she is eight years old&#8230;&#8221; Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Krishna Janma Khanda 76.43-52 &#8220;&#8230;Whoever having decorated his virgin daughter aged eight years with apparel reverentially makes a gift of her to a good Brahmin, reaps the benefits of the gift of Durga.&#8221; Tr. Rajendra Nath Sen</p>
<p>Samvarta Samhita verses 66-68 “[A maiden] eight years [old] becomes Gouri; one of nine years a Rohini; and of ten years, a Kanya (maiden); and after that, a Rajasvala (a woman in menses). By seeing a maiden in menses, her mother, father and eldest brother these three go to hell. Therefore one should espouse a maiden before she has menstruated; the marriage of an eight years old maiden is most preferrable.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Vishnu Smriti 24.41. A damsel whose menses begin to appear (while she is living) at her father’s house, before she has been betrothed to a man, has to be considered as a degraded woman: by taking her (without the consent of her kinsmen) a man commits no wrong.</p>
<p>Gautama Dharmashastra 18.21 A girl should be given in marriage before (she attains the age of) puberty.</p>
<p>Baudhayana Dharmashastra, Prasna 4, Adhyaya 1.11 Let him give his daughter, while she still goes naked, to a man who has not broken the vow of chastity and who possesses good qualities, or even to one destitute of good qualities; let him not keep (the maiden) in (his house) after she has reached the age of puberty”</p>
<p>Vasishtha Dharmashastra 17.70 ‘Out of fear of the appearance of the menses let the father marry his daughter while she still runs about naked. For if she stays (in the house) after the age of puberty, sin falls on the father”</p>
<p>Mahabharata13.44.13 “A person of thirty years of age should wed a girl of ten years of age called a Nagnika. Or, a person of one and twenty years of age should wed a girl of seven years of age.” Tr. K.M. Ganguli</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.10.16 “If he marry, he must select a maiden who is of a third of his age.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>Padma Purana II.85.62-66a ”…Wise men get married their unmarried daughter(s). As long as she does not menstruate (i.e. does not attain puberty)…” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Padma Purana II.47.47-65 “…The father should keep his daughter in his house till she becomes eight years old. He should not keep a strong (i.e. grown up) one. Both the parents get the (fruit of the) sin which a daughter, living in her father’s house, commits…” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>Garuda Purana chapter 95 “…”The relations of a girl incur the sin of wilfully creating a miscarriage, or of killing a foetus in the even of their failing to give her away in marriage before she has commenced to menstruate. A girl is liberty to make her own choice, and to be united with a husband, in the absence of any such relation to give her away in marriage…” Tr. M.N. Dutt</p>
<p>Brahmanda Purana 2.3.19.11 “Many sons should be sought so that at least one would go to Gaya, one shall marry a girl of the Gauri type (i.e. of eight years or one who is a virgin) or one shall discharge a Nala (? lean like a red) bull.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Vayu Purana 21.12 “…It is better to wish for many sons. At least one of them will go to Gaya or marry a girl eight years old or discharge a blue ox (free to wander).’ [15] Brhaspati said: A son begot after marrying after marrying a girl of eight years sanctifies twentyone generations. Moreover, he sanctifies six generations in the family of his maternal uncle. This is remembered as the benefit (of such marriage).” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Kisari Mohan Ganguli writes,</p>
<p>“Vrishalipati literally means the husband of a Sudra woman. By actually marrying a woman of the lowest order, by marrying before the elder brother, by marrying a girl that has attained to puberty, and by certain other acts, a Brahmana comes to be regarded as a Vrishalipati.” On Mahabharata 13.126 <a href="http://www.sacred-texts.com/hin/m13/m13b091.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external" class="wpel-icon-right">www.sacred-texts.com/hin/m13/m13b091.htm<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a></p>
<p>Vyasa Samhita 2.2-4 “…of auspicious signs, clad in silken garments, and not above eight years of age, and whose paternal ancestors to the tenth degree in the ascending line were all men of renown, should be solemnly wedded by a (twice-born) according to religious rites, if preferred in marriage. [7] The sin incidental to (an act of) procuring abortion (lie: destruction of the foetus) is committed, if through the negligence of her giver a girl menstruates before her marriage. He, who does not give away a daughter in marriage before she attains puberty, becomes degraded.” Tr. Manmatha Nath Dutt</p>
<p>Skanda Purana VII.I.205.80-86 “If a girl, before being consecrated by marriage rites, has her menses in the house of her father, her Pitrs become fallen and that girl is called Vrsali. If a Brahmana knowingly marries that girl, they say, he is not fit for a Sraddha. He cannot be in the same row as others. He is a Vrsalipati. Gauri virgin is the best and most important. Rohini is considered as Madhyama (middling). Rajasvala should be known as the bases though equal to her (Rohini) image. When there is no menstrual flow, she is Gauri. When there is the flow she is Rohini. If the girlhood has not fully developed she is Kanya. One without breasts is Nagnika. A seven year old girl is Gauri; nine year old is Nagnika. Ten year old shall be Kanya; above that she is Rajasvala. Through breasts she spoils the family of her father and through menstrual flow, she spoils the desirable goal (salvation) and pleasures of the other worlds of her father. He who marries one with menstrual flow should be known as Vrsalipati.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 9.41.26-47 “The World-Mother never stays even for a moment in his house who eats at the house of one who marries an unmarried girl twelve years old in whom menstruation has commenced…” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Above two verses considers the man sinful who marries a girl who started her menstruation in her father’s house which means a person should marry a girl who has not yet started her menstrual period.</p>
<p><strong>Proof that girls as young as 10 were married off</strong></p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 3.27.40 “My daughter has come to a marriageable age; I have no money. Her age has exceeded ten years; the marriageable age limit has been exceeded. Alas! What am I to do?” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Radha the concubine and aunt of Krishna was married to Rayana at the age of 12,</p>
<p>Brahma Vaivarta Purana, Prakriti Khanda, Chapter 49, Verses 36-40 &#8220;In the Varaha-kalpa, Radhika was born in the village of Gokula in the family of a Vaisya cowherd. She was born without any human contact&#8230;After the <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">expiry of twelve years</span>, finding her becoming youthful, <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;">she was married to a trader named Rayana</span>&#8230;&#8221; Tr. Shanti Lal Nagar, edited by Acharya Ramesh Chaturvedi</p>
<p>Devi Bhagavatam 5.17.3-26 “The King Chandrasena, the father, was very pleased to have this beautiful daughter and gladly called her by the name of Mandodarî. This daughter began to grow daily like the phases of the Moon. When she grew ten years old, she became very handsome. The King now became anxious to have a suitable bridegroom and used to think of it everyday. The Brâhmins then told the king that there was a prince named Kambugrîva, the intelligent son of the powerful king Sudhanvâ of Madra” Tr. Swami Vijnananda</p>
<p>Skanda Purana III.iii.18.4-6 “When she was aged twelve years, the girl had beauty of form and all good features. A Brahmana named Padmanabha whose wife had passed away, requested for the haand of the girl. The Brahmana had plenty of wealth. He was calm and qui. He was a permanent companion of the king. So the father of the girl did not dare to refuse. He gave the daughter to him. The marriage was celebrated at midday…” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>Skanda Purana VII.I.166.17-20 “…You are to behave in a manner that will give no cause to the Devas to despise me. My dear daughter, I have heard this cited in sacred scriptures. ‘If without being consecrated (in marriage) a girl discharges her menses in her father’s house the father earns the sin of Brahmana-slaying and the girl is known as a Vrsali (Sudra). Therefore, I am sending you off in the company of aged ministers. Hurry up. Choose your own husband and decide.” Tr. G.V. Tagare</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>RESPONSE</strong></p>
<p>Some Hindus have attempted to refute the above points with futile arguments, so here’s a response to those apologists. I have quoted dozens of verses, several apologists have attempted to refute only 20-30% of the article which means a large part of the article is irrefutable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: According to Rig Veda 10.85.40-41 and Padma Purana V.118.2-15 a girl should be given in marriage only after she attains puberty.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The verse actually states the stages of development of a girl, it doesn’t talk about marrying off daughter only after she attains puberty, in the Atharved it’s a prayer made by a man thanking gods for bestowing riches and sons. A girl can conceive a child only after she attains puberty and that’s what it’s stating here. The apologist has quoted Padma Purana verse out of context (to buttress his RigVed claim) otherwise the verse itself would have refuted the explanation of the apologist, here are the next lines of the verse,</p>
<p>Padma Purana V.118.2-15 &#8220;When small hair appears (on the private parts), Soma enjoys a daughter. When she attains puberty, gandharvas (enjoy her); and when breasts appear (prominent), Fire (enjoys her). <u>A man should marry his daughter as long as she has not attained puberty</u>. <u>Wise men recommend a girl&#8217;s marriage when she is eight years old</u>. She should be duly given to a brahmana who is well-versed in sacred learning, possesses moral virtue, has actually studied Vedas, and has observed celibacy. This is said to be the rule regarding a daughter to be given (in marriage).” Tr. N.A. Deshpande</p>
<p>What is alluded here is that a girl should be given in marriage before she is enjoyed by gods i.e. before she attains puberty, these are Hindu god Shiva’s words. Rigved verses 36-38 indicates that the bride was already married and then she started becoming mature.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: The translation of Valmiki Ramayana about the age of Sita is wrong, here’s the correct translation, “<em>She had been in Ikshwaku dynasty of King Dashratha for <strong><u>two years</u></strong> and got all the materialistic pleasure available for human kind.</em><em> Thereafter, in the <strong>third year</strong>, the king and lord Dasaratha consulted other kings and ministers to consecrate Rama.” </em>The word Dash here doesn’t mean 10 but mentions Dasharath, so Sita’s age at the time of her marriage was 18-2=16 not 6.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The Sanskrit words mentioned in these verses are so simple that even those fluent in Hindi language can define those words. I am quoting the Sanskrit verses,</p>
<p>उषित्वा <u>द्वा दश</u> समाः इक्ष्वाकूणाम् निवेशने |<br />
भुंजाना मानुषान् भोगान् सर्व काम समृद्धिनी ||</p>
<p>तत्र <u>त्रयो दशे वर्षे</u> राज अमंत्र्यत प्रभुः |<br />
अभिषेचयितुम् रामम् समेतो राज मन्त्रिभिः || ३.४७.४-५</p>
<p>The apologist instead of explaining the verses has mischievously mistranslated his scripture. If the word Dasha here doesn’t mean Ten but rather mentions the name of Dasharath then I am eager to know how would the apologist write twelve and thirteen in Sanskrit language? The word Dva means two, Dasha means ten, Varsha means years, which is quite same for the next verse wherein the word Trayo means three. These words are so simple that I don’t find the necessity to quote any lexicon here. In Shiva Purana, Section 1 Vidyesvara Samhita, Chapter 15, verses 42-45 the same word Dva-Dash is mentioned which is translated by all scholars as Twelve. Apologists are conveniently ignoring Skanda Purana Book III, Section 2, Chapter 30, Verses 8-9 which leaves no doubt regarding the age of Sita at the time of her marriage, it explicitly mentions that Sita was 6 years old at the time of her marriage. To convince the apologist, let me quote another verse from Valmiki Ramayana about the age of Sita at the time she was wedded to Rama,</p>
<p>Valmiki Ramayana, Sundara Kanda 5, Chapter 33, Verses 13-14 “I stayed in Rama&#8217;s house there for twelve years, enjoying the worldly pleasures belonging to human kind and fulfilling all my desires. Thereafter, in the thirteenth year, King Dasaratha along with his preceptors started to perform anointment of the kingdom to Rama, a celebrity of Ikshvaku dynasty.” Tr. Desiraju Hanumantha Rao</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After calculating the years mentioned here we get the same number that Sita was 6 years old.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ Claim</strong>: Srimad Bhagavatam 10.53.51 is a mistranslation, the verse nowhere states that Rukmini had not attained puberty at the time of her marriage with Krishna. There’s no word for puberty here.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The Sanskrit words mentioned in this verse are Stanim (breasts) and Vyanjat (budding) which means her breasts had started budding, these words are used as idioms to state that Rukmini had not yet attained puberty, because the breasts of a girl doesn’t start budding when she is a sixteen years old girl (as apologists claim), by the time a girl reaches the age of 16 she becomes an adult. Almost all translators have translated the same.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ Claim</strong>: Skanda Purana Book V, Section iii, Chapter 142, Verses 8-79 cannot be used to show that Rukmini was 8 years old because the Sanskrit words mentioned here are Adashta Varsha in which the word Ada is ambiguous so it may mean anything like she has become twice the age.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: Even the apologist himself is confused, or maybe he is deliberately twisting words in order to cause confusion in the minds of readers. The apologist instead of buttressing his claim with lexicons or texts is rather making assumptions. The Sanskrit words mentioned here are quite clear, words Ashta Varsha means 8 years. This claim of mine about 8 years old Rukmini been wedded to Krishna as per Skanda Purana remains uncontested. Here too I don’t find the necessity to quote lexicons to refute the pathetic claim of the apologist.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: As per Harivamsa Purana Visnuparva 2.59.37 Rukmini was sixteen years old when she was married to Krishna.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: To my knowledge, there are no Sanskrit words in this verse that can be translated as ‘sixteen years old’, though the text describes Rukmini as an adult. Apologist can quote the Sanskrit words which translates as 16 years old.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Apologists also quotes a verse from Brahmavaivarta Purana where Rukmini is described as of having attained puberty. But does that negate Skanda Purana and Bhagavad Purana verses? Does that nullify or refute verses from Skanda and Bhagavad Purana? No, rather they are to be taken as different versions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: The gods and sages didn’t attempt to marry off 6 years old Parvati to Shiva, the reference of Vamana Purana given is wrong.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: This story is mentioned in Vamana Purana, Saromahatmya chapter 25, verses 1-27, following is the screenshot from the scripture,</p>
<p>My emphasis was not on when Parvati was married to Shiva as Hindu scriptures don’t mention the age of Parvati at the time of her marriage. The Hindu gods had already made up that 6 year old Parvati would be able to hold Shiva’s semen i.e., she would be able to conceive the child of Shiva.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-8696" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-300x148.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="296" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-300x148.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1-768x379.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/01/1.1.jpg 808w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: Manu Smriti 9.94; Mahabharata 13.44.13 A man, aged thirty years, shall marry a maiden of ten or twelve. These verses merely tells the man to simply marry a girl younger than him, these shouldn&#8217;t be taken literally.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: Apologists are playing with words to distort their Hindu texts. It’s not a commandment that a man should marry only when he is 30 years old or that a girl should be given in marriage only when she is 10 or 12 years old, and this is what Acharya Medhatithi is also alluding to. A man can marry at the age of 25 given that the girl is very much younger than him, this is already mentioned in Vishnu Purana,</p>
<p>Vishnu Purana 3.10.16 “If he marry, he must select a maiden who is of a third of his age.” Tr. H.H. Wilson</p>
<p>So a 40 year old man should wed a girl who is around 13 years old, if a man is 20 years old then he must marry a girl who is one third of his age that is he must marry a 6 or 7 years old girl and this is exactly what Mahabharata and Manu Smriti states. The apologists are deliberately ignoring the age gap mentioned in Mahabharata and Manu Smriti that a 30 years old adult man should wed a prepubescent girl of 10-12 years who is one third of his age.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote class="quote-light"><p><strong>Apologists’ explanation</strong>: Vishnu Smriti 24.41 makes it clear that only those girls are considered degraded who haven’t given in marriage before they started menstruating, it doesn’t say keeping a married daughter who started menstruating in father’s home is degraded. It is because a girl has to stay in father’s home after her marriage till she completes her third year after she started menstruating, as we seen earlier.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Response</strong>: The author himself seems to be confused, he has acknowledged that “only those girls are considered degraded who haven’t given in marriage before they started menstruating”. As the apologist has admitted it, I don’t find the reason to explain it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/03/paedophilia-in-hinduism/" data-wpel-link="internal">Paedophilia in Hinduism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="https://vedkabhed.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sita-was-6-year-old-when-she-married-Ram.mp4" length="47713340" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hinduism and Talibanism</title>
		<link>/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ved Ka Bhed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 18:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atrocities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurangzeb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[destruction of temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghaznavi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconoclast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jains and buddhists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muslim invader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oppression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persecution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vedkabhed.com/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: MilliGazette ] &#160; Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan? &#160; &#160; Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Mukundan C. Menon [Source: <a href="http://www.milligazette.com/Archives/15042001/Art06.htm" class="broken_link wpel-icon-right" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MilliGazette<span class="wpel-icon wpel-image wpel-icon-6"></span></a> ]
&nbsp;<br />
<span style="color:#0070c0;">Which is more deplorable: destruction of Buddhism in its own birth place in ancient India by Hindus, or of Buddha statues by present day Islamic Talibans in Afghanistan?<br />
</span><br />
<span id="more-5643"></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Two well known academicians of Kerala &#8211; Prof KM Bahauddin, former pro-vice chancellor of Aligarh Muslim and Osmania universities, and Dr MS Jayaprakash, professor of history at Kollam &#8211; throw some deep insights into the dark history of India when Buddhism was systematically eliminated by Brahminical forces who control Hinduism, then and now.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Says Jayaprakash: &#8216;The ruthless demolition of Buddha statues by Taliban has courted severe criticism from different quarters of the world. Surprisingly, the BJP-led Indian Government, supported by all Hindutva forces, also condemned the Taliban action. It is a paradox that the forerunners of the present Hindutva forces in India had wantonly destroyed not only Buddhist statues but also killed Buddhists in India. Therefore, any impartial student of history would unequivocally say that these Hindutva forces have no moral right to criticize Taliban now.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
He elaborates: &#8216;Hundreds of Buddhist statues, stupas and viharas have been destroyed in India between 830 and 966 AD in the name of Hindu revivalism. Both literary and archaeological sources within and outside India speak volumes about the havoc done to Buddhism by Hindu fanatics. Spiritual leaders like Sankaracharya and many Hindu kings and rulers took pride in demolishing Buddhist images aiming at the total eradication of Buddhist culture. Today, their descendants destroyed the Babri Masjid and also published the list of mosques to be targeted in future. It is with this sin of pride that they presently condemn Taliban.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin elaborates the selfish compulsions of Brahminism to wipe-out Buddhism: &#8216;Buddhism tried to create a dynamic society in ancient India. Jainism also contributed its share. As Buddhism spread, iron ploughs and implement were used for development of agriculture. As a result, new areas were cultivated and agricultural productivity increased, apart from developing trade centres and road links. Subsistence-level economy changed to a surplus economy with grain storage facilities, exchange of goods, trade and development of bureaucratic administration. This also created social change &#8211; from elans consisting several families to tribes consisting several elans of similar socio-economic conditions. The emphasis of Brahmins, on the other hand, was for receiving and giving alms and not on production of goods. Those who give and receive alms were close to Gods and those who produce were considered as inferior. According to Manusmriti, a Sudra should not have wealth of his own. In case he has any, a Brahmin as his master can take it over without any hesitation. &#8216;Rigveda&#8217; goes a step further to kill those who do not give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the Brahmins. In other words, someone has to produce goods so that others can give &#8216;danam&#8217; to the recipient Brahmins. It was against this system of &#8216;downgrading those who produce&#8217; that Buddhism came into being.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Recalls Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;The Hindu ruler Pushyamitra Sunga had destroyed 84,000 Buddhist stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. This was followed by the demolition of Buddhist centres in Magadha. Thousands of Buddhist saints were killed mercilessly. King Jalaluka destroyed the Buddha viharas within his jurisdiction on the ground that chanting of hymns by Buddhists disturbed his sleep! In Kashmir, King Kinnara demolished thousands of viharas and captured the Buddhist villages to please Brahmins. A large number of Buddha viharas were usurped by Brahmins and converted into Hindu temples where entry of &#8216;untouchables&#8217; was prohibited. Notably, Buddhist places were regularized as Hindu temples by writing Puranas, which were invented myths or pseudo history. The important temples at Tirupathi, Aihole, Undavalli, Ellora, Bengal, Puri, Badarinath, Mathura, Ayodhya, Sringeri, Bodhigaya, Saranath, Delhi, Nalanda, Gudimallam, Nagarjunakonda, Srisailam and Sabarimala are some of the striking examples of Brahminical usurpation of Buddhist centres.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Detailing the divergence in both orientation and essence between Buddhism and Hinduism, Prof. Bahauddin says: &#8216;Equality, compassion, non-violence, utilization of human abilities for general welfare, etc. were the cardinal principles of Buddhism. According to &#8216;Sathpatha Brahmanam (22-6, 3-4-14), on the other hand, the whole universe is controlled by God, God is controlled by Mantram and Mantram is with Brahmins and, therefore, Brahmins are God (on earth). They used Mantram and Sapam to instil fear in the people to obey them, while Buddhism encouraged people to observe visible facts, to apply reason to get out of fear. Buddhism also encouraged people to do good things, besides guiding Kings to look after the people&#8217;s welfare. Buddhism considers the general welfare of the people, while Brahminism considers that the whole world was created for them all along. And, there is bound to be conflict between these two opposite ways of thinking.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr Jayaprakash, Sakaracharya had played &#8216;a demon&#8217;s role&#8217; in destruction of Buddhist statues and monuments at Nagarjunakonda (in present-day Andhra Pradesh). &#8216;A. N. Longhurst, who conducted excavations at Nagarjunakonda, had recorded this in his invaluable book, Memoirs of the Archaeological Survey of India No. 54, The Buddhist Antiquities of Nagarjunakonda (Delhi, 1938, p. 6). The ruthless manner in which all the buildings at Nagarjunakonda have been destroyed is simply appalling and cannot represent the work of treasure-seekers alone since so many pillars, statues, and sculptures have been wantonly smashed to pieces. Local tradition relates that the great Hindu philosopher and teacher, Sankaracharya, came to Nagarjunakonda with a host of followers and destroyed the Buddhist monuments. The cultivated lands on which ruined buildings stand represent a religious grant made to Sankaracharya.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Quoting Dr. B. R. Ambedkar, Prof. Bahauddin says that the conflict against Brahmin supremacy had, in fact, started before Buddhist period, between Vasishta Muni, a Brahmin, and Viswamitra, a non-Brahmin. &#8216;The dispute was about the learning of &#8216;Vedas&#8217;, the right to conduct religious ceremony, to receive gifts, and to perform coronation of King. Vasishta Muni insisted that these were the exclusive privileges of Brahmins, while Viswamitra was opposed to such exclusive rights. This dispute lasted for long period, and even Kings joined in it (Writings and Speeches of Dr. Ambedkar, vol. 7, p. 148-155. It was won by Brahmins.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin lists the different stages of Brahmin hostility against Buddhism: &#8216;1) 483-273 BC: The period after Buddha&#8217;s death upto Ashoka&#8217;s rule when attempts were made to include Brahminical ideas in Buddhist ideology. 2) 273-200 BC: When Buddhism spread all over India and became a world religion. 3) 200 BC-500 AD: The period when all possible efforts were made to disintegrate Buddhism from within by adulterating Buddhist teachings with Brahminical ideas and also through physical annihilation from outside. As a result, Buddhism divided itself into 18 sects, of which Hinayana and Mahayana were prominent ones. 4) 500-700 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in North India and efforts began to drive out Buddhism and Jainism from South India. 5) 700-1100 AD: Brahminism gained supremacy in South India and, with added vigour, it moved again to North India to obtain complete supremacy over Buddhism and Jainism. 6) 1100-1400 AD: Buddhism and Jainism were destroyed from the remaining Southern States of Karnataka and Kerala and, thus, total supremacy of Brahminism all over India was achieved.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash: &#8216;Within Kerala, Sankaracharya and his close associate Kumarila Bhatta, an avowed foe of Buddhism, organized a religious crusade against Buddhists. A vivid description of Sankaracharya&#8217;s pleasure of seeing people of non-Brahminic faith being burnt to death is available in &#8216;Sankara Digvijaya&#8217;. Kumarila instigated King Suddhanvan of Ujjain to exterminate Buddhists. The &#8216;Mricchakatika&#8217; of Sudraka describes how the King&#8217;s brother-in-law in Ujjain inhumanly tortured the Buddhist monks, by using them as bullocks by inserting a string through their nose and yoking them to the cart! The &#8216;Keralolpathi&#8217; documents the extermination of Buddhism from Kerala by Kumarila. About the activities of Sankaracharya, even Vivekananda had observed: &#8216;And, such was the heart of Sankara that he burnt to death lots of Buddhist monks by defeating them in argument. What can you call such action on Sankara&#8217;s part except fanaticism&#8217; (Complete works of Swami Vivekananda, Vol. III, p. 118, Calcutta, 1997).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, there are hundreds of places in Kerala having names &#8216;palli&#8217; either affixed or suffixed with them. &#8216;Karunagapalli, Karthikapalli, Pallickal, Pallippuram, Edappally, etc. are some examples of these places. The term &#8216;palli&#8217; means a Buddha vihara. Notably, Kerala had 1200 years of Buddhist tradition. Earlier, the schools in Malayalam were called as &#8216;Ezhuthupalli&#8217; or &#8216;Pallikoodam&#8217;. It is also worth noticing that the Christians and Muslims in Kerala use the term &#8216;palli&#8217; to denote their church and mosque alike. These &#8216;pallies&#8217; or viharas had been ruthlessly demolished by the Hindu forces under the leadership of Sankaracharya and Kumarila. They could exterminate 1200 years of Buddhist tradition and converted Kerala into a Brahminical state based on the &#8216;Chaturvarna&#8217; system. Original inhabitants of Kerala, like the Ezhavas, Pulayas, etc., were crushed under the weight of casteism. Many a viharas was transformed into temples and majority of people were prevented from entering temples under the pretext of caste pollution. It can also be noted that the name &#8216;Kerala&#8217; is the Sanskritised Aryan version of the Dravidian and Buddhist term &#8216;Cherala&#8217;. The Parasurama legend is nothing but an invented myth for regularizing the Brahminical &#8216;Kerala&#8217; hiding its glorious Buddhist traditions.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Jainism, too, met with the same fate in South India. Prof. Bahauddin elaborates: &#8216;Very little information is available about growth of Jainism in South India during 300-400 AD. The Jain book, &#8216;Digambara Darsana&#8217;, recounts the starting of a Sangham at Madurai in 470 AD and Jainism became widespread and strong during 500-600 AD (Kumaraswamy Iyengar, &#8216;Studies in South Indian Jainism&#8217;, p. 51-58)….. The Jains used to instal the images of their saints in their religious places, a practice which was followed by Brahmins. Hindu temples appeared all over Tamilnadu probably after converting the Jain religious places. The idols of 63 Brahmin Sanyasis, who led destruction of Jainism, still adorn the walls of some Hindu temples in Tamilnadu. The remains of destroyed Jain idols, their abandoned religious and living places are scattered all over Tamilnadu to narrate their story. Frescos depicting the kings of Jains could be seen on the walls near the Golden Tank at Madurai Meenakshi Temple where, of the total 12 annual festivals, five depict the killing of Jains according to Kumaraswamy Iyengar (p. 78-79).&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
According to Dr. Jayaprakash, a number of Buddha statues have been discovered at places like Ambalapuzha, Karunagapalli, Pallickal, Bharanikkavu, Mavelikara and Neelamperur in Kerala. &#8216;They are either in the form of smashed pieces or thrown away from viharas. Lord Ayyappa of Sabarimala and Lord Padmanabha at Thiruvananthapuram are the proxy images of Buddha being worshipped as Vishnu. Hundreds of Buddhists were killed on the banks of Aluva river. The term &#8216;Aluva&#8217; was derived from &#8216;Alawai&#8217; which means &#8216;Trisul&#8217;, a weapon used by Hindu fanatics to stab Buddhists. Similarly, on the banks of the Vaigai river in Tamilnadu, thousands of Buddhists were killed by the Vaishnava Saint, Sambanthar. Thevaram, a Tamil book, documents this brutal extermination of Buddhism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls the strong reasons to believe that a large section of Jains had embraced Islam: &#8216;The spread of Islam in Tamilnadu can be considered in three or four stages. Islam spread in Kerala and Tamilnadu when Jainism was under pressure (650-750 AD). The new religion was received without resistance…. Since Islam considers every human being with equality Jainism and Buddhism had no conflict with it. When Muhammad ibn Al-Qasim attacked Sindh, the Buddhists supported him because they were facing annihilation at that time. A similar situation was prevailing in South India during 650-750 AD…. Muslims in Tamilnadu are called Anchuvanthar, Labba (teacher), Rauthar, Marakar (sailor) or Jonakan (Yavankan). The Anchuvanam is the guild of traders and groups of artisans. The Muslim mohallas of &#8216;Anchuvan Vamsagar&#8217;, &#8216;Anchuvanathar&#8217;, etc. are scattered all over Tamilnadu and seem to be the en bloc conversion of Jain guilds engaged in different activities, especially weaving. Those who ran away from Tamilnadu settled down in Sravanabalagola and Gomatheswaram in Karnataka. And, those who could not leave due to their economic interests converted to Islam. If we analyze the body structure, food, language, dress, ornaments, customs and habits of Anchuvanthar, it could be see that those are a continuation of Jain way of living and customs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Till recently, the weavers in such Muslim mohallas will not eat at noon or night, and take only one meal before dusk. This was a continuation of Jain habits. There is a separate place in such villages called &#8216;Odukkam&#8217; where Jain Munist used to sit in prayer. On the last Wednesday of the month called &#8216;Odukkathae&#8217; Wednesday, the Muslims gather together to sing religious songs, which is also a Jain tradition. When religious functions like Maulood, Rathif, etc. are organized in the house, a white cloth with lotus symbol on it called &#8216;Mekett&#8217; is tied, which resembles the &#8216;Asmanagiri&#8217; of the Jains…. The architecture of Muslim stone mosques are completely of Jain architecture. The pillars of earlier mosques have practically no difference with the Jain temple pillars. The close relationship between traders and weavers had probably cemented by conversion to Islam. During 950-1200 AD, there were large number of Sufis, Fakirs, wandering poets, singing minstrels, etc. among Muslims all over Tamilnadu. Nadirshah with 500 disciples settled down in &#8216;Trichinopoly&#8217; during 1000 AD. Aliyar Shah and his disciples made Madurai as their centre. Baba Fakhruddin travelled all over Tamilnadu. Nagur became another Sufi centre. The Muslim religious literature of Tamilnadu of that period was least different from those created by Jains and Hindus during the &#8216;Bhakti&#8217; movement.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recounts the spread of Jainism and Buddhism in Kerala, thus: &#8216;Jainism spread in North Kerala around 200 BC. The Jain architectural remains in Canara and Malabar are not available anywhere else in South of Nepal. While Jainism entered North Kerala via Mangalore, Salem, Coimbatore and Wayanad, it entered Southern Kerala from Tirunelveli, Kanyakumari, Nagercoil, Chitharal, etc. The hill near Anamala, which was an important Jain centre, is still called &#8216;Jain Durgam&#8217;. The close-by Kurumala was also a Jain centre. From Anamala through Munnar, Devikulam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor, etc. they reached Neryamangalam, Kothamangalam, Perumbavoor and other places. The &#8216;Kallil Kshetram&#8217; in Perumbavoor is an important Jain monument as also the &#8216;Jainmedu&#8217; in Vadakethara village of Palakkad district. Kerala&#8217;s cave temples at Chitharal, Kallil, Trikur, Erunilamkode (Thrissur district) and Thiruveghapuram (Palakkad district) were constructed during the period of Jain King Mahendra Verman-I (610-640 AD). Temple records of Rameswaram, Sucheendram, Poothadi (Wayanad), Keenalur (Kozhicode) , etc. show that they were part of &#8216;Kunavai Koottam&#8217; during 10-11th centuries. &#8216;Koottam&#8217; is the place of living for Jain Sanyasis. Temple records show that all these present-day Hindu temples were Jain religious places till 11th century. Place names with Kallu, Poothan, Aathan, Kotha, Palli, Ambalam, etc. were all Jain centres. Spread all over Kerala, names of these places show that Buddhism and Jainism were widespread. The famous Kalpathi in Palakkad district was a Buddhist-Jain centre. The &#8216;Ratholsavam&#8217; there is akin to the &#8216;Kettukazhcha&#8217; of Buddhists. The present Bhagavati temples were also Jain temples. The group, &#8216;Adikal&#8217;, had a prominent position among Jains who became &#8216;Pisharadi&#8217; after absorption of Jainism in Hinduism.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
&#8216;Similarly, the Buddhist stoopa at Kodungallore, located in Methala village South-East of Thrikanamathilakam, is an important Buddhist ruin in Kerala…. Mahismathi was the capital of Chera King Satyaputran, which shows the relationship of Chera country (Kerala) with Buddhism. There is a reference in &#8216;Manimekhala&#8217; about a Buddhist Chaityam in Kerala. While Vadakkumnatha Temple at Thrissur and Kurumba Temple at Kodungallore were Buddhist temples, Buddha statues were discovered from Kollam, Alappuzha, Mavelikara, Pallikkal, Karumadi and other places…. Treating mental patients in Thiruvadi temple and leprosy patients in Thakazhi temple shows that they were Buddhist temples since these kind of humanitarian services were not rendered out from Hindu temples…. By 900 AD Buddhism and Jainism were almost wiped out from Tamilnadu. The second settlement wave of Brahmins in Kerala during 900 AD was with Pandyan Kings&#8217; support. Karnataka and Kerala were the only two states where Buddhism and Jainism were still surviving and the second immigration of Brahmins might have been for driving out these two religions from the remaining places.&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Prof. Bahauddin recalls: &#8216;Very few people know that Buddhism and Jainism were the prominent religions of Kerala till 1200 AD. I was also under the impression that Hinduism was in Kerala from the very beginning. When facts were pieced together, a different picture emerged. Only from the end of 1800 AD the evidence became available about Buddha, Buddhism, Ashoka, etc. That fact itself is a pathetic story….&#8217;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Adds Dr. Jayaprakash in conclusion: &#8216;This is what really happened in India, the land of Buddha. But our so-called eminent historians, except a few, are bent upon eclipsing the cruelty done to Buddhists in India. These pseudo historians have succeeded in creating an impression that India is a land of righteousness and toleration. The entire world has been duped by them. The deed on the part of Taliban can be justified on the ground that Islam does not permit idols. But one has to note that Islam does not allow the demolition of other people&#8217;s religious centres and images. Whatever may be the argument for and against Taliban action, the Hindu atrocities on Buddhism in India has no parallel in the entire world history of religious struggle. Let the world know the cruel and crooked face of the &#8216;Indian vulture without culture&#8217;!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/index.php/2014/01/02/hinduism-and-talibanism-3/" data-wpel-link="internal">Hinduism and Talibanism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">VedKaBhed.Com Fast Server</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
